I've learned something new. I've
investigated and learned about what's
called the mouse utopia experiments. And
what I've learned there has changed my
perspective on society forever. And not
in a good way. So I caution you. If you
don't want to learn about what's coming,
turn back now. The mouse utopia
experiments were conducted in the 50s
and 70s when the population of the world
was booming. They wanted to know what
happens when society reaches a certain
limit. What they did was they took nine
mice and put them in a huge enclosure.
This enclosure was the ideal environment
for a mouse. They had habitats. They had
the perfect temperature. They had
infinite food. They had no diseases.
Essentially, they wanted to study how
the population would explode and what
would happen next. Here's the most
curious part about this experiment. The
capacity of this enclosure was 6,000
mice. In other words, 6,000 mice could
live here comfortably. The population,
as you might expect, started to increase
every 55 days. the population doubled.
So that nine mouse that population just
rapidly rapidly increased. How far do
you think it would get to 6,000? You
think it would get to 6,000 and then
decline or do you think it would exceed
6,000? In your mind, think of what that
number would be? The answer is they
never made it that far. They made it to
2,000. An enclosure of capacity 6,000
and they made it only 2,000. And as soon
as they hit the 2,000 mark, their
population started to decline. And it
didn't stop declining. It declined all
the way to extinction. There were no
mice left. So nine mice started in an
enclosure which can capacitate
6,000. They made it to 2,000 and then
they went to zero. This is not good. But
what caused this behavior change? And
there's a name for this. There's a
scientific name for this called
behavioral sync. Mice have behaviors as
all mammals do. The nature of their
behaviors changed as the population
increased and they had more resources
than they knew what to do with.
Specifically, male mice changed their
behaviors to be more like female mice.
Their hormonal states even changed to be
more like that of female mice. Same
time, the female mice started acting
more aggressively like the male mice
would have. Their hormone systems also
changed. As the population increased and
the mice realized there was no dangers,
there was no room for struggle. There
was no reason to be afraid. An
interesting phenomenon arose. An
interesting type of male mouse was born.
This was called the beautiful one. These
were young males who should be at the
peak of life. They should be healthy,
vigorous, and they should be seeking out
mates. But this is not what happened.
They would instead isolate themselves
and focus on one thing which was to look
better. They' focus on grooming. In
other words, these mice would spend all
day preing themsel, looking better,
looking nicer, being more fit, being
more attractive. But for what end? They
were not interested in women. Just the
beautifification of the self. Pure
narcissism. So what does this remind you
of? Is this not at least a little bit
similar to the looks maxing movement?
Now you might think well looks maxing is
different because it's obviously focused
on girls and that is in fact where it
started. It was all about game pickup
and looks maxing. These three were the
holy trinity of the young man back in
2012. But things have changed. The other
two parts of this become less important
and the focus has shifted towards pure
looks. The black pill has emerged
ascendant. The black pill states that in
the end of the day game doesn't matter.
The end of the day behavior doesn't
matter. Just the looks matter. This
phenomenon started with the basics. Go
to the gym, have good hair, have a good
fashion sense, smell nice, be
attractive. But soon it morphed. The
first step in this morph was meuing. The
idea that you can actually change your
facial structure through behavior
patterns. Cool. I'm not against muing,
by the way. I'm just saying this was the
next step. Mewing became a phenomenon,
took off, became a trend to the point at
which even absolutely normal people
living their life know what meing is
which bizarre. Few years ago, like even
5 years ago, nobody knew what that was.
But now everybody knows what it is. But
my prediction is as time goes, 10 years,
bone smashing and these more arcane and
weird types of looks maxing will
actually become the standard and things
like mewing will become milk toast
things which everybody's assumed to do.
There's there's height maxing. The idea
of actually having surgeons cut your
femurss and insert metal rods to
increase your height by a couple inches.
Insane. Especially because yes, you gain
the couple inches of height, but in so
doing, you become less athletically
capable. You can't lift anymore. So,
think about this. So, there are guys out
there who are sacrificing actual
performance for appearance. Disgusting
behavior. All this is pure theaters. all
just pure performance in front of a
camera. It has nothing to do with human
beings. It has nothing to do with actual
human female. And in so far as it does,
it's just pure shallow sex derived from
social media apps or rather I should say
um the dating apps. And the phenomenon
of course I think comes from the dating
apps. On dating apps, there is no game.
There's only copyrightiting in the
description and the actual pictures. So
what do guys do? They just optimize the
pictures. That's the only thing they
care about. How do pictures work?
Pictures work through the eyesight, the
gaze. What's happening is these men are
enraptured. They are cornered and
trapped and ens snared by the female
gaze. This is men who are turned to
stone by women in the same way that
Medusa turns men to stone using her
gaze. Is this not the same as the
beautiful ones in the mice study? These
are mice who didn't care about women
anymore, at least female mice anymore,
but they instead cared solely about the
grooming and becoming pretty. Now, you
might think, well, there's a mouse
experiment doesn't apply to humans. Mice
dumb, humans smart. Well, has it not
already happened? Look at the Roman
Empire. After the Chads of Rome built
the city, I think it was Augustus who
said, "I saw Rome to be a city of brick
and I made it a city of marble." After
those days were passed, what did the
emperors of Rome look like? They were
twinks, illegabilous, literal
It was so funny.
Oh no. Emperor after emperor of Rome was
either a twink or mentally ill and they
brought an entire empire to its knees.
So big picture, what are we looking at?
We have these interesting phenomenon
just emerging. things like the height
maxing and bone smashing which I think
are precursors to the end. These come
about from the extreme information
overload as well as the stimulation
overload. I think it was Nietze who
would just refuse to read books at all
because he didn't want his brain to be
polluted by other people's thoughts. But
for us nowadays, we are polluted by the
thoughts of so many people all the way
from government agencies and the news
also to individuals in social media. I
think step one is to reduce your content
consumption. I want you to choose three
things that you want to improve on.
Maybe it's wealth, health, and
relationships. And choose one influencer
for each who you actually trust and just
follow their stuff. You don't need a
hell lot of perspectives. You need to
first trust your own self. Even more
important than finding influencers you
trust is actually self-experimentation.
Get good at learning how to find truth
for