When you're building LLM applications,
creating evaluators to score how well
your application is doing is a crucial
but often hard part of the job. A common
way to create these evaluators is to
create a prompt and use an LLM as a
judge to score the outputs. That
involves a bunch of prompt tweaking and
trying to guess how it might influence
the the scores that it's generating.
Today we're excited to launch a new
feature called align eval where you can
create an evaluator by clicking here and
then creating it by just labeling data.
And so the way that it works and we'll
go over this in more detail is you just
select experiments to review. You go
through and score them and then you can
quickly iterate against those scores and
be super confident about how your
evaluator is performing. Hello everyone.
My name is Harrison, co-founder and CEO
of Langchain. And today I want to talk
about this new feature that we're
launching in Langmith. So Langmith is
our platform for observing and
evaluating LLM applications. Works with
or without Langchain. And one of the
things that's in there is a really neat
flow for evaluating your agents or other
AI applications. One part of that is
evaluators. And evaluators are
oftentimes code snippets or LLM as a
judge techniques where you use a prompt
to score the output of your original
agent. And so we're introducing a new
way today to create and align these LLM
as a judge evaluators, which is often
one of the trickiest parts of building a
good eval flow. How this works is real
simple. First, we're going to collect
representative sample runs from our
application.
Next, we're going to go through and have
a human expert label these runs. And
then finally, we are going to iterate on
a prompt until it aligns with the human
expert. And by collecting these human
expert labels, we can easily track how
well aligned it is. So, let's see this
in action.
So, here I can see an example task that
I have. It's generating recipes for a
user query. And I can see that I have a
data set. This is 18 examples and I'm in
the playground. So here I can just run
this prompt through the data set and I
can start to see the responses, the
outputs come in.
And so I'm going to let this run and
then I'll open this up in a dedicated
experiment view by clicking on this
button here.
So in this experiment view I can see the
input queries and then the outputs as
well. And so let's imagine for this
recipe generation, I want all of the
recipes to not have any superfluous
adjectives in the title. And so here,
like easy vegetarian stir fry, easy is
probably superfluous. Perfectly cooked
quinoa, perfectly is probably
superfluous. If we go down here, like
garlic butter salmon with roasted
broccoli, that's great. So I want to
create an evaluator that scores whether
these generated recipe titles meet that
criteria. And in order to do that, I'm
going to need to use an LM as a judge
because I'm going to need to use an LLM
to look at the title and determine
whether it contains any superfluous kind
of adjectives. So, how am I going to do
that? So, I'm going to go back to this
data set here. I'm going to click add
evaluator. I'm going to click create
from labelled data. I'm going to now add
a feedback key. No superfluous
adjectives.
And then I'm going to select
experiments. And these experiments are
going to be ones that I label. So, by
default, it will select the most
recently run experiment. That's fine
with me. And I'm going to click this
button, annotate for alignment.
And so, you can see that it's adding
rooms, adding runs to this annotation
queue. And now I'm here. And so, here I
can now label does this have no
superfluous adjectives. This does have a
superfluous adjective classic. So, this
does not meet it. So, I'm going to label
it that way. And I'm going to continue
going on. Refreshing, superfluous. So,
let's label that zero. Grilled
asparagus. Great. Classic beef and
potato skillet. Superfluous. Perfectly
cooked quinoa. Superolous. And so, I'm
going to keep on doing this for the rest
of the labels in this queue. And so, I'm
going to skip through that.
Great. Now, I'm done. And so, once I'm
done, I can now click on to go to
evaluator playground. And this is going
to bring me to a place where I can start
to craft my LLM as a judge prompt that
will evaluate these outputs. So how do I
do that? So I can see I have this
templated thing here replace with
grading instructions and then here where
I format in some of the actual kind of
like outputs that I have. So what I'm
going to say is I'm going to say
something like the following.
So here I have a system prompt that
loosely describes what I want it to do.
Now I'm going to format in the
information that I need from the actual
runs because again remember I'm scoring
these actual runs. And so I don't
actually need the input or the reference
output. What I need is the actual
output.
And I'm just going to call this recipe
here because it doesn't actually need to
know that it's even an example or an
output. And then I'm going to match this
up. I'm going to go
output.output.content.
And so this is going into the message
and choosing the content field.
Now once I've scored this, I can start
alignment. And what this does is it just
runs this prompt over this data set and
then it will tell me how aligned this
LLM as a judge prompt is with my human
labels.
So I can see it running. I can see the
score from the LLM here. And I can see
the alignment. So I see that off the bat
I have 72% alignment. And so I can look
to see where it uh matches or where it
doesn't match. And so I sorted it
alignment ascending. So now this has all
the wrong ones at the top. Let me switch
to compact view so it makes it easier to
skim. And then let me move this so so
you guys can all see. And then I can see
that I have here these five examples.
And so if I open up
one of these given runs, I can see
classic homemade pasta. It doesn't think
that classic is superfluous. If I click
in here, this scores quinoa and chickpea
salad with lemon dressing. Um, and so
I'm not entirely sure what's going on,
but I'm going to add some more
instructions to my prompt based on what
I can see I think is happening. So I
think in the second one it thought that
other things besides the title were
superflous adjectives, but I only care
about what's in the title. So I'm going
to add something like the following.
Only look at what's in the title. Should
be the section starting with double
hashtag. Let me look for a few more
examples of where it might be messing
up. So, grilled asparagus. Grilled is I
don't think that's superfluous. So, I'll
say something like if the title contains
adjectives that relate to how the food
is cooked.
That is not considered superfluous.
Great. So let's now try this again and
see what the alignment is this time.
Okay, so I can see that the alignment's
actually worse. So I can see that it
decreased to 56. Okay, so what are some
of these examples that this just made
worse?
Classic homemade pasta it thinks is
nothing superfluous there. Classic ch.
Okay, so it's messing up on classic. So,
let me add something like anything else
to look at. Classic pepperoni pizza. I
can use these and hot keys to kind of
navigate up or down. So, classic beef
and potato. It's really messing up.
Creamy. Okay. Creamy mushroom soup.
So, this it thought had a superfluous
adjectives, but it I actually Creamy is
how is it prepared. So let's add
something like examples include grilled
and creamy.
Great. Okay. So now let's start
alignment with these things in the
prompt.
Okay. So I'm back up to 78%. Let's take
a look at what's going on. Flowerless co
chocolate cake. That has to do with how
it's cooked. So, I just need to do
another thing like,
and so I'm cheating a little bit because
I'm adding in some specific words that I
know it's using. And in real life, I'd
probably be a little bit more careful
about this is probably overfitting, but
I want to do this for demo purposes.
And also, it's good to have these
examples in there in some form. This is
probably just overfitting.
Chickpea and avocado salad wraps. I
really don't see what it could be kind
of like thinking there. So, so one thing
that I marked is include reasoning. Um,
so what I can do actually is if I click
here, I can look at this
and in the run.
Okay, so it's looking at classic vegan
lentil and veggie soup. Where is that
coming from? I think that might actually
be coming from
Yes. Okay. So here it has multiple
things
but it doesn't actually say classic. So
where
so it's just completely hallucinating.
Okay, so this is a good one to sanity
check because this is just completely
messing up the LLM as a judge is just
wrong. So let me actually switch my
model to use a more powerful model.
Let's switch to O4 Mini. I think this
should be better. And let's restart
alignment. And so I've made a change to
the prompt, but I've also switched the
model that it's using.
Okay, great. I can see that it's now 89%
aligned. There's still a few points
where it's wrong, and I could go and fix
those, but for keeping this video a
little bit short, I'm just going to save
the evaluator here. It's going to save
this.
Now, if I go back to this data set and I
go to the evaluators, I can see that I
have this LM as a judge. And if I now
run a new experiment, so I'm going to go
back to the playground. I'm going to
select my prompt, uh, which is
Harrison's food prompt. And now if I run
this,
I'll see that it first generates the
outputs, but then it's going to use this
evaluator that I defined to score how
well this prompt does on generating set
outputs. And so let's see what comes
back.
Fantastic. So I can see that this prompt
only scores around 22% on this
evaluation metric. And so now if I want
to improve how this prompt does on this
metric, I can just modify the prompt and
rerun. So let's add something like do
not include any adjectives
in the
title that may be
considered superfluous.
And let's rerun this.
Okay, so right off the bat, I can see a
few things. So I can see that I improved
my score to about 77%. But I can also
see that some of these look just wrong.
So here it quick and easy tacos. I would
argue quick and easy is superfluous, but
it's marked as not superfluous. So this
now shows how I can go through this loop
of iterating on my prompt and then but I
also want to go back at times and
iterate on the evaluator as well. So you
can do all this in Langmith. You can you
can edit your prompt. You can create
evaluators. You can modify evaluators.
You can go back improve your prompt. And
and all this is powered by having this
evaluator that's aligned with our
preferences with what we think
superfluous adjectives is. And this new
flow provides a really handy UX for
labeling data and then making sure that
the evaluator is aligned with it. Again,
just to recap, this flow is pretty
simple, but a powerful way to start
quickly onboarding to creating these
aligned evaluators. And big shout out to
Eugene Yan, who's an independent
researcher in the community who created
something called align eval about a year
ago that provided as a lot of
inspiration for this feature in
Linksmith. This feature is generally
available today. So, go ahead and try
it. Thanks for watching.