[Music]
this is a certified Hood classic
I bet when you watch that Gillette ad
four years ago you felt disgusted
frustrated and confused as to why the
producers of that ad are freaking Razer
company which caters to men would
completely misunderstand what it meant
to be a man and then you went to the
dislikes and likes ratio and you
realized you weren't alone in your
frustration you saw that there was a lot
of more dislikes than there was likes
the ratio was something like ten to one
so you realized that you weren't alone
in your hatred and disgust at that ad
and that gave you a sense of calm
because you realized you weren't the
crazy one the company the mega
Corporation Proctor and Gamble who came
up with that ad they were the ones at
fault and you along with all the other
people who disliked that message were at
least together in your disapproval of
that message but now that ad is gone and
the whole dislikes to relax ratio on all
videos is gone of course this is not
news it's been four years something like
that since the likes to listen dislikes
sure was removed you're going to find
out why that really happened and lots
more besides you're going to learn the
basics of psychological operations or
psyops also you might learn how to make
some salmon that's what I'm going to do
today make some salmon and teach about
psychological operations so first thing
the Gillette ad was a psyop the ad did
not try to sell you anything they
weren't trying to sell razors with that
ad they were trying to bring about a
cultural shift using that ad and of
course it was a failed psyop the psyop
was [ __ ] terribly designed it was
stupid and it convinced nobody so it was
a failed sire but it's too blatant
there's two on the nose but that's not
usual if a psyop is well designed you
won't even know it's a Scion so the
first type of psyop is what I call the
ham-fisted approach you know the dumb
approach where the corporations just try
to throw [ __ ] out on the media and hope
that people are convinced by them that's
not a good way you do Scion the second
kind of Scio is the Iron Fist Scion that
is what YouTube did when it removed the
dislikes through likes ratio everybody
hated it everybody understood the
importance of that ratio but but you
couldn't really do anything about it so
that's how I worked but anyway we're
going way too fast when we slow down
make some salmon and yeah I know I know
the Salmon's rubbed in plastic I told
the guy not put in plastic but I guess
he didn't want to listen so let me turn
this thing on there we go got some heat
okay so first thing I want you to
understand sire is not some kind of
Internet term or like some Reddit term
no psychological operations is a real
thing in fact the US Army has a whole
branch called psychological operations
like you can literally go and be trained
as a psychological operations expert in
the US Army that's a real thing
psychological operations have been a
part of Warfare for the longest time I
will teach you what I know about the
topic and I need to get started making
this thing you need man I need my olive
oil all right I got my olive oil there
it is and you might be thinking why am I
cooking Outdoors today well I ask you
why are you cooking indoors today this
is a beautiful day I don't see why I
would be indoors so this is salmon a
fatty fish contains a lot of fat which I
like tastes great has a lot of protein
here's some olive oil another source of
healthy fats because it is a mono
unsaturated that's right timono
unsaturated fat which I'm fine with I'm
cooking with cast iron pan which is of
course the traditional and correct and
aesthetically pleasing way to cook
anything let's look more closely at the
YouTube removing the dislikes button or
rather I should say the dyslex ratio why
did they do that they say and we don't
believe them obviously they say that
they wanted to help all creators with
their mental health [ __ ] they say
that they wanted to make YouTube a more
safe and welcoming place for new
creators so that they would not be
attacked by bullies who would dislike
their videos absolute [ __ ] no small
creators are saying they want to be
protected by dislikes that's another
thing that was [ __ ] from the start
everybody knew it but think actually
what's going on who are they actually
protecting they're protecting not small
creators but rather some very big and
unpopular creators first the
corporations the mega corporations who
put out stupid ads and have bad
messaging and they don't want to be
dislike bombed and made fun of like
Proctor and Gamble with their Gillette
that is one easy example everybody hated
that ad and probably their PR team
realized how damaging it was that's one
just one example then we have Pepsi you
know how Pepsi made that stupid ad with
Kylie Jenner and I believe Kylie Jenner
was you know Waltzing around during a
protest and the whole ad was just stupid
here's your salmon there we go there we
go got some heat
so you put this away
and then we continue talking about
psyops oh this is a big piece of salmon
I didn't want that bigger piece the
bigger the piece it's harder to cook but
that's fine more bigger the beef more
nutrition right so I'm okay with that
you want to actually start on the skin
side
so I'm going to flip it oh yes
the skin side first get the skin going
it's going to become nice and crunchy
always get the salmon with the skin it
just tastes better in my personal
opinion of course first rule of
evaluating psyops is you always look at
the Garment or corporations actions
rather than their words of course words
are wind and you never want to evaluate
a corporation or government activity by
what they say this is also true for
individuals you know if a girl says she
wants to go on a date but she always
makes excuses she's not into your book I
mean even guy friends like if they're
always not let you be a part of their
friend group or whatever it is it's not
your group they don't care about you so
you always evaluate by the actions
rather than the words because words are
wind words are cheap you can say
whatever the [ __ ] you want but when it
comes to acting that's when you have
skin in the game skin in the game a
great book by nathim nicholesterolab you
should read it the reason I know YouTube
doesn't give a [ __ ] about small creators
is they run ads on small creators you
YouTube videos and don't pay them a dime
that's right and you don't have the
ability to turn them off either if
you're an unmonetized Channel meaning if
you have less than 1 000 subscribers and
you don't have 4 000 watch hours YouTube
is still running ads on your videos
whether you like it or not and you don't
have the permission to turn Those ads
off and you want to tell me that YouTube
cares about small creators absolute
[ __ ] but anyway going back to what
actions are like I said actions speak
louder than words right what are the
actual actions YouTube performed who are
they actually protecting first they're
protecting degenerate filled music
videos like freaking Nicki Minaj and
cardi B and all that garbage music it's
more pornographic than it is actually
music they protect that that [ __ ] is not
censored even kids can watch that [ __ ]
and YouTube has no problem with it
because there's money to be made and at
the end of the day it's about the money
boys it's always been about the money
that's one thing the second thing
YouTube protects Legacy Media news CNN
then MSNBC even Fox News to some extent
YouTube protects these big so-called
credible news sources and they put out
you know garbage news half the time they
divide us as a nation they divide us as
a society and that's the [ __ ] which they
want to protect for reasons which go
beyond me well I can I sign my
suspicions but I'm not going to go into
that in this video but either case
Legacy news Medias is what they're
protecting and then they're protecting
of course your White House the White
House produced some videos which I'm not
going to mention which ones which got
massive dislikes to right likes ratio
and of course eventually they removed
that ratio you can't see the ratio
anymore so if you disapprove of
something the government does or
something a big Corporation does you
will be made to feel alone I want you to
understand this very carefully at the
surface level everybody knows that
YouTube is not doesn't care about the
small creators and they care about the
big money interests and the government
everybody knows that that's not news
that's not what the point of this video
is the point of this video is the reason
why they did it is so that you feel
alone in your frustration and your
disgusting get this straight so we all
know that YouTube's on the side of the
big advertising big money government Etc
that's fine I we know that but the
reason why they got rid of that ratio is
so that when you hate something when you
dislike something you don't have the
support of others you don't realize that
you're not alone near frustration all
you see is a number of likes you don't
see the number of dislikes understand
that carefully let me let me give an
example let's just go with the
degenerate filth videos right like Nicki
Minaj or some [ __ ] or even some and or
some bad corporate video you can see how
many people liked it but you aren't able
to see how many people disliked it so if
you dislike it you're alone you feel
alone because you don't realize how many
people actually have your back that's
the actual Psy up here that's the
Sinister and disgusting part of what
YouTube did but YouTube is just a stupid
example like there's far more dangerous
psyops out there which I will try to
deconstruct on this channel but I want
you to understand a lone wolf can be
domesticated that that's why they want
you alone it's easier to subdue you if
you think you're alone and you're
disgust of the stuff which big media big
corporations and big government does so
what's the proof of what I'm saying well
the proof is that the dislike button is
still there think about this for the
first thing as a Creator on the back end
of YouTube I can actually see the number
of dislikes so they're not actually
protecting my mental health so to speak
but more importantly they still have
that dislike button out there we can
still hit it and still dislike a video
but two things first disliking a video
does absolutely nothing it does not
change your YouTube recommendations many
Studies have shown this the second thing
I as a Creator can see the number of
dislikes but even that doesn't do
anything so why do they allow the
dislike button to stay they've removed
the ratio they could just keep the like
button but they had dislike button too
the reason why they have this well I'll
give you a study there's a study done on
mice or monkeys I forget which but they
had a button in their cage and when the
monkey hit the button it would get a
treat and then you know they let that
run for a couple weeks and then they
made it such the treat would fall
randomly when the button was hit so
sometimes when the button was hit the
tree would fall and sometimes when the
button was hit the street wouldn't fall
and sometimes that root would fall
regardless of the button was pressed or
not but the monkeys never stopped
pressing the button for weeks and weeks
they still pressed the button because
they felt that hitting the button
increased their chances of getting the
treat they thought that there was a
cause and effect they thought that they
were responsible they thought that they
had power over their situation which
wasn't the case it was random that is
what the dislike button is you are a
monkey hitting a button which doesn't do
anything like I said in the starting of
this video there's three types of sale
first of the clumsy ham-fisted psyop
like the Gillette ad which doesn't go
anywhere doesn't do anything second is
the Iron Fist psyop like what YouTube
did we knew what was going on but we
couldn't do anything about it because
YouTube owns YouTube you know or rather
I should say Google owns YouTube there's
a third type of Psy up the most
successful type of Psy of the psyob that
you don't even know is going on or at
least the vast majority of people don't
know what's going on and this is the
Sinister stuff this is the stuff which
might get me in trouble maybe I'll give
you some easy examples the sugar
industry literally paid off Harvard
professors and scientists to say that
sugar was good or rather I should say
carbs were good and fats were bad this
is not some Reddit conspiracy theory
this literally happened is documented by
the Howard Department themselves they
themselves owned up to the fact that
they were paid off by the sugar Lobby so
they created this psyop saying that
scientifically proving that carbs were
better than fat that was the ultimate
psyop the food pyramid with ssiop it was
a sire backed by the government probably
more people died because of the food
pyramid and the and the lies around the
food pyramid than the actual well the
possible viral contamination which
spread across the globe and may or may
not have come from any East Asian
country that one I would suggest that
the food pyramid killed more people than
that which I just mentioned so what are
some other examples of the velvet glove
psyop so there's the hand-fisted style
there's the Iron Fist side up and
there's a velvet glove side where you
don't even realize a psyop is going on
I'll use some more examples Tick Tock is
one of them have you ever seen the
Chinese version of tick tock I have a
Chinese friend and I saw his version of
tick tock it's actually not bad like the
content on there is is wholesome I don't
want to forget my my salmon so how do
you know your Salmon's done you can just
prod it like this and you see how it's
all pink inside that means it's not done
yet and by the way since I'm making this
for myself and not for some fancy
restaurant I will happily break my
salmon apart I don't care this is just
for my nutrition and health and taste
anyway coming back to freaking psyops
right so Tick Tock I mean this is also a
known sire but you like you and me we
know that Tick Tock is a psyop right
it's basically Chinese government owns
the freaking platform so they push out
degenerate filth on Western versions of
tick tock while they maintain the
traditional and you know social social
supporting aspects on their own Tick
Tock which is also a psy-op so basically
the Chinese government they want
pro-social behaviors in China right so
their Tick Tock promotes that kind of
behavior that's a sign up on the other
hand we in the west we're freaking dumb
immoral and absolutely untraditional so
where when we have Tick Tock all we see
is degenerate [ __ ] and that prompts our
Behavior to be more degenerate but fine
fine you say that's that's just a boring
example of psyop that's fine everybody
knows it I'll give you another one why
do we have fluoride in our water it's
for our teeth right are you still sure
about that well I'm not so sure and
perhaps I'll make a video about this if
you want that video type down fluoride
in a comment below so I know there's
interest
and then there's the trans fats so have
you ever seen a tub of margarine
it literally says It's Not Butter it's
margarine as though that's a good thing
and people believed it is a good thing
for the longest time because scientists
were paid off by the oil Lobby the seed
oil Lobby I should say to say that trans
fats were healthy for you which is
garbage trans fats are horrible for you
but no and you know how trans fats are
created they literally treat seed oils
which are kind of toxic on their own
with with hexane and hexane is it's a
toxin so this thing the stove runs on
butane or propane I'm not sure hexane is
very similar to butane and Propane in in
terms of chemical structure they use
that to treat a food product and then
they oxidize it and pressurize it and
you create trans fat and they manage to
convince the entire U.S public and the
world's public the trans fats were
actually healthy for you and then today
the current trend is that
polyunsaturated fatty acids so pufa
pufas polyunsaturated fatty acids like
canola oil all seed oils basically they
say that they're good for you American
Heart Association is completely funded
by the seed oil Lobby of course the
American Heart Association is going to
say that seed oils are good for you
they're funded by the seed oils that's
an example of a velvet glove Scion the
general public has no idea that seed
oils are bad for them every restaurant
uses seed oils but anyway that's a
different topic and I'll go into the
topic of seed oils in a different video
if you want that video comment down in
this freaking comment section seed oil
so I know that there's interest in that
topic so how do you protect yourself
from psyops that's the question right
what's the actionable steps well I'll
tell you first thing stop watching the
news freaking pointless the news of
today is just propaganda depending on
who runs the news channel it's divisive
it's useless it's emotionally
manipulative it's utter garbage it's all
done for the sake of keeping you passive
and panicked and makes you feel that you
don't have control over your own destiny
that's the point of news nowadays I
think it's a true waste of time to watch
the news or even read the news at this
point if you have knowledge but you
don't have power to act on it it's
useless I actually got that concept from
the four hour work week by Tim Ferriss
which is another book I would strongly
recommend you see it used to be the case
that you are the sum of the five closest
people to you it's now becoming the case
that you are a sum of the Phi
influencers that you follow the most so
I would suggest choose five to ten
influencers you know YouTubers whatever
you want and then unsubscribe from
everybody else turn on the Bell button
for those five to ten creators it
doesn't have to be me could be whoever
you choose and then only go to YouTube
to watch the videos from those select
select select YouTubers that way you're
not being bombarded by information that
you can't use you're getting information
from sources that you trust and you
aren't being emotionally manipulated
like the mainstream media does that's
your way to avoid all these psyops but
that's not enough because you still need
information so in my upcoming seed oil
video which I do want to make that video
I'm going to explain how I evaluate
what's true so science I'm a scientist
so I understand how that sausage is made
you know I understand the scientific
Community how peer review works all that
stuff science is a tool it's a very very
powerful and effective tool at coming to
the truth but it has its flaws and it's
only one tool in my arsenal of finding
out what is true so that's science I
also rely on philosophy I also rely on
my instinct I also rely on personal
observation of fact but anyway I don't
want to go into that in this video in my
seed oil video if you know if there's
enough interest in it I will go into how
I evaluate what is true going with the
science but also adding other elements
to make sure the design is still
misleading me anyway knowledge is
useless unless you have the power to
change your destiny and power is your
connections and how much money you have
many other things too but connections
and money are two of the big ones and
that's one of the reasons I have created
this YouTube channel I want to make more
money and I want to have amazing
connections with people who also have
power and money I've made connections
with some amazing guy eyes through my
YouTube coaching service if you want to
know anything about that check the link
in the description below but coming back
to this salmon so what's going on here
you see the fats rendering out that's
completely normal I would actually want
to increase the heat but oh I didn't
realize it but the fire had gone out
because of the wind so that's why it's
not done
well my bad so that's that's fine though
it's just a piece of fish it'll cook I
need to actually make this fish now so
what I'm going to do is I'm going to I'm
going to place this here to protect
against the wind some of you might think
I ruined myself and because I shredded
it like this not at all I actually want
every part of the salmon to get some
heat so I'm sure it's fully cooked I'm
not one of the guys who likes my salmon
slightly Raw I don't trust it
fish do have parasites in them sometimes
so I do genuinely want every single
piece of my fish to feel the heat before
I eat it it's just my concern like I
never eat sushi because Sushi literally
has parasites in it sometimes worms like
people who eat a lot of sushi they
literally have worms in their intestines
I do not eat sushi for that reason and
when I'm cooking fish like I am right
now I make sure that I'm cooking it all
the way through I don't give a single
[ __ ] how it looks or how the
presentation is I'm not cooking it for a
restaurant I'm cooking it for myself and
these are the standards which make me
happy make me contented so that's what
I'm gonna go with that's what cooking is
all about cooking is about preparing
nutritious meals that you enjoy you and
your friends and family enjoy it's not
about how the food looks like in the end
and also I should say fish right it's
fish healthy especially from a
testosterone and hormonal point of view
you see I have some bad news for you on
this on this aspect fish is a very very
healthy meal for most of human history
fish has a lot of healthy fats Omega-3s
I'm sure you already know and salmon
especially is a fantastic food until
today until the modern industrial era
until the age of plastic because you see
all the fertilizer runoff goes into the
rivers goes into the Lakes goes into the
ocean all the microplastics Plastics
endocrine disruptors all of it goes into
the lakes rivers and oceans and the poor
fish they consume these it builds up in
their bodies
and they actually have serious
reproductive health issues because of
these endocrine disruptions so fish are
literally born with male and female
reproductive organs so they aren't able
to reproduce happens all the time and
happens across the globe it's really
messed up what's happening to our marine
ecosystem so when we catch those fish
and eat them you know that's not really
healthy for us most of the time so this
is fish you might ask me you know if I
say fish is unhealthy because it's
polluted why am I having fish well two
reasons and also Mercury a lot of fish
is polluted with Mercury salmon is
actually one of the better ones so
that's why I chose salmon but even then
going back to my question if fish is so
bad for you why am I having fish right
well one thing I have fish very very
rarely so I'm minimizing my exposure to
the harmful chemicals present in most
fish the second thing is I don't want to
live in fear you see this channel has
never been about living in fear here
it's about knowledge it's about wisdom
it's about understanding the environment
understanding your food so that you can
make your choices in an informed fashion
I know that this fish probably has some
endocrine disrupting chemicals in it
however there's the highest quality fish
that I could possibly find and it's wild
caught it's not Factory farmed it's
really good salmon so that minimizes my
risk to some extent the other thing is
salmon has a lot of healthy fats which
actually help me in my testosterone
production so to some extent the
endocrine disruption is actually
outweighed by the healthy fats in this
fish so I understand the risks I'm
taking I understand the benefits of this
fish and I do think it's okay to have
high quality fish every now and then
maybe you know once in two weeks or once
in a week that's fine and that's the
level of risk I recommend you take and
again this channel has never been and my
message has never been to live in fear
of plastics and endocrine disruptors
rather the goal has always been to be
educated
and to have the wisdom to understand
with discernment to make your buying
choices and eating choices more healthy
that is not the best looking meal but
I'm not optimizing for looks I'm
optimizing for Taste and
what does it taste like
perfect
this is
salmon
stir-fried
easiest possible food literally no
ingredients just a salmon I added pepper
and salt in the marinade so yeah I did
marinate the salmon so what you got to
do is take lemon juice take your salmon
fillet put it in a glass container put
lemon juice put salt and pepper and I
didn't do this my I asked my butcher to
do it for me so he made it happen here
we are with an amazing plate of salmon
cooked the way I like it and the skin
though the skin is the best part I think
I left my like Fork a knife in the car
so I'm going to get it anyway I had fun
making this video I think I was ranting
a little bit but that's fine see you
next one
[Music]
thank you