they say that hope flation is when a man
today needs to work 20 times harder than
his grandfather to get a girl 20 times
worse than his grandmother but nobody is
talking about Chad flation Chad flation
is when men today need to work 20 times
harder to be just 20% of the man their
grandfather was it appears today we need
to do more work than ever and have less
time than ever and we still don't hit
the Milestones of success that our
grandfathers and fathers did finding a
wife and actually having kids owning a
house going on vacation every year
comfortably these things were considered
average as recently as the '90s in just
30 years Everything Has Changed
certainly there is a political and
economic angle to all this and I will
cover that in future videos but today
we're going to talk about the biologic
and genetic competition the chief tenant
of the religion of the red pill is that
male life is Relentless competition that
if you aren't obsessing over the Holy
Trinity of looks money and status then
you are worthless but is this true is
competition really everything let's look
to Nature let's take a rose plant and
let it grow in a pot with plenty of
sunshine water and soil let's take a
second roast plants that's genetically
identical to the first one and put it in
a pot alongside three other Rose plants
which one do you think will grow taller
which one do you think will produce more
flowers which one do you think will have
bigger leaves which one do you think
will have sharper Thorns the answer is
obvious the plant that has has no
competition the plant that has space to
grow and hone the full use of its powers
the plant that doesn't have to fight for
every scrap of nutrition that's the
plant that's going to win out the rose
plant that avoided brutal competition
for resources was the one with more
Beauty and indeed sexual power in the
form of bigger flowers not only that but
it also has sharper Thorns by which it
can defend itself in other words it's a
superior specimen but we're told that
competition
is always good red pill nerds will often
use evolutionary biology to make their
points without understanding what
they're speaking of they claim that the
purpose of life is reproduction and that
looks money and Status are proxies for
Reproductive success and since the
purpose of life is nothing more than
just reproduction LMS is an indicator of
selfworth again let's look to Nature
what happens when you take Noble
creature like Bengal tiger or snow
leopard of Tibet great elk of the Rocky
Mountains or the gray wolves of Germania
and you put them into an artificial
habitat you can give them everything
they could possibly desire Limitless
food complete protection from predators
you can give them medical care you can
give them new mates but don't have
reproduction noble animals do not
reproduce in captivity any form of
higher life is stunted when it lives in
owned space even mice stop reproducing
in captivity as we see in the mouse
Utopia experiments and we're told that
reproduction is the purpose of life but
it's clear from these observations and
more that we are missing something let's
look at humans in South Korea they have
food they have water they have shelter
they have medicine they have technology
they have all the material means to
reproduce but they're well on the way to
Extinction we're in a bizarre situation
where North Korea and South Korea have
the same birth rate despite radically
different material possessions again I
thought reproduction was the Prime
driver of life is this not true these
are observations that are plain to see
and you do not need to study biology for
6 years to understand that we have a
cultural misunderstanding of what life
is for and what competition does to the
individual life under Relentless Zero
Sum competition does not produce Beauty
in form or function I'm telling you all
this because mindset matters your
internal monologue determines your
overall mental state your interpretation
of Life determines your stress response
your understanding of the purpose of
life shapes your decision making this is
not an abstract philosophy video this is
tied to your life in the Here and Now
obviously a certain amount of
competition in a narrow domain of life
can be a driver towards Excellence I'm
not going to insult your intelligence by
going on about how competition can be
good in sports or business you're smart
enough to know that it's a matter of the
dose makes the poison my central point
is if you believe yourself to be a rat
in a rat race then you are going to have
rat biology you're going to have the
hormonal and neuronal Frameworks of a
rat a prey animal you're going to live
in a scarcity mindset always unsure of
advancement always skittish always
asking for permission we live in the
anxious generation responding to the
pressures of our environment and this
fear of missing out this constant
longing for being respected this is the
biology of the nerd the office Clerk and
the peon there's two ways the mindset of
splits version one that we just
discussed is the rat mentality which is
basically one I'm in competition with
all other men for resources and women
and two my self-worth is determined by
how others see me in comparison to thems
version two what I want to ascribe to is
the lion mentality which is I am an end
onto myself I will take life in my jaws
and two my selfworth is determined by
how I see myself in comparison to my
innate potential both these versions can
absolutely work brutally hard on
themselves and gain success but there is
a difference in the outcome rat
mentality man will always struggle to
find self-worth and will spend his life
looking for self-worth inside his bank
balance or between the legs of women
while lion mentality men is on a
different Quest he's on a quest not for
self- words but rather on a search for
deeper meaning and the unique expression
of his Divine talents
this is a noble life Quest and results
in the building of True Legacy even when
it comes to dating what kind of man sees
dating as brutal competition it's not
the man who gets girls easily the
Carefree man the man who is self-
assured he sees himself as above the
competition and has the competitive
Advantage this is ironic but it's true
I've experienced this myself and I'm
sure you have seen it play out that a
man only gets women when he stops
obsessing over them the whole red pill /
pickup artist space is dominated by guys
who weren't good with women when they
were young so they had to develop these
complicated philosophies and doctrines
by which to unlock some the
success of this movement is dubious
because even when they succeed they fail
their self-worth is determined by how
well they can compete for and
since no matter how good a man's game is
or how much look maxing he does it's not
going to work on every single women and
this chips away at his self-worth and
also his perception of women he's no
longer able to enjoy relationships
because in his mind he's always anxious
always thinking about how the next guy
is going to steal his girl away because
he stopped playing a fake persona or
stop using the perfect dialogues and
tone of voice and all this fake stuff
the guys I know in real life who are
genuinely successful with women to the
point of actually getting married and
planning kids don't think like this they
aren't obsessed about hypergamy and
monkey branching or any of these dark
Concepts they focus on their mission
they focus Fus on their Fitness and they
focus on their Community girls can't get
enough of guys like this and by the way
I uh recently opened up one-on-one
coaching it's a temporary offer so if
you want my help in strategy or
testosterone optimization the link for
scheduling is in the description Peter
teal one of the greatest technology
entrepreneurs of Our Generation on par
with Elon Musk said that competition is
for losers what did he mean by this his
main point was that business that find a
way to provide value in a unique way
will outperform businesses that are in
the blob of the competitive market only
a business that has freed itself from
the day-to-day competition can have a
genuine long-term vision and can afford
to place bets on projects that will bear
fruit in decades rather than months is
this not true of us as men if you have
true faith in your innate ability then
you owe it to yourself to see yourself
as higher than the steaming rat pile of
competition you rise above about the
swarming masses who sacrifice everything
to get a few more points on their exams
or lie on their resume to get the job
you need to find your own unique
competitive advantage and free yourself
from the psychological snare that
society and even your parents might trap
you in now the response to this is well
not everybody has that high level of
innate potential and that is true but
here's the thing only a very specific
type of man or women can watch this kind
of video this is a niche Channel with a
narrow appeal the topics I choose the
vocabulary I use the Aesthetics only
appeal to a certain type of person that
I care about communicating with this
Focus gives me a very valuable audience
from a business perspective it's nice
cuz I can make a good income without
Fame but more importantly I can
confidently say that every man or woman
watching this is guaranteed to be a
person of high potential it's
mathematically impossible for this to be
otherwise for high potential folk
competition is only a tool and it can
only be used to an extent competition is
amazing if you're okay with failure
remember failure is an event not a
person if you can remember this then
competition becomes nothing more than a
tool to hone your skills I'm not against
competition as such just that I believe
that having an antifragile psyche comes
first in fact this is actually part one
of a two-part series the next video I'm
going to share with you a tool called
the ud demonic Compass this tool helps
you make decisions with with confidence
and follow through with conviction this
is important because we all make choices
but in the end our choices make us so
I'll have the thumbnail pop up so you
can watch part two and complete your
knowledge and have access to the
actionable steps