if you already have momentum in your
life if you're already heading towards
your goal trip already destroyed your
limiting beliefs and your addictions
then this is not the video for you this
video is for two types of people the
first if you're stuck in a rut if you're
finding yourself in an endless cycle of
pointless pain and self-sabotage then
you need the hard reset protocol to
break that cycle as a pattern interrupt
and set you on A New Path and the second
group of people is those people who have
a path but they're just going too slow
or perhaps they have lost their
Direction along the way if you have lost
your focus and your purpose then the
hard reset protocol is going to help you
get back on track and reignite the flame
that kept you going in the first place
do you know that quote if you get one
percent every day at the end of the year
you're 37 times better this is the wrong
way of looking at things yes it's a
mathematical truth but has no relevance
to your life you see progress in life is
not a linear function nor is it an
exponential function it's more of a step
function it's very untidy you can and I
have and hundreds of people have changed
the trajectory of their life based on
one event or one day the hard reset
protocol forces a step function forces a
Divergence in your life it gives you a
chance to stop reassess and then move
imagine if you're a Spanish explorator
lost in the woods of the Amazon forest
trying to find the golden city of El
Dorado and you've been walking in
circles you're lost and there's a pebble
in your boot so what should you do right
now should you just continue to walk in
circles hoping for the best in pain or
should you stop take out the pebble from
your boot look at your Maps take stock
of your resources chart a path towards
the goal and make a deliberate move
forward obviously that's what you should
do but most people will go about their
lives in pain going around in circles
without taking stock of the resources
without taking a pause without looking
at themselves objectively and charting a
course for the best possible outcome
this is why I created the hard reset
protocol I created this years ago
actually I've been using it for years
I've created by looking at the great
minds of History I've looked at the
psychology of the human brain I've
looked at military history I've looked
at culture and tradition to come up with
the ideal hard reset protocol through
which you can change the trajectory of
your life but I will give you a word of
caution this is not going to be for
everybody and even if you do manage to
do it you should absolutely not do it
more than two to three times per year
this is a powerful tool which is only to
be used very strategically before we get
started I give you the exact actionable
steps there are five rules that you must
follow rule number one you have to take
this seriously and you have to be
intentional about it otherwise the brain
rewiring is not going to happen and
you're just wasting your time rule
number two I've already said you can
only do this twice or Thrice maybe
maximum four times per year number three
you have to set aside time for this at
least five hours ideally the whole day
number four you must complete every part
of this protocol in order for it to be
effective number five you must be in a
completely fasted state for you to do
this you'll have no food for the
duration of the hard reset protocol you
can of course have electrolytes you can
have water and I have a video talking
about electrolytes but you cannot have
any solid food the hard reset protocol
is four steps and each step has some sub
steps within it I'm going to give you
the exact instructions in the
description below the first step is for
you to buzz your hair I already know
you're having resistance even hearing
the thought you've already decided
you're not going to do it you're going
to go to step two three and four but
hear me out very carefully what if every
military on the face of the Earth from
the beginning of History insists that
their trainees have their heads shaved
from the hopletase of Sparta to the
hastati of Rome from the philangitase of
Alexander to the modern U.S army all
trainees always have their heads shaved
or trimmed or buzzed and what if every
single Monastery of any religion insists
that their acolytes have their heads
shaped why in the movie Fight Club does
Tyler Durden insist that his space
monkeys have their heads buzzed
to some extent this is because in all
these organizations you have to earn the
right to have hair you have to earn the
right to look good and express yourself
it's because you're submitting to
yourself to a time of rewiring and
transformation the only people exempt
from this rule are Sikhs and women if
you want to do the hard reset protocol
you start with buzzing your hair you
need to destroy your vanity and you need
to destroy your ego now you can do this
yourself if you have a pair of flippers
or you can go to the barber I don't care
you're doing this for Spiritual
metaphysical and practical reasons this
is not the time for you to look your
best and woo all the women and flirt
with all the chicks and all this this is
not the time for that this is the time
for you to get to work and another added
bonus is if you watched my hair care
video you know that there's a benefit to
buzzing your hair and then resetting the
cycle and not using shampoo and instead
of using shampoo you should be using
non-toxic non-drying option A herbal
option which I'll link in my Amazon
store below now we go on to step two but
you have to understand you have have to
do step one step one is not optional you
have to buzz your hair and you only go
to step two once you're done with step
one of course you can listen to the
whole video and then enact the hard
reset protocol step two you're gonna
bring to life your heaven and your hell
what you'll do is you'll put all your
devices in airplane mode you'll clear
your desk the only thing on your desk is
a piece of paper and a pen to write with
you're gonna sit down and stare at the
wall in front of you this is not
meditation I don't want you to meditate
this is not the time for mindfulness and
spirituality this is a time for you to
really suffer and feel the pain of
boredom feel the pain of negative
emotions and thoughts in your head let
the demons begin their offensive for you
are in control you are chained to your
desk you will not leave this place until
this task is done you can stand up you
can move a little bit just for the blood
circulation but you are not going to
move away from your desk until this task
is done as you're sitting down on your
desk with your piece of paper and your
pen the negative thoughts and emotions
are going to come at you you'll think
thoughts of how worthless you are you
will think thoughts of how you deserve
to end up lonely you'll think thoughts
of why not just go and watch porn you
have to understand you might be sitting
here for an hour you might be sitting
for two hours you're going to let these
negative emotions seep through your
brains saturate your brain the Demons of
your brain are extremely manipulative
they're going to find the angles of your
brain they're going to find the way to
apply leverage in order to make you move
and do something anything other than
face them head on they'll tell you to be
productive they'll say you're just
sitting down and you're wasting your
time why not go and reply to the emails
why not reply to those DMS why not make
money why not do this and that why not
organize your life why not create the
timetable the schedule for the rest of
your week so many things that you could
be doing but you're just sitting here if
that doesn't work they're gonna hit you
with the pictures of you know past
girlfriends regrets things you fumbled
businesses that didn't go anywhere
arguments that you've had with your
parents all the negative garbage must
come out for you to purge I told you get
a piece of paper and a pen I haven't
told you to start writing yet so listen
you're going to be sitting down you're
going to let these negative thoughts
come to you and then when these negative
emotions have reached their Crescendo
that's when you begin your offensive
that's when you use your pen and your
paper as your tools against this enemy
you see I told you not to use a laptop I
told you to use a piece of paper and a
pen the reason for this is I want your
concentration not to be diffused among
all your fingers on a keyboard I want it
to be concentrated and packed into the
tip of that pen and when you start
writing you are framing your future this
is what you're going to write you're
going to have two pages one your title
as hell and the other as Heaven first we
start in hell you are going to give life
to your hell all the negative thoughts
that you've had all the bad Futures that
you can potentially see I want you to
write down your worst nightmares and
worst fears make it as detailed and
graphic and emotionally painful as
possible this is not going to be easy I
know because I just recently did this
you can see from my hair that I've
already gone through a hard reset
protocol myself my health is failing
this Gambit this gamble I've taken on
making a YouTube business my hell is not
being able to retire my parents because
I decided to take a Gamble and go for
YouTube instead of my fancy engineering
job my health is being alone never
having a Brotherhood of like-minded
young men my hell is never finding the
right girl to start a family with my
hell is never breaking free from the
great game and always being a pawn of
Corporations and government I write
these things in extreme detail I want to
be anxious about this I want to feel
fear I want to feel the shame that I
would feel if I was to go to my parents
and say I couldn't succeed in my
business because too unfocused to do the
effort I want to feel the loneliness
that I would feel if I was to never have
a Brotherhood of like-minded men and
once I'm done with creating my hell I
get up off my desk move around a little
bit get my circulation back I come back
I have my pen I remind myself that the
forces of hell can do me no harm but the
forces of Heaven are with me I remind
myself that the smallest flame can
dispel any Darkness I remind myself that
in my life I am the light in the dark
that I am order amidst chaos and I
remind myself that my character is my
destiny and now I write my vision of
Heaven I write what happens when
everything goes according to plan I
write of a golden future this YouTube
channel has reached tens of thousands of
lives I have rid the minds of hundreds
and thousands of young men and women of
psychological operations have purged
their bodies of toxins and xenoestrogens
I have cut the puppet strings of
corporations in government I've launched
my private Community the country club
and I'm teaching hundreds of people
everything there is to know about health
I'm giving them a classical education
which they were denied in the modern
education system I'm even teaching them
how to set up their own synthesizer
business on YouTube so that they can be
financially free and as my business
grows I'm able to retire my parents I'm
able to live a comfortable life maybe at
some point I find a pretty girl save her
from her soul sucking nine to five and
whisk her off to Tuscany but whatever
your vision of Hell In Heaven is that's
what you write down be detailed be
articulate be even poetic be dramatic
you're a human being filled with life
and creativity let that be shown on
these pages does your vision of Heaven
include travel write down the places you
want to visit write down how it would be
to be in those places the temperature
the smell of street food in the air if
you want to meet a woman describe her
the sway of her hips the color of her
eyes make this real the more real you
can make this the more emotional
resonance it's going to have with you
and more power the hard reset protocol
is going to have overall in your life
once you're done with your writing of
your hell in heaven you're ready to move
on to step number three of the hard
reset protocol now just before I go on
to that if you want a guideline as to
how much you should write you should
write at least one page for hell one
paid for heaven ideally more but that
doesn't mean you have to write a whole
last novel right maybe one to two pages
is what you should be aiming for now
step number three is the rules I'm going
to give you five rules that you must
follow and what you're going to do is
you're going to take another piece of
paper and you're going to write these
rules word for word what I'm saying rule
one I reject my addictions for my dreams
are more important than any Temptation
rule number two I will not numb myself
with entertainment for I have no time
for mediocrity rule number three I will
meditate for 30 minutes every day so
that my mind is worthy of wisdom rule
number four I will engage in at least 30
minutes of exercise per day so that my
body is worthy of my mind rule number
five I will read these rules and my
version of hell and heaven every morning
to remind me of what's at stake these
are the five golden rules that are going
to set you apart from everybody else
most people don't have any rules in
their life you have these five rules you
adhere to these five rules and you tell
me it doesn't make a change in your life
so very briefly I'm going to explain
exactly what the rules are rule number
one says no addictions so no porn no
drugs no alcohol none of that if you
need help with breaking addictions then
I have a video on exactly how to do that
rule 2 says no entertainment so no Tick
Tock no Instagram no YouTube now you can
use YouTube for educational purposes but
you have to install the extensions the
browser extensions which Hamza is going
to recommend in this video which I'm
going to link in the description which
basically makes it such that YouTube is
only for educational purposes rule 3
says meditation for 30 minutes this
doesn't have to be 30 minutes in one
stretch it can be broken up into Parts
throughout the day but it does have to
add up to 30 minutes overall if you
don't know how to meditate that's fine
just literally sit just sit don't even
meditate but you have to do this for 30
minutes and of course I will come out
with a meditation guide soon enough so
you'll know how to do meditation in a
very small amount of time maybe if you
want to hit the Bell button to be
notified you can do that rule 4 says to
do exercise for at least 30 minutes this
can be anything weight lifting running
BJJ I don't care Rule 5 says You must
read your rules and read your
description of Hell In Heaven every
single day in the morning this is
actually a very very underrated rule you
can do all this emotional work all this
mental effort to create these documents
you see these are your foundational
documents but if you don't read them and
you don't have them in your mind every
day there's no point in putting in all
this effort and time I want you to treat
these documents as an Irreplaceable
asset this is not just a piece of paper
with writing on it you have put your
heart and soul and Imagination into this
so every morning when you read these
painful words of hell and these amazing
inspiring words of Heaven it has to have
an emotional resonance with you and
that's what's going to get you to
perform at the highest level every day
you have to read it especially when you
don't want to some days you're going to
feel so motivated that you don't feel
like you need to this is a trick played
by your mind read it and some days
you're going to be so depressed and
inactive that you don't want to read it
it's painful to even read it I don't
care you still have to read it and
finally step four step four is going to
take you the least amount of time but
it's going to be the most important step
you see your step four is a risk step
four your honor is at stake you see
honor it's a sum total of all the
promises that you've made and kept not
only to others but also to yourself and
today you're going to put that honor at
stake at this point you're gonna have
two documents you're going to have your
hell in heaven vision and you're going
to have your rules document at the
bottom of your rules document you're
going to write the exact word which I'm
going to give you you're going to write
the next 12 weeks are going to be a time
of great opportunity or the beginning of
a hellish existence even though I will
be tested I will not be found wanting I
will follow the five golden rules and
this upon my honor I swear and at the
bottom of that you're gonna put your
signature you see this is a binding
document this is a written packed with
with yourself if you break this you're
breaking this upon your honor if you
sign this there's no going back you have
to hold true to your