they are at work right now trying to
conceive the demon that'll consume The
Souls of young men and women the Unholy
Fusion of virtual reality artificial
intelligence and the bassist human
desires and the wonders of the free
market will result in an Abomination
that is almost here I want you to
understand this very carefully the v r a
i porn will be a step change from what
we are already used to it will not be
just the same thing but worse this is
going to be different the current
technology porn isn't even that
effective all it does is destroys your
dopamine circuits which leads you into
its death spiral of continuing addiction
but you can break that circuit and I
explain exactly how to break that
circuit in my video about quitting
addiction with all it really takes is an
understanding of how these circuits work
and how to short-circuit them to our own
benefit but we are AI porn is going to
be different from this it's not just the
dopamine circuits which are affected and
they know exactly what they're doing the
disgusting worms who are making this
stuff right now know full well the
implications on society which is going
to have they know full well the damage
to the brain circuitry the damage to
Society at large which this technology
is going to have but their mindset is
well somebody's gonna do it so I might
as well do it and make money this is the
evil twin the parallel or the mirror
dimension of the mindset of an honorable
man an honorable man's mindset is in
times of danger in times of tyranny an
honorable man thinks somebody's got to
stand up to this and speak the truth it
might as well be me a dishonorable man
thinks but somebody is going to take
advantage of the situation might as well
be me and these are the worms who are
creating this technology right now the
problem with technological progress is
that it gives power not to the men who
have earned it or somehow else have
earned the respect of their peers
technological progress gives power to
whoever can use the technology the best
think about the Zuck there's nothing
honorable about a single molecule of his
body he's not even evil he's just a worm
in any other time in history he would
have just been one more unremarkable
stooge a technological progress has
given him the weapons but now I want to
hone in on the Rai porn do you
understand what is coming artificial
intelligence has gotten immensely better
at understanding and responding to human
emotion it can decipher an individual's
darkest fantasies it can feed you your
worst fetishes and most taboo desires
but that's something which normal
conventional porn can already kind of do
the problem arises because it can also
fulfill you emotionally even the worst
porn addict you know that even even the
guys who actually defend porn kind of
know in the back of their head that
they're getting well gratification
instant gratification and there's no
real emotional resonance there this is
all about to change with the Advent of
VR AI porn for the first time in human
history a technology is going to give
you not only amazing sexual
gratification but also emotional
resonance and this is immensely damaging
this is damaging to the individual of
course but also to the very structure of
society the very foundations of our
marriage the very foundations of a
family are being stabbed and torn into
bits it will be genuinely possible to
have you know artificial mind who not
only fulfills your you do deepest sexual
gratification fantasies but also
responds to you emotionally and meets
your emotional needs and of course the
opposite is also true and also it gets
worse because the actual human physical
women are being lobotomized by Tech talk
and social media and porn so the
competition is actually real VR AI porn
could be actually better than a large
fraction of human physical females and
of course the opposite is also true most
men are simply unable to satisfy the
base desires of a woman they're simply
inequipped to deal with her physically
and are not knowledgeable or even
developed enough to deal with her
emotional hurricane but a Rai porn model
could do that and this is something that
you probably don't know is a lot of
women are desensitized to clitoral
stimulation because they use their
vibrators so much they're desensitized a
real physical man couldn't even give her
a real clitoral orgasm because they're
so hyper stimulated by you know the
freaking toy the vibrator of course at
present the problem is not that bad real
women do prefer Real Men Real Men do
prefer real women but how long is this
assumption true you are probably
familiar with the idea of the sexual
Marketplace the idea that it's a kind of
a free market and every individual has a
score essentially which is based on
their looks money and status and of
course the different men are competing
for the best women different women are
competing for the best men it's kind of
this economical problem but what happens
when you introduce a competitor into
this space who is objectively better
than any woman or any man and is always
available without any Hang-Ups zero
emotional baggage of its own a
technology a technology which competes
in the sexual Marketplace this has not
happened yet porn is not a real
competitor in the sexual Marketplace but
we are AI porn could genuinely be a
competitor in the sexual Marketplace and
thinking of it from an economics point
of view what happened to the horse
carriage industry when cars were first
created what happened to typewriters
when computers were invented what
happened to traditional handmade clothes
when the loom was invented and what
happened to the monasteries which will
actually write books by hand when the
printing press arrived every time when a
superior technology competes in an
existing Marketplace the existing
Marketplace either changes radically or
is destroyed so I genuinely fear for
what happens in the sexual Marketplace
when a technology is involved which is a
genuine competitor to most average
people you and me we aspire to be the
top of the food chain in this
Marketplace and we want to score with
the top of the food chain among females
in this Marketplace we want a 1 wife who
is genuinely one of the best of the
females and of course these women are
seeking the best of the males but the
fact of this is it's a competition and
only at the 10 top males and the 10 top
females are going to be in the top it's
a zero-sum game so what happens to
everybody else where the technology is
involved it's tempting to say the 10 top
will be fine because they're not
affected but that's not true this
technology has the power to disrupt
Society at a large scale caused the
increase in divorce rates genuinely I
think that men will leave their wives
and wives will leave their husbands for
this technology that's why this
technology needs to be banned right now
I want the people who are developing
this technology not to make a single
dollar from their efforts any company
trying to fuse VR Ai and pornography
needs to be destroyed as for actionable
steps so to what you need to do right
now you need to fix yourself right now
you need to fix yourself mentally
physically spiritually you need to let
go of any addictions that you're still
carrying with you if you're still
addicted to porn in 2023
that's not acceptable anymore you see
the prison walls are getting higher if
you're addicted to Conventional porn
right now what's going to happen is at
some point you are going to acquire the
next technology you're going to acquire
VR AI porn and that's going to keep you
in prison for the rest of your life so
you need to break free from the
addiction right now before the
technology materializes not only that
you can Safeguard your own mind but also
that of your future children now is the
last chance before the technology is
revealed you need to break free from
your addictions right now I think I can
contribute I can think I can help you
I've made a whole video on how to break
any addiction but especially focusing on
porn addiction so if you're still being
affected by this that is the video you
need to go to you need to watch it and
take those actionable steps you see just
as they are creating weapons to enslave
Humanity we are coming up with counter
weapons we are coming up with media
videos like this one we're coming up
with books like your brain on porn we as
a society are reacting we are kind of
arming ourselves against the technology
as we speak and I believe my video on
erasing porn addiction is one small part
of this the only thing I know is
Humanity will not go down without a
fight