the morning is not something that
happens it's something you do your balls
will literally get bigger if you follow
this guide most people don't know this
but literally every single cell in your
body has a little clock and when these
little clocks get out of sync that's
when you feel like [ __ ] that's why when
you go to a new time zone you might have
digestive issues you might have brain
fog you might get sick more easily most
people live their entire lives feeling
like [ __ ] because they don't know the
importance of sinking their clocks and
most people don't know that their skin
is literally the biggest endocrine organ
in the entire body literally getting
sunlight on your skin increases your
testosterone production and your
dopamine levels what does that mean it
means that not only become more manly in
the sense that you have bigger balls
bigger shaft more aggressive more muscle
Etc you also have more dopamine which
means you're much better much much
better at goal Pursuit so whether you're
striving for success in like Finance or
women or sports or whatever it is the
dopamine gold Pursuit angle is going to
make you far more successful than
anybody around you that's because
dopamine is not the molecule of pleasure
dopamine is the molecule of Drive of
Forward Motion it's the molecule of
satisfaction and happiness when you
achieve the goal that you set out to as
important as increasing testosterone is
increasing your Baseline dopamine level
because that alongside with testosterone
is going to take you to a whole
different level and if you're a woman
it's even more important for you because
the sunlight is going to help you
regulate your sleep cycles and that's
going to help you regulate your
menstrual cycle and that is the sacred
source of your feminine power very
interesting then that the sun has been
so demonized they make you think that as
soon as you step out in the sun if
you're not wearing sunglasses and like a
pound of sunscreen you'll immediately
Sprout tumors like freaking Deadpool so
you need to get outside first thing in
the morning because what it's going to
do is it's going to purge your brain off
the Sleep chemicals and not only that
but it's also going to give you a
cortisol Spike you might think that
cards soul is a stressful hormone and
it's bad that's not the case there's no
such thing as a bad hormone it's more so
that different hormones have different
purposes and sometimes because of the
modern things that we do these chemicals
get out of sync it's actually that
cortisol Spike which gets your internal
clocks in sync so I told you every
single cell has its own clock it's that
cortisol Spike that makes all the clocks
synchronize and literally get your body
in order and of course if you do the
opposite if you don't get outside and
get some sun early in the morning your
cortisol spike is still going to happen
but it's going to happen later in the
day and this is a bad thing because this
is going to result in other mental
problems it's going to result in lower
dopamine depressions it's going to
result in low testosterone I want you to
think of this very carefully why are
doctors prescribing antidepressants
before first prescribing sunlight early
morning sunlight as the first therapy
first line of defense against depression
well for one thing sunlight is free it
can make money off of it so you might
have the question should you Sun your
balls this has been a thing on social
media it's been like a meme almost it's
on your balls to me doesn't make a lot
of sense because the way the system
works is your balls are the factory of
sperm and testosterone yes but the on
off switch is actually a pituitary gland
in your brain and the way you stimulate
it is actually getting sunlight on your
eyeballs especially morning sunlight is
going to turn on your pituitary gland
that's going to Signal your balls and
your balls are going to produce a
testosterone it's not like you can get
more testosterone by just sunning your
balls directly that being said maybe the
science simply isn't there yet maybe in
the next 20 years you'll find out that
actually stunning your balls does help
so you can try it it's not going to hurt
you try it and tell me what happens but
as of right now I think it's more of a
meme than reality much more reasonable
productive and beneficial is getting
sunlight on your skin in general and
this becomes doubly important in the
winter or cloudy days and the science is
very clear on this this literally
increases your testosterone it's going
to increase your size of your balls and
it's going to increase sex drive this
has been shown there's no debate about
it so you might be asking should I take
a vitamin D supplement instead of
getting sunlight the answer is no
sunlight is definitely the superior
method and on top of that most
supplements are ethyl most supplements
have piss poor quality control and they
aren't even absorbed by the body half
the time so I don't take supplements in
pill form most of the time there are
some good ones yes but I don't usually
consume a lot of like pill-based
supplements I will consume cod liver oil
for vitamin D especially in the cold
winter months or even if it's really
cloudy or something like that but even
here there's pitfalls so most fish are
polluted because the micro Plastics that
we consume end up in the ocean and they
poison the fish and if we get cod liver
oil from the fish then that cod liver
oil contains microplastics however
there's some small good brands out there
which are making quality stuff which are
free of these toxins I personally use a
fermented cod liver oil plus butter oil
blend very interesting product worth
checking out I'll put the link in the
description but don't let that fool you
just because there are some good
supplements out there they're not better
than the sun you still need sunlight as
much as you can get especially when it
gets cold and it is cloudy and now I'm
going to show you how to power up your
sun exposure with something called
double breathing now this is something
you can do anytime I want you to do this
right now and tell me how how it feels
what you do is you take your hands Place
one on your belly and one on your chest
and you're going to do a double breathe
so you're going to take air into your
belly and then your chest and then
you're going to breathe it out so it's
like this
so I notice what I did I took two breads
essentially I took into my belly
into my chest
out so it's one
one two
three
try this right now try this right now
and tell me you don't feel better
already that's because breath is the
interface between your subconscious and
your conscious mind why is that it's
because there's many parts of your body
that you have willful control over like
my hands the only way I can control my
hand is by actually thinking about it
and moving it there's also other parts
of your body like your digestive system
which you don't really think about you
there's no way to control your digestive
system by thinking about it but the
breath is interesting because most of
the day you're breathing without really
thinking about it it's subconscious but
you can do it you can think of your
breath and breathe manually right so
breath is interesting because it's both
involuntary and voluntary it's
subconscious and it's conscious so it's
the bridge between the subconscious and
conscious mind so you can use the breath
in a way as a communication device you
can use it to communicate with your
subconscious and to tell it to de-stress
and be in a rest and relaxed mode and at
the same time you can even amp it up so
you can use something like Wim Hof
method and boost up your body using the
breath also but that's not what I want
to do in the morning though that's
something worth trying as well for me
what I I want is Extreme Clarity and
relaxation in the morning that's what
helps me be more productive that being
said if you're going to do exercise or
Sports early in the morning perhaps you
want to actually get amped up and not
relaxed maybe you want to do the Wim Hof
method rather than the breathing which I
showed you really depends on what you're
trying to achieve in the morning if
you're going to exert yourself
physically Wim Hof method if you are
going to exert yourself mentally use the
esoteric double breathing method so
you're doing this double breathing as
you're gazing towards the sun you're not
looking literally at the sun don't be
dumb right so what you do is you gaze in
the direction of the Sun but not at the
Sun as you're taking these deep breaths
and resetting your nervous system
ideally you're doing this bare feet on
the grass and think about it when is the
last time you step Barefoot on the
ground or Barefoot on grass in general
it's kind of sad isn't it it's probably
like since your childhood you barely
step on grass Barefoot barely step on
Sand Barefoot barely step on soil or
actual forest floor Barefoot do you even
remember what it feels like to have
anything but shoes on when you step
outside this is not normal your feet are
actually very sensitive organs we were
evolved to collect valuable data about
our surroundings from the base of our
feet so stepping out into the soil
stepping out into nature with your socks
and shoes off is a great way to kick
start your nervous system in the morning
so the first thing you do after of
course you go to the bathroom in the
morning first thing you do is getting
the sun exposure ideally standing on the
grass and doing the double breathing and
then you tell me how you crush the day
with just implementing this one practice
we spend way too much time indoors think
about it in ancient times if you were
the guy who's going outside and hunting
and Gathering Etc and you know there's
this one guy who just sits in the cave
all day you would think he's some kind
of weirdo right there's a reason if you
have a pet if you have a pet dog
especially you'll know this for a fact
in the morning dogs seek out the Sun
Animals instinctively know how to do
this it's just we humans who need to
relearn these ancient practices there's
a reason why all ancient cultures
worship the sun in one form or other
think about what the sun is the sun is
literally a billion nuclear warheads
going off every single second by
stepping out in this sun and getting
recharged by the sun you're literally
running on nuclear fuel right now use
that power and conquer the day I'm going
to give you the raw tier esoteric
morning routine so that you can conquer
the day I'm going to make it simplified
so that you aren't spending like half
the day doing freaking morning routine
and you don't actually get any work done
only the essentials will survive in
disgust and what about sunscreen our
sunscreens bad well most of them are
most of them are toxic most of them
contain endocrine disruptors but not all
of them are bad so make sure you know
what you're getting so after you get
yourself an exposure what do you do you
need to replenish your electrolytes and
I'll show you how to make the esoteric
morning Elixir so should you have
caffeine should you have coffee well you
can but only after 90 minutes after
waking up why because in the morning
your brain still has an accumulation of
sleep chemicals in it which is natural
and it's fine and your brain has
processes to purge these but if you
drink caffeine it disrupts those
processes and you get a low energy crash
later in the day cold showers is that
just a meme or does it work it actually
actually does so cold showers will boost
your Baseline dopamine for like six
hours very very beneficial to get a
massive amount of work done but you
might be asking like how do you actually
do it how do you actually get the cold
shower done this is what I do it's work
for me you step into your shower and you
take 30 deep breaths I'm not asking you
to hyperventilate I'm not asking you to
do Wim Hof method I'm just saying you
take 30 deep breaths and you have a
thing in your mind you have a promise to
yourself that at breath number 30 you're
going to crank the valve you're gonna
crank the thing and the shower head is
going to pour water on you at that point
so I'll do my 30 breaths I'll go as slow
as possible because I don't want to get
hit by the water but at bet number 30 is
done I crank the valve the shower water
hits me and for maybe one or two seconds
is uncomfortable but after that the
endorphins kick in the dopamine kicks in
and you actually feel really really good
and here's the interesting thing cold
showers actually warm you up it's
paradoxical so your brain feels the cold
and then freaks out and releases
adrenaline and heats up your body which
is actually something which you really
really want early in the morning that
body temperature increase plus the
cortisol spike is going to sink your
clocks perfectly and you're going to
have an amazing day and in fact you're
going to improve the quality of your
life overall after this I'll use a Neti
Pot which is a nasal irrigation device
it passes water to one nostril and now
the other and helps you essentially
clear up your Airways and have better
breathing I go more into depth in this
in my breathing esoteric guide so you
can check that out if you need to and
then it's time to work 90 minutes heavy
work session I will take the most
difficult challenging dreaded job and
smash it out in the first 90 minutes of
the day because that's going to give you
another increase in Baseline dopamine
and that's going to make you even more
productive during the day if instead
you're doing these low level tasks which
don't actually need any hardcore brain
and focus then you're kind of wasting
the benefits of this ritual so think
about what you did you have that
cortisol Spike you have the dopamine
Spike you had the testosterone boost you
have all these chemicals urging you to
do the most difficult work you should of
course use these benefits to smash out
the most difficult work why would you
waste it in a low level task right so
smash out the most challenging thing
that you want to do that day you've
already won if you literally do just
that one heavy task every day you're
already a million leagues ahead of the
average person and then you have the
rest of the day to conquer think about
that it gives you it gives you such a
massive Advantage your head and
shoulders above your average peers this
is the ultimate asymmetric Advantage if
you know how to use it right so when
should you sleep and when should you
wake up according to like the scientific
principles and whatnot 10 pm is the
ideal time to sleep but I've
experimented personally right and this
is going to be different for everybody
because science works on averages and
for whatever reason I don't get to sleep
very well at 10 pm for me midnight is a
perfect time to sleep and I naturally
wake up fully refreshed at 8 to 8 30 a.m
in the morning so while science is
amazing Baseline guide for understanding
what is true much more valuable for your
health is actually personal
experimentation and then do you use an
alarm well I do not use an alarm I wake
up whenever my body is refreshed and
ready to go but I understand that you
may have to use an alarm because you
have school or work in which case it is
what it is it's not ideal because sleep
happens in cycles and the alarm might
break the cycle at any point right so I
don't use an alarm so that I wake up
when my body is best suited to waking up
I will give you a powerful tool it's
called nsdr non-sleep deep rest let's
like the modern scientific name but the
ancient name for it because it is an
ancient practice 10 000 years old
practice called Yoga Nidra and it's kind
of a guided meditation type thing I have
made one of my own like I have made a
guide for it and I will link that in the
description what this does for you is as
you're going about the day you might
feel tired you might feel your dopamine
level is coming down that's normal it's
expected especially afternoon like 1 pm
2 p.m you're gonna have a crash in
energy that's fine that's normal but in
order to restore yourself you can of
course get a afternoon sleep that's fine
but if you don't have the time for it
nsdr is the way to go it takes about 15
minutes or less and it recharges your
dopamine recharges your energy levels
refresh measures your nervous system and
you can conquer the rest of the day so
check that out you can actually do that
anytime whenever you're feeling a little
bit drowsy a little bit sleepy nsdr is a
tool for you and for accountability this
is what you're going to do tomorrow
morning you're going to follow this
morning routine you're going to do it
correctly and smash out an important
piece of work you're going to get your
sun exposure and you're going to come
back to this video and type in all caps
praise the sun I want to know how many
people actually took any action based on
this video and if you didn't do it
you've got to type I am a cave dweller
keep yourself accountable none of this
knowledge is useful unless you actually
take action now I'm going to guide you
through a visualization that's going to
make it 110 more likely you actually
follow through you went to bed at 10 pm
after a super productive day's work
you're getting so close to your
financial goals you basically have the
money in the bank you wake up feeling
like this literal engine revving in your
heart you woke up even before the alarm
rang you powered your phone down
yesterday night and it's going to remain
powered down until your entire morning
routine is complete you go to the
bathroom you stop at the kitchen to make
your esoteric electrolyte drink then you
step outside into the crisp morning air
might be a little cold but the sun rays
are warming your face your eyes are
adjusting to the brightness you take
some nice deep breaths as you sip your
electrolyte you feel a sense of calm
from the breathing but also a surge of
energy from the electrolyte in the
sunlight you go back into your home open
up the windows stretch out your muscles
or if you're feeling really esoteric you
do your stretching routine Under the Sun
and then you get ready for your cold
shower like every day you feel a bit of
hesitation but you've been there before
and you know that the anticipation is
the painful part the shower itself is
actually quite refreshing after the cold
shower you feel your core temperature
rising you know the corn salt kick is
happening right now in your body
literally give you superpowers over the
average cave dweller and then you
approach the first task of the day you
know you'll emerge Victorious for in
your mind you have already triumphed the
morning is not something that happens to
you it's something that you do seize the
day