welcome to the 30-day brain reset we're
going to be doing the esoteric
meditation protocol instead of watching
a video and then executing on what I say
we'll actually do this together all you
have to do is put your headphones in or
have your speakers on and just follow
along with the
instructions phase one of the esoteric
meditation protocol is the setup we
don't want to do meditation in a
disordered environment because the
external does reflect the internal we
want to clean up our environment as much
as we can Within reason you don't have
to do complete you know overhaul of your
room just make sure that the egregious
disorder is under control make sure
there's no clothes lying on the ground
make sure the trash is not overflowing
just make sure your room is relatively
within control the second piece is to
grab a notebook and a pen this is going
to be a meditation Journal you don't
have to do a lot of writing it's just
good to have a piece of paper with you
when you're meditating because often
times your brain will give you genuinely
creative thoughts you'll have awesome
business ideas you'll have creative you
know video ideas whatever it is that you
do as your job it very easily removes
you from the meditative State because
now you're thinking that you need to
execute on that idea as soon as you're
done meditating and that just gets you
out of the awareness state so it found
it very beneficial to just have a
notebook and a pen near me so if I have
a really good idea I'll open my eyes jot
down my idea and then continue with the
meditation in the knowledge that that
idea is now preserved and I don't have
to expand more brain energy trying to
store it
all right boys we're in the stress test
component of this there's really no good
way to record this so this is what we're
going to do all right so I just wanted
to show you what the stress test is so
in this esoteric meditation protocol we
want to combine the physical and the
mental right we want to actually stress
ourselves physically easiest way to do
this is Max push-ups in 1 minute this is
not going to affect your recovery you
can absolutely work out and lift weights
and everything completely unimpeded by
this this is just a one minute hardcore
how many push-ups can you do in one
minute type challenge so you literally
have your phone have my timer on this so
as soon as I hit start I'm going to
start cranking these push-ups out and
I'm not going to stop until the 1 minute
expires it's enough stress that'll get
my fight ORF flight response it'll get
my stress up it'll get my muscle to be
um met metabolically stressed it'll get
my heart rate up it'll get my breathing
up that's all I really need for this so
hit start and
then feeling the
burn still got 30 seconds left
I'm going down on every single rep and
if I don't touch the floor with my chest
it doesn't count
all right that's 60 seconds that's a
minute of work so what do I do now
obviously my breath has increased heart
rate's
increased and that's good I'll sit
down and I'll meditate obviously I'm not
going to do a good job of narrating a
guided meditation in this state so we'll
skip back to our audio I'll guide you
from there youve just finished your
stress test you've had your calisthenics
now your breathing is heavy your heart
is beating and you might even feel the
burn in your muscles excellent that
brings you into the present and that
brings you into your physical body and
your physical Sensations the only thing
which exists is the present so now it's
really good that your attention is
completely in the now so what we do now
is a session of spherical awareness and
that's what I'm going to guide you in
right right now so go ahead and sit down
and however is comfortable for you you
can sit on the floor if you want or on a
cushion or on a chair it doesn't matter
just have your back straight and just be
comfortable sit down I know that your
heart is pounding and you know your
breath is ragged and it doesn't really
feel like a meditation session at all
that's the whole point now we change our
mindset we change our mindset from this
attack mode from this push-ups mode from
this performance mode into relaxation so
now that you're sitting down just listen
to the prompts and do what I'm
instructing in this audio
guide bring your attention to your
breath notice the rapidity of your
breathing and the loudness of your
heartbeat feel the air entering through
your nose feeling your lungs and then
leaving your body breathe with the belly
and not your chest close your eyes
attempt to bring the breathing and the
heart rate down through deep
diaphragmatic
breathing now we're going to be doing a
deep inhale and a hold so deep inhale
until your lungs are full to bursting
and as you release open your eyes and
expand your peripheral vision you're
suddenly taking the entire field of
vision not focusing on one object when
you're in attack mode your focus is on
one thing when you're in relaxed mode
you have this deep peripheral vision
where you're aware of your entire
surroundings so now that's what you're
trying to do becoming aware of the edges
of your eyes sides just maximizing the
visual field your awareness of the full
field of vision is the key to this
meditation Style can blink as normal but
have an awareness of the F field of view
this keeps you in effortless
awareness at this phase of the
meditation just focus on the vision just
increase the perception that you can see
just increase the detail at which you
can
see e
now we're going to expand the auditory
field so the field of your hearing
you still have this vibrant awareness of
your eyesight your vision but you're
adding in the additional factor of our
ears our hearing our hearing sense
process an intimate detailed sounds
coming from within your own breath and
heartbeat and then expand that awareness
outwards in a
sphere we're beginning to have a
spherical awareness as we become
effortlessly aware of the immediate
surroundings
imagine your awareness expanding in all
directions forward backwards to the
sides and even upwards and downwards
imagine an aura of awareness forming a
sphere around you we're going to spend
the next few minutes just existing in
this calm awareness which has been
focused by the calesthenics work that we
just
did e
allow each breath to strengthen the
awareness of the sphere around you
imagine each exhale pulsing a wave of
power outwards
you may have noticed two main
differences between this kind of
meditation and any meditation that
you've done previously first we aren't
starting from a relaxed State we're
actually starting from the agitated
State and the second is instead of just
focusing on the breath and going inwards
we're actually expanding our awareness
outwards
e
e e
and now we come to the close of this
meditation take a few deep breaths in
and out and feel how you are different
compared to when you began
now we begin to retract the sphere of
awareness back into the body close your
eyes and take a deep breath in and
imagine the sphere of awareness
Contracting inwards into the center of
your forehead it might take a couple
cycles of breath to fully contract this
awareness
now when you open your eyes you'll feel
the energy radiating within your body
you're finally ready to finish out this
meditation and conquer the day I thank
you for joining me on this meditation
you should be proud of being here at
this time update your progress tracker
and comment in the post below with a
picture of the updated tracker to mark
this task as complete to do this you'll
need the school app such that you can
interact with this community from your
phone you can then briefly mention how
you felt or even ask questions in the
comment below mark this module as
complete by hitting the checkbox on the
top right corner and I'll see you
tomorrow