The pituitary produces luteinizing
hormone LH and follical stimulating
hormone
FH. These are the hormones that tell
your balls to start producing
testosterone and sperm. Damage to the
pituitary can permanently kill off
testosterone production. If you're doing
boxing, try to avoid hard sparring where
you're taking knocks to the head, unless
you're purposely building up to a fight,
in which case, of course, all bets are
off. You can do everything right, but if
your pituitary is getting rocked, it's
game over. However, there's many jobs
that involve a lot of shocks to the
head. If you operate a jackhammer for
your job, it's a lot of vibration
traveling up to your brain pan. Another
example is if you're in the military and
operate heavy weapons like the 50 cal or
worse, the shouldermounted weapons like
the Gustav. We know that this is
terrible for the brain. If you're in
construction, military or martial arts,
neck training is a non-negotiable along
with good hearing
protection. If you're overweight, you
need to reverse this. You need to get to
a sustainable 15% body fat. So, what
does 15% body fat look like? Just means
that you can see your abs if you flex
and have good lighting. It's not even
that hard to get except that it is. It
is hard to get if you're already
overweight because you're working
against a powerful feedback loop. So,
let me explain. If you already have a
bunch of fat tissue on your body, this
fat tissue is producing aromatase.
Aromatase converts testosterone to
estrogen. Here's the kicker. More
estrogen causes you to store more fat
and therefore create more aromatase. So
you're in this vicious cycle that's
keeping you fat. That being said, you
can also create a virtuous cycle to
combat this. Hormone optimized training
will lead to muscle growth and this new
muscle will act as a glucose reservoir.
Why is this important? It's important
because this will dampen the insulin
spikes and if the insulin spikes are
dampened then the food cravings will
reduce. overall calorie intake will
reduce. Yes, it is true that most people
who go through a weight loss or fat loss
program regain the fat and actually
exceed the baseline, get even fatter.
However, that's because most fat loss
programs do not have a fundamental
understanding of the underlying biology
and the hormone
engine. Don't drink beer or smoke weed.
If you want to drink, drink wine like
the ancients did. Modern beer is fake
and gay. If you're going to smoke, don't
smoke weed. Smoke tobacco like a man. At
least the nicotine is going to make you
sharp and alert. Great industries and
empires have been built on wine and
tobacco. Nothing has been built from
beer and weed. Now, how much do you
drink? Personally, I don't go more than
two to three glasses of wine per week,
and that's only on social occasions. You
can absolutely have fun in a social
setting without alcohol. Don't ever feel
that you are obligated to partake
because other people around you are
drinking. In fact, the ability to reject
peer pressure is a sign of a strong
man. Don't be afraid to ask for
non-toxic options. If you go to
Starbucks and you ask them to use a mug,
like an actual ceramic mug, they will.
It's just a matter of asking. In fact,
this is something you need to practice.
At sitdown restaurants, you can ask them
to prepare your food in butter rather
than oil. Now, don't say seed oils
because they probably don't know what
that means. Just ask to have your food
prepared in butter. This will be
socially awkward or socially challenging
if you haven't done this before, but you
need to get used to having your way. I
want you to behave in such a way that
you expect the best service. Ask for the
non-toxic options. Let the normies eat
the slop. You could instead insist on
preserving your health. Be that guy. Be
the leader. Teach your body that you are
that guy and soon you will