the scientific Community is comprised of
human beings and human beings are
subject to the same pressures money
Prestige promotions all that kind of
stuff so it is not impossible to
influence or bribe scientists the food
pyramid was a psychological operation
the food pyramid was known to be BS from
the very start and there were some Brave
scientists who stood up against it even
in the start but they were silenced and
of course the media government and the
companies promoted the food pyramid
knowing full well that it was BS so I
don't believe that you should be
somebody who blindly trusts science
science has been co-opted before and
will continue to be co-opted by big
business interests another example is
the sugar industry the sugar industry
literally in the 1960s I believe paid
off Harvard scientists to say that carbs
good fats bad and that's where the whole
you know fats are bad ideology comes
from companies have succeeded in paying
off scientists before which is why I
believe in to look more broadly not just
at the science to understand what is
good for us because understand this I
have this system I call it the psyop
system science s i intuition oh
observation and P philosophy and I use
this system to evaluate what is true and
false in my life and I can share that
with you so we talk about the science
now I'm going to hit you with some
philosophy science gives us facts and
observations it doesn't tell us what we
should actually do should belongs to the
realm of philosophy understand this we
use the system of innocent until proven
guilty in courts but when it comes to
our health and when it comes to adding
new alien substances to our diet which
could harm us and the health of our kids
and our families we should use the
principle of guilty until proven
innocent so understand this thousands
and millions of years humans have gone
without poorly unsaturated fatty acids
this is a new addition to our diet which
industry has created for us they might
be good but it's on them the burden is
on them to to prove that it's good the
burden is not on us to prove that it's
bad you understand the burden of proof
lies with the people who are creating
this stuff to show that it is harmless
and good for us which they have failed
in doing for me I'll happily say that
this is guilty until proven innocent so
when the science is a toss-up I will
avoid these newfangled inventions and
defer to tradition so that's your
philosophy observation now I'm going to
talk about observation what have I
experienced in my own personal life when
I switched over from seed oils to
saturated fats well one thing skin
quality so understand that the skin is
made of cells like your entire body is
made of cells right and cells have a
membrane around them and this membrane
is made of fat
literally the fast that you consume will
incorporate into those membranes so if
you use good fats that will incorporate
into the membranes if you use unstable
fats that'll incorporate into the
membranes I I saw my skin go from you
know I had pimples and I had acne I had
all the stuff become clear and healthy
and you know I have I have no complaints
at all about my skin nowadays that I
switched to seed oils I also have a very
powerful esoteric skin care routine so
if you want that video let me know in
the comments you know what a country
club is it's where it leads hangout and
you're not invited if you're subscribed
you're likely interested in the esoteric
Health movement and also the multiple
psiops inflicted upon us if you want to
learn directly from me it also meet
fellow people just like you who are
interested in esoteric knowledge then
you should consider joining the college
Country Club another observation energy
levels so like I said the skin cells
have membranes which these fats will
incorporate into every cell in your body
has mitochondria and mitochondria is the
PowerHouse of cell I know everybody
knows this so mitochondria also has a
membrane and if you have unstable fats
in it it messes up the energy system
which is why you feel slow and sluggish
if you had seed oils most people know it
as vegetable oil we in the know know it
as seed oil but the industry term for
this stuff is RBD oil that's refined
bleached and deodorized oil that's the
stuff which they have convinced you and
your family that is good for you you
know something's wrong with a product
when the company literally spends
Millions upon millions of dollars on
marketing to convince that that their
product is better than what we had
traditionally if the polyunsaturated
fatty acids were the miracle they
claimed it to be it was cheaper and
better for you then they wouldn't have
to spend so much on this fraudulent
marketing campaign the psychological
operation in order to make you buy it
the free market would have selected for
that product but no here's what they did
here's the psychological operation
you've heard of the American Heart
Association you probably recognize the
logo do you know that that organization
is completely completely bought and paid
for by the seed oil industrial complex
that's right so what they did in the
1960s I believe they literally had this
radio campaign and it was a lottery
system so a company wins a prize from
Procter and Gamble which at the time and
even today is probably the biggest
player in the seed oil industry
so they have this radio contest and the
American Heart Association just happened
to win it completely by coincidence I'm
sure and they were pumped with 19
million dollars
by PNG and do you think there was a
conflict of interest of course there was
so in a few years you know the American
Heart Association goes from being
underfunded to massively funded and
literally every single piece of
propaganda they put out is in favor of
the seed oil industry is that a
coincidence I think not the reason why a
lot of people believe that Paulie
unsaturated fatty acids are good for
their heart
literally the afha's logo has a hard
picture on it it's because they make the
claim polyunsaturated fatty acids are
good for the heart which is a claim that
is in my opinion
fraudulent at worst faulty at best today
you're going to learn everything you
ever wanted to know about cooking oils
seed oils all that stuff what you should
be using how you should cook your food
for both Better Health better skin and
better testosterone levels and if you're
a woman watching this keep watching
because this is not just about
testosterone your hormonal levels are
equally important as men's and these
seed oils affect you just as much as
they affect us and along the way you
learn how to make amazing chicken
drumsticks sauteed in duck fat and it's
going to taste amazing right now I'm
going to lay some foundations I'm going
to teach you the terms I'm going to use
for the rest of this video so if you've
heard of polyunsaturated fatty acids
you've heard of saturated you've heard
of monounsaturated what are these and
what are some examples I got them all
right here so there's three types
there's the saturated monounsaturated
and polyunsaturated and I'll break it
down super easy for you so the solid
stuff solid think of it it starts with s
right solid is saturated it's stable
that's what you need to know so like
butter butter is literally solid right
you're not going to be able to run a
fork through butter it's a solid it's a
saturated fat and it is stable at all
temperatures that's butter highly
nutritious you should cook with this
here we have ghee ghee is also pretty
solid like you cannot you know just run
a fork through this this is a saturated
fat it is stable it's a solid SSS
then we have duck fat it looks like it's
more liquid but it's still like kind of
solid like you can see the bottom is
pretty solid it's a saturated fat very
good highly temperature resistant
doesn't oxidize in high temperatures you
should cook with this then we have olive
oil which is a monounsaturated fat so we
were talking about saturated fats SSS
stable stable stable and now we're
coming to a liquid so this is different
this is different now we have
monounsaturated fats this is a oil of
course olive oil so what do I mean by
monounsaturated it means it has one
unstable Bond one double bond which is
inherently unstable for organic
chemistry reasons which I'm not going to
go into in this video so should you cook
with this yeah you can because it has
only one unstable Bond it's still
resistant to oxidization and olive oil
naturally contains a whole bunch of
antioxidants which also help it resist
oxidation so it's pretty stable I don't
have any problem cooking with olive oil
I approve now we have the bad guys so we
have here is Sunflower Oil it's almost
like water it's not very thick at all
it's pretty light it's not viscous and
then we have also sesame oil so these
are your pufas pufas polyunsaturated
fatty acids so poly means many mono
means one which is very the olive oil
comes from so polyunsaturated fatty
acids it means it has many unstable
bonds many double Bonds in the carbon
carbon molecule structure so these ones
I don't recommend you cook with these
are unstable they're not resistant to
oxidization and I will not cook with
these I know a lot of people do I do not
recommend it I will go into more details
but that's the basics now before I take
too long with all the science stuff I
want to get my dinner cooking so here we
go this is how we prepare this okay I'm
just gonna dump these guys in here we
got some chicken now what you want to
look for with chicken ideally you want
pasture raised if you have cage free
that's fine too the reason why that's
true is you don't want grain fed quite
often the grain feed which they give to
these chickens is moldy and mold
releases something called Zea which is a
estrogenic substance so you don't want
your chickens to be eating moldy grains
so you should go for pasture raised and
also let me explain what I'm going to
put on these before I cook them so this
recipe which I'm doing is with duck fat
you can use ghee you can use butter you
can even use olive oil no problem but
I'm going to use duck fat so we were
talking about unstability and why that's
important here's why so when those
double Bonds in the carbon structure
gets disrupted by oxidation processes it
can lead to the formation of something
called aldehydes which is a class of
organic compounds aldehydes one of them
for example is 4-H and E is literally a
known carcinogen so when you oxidize
some of these oils you literally create
cancer-causing substances to form in
those oils that's why I would never cook
with polyunsaturated fatty acids pufas
seed oils in other words so I'm just
adding my duck fat right onto the raw
chicken and
you can eat the stuff tastes good
so putting that away
and now I'm going to essentially add all
the spices I'll tell you which spices
you need which spices you don't really
need and what's the easiest way to make
this stuff so first I'm going to add
salt that's the main thing salt is
indispensable you need salt a lot of
these people like the mainstream Health
types they think salt is bad for you and
it's going to cause hypertension and
whatnot it doesn't it's actually pretty
good for you and if you're an athletic
person you absolutely need salt as a
part of your diet so how much salt am I
adding like I don't measure these things
you know how other cooking channels will
literally measure like at an at an
autistic level like how much salt
they're adding I don't this is how it's
salt I'm adding you have a camera like
just make your own judgment right okay
adding the salt we're gonna rub all this
stuff together anyway so it's fine if
it's not evenly distributed at this
point right so I said before that you
should not be heating seed oils
understand the process by which seed
oils are being manufactured so in the
start I said see those are called RBD
oils right refined bleached and
deodorized oils understand that each of
those processes is a high heat process
and these oils shouldn't be subjected to
heat in the first place for example the
process of deodorization so what's going
on here right so most seed oils are
toxic or are inedible in a natural form
for example canola oil or it's called
rapeseed oil it's literally toxic
straight out of the plant like even if
you have the best extraction techniques
and you only use cold pressing or
expeller pressed canola oil is still
toxic so canola oil is a no-go like you
should never have it under whatever
circumstance and then the refining
process you subject it to a process
called deodorization which removes the
bad smells from this product at a
temperature of 500 degrees Fahrenheit
which is more than sufficient to oxidize
and make this stuff literally well I
don't want to make claims I cannot prove
so I don't want to say that a
carcinogenic oil but it has been proven
that these oils upon Heating and
reheating do formaldehydes such as 4-H
and E so you can make all that what you
want I personally will never touch
canola oil coming back to here so
chicken adds some garlic powder
oh [ __ ] that's a little bit too much but
it's fine turmeric
we have ginger powder and you see how
generous I'm being with all this stuff
it tastes good so why wouldn't I be and
also I have Cayenne Red Pepper so this
is so the other ones I would definitely
recommend you add them the red pepper is
optional for sure it's going to add a
lot of spice so if you don't like spice
don't add any Cayenne Red Pepper because
you're going to add actual like ground
pepper anyway so you don't need this
step I personally like it with a little
bit of spice so I'm okay with adding a
small bit of cayenne pepper that's more
or less what we need so I won't add the
pepper right now because if I heat this
this pepper just burns so I add the
pepper at the end actually I've already
added everything I need for this
probably not enough though I'll mix it
up and I'll see I'll make my judgment
and if the oxidization issue wasn't bad
enough look at what these oils and fats
are stored in if you notice olive oil
often comes in these dark glass bottles
why is that it's because first olive oil
is expensive and people expect quality
from olive oil so the manufacturers put
them in glass bottles to prevent
oxidization you understand oxidization
can be caused not just by heat but also
by light that's why the dark glass
bottles and then of course the saturated
fats they're already in glass so that's
fine I have no issue with that but look
at your seed oils almost all seed oils
are packaged in Plastics and here's the
problem the Plastics contain either a
bisphenol so BPA BPS bpas BPF different
kinds of bisphenols which are all highly
estrogenic substances which mess up your
hormones in a terrible way that's one
thing but even if somehow they had a
plastic which didn't contain BPA which
is unlikely because this is the cheapest
kind of plastic it would still contain
talates and talits are also endocrine
disrupting I would be very surprised
indeed if any seed all came in plastic
which was free of those I would say it's
impossible it's unlikely so here's
what's happened estrogenic substances
all of them are fat soluble that is they
dissolve in fats they dissolve in oils
so when you store these oils in a
plastic container what do you think is
going to happen the estrogenic
substances are going to seep into the
oil and estrogenics are not destroyed by
heat so when you consume canola oil
grape seed oil sunflower oil mustard
sesame oil coming from these plastic
containers you are consuming estrogenic
substances you are there's no question
about it that's another reason why you
should prefer the saturated fats or
olive oil in your cooking rather than
the seed oils so you want to heard the
term called trans fats and by the way it
looks like I didn't season my chicken
enough so I'm going to add a little bit
more trans fats you've heard of the term
trans fats you know the trans fats are
bad but you know there was a time in
which the science and the media
everybody was saying that trans fats
were good and you should have more of
them so understand that Procter and
Gamble is a massively wealthy company so
here's what they did they took seed oils
in fact they took cotton seed oil which
is one of the worst seed oils they took
cotton seed oil which is an industrial
lubricant it's literally used to oil
machine parts it's not fit for human
consumption and they subjected this oil
to some something called hydrogenation
later on they come up with something
called partial Hydro hydrogenation but
they subjected it called to something
called hydrogenation which causes the
substance this liquid to become a solid
all right and they give it a name called
Crisco Crisco it comes from get this
crystallized cotton seed oil Crisco and
this stuff is toxic it's literally made
of trans fats no human or animal should
be consuming this stuff but the
marketing campaign was on point they
convinced everybody that trans fats Now
understand something about trans fats
trans fats don't exist in nature or the
existing Trace quantities only no living
species is equipped to deal with trans
fats and crisco was sold you know to
moms and kids ate this stuff like no
human should be eating this stuff or
Procter and Gamble they said [ __ ] you
give me money so they literally forced
or didn't force but you know use their
marketing Wing to sell this stuff which
literally even an animal should not be
eating that's the story of Crisco so I
the reason I bring that up so it trans
fats have now almost been banned you can
barely use trans fats but the story I
want you to focus on so trans fats the
scientists said it was good the media
said it was good it turns out it was bad
all right poorly unsaturated fatty acids
pufas again it's the same story The
Scientist said it's good the media said
it's good but the emerging research is
showing that it's not good at all and
and this is a whole story about
cholesterol so in the 90 like the late
1900s right there was a huge fear about
heart disease I believe President
Eisenhower I think he died of heart
disease so the question of heart disease
was on everybody's mind you know how do
we prevent heart disease and all this so
the American Heart Association which I
talked about before they come out and
they prove that the lower cholesterol
means lower heart disease risk which is
not a claim which I actually believe in
what happens then they find this link
that polysaturated and fatty acids
reduce cholesterol so there it is you
know literally thousands and millions of
Americans bought into this stuff and not
just Americans obviously worldwide
Procter Gamble is a multinational
multi-nation company massive profits
from this fraudulent marketing campaign
I'm also going to add bay leaves which
is optional I'm just adding it because
you know I haven't you don't really need
this for this recipe I'm adding some
star anise and I'm adding a stick of
cinnamon because I want this meal to be
S tier you don't really need all this
stuff you can make a perfectly good
chicken drumstick with half this stuff
you only really need the pepper and salt
everything else is optional so I'm going
to give this a nice rub one last time
and you have two options on how to cook
this you can either do it on a stove top
and that's fine but I'm going to put it
in the oven just because it's easier and
besides why do I have this what kind of
soap are you using to wash your hands
check your ingredients list if it
contains ethyl or metal paraben
you need new soap as I wait for my
chicken to get made there's a few more
things I don't talk to talk to you about
so should you never have sunflower oil
or sesame oil not necessarily so I was
talking about the extraction processes
there's other kinds of extraction
processes which are much less common you
can find sunflower oil or sesame oil
from expeller pressed so it'll say on
the bottle expeller pressed or cold
pressed and that's fine if you and if
you use those I'd have less of a problem
with those polyunsaturated fatty acids
because they haven't been destroyed by
these high temperature processes so I
would still not use them for cooking but
I could use them as a drizzle on
something else and same thing for sesame
oil sunflower and sesame oil are not the
worst the problem with these is the
processing and the refining with things
like cotton seed oil corn oil soybean
oil and even canola oil these even if
they were expeller pressed I would
highly not recommend them these two are
a little bit different and what about
avocado oil or Mac Academia nut oil yeah
these are fine too avocado oil olive oil
and macadamia nut oil are actually
monounsaturated so you can use them to
cook if you wanted to let me check if
this is done
all right here's a tip on how you should
use your oven so if you have an oven you
have a broil setting so to make chicken
easy instead of setting you know the
temperature and the duration and all
that you just put it on broil you wait
for it to have this Browning and
charring you flip him and then you put
them back it's that easy you don't need
to sit there and try to find out like
what temperature is ideal this is the
superior Method All tastes good oh yeah
it has the kick I know my seasoning is
on point boys and it goes
I'll let it be for a couple more minutes
we talked about science philosophy
observation that still leaves us with
intuition and this may be the most
controversial or important thing in this
video my intuition I I used to think I
used to defer to science you know the
science is what they say then I believe
the science I don't believe my
intuitions I was that kind of guy not
anymore nowadays I trust my gut I trust
my instincts I trust my intuition about
everything including diet including
interactions with people including you
know the choices I make the videos I
make all that I do trust my judgment
because I'm in a better place now I have
good mental health I have good physical
health and I have no problem with
trusting my judgment because judgment
comes from evolutionary wisdom
programmed into us over thousands and
millions of years why would I not trust
it so what does my intuition say I'll
give you a short story so I was doing my
research for this video and one of the
videos I saw on YouTube which is the pro
seed oil the presenter of that video he
made an interesting argument he said
that in online right-wing groups
everybody there hates seed oil and they
the low saturated fats and the reason
why these right wing online guys
masculine toxic masculinity type guys
hate seed oils is because
they associate meat with the hunt
and the hunt with war and all these are
right-wing topics that is associated
with toxic masculinity and then these
guys hate seed oils because seed oils
are you know bird food and birds are
effeminate and that's why they hate seed
oils and that's why they allow meat and
dairy products because that comes from
the hunt and and farming and all the
masculine stuff and he used this as an
argument for seed oils he said we
shouldn't be toxic masculine and we
should prefer the seed oils because the
science said so when you just trust the
science
it's interesting when I saw that I was
amused because his little story about
you know the right-wing guys and the
toxic masculinity type guys preferring
saturated fats because of their
association with the hunt
that appeals to me I don't care what a
random YouTuber has to say who wants to
call me toxic masculine that's fine I
don't care that story appeals to me to
my intuition It Feels Right humans were
a hunting species we were pastoralists
we literally made this stuff for
thousands of years this is the new stuff
we didn't have freaking seed oils
thousands of years ago this is
newfangled this is tradition my
intuition says this is the healthy stuff
so the science is a little bit iffy
because the predominant government
sanctioned consensus is that Cedars are
good and saturated fats are bad so the
science is 50 50. I mean I would I would
even say the science is actually in
favor of seed oils if you look at all
the papers so you can make if you want
to trust the science you go right ahead
buddy the science the philosophy the
philosophy says suspect new inventions
until proven healthy so the philosophy
is on the side of saturated fats
observation my observations saturated
fats are winter clear as day then we
have the intuition my intuition says
saturated fats are the way to go your
intuition might be different and for all
those reasons for the science philosophy
intuition and observation I prefer
saturated fats and mono unsaturated fats
over seed oils any day now time to check
up on my chicken let's see what happened
here
I'm going to grab these out and I'm
going to finish my chicken with a little
bit of where is that duck fat I see that
it's getting a little bit dry
so I'm going to rub some duck fat on it
before it gets too dry and then I'll put
it back in for a little bit more so
we've already established the seed oils
bad saturated fats good that's fine but
how do you actually avoid them because
they're everywhere you don't understand
just by making better buying choices
doesn't make you safe so yeah you could
just buy the better ones and cook in
your home but literally every single
fast food uses reheated seed oils all of
them all of them use reheated seed oil
you think Chipotle is healthy because
they have like rice and chicken but that
chicken was cooked in seed oils and and
it's not just seed oils there's hundreds
of different examples candy bars snack
cakes I actually have a little list of
things which seed oils are present in
snack cakes chips margarine cereals
dressing Ranch fake meat most candy bars
mayonnaise is basically just soy soy oil
and it's emulsified
I'll make a list I'll put in the
description all the stuff you should be
avoiding but I think I've made my point
avoid seed oils go for saturated so I've
gotten my chicken out of the oven
so it's been in the oven for about 10
minutes so that cooks the chicken
completely so it's all fully cooked now
all the way down to the bone but I like
the Char and the the skin to be nice and
burnt and tasty so what I'm going to do
now is take my duck fat again and grab a
new spoon I'm gonna finish it off on the
stove top so this cast iron is like
really hot so I'm gonna have to be
careful with it take my stove top and
I'm gonna get it to medium high so just
between medium and high it's going to
take a little bit to heat up so in that
time I'm going to get my duck fat I'm
gonna this is my third tablespoon of
duck fat by the way if you're counting
and you might be thinking oh my God this
is so many calories doesn't matter if
you're having a good healthy lifestyle
which involves a lot of walking and
jogging and running and working out in
the gym
Etc calories are easy to burn man it's
hard to gain weight if you eat the right
foods and eat the right fats it's
actually hard to gain weight it's hard
to get fat human beings aren't meant to
be fat that's the most unusual thing
it's so sad that in the modern day being
fat is the normal
it's actually really hard to get fat
think about it in caveman times you you
would really struggle to get fat even if
you tried you would fail
so here we are in the modern world in
which getting fat is the normal there it
is that's the color I want to see this
is the stuff I want to see all right I
have my plate of chicken right here
I'm gonna just take a take a bit of it
because it's really really hot
oh yeah
perfection
look at it see how see how much
duck fat is coming off of it that's fine
that's the good stuff saturated fat
that's what I want to eat and like I
said saturated fats are stable in high
heat so this is
too hot too hot
yep I'm going to go ahead enjoy this
amazing amazing chicken it's an
exclusive Community where I will give
you three live lectures per week and
delve into the heavy topics so I can
give you an unfair Advantage you'll also
meet people just like yourself who are
unsatisfied with the common wisdom and
seek out esoteric knowledge each month
you get a free mini course on topics
like strategy YouTube growth
testosterone boosting Etc chosen by
popular vote by the people inside this
group we'll have a library a book club
where we meet weekly and discuss
forbidden texts we also have a kitchen
where I teach you exactly how to cook
good high quality testosterone boosting
hormone boosting meals you'll even have
a movie haul where I intend to watch
along with every member of this group
High tumors movies like 300 Flight Club
Etc along with my commentary on the art
and history of these movies and finally
of course we have the gymnasium where we
shall contemplate the ideal physique and
on every Friday we have physique Friday
so what do you get as a benefit you get
early access to all my YouTube videos
you get prizes so school.com has a
leaderboard where you can win prizes for
your contributions to the group and I
will mail you actual physical prizes
books supertonics other things which I
find interesting in my life I'll send
them to you as a reward for good
contributions you get hormonal health
and YouTube growth strategies from me
directly right now I'm only looking for
25 members to start the foundations of
this esoteric Health movement if that's
you check out the link in the
description below