a good life is a sequence of days well-
lived and a bad life is a sequence of
days wasted it seems like everybody
especially nowadays has all these clear
goals that they're striving towards but
you don't have that Clarity well this
video has exactly one objective you will
gain Clarity over your goals and be able
to define the steps needed to achieve
these people talk about the circle of
life but it's not a circle it's a
triangle health wealth and relationships
The Big Three human priorities The Big
Three rule on health is exercise
nutrition and Recovery the big three on
relationships is family friends and
female attraction the big three on
wealth is income investment and spending
it's literally that simple you can solve
exercise nutrition and Recovery you have
solved Health if you solved family
friends and female attraction you have
solved relationships if you've solved
income investment and spending you've
solved wealth that's literally it the
entire breakdown of the big three human
priorities now how can you convert this
framework into action it's always the
catch the simple answer is stop wasting
your time I am not speaking of
productivity a life is not wasted in one
day it is wasted and pissed away in
weeks and months and years I was pissing
my life away for years cleaning test
tubes in a biolab so trust me when I say
I know what confusion stagnation and
lack of identity feel like but today I
have the ability to travel anywhere I
please make money as a writer and meet
the kind of people who lift me up if you
mentally lock in to this video you will
unlock certain schemas which will help
you carve out the lifestyle you want and
ReDiscover the identity you truly have
so that when you are alone you are not
left thinking of what could have been
the first schema I'll give you right now
it is to stop thinking about the dream
life rather to think of the dream
lifestyle I've found it much easier to
solve for a good lifestyle than it is
for a good life the reason because the
concept of life is just it just has too
much baggage every religion or
philosophy has something to say to the
point at which I find it too hard to
take any action I found it much easier
to visualize the kind of Lifestyle I
want to have and it's much easier to
Define it's much easier to take action
towards this in the pursuit of this
dream lifestyle I found that I met
amazing people I've experienced the
stories that are the ingredients for a
good life but first I have a quick
disclaimer I'm not interested in
entertaining you or even educating you
I'm only interested in outcomes you will
acquire practical tools and schemas I
will give you context to these schemas
using real life stories I do this
because this is the way our brain
encodes information stories matter they
reprogram your brain before we start
we're going to do the huberman saai a
breathing technique that will help you
retain the information in this video
twice as better let's take a quick
double inhale and then let it out so
it's like
this so notice what I'm doing right it's
a belly breath a chest
breath and then let it out so let's do
this
together most people don't know that
finding Clarity building structure and
gaining momentum is a process not an
event it is an ongoing project that
every successful man in history has had
to learn and practice the goal of this
video is to get there faster in Winter
2017 my job was cleaning test tubes I
spent entire days transferring frog
cells from a cotton swab into a
centrifuge tube I was doing this all day
four weeks four months even and I was in
graduate school I was making less than
minimum wage and in the winter there
were entire weeks that I didn't see the
sun because I had to get the lab before
the sun rose and I would leave only once
the sun had set even though all all this
would have been worth it if I was
actually succeeding and I wasn't I loved
biology that was the reason I was in the
PHD program I'd worked myself into this
lab that studies human lineages using
gws it's um it's kind of like K3 and me
or ancestry.com but it forms the basis
for those website essentially we had
these weekly meetings every Thursday at
400 p.m. and I I hated them I used to
dread them I used to dread them because
well well my posture used to change and
go from the triumphant Lobster to the
defeated Lobster as I got crushed every
week I couldn't perform in this
environment because one I didn't have
Clarity I didn't see a connection
between my day-to-day activities and my
dreams I didn't have structure because
in a PhD program you don't have
structure almost no classes exams or
assignments you're just kind of left to
figure it out third I didn't have
momentum because I didn't have a sense
of growth research isn't linear half the
time you feel like you're moving
backwards or sideways as competing with
these fat neck beard nerds and these
neurotic females for a position that was
kept at the six figures low six figures
I remember thinking even if I win this I
still lose and this was when I made the
decision that would change my life
forever I hit the emergency button I
decided to join the Army there's this
silly saying which is not true but it's
it's funny
they say that when a woman hits Rock
Bottom she becomes a stripper when a man
hits Rock Bottom he joins the Army well
for me this was my chance this was my I
was going to go and transform in the
Army I quit the program the next day I
sent two emails and had two
conversations in a total of 20 minutes I
had burned years of Goodwill and years
of progress I was so sick of living this
life that I was conditioned into I
didn't know what I wanted but I knew
that I wanted CL I wanted structure I
wanted momentum I wanted to be people I
wanted to be around people I liked and
respected I wanted to restart reset and
reboot I felt that joining the Army was
the best way to get this though of
course I was naive at the time I
finished out my masters in biology and
got on a flight to Ford Benning Georgia
to be a part of the US Army infantry I
shared the story to show you that you
are only ever one decision away from
changing your life forever now this is
not advice I'm not suggesting you follow
the road that I took I think army
training was valuable to me but it was
also an absolute train wreck it was
beyond [ __ ] the Army had the chance
to mold confused boys into disciplined
and motivated men but it fails at that
mission every single day there are
absolutely some amazing drill sergeants
out there who serve as an inspiration
but the program as a whole was stupid
still leaves a bad taste in my mouth to
think of it not because the program was
too difficult which would have been fine
which have been cool actually but
because the Army made zero effort at
actually building up its Personnel the
actual tactical training like with
weapons training like using I don't know
using the Claymore or m4s whatever
equipment that we were using that was
actually cool but you may not believe
this I swear this is true my platoon
performed better on week 2 than it did
on week 20 we went for eager and ready
to learn and grow and work as a team to
just counting the days to get out it was
stupid man despite all this I succeeded
in using these months as a training
opportunity for myself I used it as a
golden opportunity for transformation I
had Clarity we as a platoon knew our
purpose we wanted to earn the crossed
rifles of the Infantry we wanted to earn
the blue cord and get the [ __ ] out of
Ford Benning I handly had structure as
well the drill sergeant told you when to
wake up they told you what to eat they
told you when to sleep you didn't have
any choices you only had four sets of
ocp pattern camo to choose from there
was no clothing to choose I even had
momentum I was able to rock longer
distances my pain tolerance and overall
ability to manage stress was clearly
improving I finally had a group of guys
around me though I didn't like all of
them they still made the same sacrifices
that I did I finally had time to think
through my limiting beliefs deprogram my
conditioning and detach from the friends
and family who are keeping me stuck in
the identity that I had in the past as a
direct result of this introspection I
started my YouTube channel and the
business that supports it for me I just
wanted the freedom to travel read books
go to museums play video games have
coffee at nice cafes meet interesting
people support my family and build cool
stuff with my team I don't want to worry
about gas prices inflation and grocery
bills I can say without a doubt that
going through the Infantry training
pipeline was a pivotal journey in my
life during this army training I
maintained a series of three black
journals years ago I had journaled about
the lifestyle I wanted I wanted to live
the beach life in a tropical refugium I
live in Hawaii one of the most beautiful
places and is and is home to one of the
most beautiful beaches on the planet I
wanted to travel the world to live and
meet guys who are on the same path of
asent as I was I spent the last month at
turkey with five amazing entrepreneurs
every lunch and dinner we had was
something that I would look forward to
we had a private Chef who cooked up
these amazing meals every day every
conversation we had led to new ideas
that I could use in running Crusade none
of this is Magic or manifestation all
comes down to cause and effect every
project small or large was nothing more
than an idea in a man's head if you're
living a lifestyle that you are not
satisfied with it may not be your fault
but it is your problem you will now
learn the exact schema to impose Clarity
on reality it is said that the goddess
Fortuna responds only to Men of strong
will and clear mind now you are going to
receive the actionable steps I'm going
to give you an exercise to do grab a
sheet of paper and divide it into two
halves if you're driving or otherwise
unable to do this at this time that's
fine just do it later the First Column
should be titled a normal day in one
year's time the second column is titled
sacrifices if you do not sacrifice for
your dreams your dreams become the
sacrifice this is going to be a key
learning so pay attention since ancient
times sacrifice has always been
important the ancient Greeks believed in
animal sacrifice and burnt offerings
they were not unique in this belief the
empires of Central America and the VC
kingdoms are just two easy examples that
come to my mind the carthaginians
sacrificed their own children to their
demon god Bal hamon until the Roman
Legions of course brought the fires of
Retribution and Vengeance to their
cursed City but sacrifice was never just
a matter of Slaughter even a butcher
could do Slaughter you had to perform
the sacrifice with specific details you
need to sacrifice a Bull of the right
color and quantity you needed the
sacrifice to be conducted by a priest of
sufficient power you needed the right
time of day you needed the right
direction of the wind you needed the
right phase of the moon if you didn't do
this right the gods wouldn't listen and
worse they would be offended now we
don't believe in this kind of sacrifice
anymore but the specificity of the
sacrifice this aspect is important
sacrifice is a trainable skill and this
video will provide you the basics you
have these two columns in front of you a
normal day in one year's time and
sacrifice under a normal day you will
write out a narrative From Dusk to Dawn
of a normal day in your life one year
from now from your perspective visualize
the details in your mind's eye and carry
it onto paper make sure it is so
beautiful that it hurts that you aren't
living that way right now I know there
are some of you who will be skeptical of
something like this You' say
visualization doesn't work hear me out
I'd like to show you a visualization
board that I created years ago you can
actually see the time stamps you'll see
beaches pineapples and volcanoes you'll
see food and drink with friends some
things are still pending like going on a
sailing Expedition and some goals have
changed for example I'm no longer
interested in the Porsche i' would
rather get a spec out Land Cruiser the
point is years ago I had added these
pictures as a collage describing my
dream life and now I live in Hawaii
which has guess what pineapples
volcanoes and beaches I never thought I
would live in Hawaii I had no opinions
one way or other as to where I wanted to
live it just so happened because that is
what I primed my mind to seek here's the
key learning you have to build castles
in the clouds before you can build them
on land even craus chaler was just a
vision a scribble on paper before it
became the Fortress Monastery of the
knights hospitaler so I take my vision
very seriously here are some questions
to get you started pause to Think
Through each of these before you answer
where do you live who do you live with
what's the weather like where you live
what time do you wake up do you have an
alarm clock do you make coffee or go to
a cafe when do you start working what
kind of work is it that you do how much
money do you make per month how much
money do you have in savings is there a
woman in your life what is she like do
you have pets do you have kids what does
your dream physique look like there are
no right or wrong answers to any of
these questions and if you have more
details and more questions that's a good
sign it means your imagination is acting
and in answering these questions for
yourself you are training your
visualization you're essentially
training your ability to set goals and
that is the step one in actually hitting
those goals the only way you can mess
this exercise Up Is by regurgitating The
Dream Life you heard from somebody else
if you talk about getting a Russian
girlfriend and living in Bali because h
said so you're wrong if you talk about
Bugattis and bimbos cuz Tate said so
you're wrong if you want to start a
school Community because horoi said so
you're wrong right until something
resonates with you another way you can
do this exercise wrong is by thinking
small if your vision doesn't intimidate
you slightly you're wrong people
overestimate what they can do in a day
but underestimate what they can do in a
year if you're actually locked in if you
actually had clarity structure and
momentum what could you do here's the
dream lifestyle I Envision for myself I
share this as an example one year from
now I'll live in Rome the Eternal City
I'll host a growth house in the city
similar to the one I hosted in Austin
Texas I'll spend time with guys who have
a similar level of experience of life
and business as me I'll get gelato every
day I'll go to the gym with the boys and
spend 10 to 20% of my income this is
important for me I'll spend 10 to 20% of
my income on being a patron of the Arts
I will commission artwork from real
human artists I will commission music
from real human artists I will increase
the beauty of the society I live in and
use these artworks and music pieces as a
part of my business I will show the
world what it means by the term business
as art I will treat my body as art after
surgery I'm finally able to rebuild I
will never take my breathing for granted
again I will Forge the Bronze Age
physique I don't want you to copy my
vision but if there are aspects of that
that resonate with you then you should
take them to be your own spend time on
this assignment any time that you spend
building your mind which is your primary
asset cannot be possibly spent in Wayne
the invisible work that we do today will
have visible results tomorrow results
comes from vision and action but action
isn't just the things we do it's Alo the
things that we choose not to do there
are no Solutions only tradeoffs this
means that to get closer to your goals
there are some things that you will need
to trade off when I sacrifice my fear of
being on camera I was able to grow a
personal brand that allows me to do work
that I find meaningful here's the thing
you cannot avoid sacrifice you can only
choose what sacrifices to make I will
share mine again as an example so you
have an idea of what it looks like here
are my sacrifices for the year of 2025
first I will make sacrifice of sweat and
toil in the temple of iron until I learn
to love it I will rebuild my body and
Purge the weakness for my body I'll use
my knowledge of biology to forge steal
second I will make sacrifice of money I
will go broke investing in myself I will
retain an emergency fund but other than
that I will pour my money into myself
and my business which is of course an
extension of myself I will sacrifice the
fears and limiting beliefs that my
parents transferred on to me I will
spend a minimum
$330,000 in self- investment over the
year of 2025 third I will make sacrifice
of time to make more and better videos I
will spend the time to do real research
and real thinking instead of using chat
GPT like all the other YouTubers you may
not know this but for every minute of
published content you see on my channel
there was 1 hour of work in the back end
in research writing recording and
editing most YouTubers who talk about
health aren't actually reading the
research they're just regurgitating what
other YouTubers say or reading blogs
they're not actually going through the
research because first to be fair it's
this is not on them because a lot of
research is behind a pay wall fine but
the second it's kind of hard to read
research papers you need training to do
this at this time pause the video and
take the time to complete the exercise
with the actual specific sacrifices that
you are prepared to make the the more
specific the sacrifice and more
emotional resonance that it has with you
the better at this time you know what
you want and you know what forces you
want to commit to achieve those
objectives so if you don't make those
sacrifices you don't have the right to
be surprised when you don't meet your
goals the objective of this video was to
give you Clarity not Comfort if you take
away one thing from this video it should
be this if you don't sacrifice for your
dreams your dreams will become that
sacrifice