all right boys today we are going to
prepare the legendary Lord of pepper
chicken in 5 minutes of preparation and
just 25 minutes in the oven you can
prepare 300 G of high quality protein
it's easy to eat easy to prepare easy to
store easy to heat up after cooking this
is for men who just don't have the time
for complex recipes when it comes to
chicken we have only five options
chicken breast thighs drumsticks wings
and the whole leg I don't like chicken
breasts because it doesn't have a lot of
fat which means it doesn't have a lot of
flavor which means the cooking process
to prepare good chicken breast is just
more complicated doesn't taste that good
anyway and the fat is a feature not a
bug so I actually want fat so chicken
breast off the table chicken wings it
it's like a bunch of work for not that
much reward cuz there's not much meat on
the wings anyway so I don't use chicken
wings that leaves us with drumsticks
that leaves us with thighs and whole
legs whole legs is just thighs plus
drumsticks so just get the whole legs
why is this is because is it's cheaper
per pound it's the same nutrition value
but it's cheaper per pound because there
one less uh manufacturing step or like
processing step really so whole legs is
the superior cut of chicken just always
get whole legs easy always get them to
the skin on because the skin is
nutritious the skin has essentially it
has collagen and other micronutrients
that are good for your own skin so you
want the skin on not just for that
reason but also because once you put it
through the oven it's going to crisp up
and the crispy chicken skin tastes
amazing so skin on always and of course
you know that not all chicken is created
equal we don't want to consume the
chickens that are kept in those little
cages or are in these cooped indoor
environments these have a lot of
antibiotic load because of the stress
and strain they're subjected to because
of their um environment essentially so
what do we do we look for pasture raised
if you see better chicken project or
Animal Welfare certified you can be sure
that this is some high quality chicken
and if you have more questions about
labels just put them in the comments
foods like this whole foods that aren't
too different from what our ancestors
ate is what I use to build up my body
relatively quickly this is what I looked
like posts surgery last year and these
are my latest gym progress photos
nutrition is of course one of the three
pillars of hormone optimized training
and this cannot be compromised to do
this recipe you need a few spices you
need a few seasonings all of which which
are easy to get in any grocery store
most people really think too much about
the salt they use but the truth is the
salt you use has a huge impact on the
flavor of the cooking in fact when I was
at the Austin growth house last year one
of the members Steven actually said that
he had the best steak he's ever had in
his life which I prepared for all the
boys and it wasn't because I'm some kind
of amazing Michelin store cook it was
because I was using high quality salt
and most people don't know anything
about salt so what is highquality salt
you can get Celtic Sea salt you can get
Peruvian salt or if you want the
absolute best microplastic free spring
salt you can get Vera salt then you need
the spices you need ground black pepper
you need crushed Rosemary you need thyme
you need onion powder garlic powder and
grounded Ginger basically the onion
garlic and ground ginger are kind of
support and boost the flavor of the
pepper and the rosemary thyme they add a
kind of aromatic uh frag
and freshness to the recipe But first
you need some cooking fat and you can
use butter like this carry gold I have
here or you can choose to use duck fat
now I'm going to coat this these chicken
legs up with a duck fat which means I
need to I need to remove this ring which
has gotten a bit stuck and I also need
to remove my legendary Seiko alpinist
don't want that to get dirty I am going
to open this up by the way boys if you
have duck fat or lard or Tallow once you
open it you do need to keep it in the
fridge it's just going to last way
longer so what you do is don't be afraid
to get get your hands dirty get some of
the duck fat put it on your palm it's
going to melt under the body
temperature and once it has you're just
going to apply it on the chicken uh
whole chicken legs just make a nice even
coat
and just move them around so the thing
about chicken is chicken actually has a
much higher and food contamination risk
than red meat like beef does you need to
be careful when you you're dealing with
chicken because you don't want to touch
the raw chicken and then touch other
things if you do you're just increasing
the chance of getting some terrible
illness so why is that right let's talk
about that um
simply the simple answer is this
chickens are
smaller so what's going on because a
chicken is smaller there's a higher
there's a the digestive tract of the
chicken is closer to the actual meat
that you consume so think about a cow
think about a large animal like a cow a
lot of the meat is coming from places
which are not in close proximity to the
digestive tract that digestive tract is
where a lot of the eoli and other
bacteria live so in case of chicken it's
there's a high likelihood that the
bacteria can jump from the digestive
tract onto the whole chicken legs which
is why we want to be careful but in
terms of red meat you can theoretically
I'm not saying you should do this you
can have red meat raw and that the
reason why red meat raw can work but raw
chicken meat cannot work is because of
the size of the animal and the proximity
of the digestive tract to the actual
muscle meat that you're consuming but
let's get back into this chicken recipe
I said that this recipe can be used to
get 300 g of protein I should be clear
about this so this recipe like what I
have right now is 150 g of protein but I
can just double up so I have two whole
legs right here but this this 12in
Skillet 12in cast iron skillet does have
enough room for two more and I've made
that before I just I'm not choosing to
make it right now because for the
purpose of the video this would be
faster so two legs 150 g of protein four
legs would be 300 of
[Music]
protein now what I'm going to do is just
knead all these spices and herbs into
the chicken here's an important
information that I need to give you the
oven so for long time I just didn't know
how to use the oven it's like there's so
many settings I didn't want to
understand how to use it and it was just
a pain in the ass so I just never
invested the time to learn it but oven
cooking is actually the easiest and best
because you can just make so much food
for no effort so here's I'm going to
show you the tricks I'm going to show
you the things which I've learned over
the years and now you don't have to
spend the same time and effort to learn
it so I'm going to show at this point
how to use the oven and this is kind of
my setup so I'm going to have to move
this chair so OB obviously everybody's
oven is going to be different but the
basics are still going to be the same
every oven is going to have a broil
setting going to hit this until it goes
to low and I want you to understand
where the element of the oven is so you
know where to adjust the the rack let
going open this
up so check this out in the oven right
the element is on the top which means
that the top of the oven is going to be
the hottest part of the oven so if I
have this rack all the way at this
setting then the food is going to be so
close to the element that it's going to
CH it's going to burn and it's going to
throw oil into the element and that's
going to cause a lot of smoke and might
even cause a fire so we never want to
use the setting we want to have the the
rack one 2 3 the third setting from the
top which will be perfect for this
recipe so there's there's different ways
to use the oven right the broil setting
what the hell is even the broil setting
so what is an oven how does it work
what's broil and what's bake so baking
in the oven is the the oven is set to a
certain temperature and it uses a
thermostat to maintain that temperature
so if you set 400° F it's going to get
the oven to 400° F and it's going to
keep it there that's one way of cooking
and that works great broil is different
broil does not have a set temperature Bo
broil just means that the element is
always going to be on so if you set low
broil it's going to it's going to set
itself to low and just stay on
throughout so what's the difference
between B bake and broil bake the
element is not always on
so once it gets the temperature to 400 c
not 400 F or whatever you set it at it
just turns on when that temperature
Falls below the set temperature like a
thermostat in fact it is a thermostat so
when the thermostat triggers the element
turns on but with broil the element is
always on so it's different cooking
techniques I could use the bake function
for this but it takes too long so I
instead I use the broil function because
the heat output of the element
is continuous and it Cooks the meat
faster so now you understand a little
bit of the the physics behind how this
equipment works and you can use it can
use better so what we do now we just
need to wait for the oven to heat up it
will take about 5 minutes and then we'll
get back into it now the oven's heating
up going to put the guy
into the top rack close her up and set
the timer
to 15
minutes at 15 minutes we flip it and
then set it for another 10
minutes all right boys it's been 15
minutes let's take her out and see what
she looks like oh got this the steam
steam Rising all right let's check
it okay looks good you can see some
initial Browning on the top which is
exactly what we'd expect I to flip her
over but to do that I need some Tong
and she
goes let's
check all right looks done maybe but'll
have to verify and how we check well I'm
going to switch my camera I'm going to
slice into the thickest part of it that
I can
find and let's see
so it looks to me like it's done so
let's see I'm cutting all the way to the
Bone and what are we going to see you
going to tell us if it's cooked or
not all right now it should be
completely done that is a completely
ready to go beautiful lot of pepper
chicken now it it's has too hot to taste
test right now so we'll come back to it
once it's cooled down in fact you want
to allow this chicken to cool down in
its own juices because it it kind of
reabsorbs some of it and retains some of
the moisture and as the chicken has
reached completion so it has the quinoa
look at that it's nice and fluffy has
not stuck to the bottom of the vessel
exactly how we want it
so how does it taste the quinoa tastes
light and Airy and the chicken the meat
is Juicy and fresh their skin is crispy
and peppery overall amazing nutritional
profile