what's up bro come on in hey
I never hit out without my New York City
hot outside I urge every New Yorker
doubt
aren't you happy that Our Benevolent and
kind and all-knowing government put
fluoride in our water aren't you happy
they found such a good use for
Industrial Waste sure it might build up
in our brains but at least it keeps our
teeth safe right
at a bar and a guy comes up to you in a
white lab coat and sprinkles something
into your drink and you ask him hey what
are you doing and he tells you he's from
the government and he's here to help he
says despite the fact that Florida
accumulates in your pineal gland in your
brain and despite the fact that there
seems to be a link between lower IQ and
fluoride it's still okay because it's
good for your teeth he says that the CDC
labeled water fluoridation to be one of
the greatest Health achievements of the
20th century the same CDC who have deep
grievance with you see when the pandemic
reads across the U.S and across the
globe the CDC had data showing that
obesity rates were strongly linked to
fatalities caused by that disease
however they did not try to raise
awareness about that at all they could
have had a campaign saying that obesity
is strongly linked to that disease which
I shall not name and that they should
reduce obesity rates and as a way to
fight against the disease but it chose
not to do that instead they promoted
regulation which caused the shutdown and
the bankruptcy of your small business
diabetes obesity and cancer rates the
government didn't do much of anything
regarding all of these but two Decay is
the one thing they care about they did
huge multi-year multi-city studies
studying tooth decay and water
fluoridation
they could have spent those resources
trying to figure out the root cause of
the increase in truth Decay they could
have realized is the high fructose corn
syrup and the carb intake and the sugar
intake which is causing this new
epidemic of tooth decay but they didn't
do all that instead they decided they
would solve the problem not by removing
the additives which are high fructose
corn syrup and refined sugars instead
they added a new additive fluoride to
try to fix the problem this goes against
everything the esoteric Health movement
stands for the esoteric Health movement
stands for a return to tradition to
return to the things that we know that
work and a removal of additives which
cause more harm than good you know you
have a successful psyop but instead of a
rational approach to your legitimate
concerns you get a irrational and
fearful and even angry response so the
fear against fluoride is completely
legitimate I'm just thinking you know
why should the government be adding
additives for medication purposes Mass
medication is not something to be taken
trivially but yet whenever anybody
raises any concern against water
fluoridation that immediately labeled as
a crank conspiracy theorist that
immediately dismissed out of fear and
misunderstanding why I mean think about
this most people all they know about
fluoride is the government says it's
good for your teeth so if you question
that narrative you question perhaps it
may not be that good for our teeth in
the first place number one and two it
might have other effects which have
nothing to do with teeth and instead
have to do with the brain the immediate
response for the most of the general
public is going to be well what else am
I thinking what else am I assuming which
is actually Incorrect and this causes
unease this causes a breakdown of
assumptions it's like when you pull a
car down from the bottom of the
cardstack and then Tire stack comes
crumbling down that's what happens when
it comes to talking about water
fluoridation it's such a foundational
thing that we think about when you think
about public health efforts and to
undermine that undermines all of Public
Health and this is why there's so much
resistance against talking about this
topic not that that's going to stop me
though but I want to reiterate that this
channel has never been about spreading
propaganda or fear or anything like that
the fact of the matter is I have some
facts which I want to share with you I
have some insights which I want to share
with you observations which I've made
you can make up your own mind and I'll
give you mitigation strategies which I
have used and I recommend fear and
mistrust of the overlords or the Puppet
Masters The Matrix Etc is completely
useless you aren't going to be able to
make a massive change in those
constructions those entrenched forces
what you can do is affect your daily
life your friends and Family's daily
life and that's all I'm recommending to
arrive at the conclusion that I'm
arriving to I use What's called the psy
op method science intuition observation
and philosophy so first let's look at
what the science has to say two things
pique my curiosity first that fluoride
is known to accumulate in the pineal
gland second that there seems to be a
link between lower IQ among among the
children born from women exposed to
fluoride as compared to women who are
not exposed to fluoride looking first as
the pineal gland issue we barely
understand the pineal gland how we
barely understand the brain in general
so what is going on here it seems that
calcification happens due to a variety
of reasons including just a normal part
of aging but the fluoride the fluoride
goes ahead and uses the existing calcium
to bind to and now we have not only the
calcification of the pineal gland but
also a buildup of fluoride in fact the
most fluoride saturated organ of the
body is not the teeth or bones it's
actually the pineal gland which boggles
the mind it's like why are we adding
this to our water supply then the
question of is fluoride really essential
for tooth Health answer is no most of
Europe doesn't fluorinate their water
I'll link to the countries which do
fluoride fluoridate that water now fair
enough Europeans get their fluoride from
toothpaste so am I against toothpaste
fluoridation or not that's a different
question which I'll get to the fact of
the matter is water fluoridation isn't
actually that effective or important
when it comes to tooth health so we have
this effect on the pineal gland that we
know of we also know that the effect on
tooth decay is minimal if anything so
the risk to reward ratio is already poor
and then we look at what's actually
going on again in IQ before we even get
to IQ there's something interesting that
I want to point out the rate of
calcification of the pineal gland is
actually twice in males what it is in
females and we don't know why like even
the best scientists in this field don't
really know why we barely understand
these things and when we don't
understand something the last thing we
should do is tamper with it now going
more deeply into the IQ issue what's
going on here again there seems to be an
effect more on males than females which
again scientists don't understand why I
don't understand why it seemed to be
happening but it's not clear why this is
happening what the information I'm
drawing from is coming from a 2019 paper
which shows that there's almost a five
point decrease among males who've been
exposed to fluoride as an infant in
their mother's womb and a 3.66 decrease
in females when they're exposed to
fluoride concentrations in the mother's
womb why this is happening is still
unexplained and the paper is actually
pretty good they control for other
pollutants the control for mercury lead
and other known neurotoxins so that they
can isolate the effect of fluoride and
they still found this lowering of IQ I
already know there's going to be a whole
bunch of comments at this point saying
well fluoride is actually present in
nature well yes it is well that's not
what you're getting in your tap water so
understand this magnesium fluoride yes
it's present in nature calcium chloride
yes it is some small amounts of sodium
chloride yes the fact of the matter is
hydrofluorocilicic acid which is what
they use in the water salination or
sorry water treatment plants is not
something present in nature it is a
industrial byproduct it's an industrial
waste it is a byproduct of either
aluminum production or fertilizer
production so phosphate fertilizer
production so it's a waste product which
is why they government gets it for so
cheap and that's what they use in the
plants they use to create the fluorides
which they put in your water why are
they doing this and why is it so
acceptable that they do this the
calcification of the pineal gland issue
especially is very concerning to me you
see the pineal gland again like I said
it's poorly understood but we know for a
fact that it does have a huge effect on
sleep cycles it has a huge effect on
menstrual cycles it's a very very
important gland it has important
functions when it comes to sexual health
so what's going on here we cannot mess
with this gland which we barely
understand by adding fluorides which
shouldn't be there and then hope that
it's all okay just because it's good for
our teeth the hubris the absolute
Madness and hubris which goes into the
decision-making process of the scientist
slash garment is mind-boggling to me we
have to be extremely careful when it
comes to things relating to the human
body especially the brain think about
this the most complex organ or the most
complex structure on the face of the
Earth and probably in the universe as we
know it is the brain some of you are
already pulling out papers saying
fluoride is safe you misunderstand the
point that I'm making the point I'm
making is philosophical so there is
clearly some mud in the water there are
some doubts as to whether fluoride is
actually safe for all organ systems in
the body understand this there's a
principle called informed consent in a
medical Sciences you only provide
medication to people who provide
informed consent the only two exceptions
are one for children who aren't able to
provide informed consent so that
guardian or parent provides you from
consent and then of course we have the
extreme elderly who again for the same
reasons you have Guardians providing
information informed consent means you
understand the risks and the rewards of
a treatment program and knowing those
risks and rewards you say yes when it
comes to fluoride even the top
scientists don't understand fully what
it does to the body so none of us are
really in a position to give informed
consent but the government deems it okay
to add this medication to the water
regardless of this principle so it's a
violation of a medical principle and
then we have the Hippocratic oh doctors
take the Hippocratic Oath it's an oath
which says Do no harm first Do no harm
it means when you do a medical
intervention your first priority to make
sure that you're not causing harm in the
due course of your medical intervention
so what's going on with the fluoridation
systems yeah you could say that it does
help our teeth which I have some doubts
about that but let's say it does help
our teeth it does harm other organ
systems you violate the Hippocratic Oath
you are potentially doing harm so both
philosophical principles are violated
then we have of course the idea that the
brain is a complex system probably it's
the most complex system that we know of
and then when you take into account that
Society what is society Society is a
network effect of millions and billions
of brains right brains are all really
impeccably designed designed and
amazingly complex you take those and you
have a network effect and that's what
Society is we barely understand these
things it's extreme hubris which says
you can add things to protect our teeth
which could have other effects on
society and our brains so for those
philosophical Reasons I'm very very
negative towards the idea of mass
medication and this is the Crux of the
esoteric Health movement where finding
out that the cutting and science backs
up ancient Traditions is finding out
that there are secrets hidden from us
the common people simply don't know
various facts about what they consume
I'm planning to make one mini course per
month for this exclusive community and
the first I'm thinking of is of course
testosterone boosting and esoteric
Health but later on I would like to do a
course on being a synthesizer which is
what I'm doing right now I'm
synthesizing Knowledge from a variety of
sources and bringing it together in an
easily understood and narrative fashion
with storytelling so that you retain the
information which you're learning we
talked about some of the bad stuff but
there is good news too there was a study
done on mice brains well mice are not a
perfect proxy for the human brain
obviously but they are pretty good
because they're mammals so they took
mice brains and they studied what
happens if they remove fluoride
completely from their diet and water and
what they found is actually the pineal
gland cells start to grow once you
remove fluoride so that's a very good
sign for us it means that if we cut out
the fluorides from our diet and water it
actually might help us grow our own
pineal glands back and might reverse
some of the damage which was done so the
question becomes well how do you do this
how do you cut out the fluoride from the
water I will give you all the
information you need to know regarding
mitigation at the end of this video we
talked about science and philosophy now
it comes to intuition what does my
intuition say well the one thing
everything just feels off about the
whole fluoride thing the fact that the
government cares so much about well our
tooth decay and doesn't really care
about diabetes cancer and obesity is
very concerning to me and it just is a
red flag to me this is intuition this is
not science I'm not proving something
with evidence this is my gut feeling
that that what's going on here isn't
correct so I'm trying to separate out
the science and my own feelings I don't
want to necessarily bias the science
right so another thing is the
evolutionary angle behind this humans
have been around for millions of years
why is it suddenly that we need fluoride
to keep our teeth safe if you look at
the fossil record this is interesting
you actually see the best quality teeth
the strongest teeth strongest skulls in
pre-agricultural human beings so before
agriculture was invented that was when
humans were the most healthy so
agriculture does not actually help the
human condition it was actually when
people were hunting for their food that
people were more healthy looking at bone
structure looking at teeth health but
even then really think about this so the
incavement times you know like
prehistoric and even the Bronze Age
times even after agriculture if people
didn't have teeth by the age of 10 if
people's teeth were rotting off by the
age of 10 or 15 then a humans wouldn't
have made it this far right humans
wouldn't have made it this far if teeth
literally just brought it and fell out
from ages 10 to 15 which was what was
happening in the mid 90s and and of
course instead of looking at the root
cause which was probably high fructose
corn syrup and carbohydrate intake
increase they found an artificial
solution for an artificial problem they
found an industrial solution for an
industrial problem this is backwards
what they should have done is gone right
to the source and then cut the source
they didn't do this and this is a
failure on a Monumental level we talked
about science we're talking about
philosophy and intuition now we come to
the observations what did I observe when
I cut out fluorides from my water supply
so here's something interesting I didn't
connect the dots when it first happened
because it's a very very very slow
process when you come off the fluoride
right I cut out the fluid from the water
and I was looking for non-fluoridated
toothpaste and I bought one I used it I
was looking for a different one I looked
at the reviews on Amazon for one of the
non-fluoridated toothpaste and what I
learned was a lot of people in the
reviews were saying that they were able
to dream better and I remember thinking
yeah I felt the same thing I saw the
same benefit I found that I was dreaming
more nights like I was able to retain my
dreams it remember my dreams for more
nights and I realized that all these
people who were all doing the um
non-fluidated toothpaste they probably
were like me being skeptical of the
fluoridation of our water and probably
used fluoride filters as well so a large
collection of people all of them had the
same result which was a result in deeper
and better sleep which makes sense
because I talked about the pineal gland
before and the pineal gland has a huge
effect on our sleep cycles so perhaps
now of course this is just a hypothesis
right this is not a scientific study and
I don't claim to make a scientific
theory on this topic I'm just saying
that a large number of people when they
came off fluoride are dreaming better
and that's all I need to know that's
enough for me that's enough observation
for me to recommend this to you over the
past eight months or maybe even nine
months I've been practicing an esoteric
oral hygiene routine if you want that
video put it in the comments below did
you know that Listerine was literally a
psychological operation Listerine is not
a mouthwash it's a floor cleaner the
company which made Listerine rebranded
and resold a floor cleaner as a
mouthwash with very clever Marketing in
fact I think the word halitosis which is
bad breath with literally coined by them
to make bad breath sound like a scary
disease rather than just what it is it's
a common problem and instead of
addressing again root causes of probably
carb intake and high fructose corn syrup
they decided to sell a literal floor
cleaner as a mouthwash and guess get
this Listerine actually doesn't help
halitosis Listerine has alcohol in it
which dries out your mouth which causes
imbalances of microbes in your mouth
there's the gut microbiome which I'm
sure you've heard of is also the mouth
microbiome and I don't even want to go
into what fluoride does to the mouth
microbiome but the fact of the matter is
Listerine actually destroys your
microbiome and reduces saliva output and
that causes
bad breath in the mouth so I will give
you my entire oral hygiene routine if
you ask for it in the comments but don't
worry about it I'll give you your
esoteric skin care before I do that but
jumping back into Philosophy for a
second who does the burden of proof lie
on this is a very important Concept in
Philosophy for example in Criminal
Courts the burden of proof lies on the
accuser the accuser has to prove that
the guilty is guilty only then is a
punishment made it out that's not the
case when it comes to our health and
additions to our health like artificial
additions to our health the burden of
proof lies in the claim that they should
add X Y and Z to our diet to make us
healthier because more often than not
additions harm us so we should be extra
skeptical the burden of proof should lie
on those who want to change the status
quo it is not up to us to prove that
fluoride is unsafe it is up to them to
prove that fluoride is safe not only
safe but safe for every single person
and every single organ system in every
single body it's only then that we can
allow this to be be added to public
water supply because they literally
force you to drink this understand this
it's going to take you about 200 to get
the fluid out of your water I haven't
even gone into the mitigation section
yet but I'm telling you right now it's
going to cost 150 to 200 for you to get
your water purified so the government is
adding this stuff to our water and then
charging essentially 200 to get it out
this is simply unfair it's an example of
government overreach finally here we are
at the mitigation sections reactionable
steps what do you actually do like what
do you physically do and what purchases
can you make right I'll tell you first
thing charcoal filters so charcoal
filters are those Brita charcoal filters
you attach on your Taps Unfortunately
they don't do a great job of removing
fluoride from your water they do an
excellent job of removing estrogenic
substances from your water so if all you
can afford is the chi 40 charcoal filter
you should still get one it's still
worth your time still worth your money
that's literal birth control estrogenics
in your water do you know that the water
filtration plants don't remove birth
control from the water so women who take
birth control they pee those molecules
out of their body that goes into a water
supply Ai and the water treatment plant
does not filter these substances out
when you drink them so you're literally
drinking birth control estrogenics which
come out of a woman's pee the effects
that it has on the male body and also
the female body is something you will
see in a different video if you want
that video let me know and then we come
back to the mitigation section right so
you should buy a charcoal water filter
if that's all you can afford that's fine
do it because there's a difference
between the estrogenics and the fluoride
so the estrogenics had an immediate
effect on your body the fluoride
actually is a buildup process it takes
some time to accumulate and then become
toxic so you have some time if you're
too broke right now to afford a better
filter get the charcoal filter and then
stop being broke like you got to make
money this is not a money making Channel
find the right guys the right channels
which teach you how to make money and
start making money that you can afford
an RO system a reverse osmosis system is
what I recommend a Reverse Osmosis
System removes up to 95 percent of the
fluoride in your water so if you can
spend 200 bucks and get an RO filter
that's exactly what you should do and of
course not just the fluoride right the
RO filter is going to remove the and
other substances as well so you should
absolutely absolutely invest in that
spending 200 on an RO filter is far more
beneficial than spending it on like
supplements or something like that and
the other alternative is a water
distiller this is the ultimate option
now the RO filter is very convenient
because you just turn on a tap and you
get clean water a distiller is more hard
to use but it is very efficient the
difference between the RO filter and
distiller is distiller literally removes
everything from the water so maybe you
lose out on some minerals and
electrolytes by doing that but a
distiller it's also about 150 to 200 US
dollars it will evaporate the water and
then condense it so that you have pure
H2O pure water as pure as you can get it
anyway but the thing is if you use a
distiller you need to add electrolytes
back into the water for you to actually
use it don't drink distilled water like
it'll actually harm you you need
distilled water plus electrolytes for it
to be absorbed better by the body
understand that you are at The Cutting
Edge you are at the Forefront of the
esoteric Health movement you need to
watch my video on seed oils which is a
whole different topic to check that
video