80% of the people who tried prayer felt
the power boost so what is this power
boost actually it's more than one thing
so let's discuss a few of them the first
is luck you literally become more lucky
and things just start to go your way
when you engage truthfully in prayer
this is one of the chief differences
between meditation and prayer when you
start praying for something a solution
to a problem guidance to make a decision
or a fresh opportunity to take control
of your life often times you'll get it
some of these experiences be so surreal
that you never want to share it with
anybody prayer primes your brain to
detect opportunities and find Solutions
it is literally a strategic asset the
second Advantage is the aura of command
consistent prayer gives you this Primark
Aura basically a Halo of Charisma that
you never had before this happens
because you move with a purpose through
life and people are going to tend to
notice Goan is the Gloom of nihilism you
are wrapped in this armor of purpose
that most people can absolutely detect
most people will be drawn to it both men
and women especially women though
because they're more perceptive about
these things I'm not speaking of sexual
attraction I'm speaking of something
different people will trust you more not
because you're using some of these
Robert Green's disgusting little weasel
tactics but rather you're genuinely a
more trustworthy person by the way if
you've read 48 Laws of Power you need to
watch my video on it to understand its
weaknesses as well well as its strengths
you become memorable to the people
around you because nobody carries thems
with that kind of shity anymore you
aren't just thinking about the next exam
the tax deadline or how to approach this
damn Starbucks Barista you're thinking
of higher and greater things the fourth
Advantage is the death of nihilism
here's a question for you how much light
does it take to light up a dark room not
much if you can light up a single candle
you can pretty much see around you no
matter how much Darkness there is the
smallest flame can still defeat it light
has an asymmetric advantage over the
dark and so it is with hope against
despair it is impossible to be consumed
by nihilism when you have a habit of
daily prayer the fifth Advantage
resilience prayer builds faith and Faith
builds resilience sometimes the
situations that we find ourself are so
miserable that there seems to be no
logical reason to continue the struggle
but there in lies the weakness of logic
logic relies on knowledge and knowledge
is always incomplete or sometimes
incorrect sometimes you need a reason to
continue the fight that is illogical
that is not based on facts sometimes you
need faith that it will all work out in
the end and so it is better to start
with the habit of prayer before
circumstances force you to the fifth
Advantage is physical strength you may
not believe this until you try this out
dedicate the last few reps or even the
last full set to the heavens and you
will feel the second win you'll feel the
weights becoming lighter and you'll be
able to get more reps in it's kind of
crazy it's something you can literally
try today to verify that I'm telling the
truth the sixth Advantage protection
from addiction most people don't know
this but people don't get addicted to
porn because they're horny or drugs
because they need the high rather
there's a vacuum inside the psyche that
they're trying to fill you get a massive
power boost in terms of willpower if you
manage to squeak out a prayer before you
act out your addiction now I ask you a
question have you felt any of these in
your life if so tell me in the comments
below because this would be so helpful
for guys from different perspectives to
have this discussion as to our personal
experiences now I know that I've given
you selfish self-centered and practical
and materialistic reasons to consider
the act of worship and besides that I'm
sure many are thinking that these
benefits are nothing but Placebo let me
answer the first objection first first
and here's the reason why I'm doing this
I'm doing this because the reason you
start is not the reason you stay you
think about going to the gym ideally
You're motivated to go to the gym
because of the innate health benefits
however most of us start going to the
gym because we had a bad breakup we were
bullied in school so we wanted to
toughen up or even the most common one
we just wanted to get laid but once you
start working out you see benefits that
you didn't even expect you start
learning about diet and nutrition and
now you have more energy and focus than
ever before you wanted to get good with
chicks but your new confidence actually
gives you more success in business and
college the reason you start going to
the gym isn't necessarily the reason you
stay the same journey is true for prayer
and I know that because I've been on the
same road you start doing it for the
power boost but you stay doing it for
higher Reasons I'm going to tell you how
to reap these rewards and how you can
get started with time you'll find your
own way you might choose to
wholeheartedly Embrace religion or you
might not that is a personal choice that
I am not going to try to influence you
with what I can help you with is just
getting started the central question of
this communic is does prayer work and
the answer is an unchallenged yes from
every mud hut tribe to the grandest
civilizations man has ever built if
these folk didn't see a benefit on a
day-to-day basis they would have stopped
wasting their time with this because
after all people in the past had zero
free time but they always made time to
pray now let's look at a different
context let's look at physical health
our modern diet is trash and everybody
kind of knows this but what happens when
you remove the modern ingredients from
our diet like seed oils and replace them
with traditional ingredients like butter
or Tallow we get a power boost let's
look at hormonal Health as soon as we
get exposure to Daily Sunshine like our
ancestors did we get a power boost when
we look at Social Health as soon as we
focus on real life interaction over
internet interaction we get a power
boost the Modern Age We live in is not
inherently bad it's just that we have
divorced ourselves so much from our
biological and cultural roots that we
start becoming ill health as you know
has five aspects physical hormonal
mental social and spiritual it's a
surprise to nobody that Society is ill
in all five of these aspects to the
degree that we move away from what our
ancestors did we live in a Godless age a
post religion age of nihilism and
direction we live in an age of physical
hormonal mental and social and spiritual
deine for the first time in human
history we've had the hubris to think
that we are the Masters of the Universe
we think that the scientists in their
lab codes have it all figured out the
funniest part is though that the
greatest scientists of the ages have
believed in God it's wner Heisenberg the
father of quantum mechanics who said the
first gulp from the glass of the the
Natural Sciences will turn you into an
atheist but at the bottom of the glass
God is waiting for you so what is he
speaking of he's talking about the fact
that when you spend time to learn about
creation it's the same as spending time
to learn about he who creates in modern
times our very own Chad neurobiologist
Andrew huberman talks about prayer out
loud every single day he talks about
publicly and openly how his life changed
when he restarted and embraced his
childhood practice of prayer this video
is for atheists agnostics pagans
Christians everybody this because I have
no intention of pushing my belief system
on you I have zero authority to tell you
what to believe for most of my adult
life I was an atheist I was an atheist
because I was logical and skeptical I
wanted to make sense of the universe
without resorting to assumptions and
hand waving I did not accept the idea
that a holy book could be proof for the
religion because that would be just
circular reasoning more importantly I
found no spiritual resonance in the
houses of religion it looked to me then
as it looks to me now that most people
at these places of worship are just
laring none of it was inspiring to me
and I had no time for such things so I
just dismissed it I assumed that prayer
itself was meaningless because it felt
like Santa Claus wish fulfillment for
adults but here's the thing it works
anybody who engages truthfully and
honestly with prayer will tell you that
it just works you don't have to take my
word for it if you try what I'm going to
suggest for 7 days and if it doesn't
work out then it just quit you might say
that prayer is just a placebo that's
fine I'm not here to argue with anybody
the fact is there are life-changing
benefits that you can choose to access
if you want to I'm not making a
spiritual argument or even a scientific
argument I'm making an intentionally
practical argument because we live in a
materialistic Society not a spiritual
one I cannot prove that God exists nor
that he doesn't however I can prove that
prayer has tangible benefits it's a
testable hypothesis you can test this
out right now well in the 7-Day frame
and see if I'm right or wrong the worst
outcome is you wasted a couple minutes
if I'm right however you just change
your life forever if a belief system or
practice improves your life and gives
you power there's no reason to not at
least give it a shot even Jordan
Peterson is in line with this message
when people ask him if he believes in
God he always answers I act as though
God exists he doesn't give a yes or no I
I always assumed that he was trying to
weasle his way out of it he doesn't want
to commit one way or other but now have
a deeper appreciation for his wisdom
what he's saying is actions speak louder
than words if he acts as though God
wants him to then that is more valuable
than just saying that he believes in God
besides it's impossible to choose to
have faith like I said in my previous
video where I discuss the history and
future of religion and make a prediction
as to what's coming in the internate age
faith is not a switch that you can turn
on or off you cannot choose to have
faith even if you wanted to you could be
a naturally skeptical and logical person
who simply cannot accept this stuff
without proof that's fine in this video
I haven't actually told you to believe
in anything I'm only here to tell you
the Practical and materialistic benefits
of prayer if you eventually change your
views after engaging in this practice
that's all you that's nothing to do with
me I going to give you a practical guide
and framework to get you started the
first step is we need to understand the
nature of God we need a framework to
understand God that is not so
philosophical and Abstract that we lose
any sense of intuitive understanding if
we'll think of God in the same way as
our ancestors did they thought of him as
a father Christianity calls God the
Divine father one of the three aspects
of the Holy Trinity the pagans worship
du putter or Sky father this is Zeus of
the Greeks this is Jupiter of the Romans
this is Indra of my forbear
regardless of your beliefs it is clear
that we as a species have this intuition
that God is a heavenly father who rules
over all let's use that exact same
picture of God as we move forward
imagine you were a father and you had a
son you'd like to shower your son with
gifts and love all the time but you also
want to see your son grow up to meet his
innate potential this means you can and
will help him but only if he's earned
your favor if your son is honest
hardworking resourceful and receptive to
your advice then of course you'll give
him a little boost and on the other hand
if your son is a lying cheating little
prick you might let him have success for
a little while but at the end you're
going to teach him a harsh lesson this
is the intuition for how God works the
Second Step you don't need to explain
your beliefs or your faith to anybody
it's not your job to be a spirit guide
to anybody perhaps except your own
children and your wife strangers don't
need to understand or be convinced this
is personal if it makes sense to you and
you gain benefit from it then literally
the entire Globe can call you a fool and
it wouldn't matter to be a man of faith
in this modern world is to be the
ultimate non-conformist we live in a
society that actively tries to Snuff out
any vestage of the spiritual and the
Divine wonder is not permitted here only
bureaucratic truth in the form of
peer-reviewed journals is available here
I want you to understand this science is
a powerful tool to understand reality
but its greatest strength is also its
greatest weakness science relies on the
ability to replicate results if an
observation is non-replicable it is
considered junk but here's the thing
there are observations that you can make
that are true yet they are nonreplicable
so many stories in history have men
doing heroic Deeds because they saw a
vision if a modern man was to see a
vision that he couldn't explain he would
immediately dismiss it as a
hallucination and considered himself to
be a schizophrenic don't be a modern man
have the courage to believe your own
eyes your own ears your own senses your
own intuition over trusting the words of
others this is why I always insist on
the Primacy of direct personal
observation and testing and to have
faith in your own intuition even when it
comes to health and diet topics which I
am passionate about and have covered in
this channel a couple times I openly
tell you to doubt my words until you try
them and see for yourself and so it is
with worship try and see for yourself
with 100% sincerity don't take my word
for it third step it is important to be
very careful what you ask for if you ask
for material things like cars and money
and women you'll likely get it but you
need to be very careful because stuff
like that comes at a heavy cost the
greatest things you can ask for will
actually strengthen your bond with with
the father think about this if you're a
kid and you ask your father for a PS5
you might get it but there's no
improvement in the bond between you and
the father if anything if you spend all
your time playing video games the bond
with your father might actually suffer
on the other hand if you ask your father
to get you a gym membership to the gym
that he goes to now we're on to
something not only do you get your
father's respect but your father will
actually grow more fond of you and
support you in your future endeavors and
spend more time with you much better to
us for things which will actually least
help you become a better person rather
than ask for physical stuff that you own
you can ask for good health you can ask
for the strength to be an honest man in
a dishonest time you can ask for the
courage to sacrifice pleasure for future
growth step four you use your voice
there is a difference between thinking
thoughts in your head versus saying them
out loud there is a difference between
thought and action huberman actually
talks about this how he verbally
expresses prayer rather than just saying
it in his head that the third sentence
in Genesis is and God said let there be
light and there was light God didn't
think light into existence in the
Christian tradition he spoke light into
existence now there's a question as to
what you should say how you should say
it and I'll give you a basic guide after
step five speaking of step five is
consistency and Progressive overload we
know how important the stuff is when we
think of the gym or even meditation the
same is true for prayer that being said
there are some clear differences you
cannot really track progress you cannot
buy better equipment or more supplements
however you can feel the progress and if
you can't put numbers on it you can
absolutely feel a protective Aura you
feel more resilient you become more
honest with others because you care less
about the Judgment of people you feel
Unstoppable because the heavens are with
you literally just include prayer in
your morning and nighttime routines and
just do it as a daily thing habits stack
it with something you do every day one
of the most important parts of my
morning routine is just stepping outside
in the sun after waking up I've always
said that this is to reset my circadian
rhythm to get better sleep at night and
to just have better overall health but
also what better time to offer up
worship to the heavens now I'm going to
give you the actionable steps the
autistic level practical guide here's
the basic format of worship start by
giving thanks Express gratitude for
literally anything which comes to your
mind the gym session laughing with your
friends the nice weather outside
whatever visual comes to your mind talk
about anything that made your day just a
little bit better even if you're having
a terrible day you can be thankful for
the ability to speak the ability to
breathe to walk then you speak of
something that could be improved
something that you need help with
something that is causing you pain think
of what character trait you would need
to overcome that pain that is imagine a
version of you that could defeat that
problem and come out on top do you need
to be more brutally honest with yourself
ask for the strength to be honest are
you struggling with a difficult decision
that's eating you up ask for guidance
are you feeling guilty about something
that you did ask for forgiveness in this
poll I asked what is causing the most
pain in your life and the majority
answer was lack of Direction well
there's two pieces to solving that
problem one is to take action to try new
things the other is to be able to listen
to the voice inside your head to listen
to that guiding voice but you have have
to ask for guidance in order to receive
it and that's it really that's the
fundamentals of prayer it's true of all
religions obviously if you have
adherence towards any particular
religion just incorporate my advice to
the practices of that religion I
personally have found a lot of benefit
in having a recital prayer every single
day this is the prayer dear father I
thank you for this day give me the
strength to speak honestly give me the
fortitude to live with honor give me the
wisdom to know my duty may my actions
speak for me as fortune favors the Bold