every civilized man regardless of where
he's from or where he lives thinks about
the Roman Empire every single day and
after this video you'll know exactly why
in July of this year I marched upon the
city of Rome well actually I took the
train from Naples but you get the point
so most people plan their Europe trip to
go and have good food drink good wine
meet fine women Etc not that I didn't do
any of these but my true objective was
to trace the path of the great General
Hannibal Barca as he voyaged into Italy
two words Rome so I better understand
what it is about the Eternal City that
captures the male psyche so well I went
from the coasts of Liberia across the
French Riviera through the Alps into
Italy proper to Naples and then to Rome
in order to bring you this story most
people don't know this but Rome wasn't
always a superpower there was an other
superpower across Mediterranean in
Africa this superpower was called
Carthage Carthage was the enemy of Rome
and their General Hannibal burka was the
arch nemesis is of the Roman Republic
the thing is the Romans knew he was
coming and the Roman knew how good an
army and a general that he was so they
were very they were warned they thought
that perhaps he would attack from the
West attacking at masalia from the
Iberian Peninsula perhaps he would
attack from the East maybe he would be
making allies with the macedonians in
Greece perhaps your attack from the
south may be attacked directly from
Africa which is his home base but no our
mad lad takes Italy from the north
across the Alps our feet were just
considered impossible marching his army
with elephants across the Alps during
the winter and then he of course lost
men during the grueling journey across
the Alps but when he came into Italy he
was taking Rome completely by storm
completely by surprise now Hannibal knew
exactly what he was doing he was a
fantastic General one the best on the
planet across history across time so he
knew why he did what he did he had to
take Rome by surprise Rome at this point
was a powerful powerful force with the
Navy and an Army strong as his if not
stronger in terms of Manpower but
Hannibal was not to be dissuaded he
would take Rome no matter what he had a
job to be done and in his own words he
would rather find a way or he would make
one and as I followed his path from
Portugal and Spain all the way to France
and through the Alps into Italy I
actually met up with Channel subscribers
and they took me to the coolest little
places which only locals would know the
best part about having an audience on
social media is every city I go to I
know people there or at least people
know me there and they're willing to
take their time out to show me cool
places but regardless even after Rome
was invaded from the north completely by
surprise by Hannibal Barker the Roman
Empire was quick to recover and quick to
react Rome marshalled its armies
thousands of men strong tens of
thousands of men strong and they sent
them against the great General Hannibal
Barker but you think that Hannibal
Parker didn't really have reinforcements
he was in enemy territory all he had was
what he came with across the Alps he
couldn't really refit he didn't have
more equipment he did have more food he
was on the back foot kind of but then
again he was Hannibal Barca No Ordinary
man like I said before so when the Roman
armies arrayed against him at Lake
tressamine they were pushed into the
lake at trebia they were annihilated at
Kanai they were butchered you understand
that these are not normal defeats in the
same sense that we understand it in
modern battle and Modern Warfare entire
armies were wiped out 80 000 men lost in
an afternoon at the Battle of Kenai when
they got encircled and butchered by the
carthaginians and what does Rome do what
does a sane Nation do when nearly
one-third of its male population gets
wiped out in a day they would capitulate
any sane Empire anything Kingdom I
should say or actually Republic would
have in fact capitulated and sued for
peace try to get the best terms of peace
with Carthage but not Rome Rome would
rather be raised to the ground rather
than be subjugated or defeated in battle
that was the kind of Roman Republic that
existed in the day of Hannibal
impossible to be every time you beat it
it only becomes stronger it's resolved
hardens with every defeat how do you
defeat such a foe and yet that same room
about six to eight hundred years later
when the barbarians were at the gates
they couldn't resist even though they
had more riches than ever even though
they had better technology more soldiers
they had everything on their side they
were not caught by surprise when The
Barbarians came to take their lands and
take their women and destroy their city
but they couldn't do anything about it
they didn't have the resolve they didn't
have the training they didn't have the
backbone which they had during the time
of carthaginian invasion that same room
which despised tyranny above all the
same room that hated Kings and dictators
would eventually become the home of the
worst excesses the worst Emperors Mad
Men and incompetence tyrants and
Emperors would rule over Rome and take
it to the ground of course we had some
good Emperors as well but the same room
which would never accept tyranny became
one of the biggest tyrannies on the
planet and across history so understand
this during the time of Hannibal they
hated the idea of a tyrant so much that
they didn't want to put all the power
into one man's hand so even the Roman
army would not be controlled by one man
they would actually change the general
they would have actually two generals
for the Army and they would switch them
out every other day so that one man
doesn't accumulate too much power how
crazy is that they hated tyranny that
much that they would go to absurd
lengths in order to prevent the
centralization of power in one man's
hand and in fact this this Quirk of the
Roman army was taken to its advantage
taken advantage of by Hannibal Barker he
realized that the Romans would change
their General every single day and use
that as a part of his tactics to defeat
them but regardless the points of stands
that they hated tyranny Rome hated
tyranny more than any Nation across
history and yet they fell to corruption
and tyranny this is a Learning lesson to
us all in every civilized part of the
globe this is one of the reasons why men
think of the Roman Empire every single
day they must that is their job and a
lot of external threats the Rome that we
know the Rome that we read about of
course destroyed the external stretch
one after the other conquering across
the Rhine into Germania let me give you
a list of reasons why men think of the
Roman Empire every single day first of
all the Aesthetics of course the
architecture art and the color scheme
the color scheme of gold against Crimson
the Aesthetics of the Roman Empire were
top-notch the architecture of the city
of Rome is breathtaking and I should
know I was there a couple months ago
it's gorgeous and you have to think what
we have now is just the ruins of a dead
Empire the pantheon Temple to the god
Jupiter amazing structure I mean it
still exudes so much power that Dome is
so large it's impossible almost to
recreate its towers still stand reaching
Towards the Sky you can actually go
there today and touch the very columns
that held this wall up for hundreds of
years and to this day the Roman Empire
inspires so much art and culture and
music and believe so long as
civilization stands Rome will never die
away from our hearts the second reason
why men think of the Roman Empire every
day was of course because of the values
they stood for they stood for honor and
courage and virtue and Legacy and family
and these are the virtues which are
dying in this day of course we think
about these things about the things that
we lost the things that the Roman Empire
stood for but that being said the Romans
were not just a bunch of disciplinarians
always doing their Duty Etc no they knew
how to have a good time read about what
they did during the Festival of
saturnalia and most of all we remember
Rome because of the greatness that they
achieved and of course the great fall
that they had they achieved all the
glory that was known to man but they
also therefore felt the hardest and is
up to us to learn what they did right so
that we can emulate that and we can also
learn from what they did wrong that we
may be warned indeed let's get into that
last Point what can we learn from the
decline in fall of the Roman Empire
first of all I want to talk about the
praetorian Guard the praetorian guard
were hand-picked Elite soldiers from the
legion whose only job was to defend the
emperor against all ill they were just
Noble and fiercely loyal to the emperor
and what they did their job was to be
kind of a secret service they were
intelligent and brave men who would
protect the Empire against all threats
internal and external and this they did
do for quite a few decades until they
too fell to corruption and what happened
there is the praetorian guard the Secret
Service of the Roman Empire they
realized that their power and money
doesn't depend so much on the job they
do but rather how much control they have
over the emperor so if they had a
genuinely competent and good Emperor he
would Reign their power in and so their
incentives were bad you know their
incentives were in fact to install a
puppet their incentives if they wanted
the maximum amount of freedom for
themselves and a maximum amount of money
for themselves was to install a puppet
Emperor who they could control and of
course kill murder any Emperor who was
actually showing signs of competence and
they did this it happened a lot the best
Emperors or at least the best Emperors
who could have Arisen and restored the
Roman Empire were butchered by their own
bodyguards for their own benefits
because of their own greed and
Corruption and they installed
incompetence who they could control and
now this of course has certain
disturbing parallels with what we see in
the modern world I won't go too much
into this but any man with a thinking
mind can understand what it is I'm
trying to say next let's talk of
demographic change the Roman Empire was
vast and had many many different
cultures in a time where different
cultures actually were different so they
had many cultures they had many
different races and demographies and you
know different kinds of people living
inside the Roman Empire the Roman Empire
was fairly okay with that simulation but
that's not the issue the problem
happened when the Roman Empire's armies
were mostly made of non-romans the
armies Rome at one point were made
mostly of Barbarians and then it's no
surprise then is it when the armies
marched upon Rome the very armies
weren't to protect the city actually
were the ones who raised it and attacked
it again and again many generals turned
traitor and why not their armies weren't
even Roman every country must realize
that there is a loyalty when the people
of that country are tied to its land and
it's very important you cannot just
import a population and expect the same
amount of loyalty to the initial country
that's just not how human tribalism
works and then finally let's look at the
debasement of currency debasement of
course the word debasement actually
means to change the nature of gold coins
by adding base Metals into them this was
done by many different kingdoms across
time of course but the important one I
remember is the one done by Diocletian
diet Collision is actually considered to
be one of the restorers of the Roman
Empire but he'd made a huge mistake when
he debased the currency of Rome so what
does the acquisition do he makes more
money he doesn't have access to more
gold because to collect more gold would
increase taxation he didn't want to
increase taxation because doing so would
actually inspire Revolt so what does he
do he takes the coins that he already
has and adds cheaper Metals base Metals
into them to increase his monetary
Supply understand these terms monetary
Supply and then essentially this is a
policy of inflation he uses inflation to
steal away the savings of his citizens
that's what inflation is inflation is a
tax inflation is nothing more than
taxation the only thing is it's not old
word that's what inflation is and now
you must really consider what it means
when the biggest PhD macro economists
who run the Federal Reserve insists that
inflation is actually good for you and
that is good for the economy and it is
actually why we have Prosperity no they
lie to you to your face look upon what
happened to the Roman Empire when
inflationary policies were adopted now
you could actually excuse the Romans
they didn't understand economics to the
level that we do they didn't have the
data that we do today so you could
excuse the Romans for having an
inflationary policy but no such cues can
be made for those who run the Federal
Reserve now the question becomes who
runs the Federal Reserve and what their
true aims are and that's beyond the
scope of this video that's for sure now
let's look at why it is that it is men
who think of the Roman Empire every
single day and not women women are
completely Bamboozled by the fact that
we think of this all the time at least
once a week well to put it simply that's
the job that's the job it's not women's
job to think of the Roman Empire because
they are not in charge of defending the
nation against tyranny from within or
external threats Barbarians at the gate
we must think of these things so that
women do not have to think about these
things and of course the Roman Empire is
connected to everything that we see on a
daily basis this is not to say that
women don't have an important role to
perform in society of course they do
equally important as that of men or it's
just that the roles are different and
the responsibilities are different and
of course the biology is different we
think about different things man
gravitate to think about stuff things
Concepts ideas women tend to think more
about people cool relationships that's
fine that's not a bad thing neither is
better than the other there are
different purposes for the functioning
of a healthy Society indeed it is up to
men to think about the preservation of
tradition tradition is of course not the
worship of the ashes but the
preservation of flame you see all power
tends to tyranny and the Romans were the
best example of this the people who
hated Tyrion the most even became
tyrannized but of course this is
different in the Modern Age you see we
have Technologies which the Romans never
had so when our civilization it's not if
it's a when our civilization goes
towards a more tyrannical Direction the
technologies that the governments will
possess exceed anything that the Romans
ever had think about this the Roman
Empire Diocletian even he couldn't truly
change the currency that much because it
was physical gold or bronze whatever
coins that he tried to make right what
happens when the government enforces a
Central Banking cryptocurrency nothing
good that much assure you indeed it is
the role of men to look at these things
see the mistakes on the path and make
sure that we don't repeat them that's
the job that's the nature of it all it's
up to you to armor your body against the
xenotoxins and the xenoestrogens
inflicted Upon Us by the corporations
with the blessing of the government it
is up to you to train your mind against
the endless psychological operations
inflicted upon you by the powers that be
it is up to you to gather around
yourself men like yourself who have a
similar mindset and thinking and it is
up to you to contemplate the cycle of
civilizations and where in that
structure we lie but finally a word of
hope you see Rome wasn't built in a day
but nor was Rome burned in a day many
times when the Empire came close to
collapse a man arose to change the fate
of the Roman Empire think about the
restituter or best the restorer of the
world Aurelius the Roman Emperor
Aurelius changed the path of the Roman
Empire from one of their client to one
of great Fame and power again in just
four years he managed this and he would
the restored Rome to its former glory
has he not been assassinated by his own
bodyguard what about the emperor
stillico what about Diocletian these men
made massive strides in reversing the
decadence of their civilization and what
about Justinian Justinian was born in a
time when the Western the Roman Empire
completely collapsed and yet he sent his
best General belisarius to take back and
he almost succeeded he almost United the
great Empire once again almost just a
hairs with away from complete
restoration the greatest Romans were not
the ones who were born in the Heyday of
Rome but rather the ones were born in
darkness and brought forth the light
comment down below Roma in Victor and
give me the latest thought about the
Roman Empire that you have had there's
no question as to why men think of the
Roman Empire every day that much is
obvious the real question is what the
hell do women think about all the time