I worked for Hamza for about three to
four months as his thinker strategizer
his visualizer so this is a very
interesting job one of the most
interesting jobs I've ever done at some
point the YouTube algorithm decided that
I needed to watch hanza every other
recommended video was this guy's face
wearing a bathrobe on my feet and I
didn't really like his titles or
anything but after seeing him so so many
times I had to click on it I went
through the Hamza Rabbit Hole I watched
a whole bunch of his content really
liked it I really liked his message I
was really convinced by him I found that
he was genuine and eventually he makes a
community post saying he wants a thinker
so he wants somebody for strategy and to
be a Visionary and have a vision for his
channel somebody to discuss things with
and plan with I thought this was the
perfect job for me and if you don't mind
I'm going to be preparing my breakfast
while I talk to you about how Hamza is
in real life outside of YouTube so I
filled up the application for his
thinker position he literally was hiring
somebody to think for him hear me out
it's not as stupid as you think so Hamza
is a very very intelligent guy he's much
more intelligent than he seems just by
looking at his videos he has a very
strategic mind and he has a very good
understanding of his emotional
capability and how to use that and
balance it out with logic so anyhow so I
sent in the application out and I try to
make the application as good as possible
I talk about my experiences in college
in traveling the military and a hundred
other things which show that I can
actually help humza strategize I told
him about the books I've read the things
I've written and my goals and Ambitions
for the future and Hamza really liked it
so he sends me an email hey I saw your
application and I really liked it would
you like to do a video call just like
that here was a big YouTube channel I
think he had half a million followers at
the time and he was willing to do a
video call what happened is I did this
video call with him and he asked me why
he thinks his movement is important so I
told him the truth I told him perhaps
the most important mission in the world
right now is this crisis of masculinity
to use the cliched phrase that men
simply are not taking responsibility for
their actions and not taking
responsibility for the con consequences
because of this there is massive
depression mental illness all kinds of
societal problems that we see today my
case was of course there's big problems
like climate change climate change
climate change income inequality 100
other things that you can talk about but
you can only solve those problems if you
have a strong Society to begin with so
you need a society of well-disciplined
responsible determined men who can
actually fix the problems that we have
so Hamza really liked the logic of that
obviously because that's his brand right
he does absolutely believe in his brand
so I get the job I'm harms a thinker how
it worked is we would do video calls I'm
going to put this piece of bread in the
toaster oven we do video calls every
week or so discussing strategy so when
we first started this was when we
realized that the Jeffrey and Adonis
intro right it used to be that Hamza
kind of views Jeffrey as the enemy now
Jeffrey is a thing which we should not
be like we should kind of hate and
Adonis is the aspirational figure but we
discussed this at length and we realize
well Jeffrey is not really the enemy at
all Jeffrey is a victim of a broken
Society what I mean is the structures of
society that exist today have no support
for young men growing up and finding
their identity which is of course
hamza's entire message so Jeffrey is not
the enemy Jeffrey is actually the
audience themselves and in fact it is
Hamza himself when he was younger so he
discussed this and now instead of doing
Adonis good Jeffrey bad type intros we
would do Adonis helps Jeffrey improve
his life or rather Jeffrey looks at the
honest and improves his life or
something along those lines instead of
making Jeffrey the enemy we treat
Jeffrey as a friend and every single
Jeffrey is a Adonis in the making so he
had a better understanding of our intro
when we had those discussions then
Andrew Tate decided to blow up
flip the burners dumb this is what
Andrew tape was he was not in jail or
anything you know he was doing very well
for himself on Tick Tock and YouTube and
everything was just blowing up and Hamza
and undertake kind of share a similar
audience of young men who want to
improve themselves so the question was
should harms associate with Andrew Tate
see Andrew trade is highly controversial
compared to Hamza Hamza is talking about
wholesome things like mental health
physical health spiritual health and
undertale is just talking about
cars and smoking cigars and has very
controversial opinions on women and
everything the question for Hamza was
Andrew Tate and him share a similar
space and by the way guys you're going
to learn how to make a very good bomb
omelette so I'm going to make my
omelette with ghee actually if you're
using oil top at least use butter and if
you want to be really elite elite level
omelette you got to use ghee Elite
omelette coming up and of course if you
want to make a good omelette you got to
get the best quality eggs I get these
happy egg company eggs they're really
good but anyway where was I and rotate
so the question becomes a question of
strategy because Andrew Tate was
unpredictable we didn't know what he was
going to do next or saying X so if Hamza
decides to associate his brand with
Andrew Tate's brand and Andrew Tate does
something stupid slash very
controversial that could reflect badly
on hamza's wholesome image my advice to
him was don't associate with Andrew Tate
publicly because it was just too much
risk we didn't know him personally we
didn't know what he's going to do and
besides Andrew Tate was very successful
before he even became a influencer
Andrew Tate made his money before he
came to YouTube on Tick Tock that's not
the case for Hamza hamza's
infrastructure depends on YouTube he
wasn't Rich before YouTube so we decided
not to deal with Andrew tatron to
publicly support or talk about Andrew
Tate but in the end Hamza disagreed with
me and I'm glad he did because I made it
such that it was a question of strategy
you know what's best for hamza's image
what's best for Hamza as a brand it was
never for me about hamza's honesty and
the fact of the matter is Hamza did like
Andrew Tate's content and I did too I
don't agree with everything Andrew Tate
says but his mindset on success
connections and networking are really
really good and Hamza believed the same
so Hamza according to my advice did not
talk about annotate at all but
eventually he did break with my advice
which is good and he talks about how
Andrew Tate is the most misunderstood
man and actually supports undertale in
public now big Divergence from where he
was I'm glad he was able to do that we
spoke about monetization of course we
talked about how to make money so Hamza
really doesn't want to be like all the
other influencers who just sell and
make money I was of the opinion that
selling stuff so long as the thing
provides genuine value to your customer
it's not a bad thing and wouldn't harm
His Image but see harms us right if he
sold low ticket items he would hurt his
image in the long run and I was
incorrect hats off to Hamza for having
his own thoughts and not just following
whatever I said so in the end Hamza did
not actually sell any low ticket items
he didn't sell any low ticket courses he
sells one extremely high ticket course
which I don't think you guys even know
about but he sells a course on how to
have better sex literally Hamza has a
sex course a high ticket sex course
which is cells not publicly like not on
his main Channel or anything but only on
his like download channels if you're on
his email list you might have access to
it and even then it's not a sure thing
so he has a high ticket course but
doesn't publicize it at all because he
doesn't want the negative image he
really really cares about the
genuineness and honesty of his brand so
when I was working with thumbs up I had
to actually report for a two-week stint
of training with the army so I was gone
you know I was in the army barracks in
the cam training and I would still be
able to find the time to talk to Hamza
do these video calls and discuss
strategy because even though I was
really tired and I was doing this Army
I actually found so much value from
Hamza that I decided to sacrifice a
little bit of my sleep even though I was
tired I would still talk to him help him
if I could that's how much I respect the
guy I would not do that for anybody else
except for Hamza so I am a fan of him
there's no question about it he brought
a lot of value to me and I'm really
proud of having worked with him I'm kind
of sad that we don't work with each
other anymore so what is Hamza like off
camera you might be surprised to know
this but Hamza is literally the same guy
AI on and off camera is actually legit
he's actually the real deal that's my
assessment after working for multiple
months with him no one can make a fake
appearance last for three months so I
did multiple calls with him and he is
really the guy behind the camera so what
I mean by that is he genuinely cares
about the upliftment of young men in
today's generation no question in my
mind that At His Highest priority so
when we realized that Jeffrey was not
the enemy we tried to find out who the
enemy really was and our conclusion was
the enemy was social media and porn so
we decided to go after social media just
talk and expose the way social media
apps and channels manipulate our minds
and we were making videos about this
consistently for at least two weeks just
talking about Instagram and this also
the time in which Hamza got banned off
Instagram actually and it was really
interesting because Hamza makes a video
against Instagram and just two days
later he gets banned by insta and he
didn't do anything he didn't post
anything inappropriate or anything like
that so it seems to be that somebody at
Instagram saw this video and saw the
power that he could have and decided to
to ban him on Insta till now we have no
idea why he got banned at that time
eventually Hamza gets banned on more and
more channels I believe he's banned on
Discord now and before he was banned on
skillshare so his skillshare course was
making him about 50 of his income at the
time when I was working with him so when
he got banned off of skillshare he had
to cut some employees off and that was
why I don't work with him anymore after
watching hamza's latest video I realized
how far he has come in just two years
just two years this man didn't even have
a channel in two years he not only
created a successful YouTube channel and
a business he managed a whole team he
started a movement of a million plus men
who genuinely want to get better at life
he did everything without much
controversy I mean he had that one beef
with sneaker but even that's nothing
compared to a lot of what these
influencers do so it really goes to show
you how a normal man an intelligent man
mind you was able to go from almost
nothing to so much having such a massive
Global impact in just two years so it
inspires me it tells me that I have no
idea I cannot imagine where I will be
that should be what hamza's story is to
you is a story of inspiration of how
much you can accomplish when you focus
yourself on one goal on one purpose and
do it consistently over the long time
period and Hamza he really proved that
you can do it everybody was talking
about how YouTube is saturated social
media is saturated but no the man just
went for it and in two years he built
this whole empire of wholesome good
advice for young men that is such a
difficult yet Noble Pursuit that he has
absolutely succeeded in and watching his
latest video when he talks about how
that outer layer of purpose of helping
other men has kind of dissolved and he
needs to re-revisit that all that
concept comes from David data's the way
of the superior man that book was very
influential on Hamza and a lot of men
including myself one of the principles
from that book is there are layers of
purpose every single person on this
planet has a purpose but the purpose is
not just one thing you work on a purpose
for a good amount of time and when you
reach a certain level of success it
falls off and then a deeper level of
purpose is revealed to you that is what
has happened to Hamza he has succeeded
as much as you can succeed on YouTube
could he get more followers probably yes
but his outer level of purpose has been
met and he has found a deeper calling in
martial arts so I wish Hamza the
absolute best of luck and I hope he
really succeeds in finding what he's
looking for through martial arts his
journey has inspired me to start my own
I have no idea where this will lead me I
invite you to be a part of it and I well
first I gotta make my breakfast all
right you guys I was able to make my
breakfast and I'm gonna crack open a new
bottle olive oil and I would like to
conclude by saying what Hamza achieved
is not closed to any of us all of us can
take something from what Hamza has done
learn from it and even improve upon it
here's what was unique about Hamza and
how he was able to blow up he was
brutally honest about his problems and
he was brutally honest about his
failures he was radically open about his
worst insecurities he was talking about
how he had gynecomastia he was talking
about how he had man boobs like how many
guys have the courage to get on new to
be in front of thousands and thousands
of people and say I have man boobs I
don't know how to fix it I've always
felt insecure about it how many people
have the courage to say that the fact
that he was brutally honest was what
made his channel stand out and grow when
so many other channels fail to from
Hamza I learned that brutal honesty
radical transparency consistency are all
you need to live a fulfilled life enjoy
your breakfast