most YouTubers like freaking Alpha M
will give you five products that you
need they'll give you an AM cream a PM
cream a scrub a cleanser and an eye
cream and all of these are supposed to
be required a requirement for your skin
to look good this is BS I will share
with you ancient wisdom 10,000 years old
wisdom to help you have the best hair
and skin you've ever had in your life
this video is not just about sunscreen
but we might as well start start there
the first scop sunscreen so sunburn is
not a problem which I ever had sunburn
is a white person problem however I used
to think that if you don't have
sunscreen on you you'll straight up get
skin cancer which is not true in fact
I'll tell you something interesting most
sunscreen all major brands they contain
either benzo phenone or 4 MBC benzeno
and 4 MBC are estrogenics and
estrogenics are known to be cancer
causing I blame the seed oils
polyunsaturated fatty acids integrate
themselves into your cell membrane in
your skin and they caus the skin to be
more sensitive to sunburn so they added
a foreign substance seed oils to our
diet which caused a problem excessive
Sunburn and skin cancer even and then
they came up with a product which is
supposed to solve that problem and sold
us sunscreen this is exactly what the
esoteric Health movement opposes all
major brands like freaking Jurgens which
you should never use contain either
parabens or Tates or benzines or phenols
in general if an ingredient has the word
Benz or fi as a part of its name I try
to avoid it almost every single major
brand every single major product has
parabens tads 4 MBC or benzophenone if
it's a sunscreen the sub substances I
mentioned are estrogenics they are
endocrine disrupting which means that
they interfere with your hormone systems
and if you specifically look at the
sunscreen estrogenics which is
benzophenone and 4 MBC what's going on
here is very interesting these molecules
they bind to the cell membrane of our
skin cells and the sun radiation UV
radiation actually fuses them onto the
membrane so not only are they signaling
estrogenic Pathways they are actually
fused by the UV radiation and they
remain affixed to the skin cell
literally for the entire life cycle of
the cell until it dies so not only is an
estrogenic substance it actually gets
worse when exposed to sunlight which is
ridiculous because sunscreen is supposed
to be used in sunlight so what should
you do well I have this video for you
which is the esoteric skin care system
but listen it doesn't start with the
products it actually starts with the
water your water your tap water
regardless of where you live on the
globe contains fluorides and chlorine
definitely chlorine so chlorine is what
they use to kill bacteria in your water
right so here's the problem chlorine
literally kills cells it literally
causes DNA damage in order to kill
bacterial cells and that's true for your
gut microbiome that's also true for your
mouth microbiome but of course when it
comes to the skin it causes skin damage
and I I bet you've never even heard of
what a shower filter is so here's the
interesting thing most skin problems can
be solved by just getting a shower
filter just remove the chlorine and
you'll be fine half the time but you'll
never hear a dermatologist talk about a
shower filter cuz you know they lose
their jobs so shower filter that's
priority number one get yourself one I
briefly mentioned fluoride but the deal
with fluoride is way too complex to go
into this video I have a video out on
that go check it out I'll put in the
description next thing you do is cut out
seed oils from your diet so like I
mentioned before seed oils poly
unsaturated fat fatty acids integrate
themselves in the cell membranes of your
skin and cause them to be more prone to
Sunburn and sun damage in general now
finally coming to what products to use
and I literally have just one product
and well this one is empty I have
literally one product which is called
Tallow balb you probably haven't even
heard of Tallow Bal but this was the
moisturizer and sunscreen which people
used tens of thousands of years before
we switched over to our modern and
inferior products Tallow bom is esoteric
certified but what is it right so Tallow
bom is nothing it's just Tallow Tallow
is animal fat rendered and purified
that's literally all it is I think it's
just one ingredient in here and this is
the only one which I use I don't have a
separate eye cream I don't have an AM
cream and a PM cream I don't have a
retinol so here's here's something
interesting Tallow bom contains a lot of
vitamin A which is retinol so some
people buy a whole retinol product for
that purpose this has that in it as well
another scop aftershave this is better
than any After Shave you'll find in any
store so humans have been using Tallow
bom for tens of thousands of years
probably more and we live in interesting
times it's finally a time in which small
businesses and small farms are able to
come up with high quality products at
scale to allow you know manufacturer
that we can all afford to get they can
successfully compete with and win
against these big Brands and I'm all for
supporting small businesses who have a
strong Mission and are making good
products this is one example of that the
TB bomb which I use is by a brand called
vintage tradition there are other brands
which you can go to I know the owner of
this brand which is why I trust it more
than any other brand guy called Kenneth
he and his brother run this thing they
only use the highest quality ingredients
I trust them if you want to check this
brand out in particular they were
actually able to give me a discount code
so you can check it out out I put in the
description I think the reason why tbom
works so well because it's an animal
product so we're animals the fat profile
the fatty acid profile of plants and
animals are simply different so even
things like Shia butter Etc yeah they do
the job and they're organic and
everything but they're simply not able
to compete with an animal fat-based
product which is why this is nice it
contains you know all the vitamins a B12
k d in a bioavailable form so I think
that's why it's supered though I don't
have any scientific studies or anything
proving that I just have personal
experience and from my personal
experience this is easily the way to go
interesting story I read the book
estrogenics which I strongly recommend
it's a deep dive into all topics
estrogenics related right and he
mentions the author mentions that
lavender so check this product out it's
a pretty good product no parabens no
Tates but it has lavender lavender is an
estrogenic substance but not so stri
straightforward so most lavender on the
market today like which they use in
fragrances and whatnot is artificial
lavender and it's the artificial
lavender which is estrogenic natural
organic lavender from the actual plant
doesn't seem to be estrogenic so if you
find a Tallow bomb which has a lavender
essential oil in it from this company
it's fine because I know the guy he he
confirmed that he only gets his lavender
from Plants but other brands which have
lavender I would be suspicious of
especially your detergents if if your
detergent has a lavender scent highly
suspicious that's probably artificial
lavender you shouldn't use it try to go
for odorless as much as possible but
literally everything I spoke about till
now is completely irrelevant without a
solid diet and sleep so regarding sleep
if you want a esoteric sleep guide let
me know in the comments and I'll make
that and diet half the skincare routine
videos on YouTube have nothing to do
with diet they say nothing about diet
diet is more important than the products
that you use So speaking specifically
about skin care and its relationship
with diet carrots carrots are important
the beta carotenes in carrots literally
adds pigmentation to your skin makes you
look good eat your carrots then you need
collagen chicken skins very good source
of collagen eat your chicken skins but
then it may not be sufficient especially
because you aren't eating chicken skins
every day or anything I would suggest
supplementation with a collagen powder
so collagen powder is just a white
powder looks kind of like whe protein it
just dissolves in water gives you
collagen and here's something
interesting about collagen collagen can
break down into Glycine and glycine
improve your sleep so diet plus sleep in
this particular supplement but is Tallow
balb a sunscreen it's not so here's the
thing though and some of you might
actually still need sunscreen maybe you
are just a very pale skin and your skin
just burns in the sun I understand that
so I will put in the description some
sunscreens which are actually clean and
which you are okay to use which don't
have estrogenic substances I'll also
provide non Tallow moisturizers and
recommendations because in case you
wen't able to get the product or because
you don't want to use it for whatever
reasons then I would suggest those
products instead coming back to cleaning
your face most YouTube videos will
suggest a cleanser and a scrub they say
that the scrub is required for
exfoliation not true but coming for the
cleaning first right I use this cream
cleanser very gentle very moisturizing
it's a good product so I said facial
scrubs were BS which is true but you
should possibly use this bentonite clay
calcium bentonite clay so this stuff is
not a exfoliant it won't like rub and we
your skin it's a clay it's like a face
mask you can read the instructions and
follow them you basically mix the powder
it's like a powder I'll show you it's
like a powder very fine clay powder I
don't know how well you can see it but
you take that stuff and you mix it with
water or ideally Apple cider vinegar you
mix it up it becomes a paste you apply
the paste onto your face and then after
10 minutes you just wash it off and your
skin guaranteed will look better and
this is superior to any stupid face
scrub which people are selling now what
do you use of body wash because body
wash well this is a pretty good body
wash to be honest but even this does
does contain the artificial lavender so
I don't use it most body wash is pretty
terrible it has the same issues the
parabens the Tates everything so what
I've gone to using is a literal bar soap
this is also by the same company vintage
tradition it's literally a bar soap made
from Tallow it's very good I've been
using it but I'm sure this is not the
only company which makes similar stuff
right get a bar soap get a good bar soap
it doesn't necessarily have to be Tallow
and you might be thinking how often do
you do all this you wash your face once
in the morning and once at night with a
gentle cream cleanser you apply the
Tallow bomb after youve wash your face
the bent toight clay I only use it once
a week and of course you shower every
day with the bar soap now coming to Hair
Care the first thing most important
thing is get yourself a wooden comb
don't be using a plastic comb get
yourself a wooden what do you call these
things like wooden barbs and this is
just so much better for your scalp than
the plastic ones are and then shampoo so
shampoos which contain Tates Tates
damage your hair follicles if you're
balding it's a good chance it's the
Tates which are causing it so make sure
that your shampoo is good quality which
means no parabens no Tate no estrogenic
of any kind so that's this is a good
shampoo which I found it's sulfate free
paraben talate free and of course you
don't have to use this brand necessarily
I'll show you this brand in uh in the
link you can check it out then after you
shower after you wash your hair you
still want to have a way to moisturize
your hair what do you use well the most
esoteric answer is olive oil that's
correct so just one or two drops of
olive oil spread it out in your hands
apply it you'll get that shine you'll
get the moisture speaking about my hair
so I started this video talking about
how my hair was turning gray when I was
freaking 20 and I I plugged it out
because you know I I was insecure about
having gray hair at that young age now
my hair is super thick super strong and
if I go to a hairdresser right every
time the the hairdresser lady she'll
comment like oh my God your hair is so
thick it's hard to cut you're going to
blunt my scissors so it went from really
bad quality hair which is graying to
very thick and strong hair which is
noticeable right you can see how much
wume I have it's because of the olive
oil and of course removing the Tad from
my shampoo can you use coconut oil yes
you can use coconut oil but the thing is
I don't like the smell of coconut oil
olive oil smell kind of just vanishes
after a couple minutes so it's fine and
then olive oil isn't sufficient cuz I
still want to kind of have some texture
some style some hold in my hair so I use
this particular product Seattle Pomade
company so this is an excellent product
it's very cheap surprisingly cheap this
is just beeswax essentially the the base
is beeswax and then they add some honey
fragrance or something like that and not
an artificial fragrance by the way so
I'll link this also in the description
this you just take it in your hand apply
it on your hair and you get this nice
texture nice hold otherwise my hair
would just kind of flop down so I mean
you might have to find the right product
for yourself but this is the one which I
use and for your body what do you use to
moisturize your body skin Tallow works
as well as it does on your face you
don't need another product you can use
your Tallow if you aren't able to get
yourself some Tallow you can actually
use all olive oil just take a couple
drops of olive oil and drop it on your
skin and that's the best you can do but
if for whatever reason you don't want to
use olive oil there are some good brands
I have this everyday Shia butter type
lotion which I do use this is a good
product pretty clean no parabens no
Tates I can link that on in the
description also and then finally you
have pore strips so these are strips
which go on your nose and you leave them
on for like 10 minutes and then you rip
them off and it removes it cleans your
pores I should say from your nose you
don't need to do that often maybe once
in 2 weeks is fine but it doesn't matter
how good you look if your breath smells
awful so if you want the oral hygiene
esoteric guide let me know in the
comments and if I make that guide I will
put the end card right
[Music]
here