Hormones are the real big magic. A few
nanogs of a hormone can turn a baby calf
into a Belgian bull on a diet of grass.
Hormones can put a beard on a woman or
give a man tits. They can take a skinny
man and turn him into Hercules reborn.
But the changes are not just physical.
The right hormonal profile, and I'm not
just talking about testosterone, can
turn an underachieving brain fog man
into a beacon of light and success in
his community. The question is how does
a man achieve the ideal hormonal
profile? The mistake many scientists
make is that they take a reductionist
approach. That is they speak of the
various hormones to optimize in
isolation without looking at the whole.
This approach is doomed to failure when
you take these theoreticals and try to
put them into action. I will tell you
the story of the magic elephant of Nepal
to drive this point home. You may think
that you've heard the story, but you
haven't heard the secret ending. The
king of Nepal brings his magic elephant
to the village of the blind. The blind
men naturally want to examine this
wondrous creature. One man, the first
who gets there, says, "Behold, the
elephant is like a python, strong but
flexible as he holds the trunk." And the
other says, "No, sir. The elephant is
like a pillar, rigid and mighty as he
has his arms wrapped around the leg."
The third man says, "Are you all fools?
Clearly, the elephant is like a spear.
The mighty curved thunderbolt of Lord
Indra himself. You may have heard this
first part of the story, but not what
comes next. The wise old elephant who
had been patient all along bellows. You
are all fools. I'm the mighty elephant,
king of beasts. I am the python, the
pillar, and the spear. I am also a rope,
a fan, and a stone wall. Even if you
could comprehend all of these, you would
not truly understand me. Allow me to
roam freely in nature to do as I please
to meet my tribe to meet my wife and
calves then you may begin to understand
when I'm here brought as a prisoner
against my will even the mighty king who
does have the eyes to see cannot
understand what I am and what I can be
the elephant of course is correct it is
not sufficient to understand the parts
of a system to understand the whole it's
not even sufficient to understand how
the parts are interconnected in fact you
must step back and watch the system
behave and go towards its goals. And so
it is with the hormone engine. You must
step back to understand the whole. In
this course, I have an ambitious goal to
present to you a unified field theory of
the hormone engine in men. I want to
give you the whole elephant. Not just
that, but I also want to teach you how
to ride the elephant. That is how to
harness the hormone engine to take you
where you want to go and to crush any
obstacle that comes your way. If you are
living beneath your ability, if you
don't have clarity, energy, and follow
through in order to achieve your dream
lifestyle, it just means you don't have
the right hormone profile. That's what's
holding you back. It's not your
background. It's not your parenting. All
of that is secondary to the hormone
profile. I know exactly how this feels
because I spent years in the dungeons of
the biology department trying to earn a
PhD to impress my parents and to gain
status. I spent years in brain fog and
confusion. I was broke. I was depressed
and I lost the girl off my dreams
because I didn't have the mental frame
or mindset that I have now. Most people
don't know this, but mindset is
downstream of the hormone profile.
Recently, I asked you what would make an
unstoppable entrepreneur. You said
creativity, confidence, risk-taking,
impulse control, unshakable pain
tolerance. But where do these really
come from? I could have saved years of
my life if I knew what I know now. Our
hormone profile shapes our actions and
our actions shape our hormone profile.
This is a feedback loop, a vicious
cycle. Losing gives you a hormone
profile that makes you lose more. This
can quickly become an iron cage with no
escape. But the opposite is also true.
Winning gives you a hormone profile that
makes you win more. Instead of an iron
cage, you have an iron train engine that
gains momentum with every yard. The aim
of this course is to help you turn your
hormone engine on so that it can take
you wherever you want to go. For me, my
dream was freedom. Just freedom, man.
Freedom to travel where I please. Travel
to work when I please. The freedom to
associate with whom I wanted to.
Location freedom, time freedom, and
relationship freedom. That was my
deepest and dearest objective for so
many years. The sooner you fix your
hormone engine, the more time you will
have to reap the rewards of doing so. In
this course, I will share a decade of
bio research that have tested on men
just like yourself. This video will
serve as a reference and as a toolkit
which will help you gain an asymmetric
advantage over other men, but only if
you make the choice to act on it.
Remember, we all make choices, but in
the end, our choices make us. Most
people don't know this, but we go
through two puberties in our life. One
is in our late teens or early 20s, but
really that's the second one. The first
puberty is when you are still an unborn
infant in your mother's womb. You get a
massive testosterone spike during this
phase. The strength of this testosterone
boost is actually phenomenal. Every baby
starts off looking basically female.
Actually, it's this testosterone boost.
It changes that it causes the formation
of the balls and the dick. It literally
is what makes you male in the first
place. You can actually check this right
now if you got a sufficient boost as a
baby or not. Place your palm flat on the
tabletop and see if your ring finger is
longer than your index finger. Bigger
the difference, the more of a
testosterone spike you received as a
baby. This weird ratio of the lengths of
your index and ring fingers is actually
correlated to athletic performance and
even aggression in males. If you do the
same test on a woman, you'll find that
there's actually no difference between
the length of the ring finger and the
index finger. And this makes sense
because women did not receive that
legendary testosterone boost. Here's
another test to check if you have enough
free testosterone in your bloodstream
right now. If you're below the age of 40
and you don't wake up with a boner most
days, you're either chronically
stressed, underreovering, or possibly
have low free testosterone, or more
likely a combination of the three. Now,
why would you not get the full
testosterone boost as a baby? It's
either genetics, or it's the mother's
health, or it's because of
xenoestrogens, toxins that have found
their way into our food and water that
mimic the female hormone system. Now,
this is not news to you, so I will not
dwell on it for long. You already know
this that testosterone rates are in
freef fall. You already know that sperm
counts and fertility rates in most
countries are in existential level
threat. But what you may not know or
what you may not have realized is that
this is not a new phenomenon. Even
before the advent of xenoestrogens, most
of human society is manufactured to
control
testosterone. Laws, customs, and
religions are all built to regulate and
channel testosterone. However, today we
are more aware of this than ever before
and we have the tools to chart our own
destiny. Let us discuss these tools and
the underlying mechanisms at this time.
Testosterone makes effort feel good.
You've likely heard this before. Here's
what you have not heard. Feeling good
about effort makes testosterone. If you
study the hormone engine long enough,
you will see some patterns. One of the
patterns which I've seen is that which
causes a result is also caused by the
result. Here's an example from the great
neuroscientist Robert Sapolski that will
make things clear for you. You've heard
that if you win at sports, you'll get a
huge testosterone spike. Not so clear.
When you dig in, it actually becomes
much more interesting. In the '90s, they
looked at testosterone levels of men who
were participating in a marathon. Yes,
the winner had a spike of testosterone,
but a minor one. The guy who came 73rd
had a much bigger spike. So, it's
confusing. What's going on? Turns out
the guy who came first did 3 minutes
worse than his best time. So, he didn't
feel like a winner. And the guy who came
73rd, he just aimed to be in the top
100. So, that the fact that he made 73rd
was actually a huge win for him. In
other words, perception and testosterone
have a two-way connection.
You've probably heard of testosterone
being used in a hierarchy, as in the top
male in a hierarchy has more
testosterone, the bottom male has the
least. And this is taken to mean that if
you increase testosterone, then your
position in the hierarchy would
increase. But this is not true. Let's
say there are five chimps and they
formed a hierarchy. If you took the
middle chimp, chimp number three, and
you shot him full of testosterone, he
would not magically take the number one
spot. In fact, he would continue to
cling on to the number three spot even
more strongly. In other words, he would
actually be more subservient to number
one and number two. But not just this,
he would also be more tyrannical to
chimps number four and five. So, put it
another way, if you were a normie to
begin with, then increasing testosterone
just would make you a turbbor.
Testosterone on its own does not make
you a winner. It's like money. Money
doesn't make you a winner. It's like
Andrew Tate of all people said, "Dorks
who made their millions from
cryptocurrency just became turbo dorks."
All testosterone does, it turns up the
volume on the personality traits that
already exist. That is why in my cohort
systems, we employ a novel technique
that targets multiple hormone systems in
parallel with testosterone. Since we are
not going for a testosterone boost as
such, we're going for comprehensive
transformation.
Sapolski gives this funny anecdote that
if you pumped a group of Buddhist monks
full of testosterone, then all of them
would aggressively compete to see who
performed the most random acts of
kindness. This is because all
testosterone can do is amplify
competition within existing frameworks
and amplify behaviors also within
existing personality frameworks.
Speaking of competition, most males of
any mamalian species don't have sex, let
alone have kids. Yes, testosterone is
predictive of sexual success, especially
in elephant seals and antler animals.
The correlation is striking. In fact,
males will tear off each other's balls
in a in an a bid to win the fight.
Essentially, nature is brutal and the
brutality of nature is always just an
inch beneath the surface of human
society. Testosterone males forage
further. They fight harder and endure
much more punishment in order to get
what they want. But it's not just that.
They also seek more novelty. That is,
not only do they fight harder for what
they want, they also want more to begin
with. And if you don't relate with this
behavior pattern, it's just a matter of
turning on your hormone engine. Until
you do, you don't truly know what it is
that you are capable of. By the way,
it's not just necessarily competition
that boosts testosterone. Collaboration
also boosts testosterone just as well.
In fact, I would say that the ideal case
is belonging to a collaborative group
that is in competition with other
groups. So this could be in a sports
setting where you are in a team who is
competing against other teams or even in
a military setting. Collaboration for
the sake of competition is the greatest
social game possible. So find your tribe
and then defeat other tribes. A tale as
old as time. Build a business. In that
process, you will build a team and
together you are competing against other
businesses. Of course, building a
business is just one example. The key
here is to find something that you can
actually see yourself doing and
enjoying. Here's the easiest way to do
it. Just join any fitness community. And
running, dancing, climbing, skating,
table tennis, chess, could literally be
any of these things. It doesn't matter.
And if you can't think of anything, all
that means is you got to try things
until something clicks. Your health
depends on it. Collaboration and
competition are the best testosterone
supplement. I've already mentioned that
testosterone makes effort feel good. But
the question is, how do you leverage
this? It comes down to how the body
interprets a stressor. The same person
who's afraid of heights might
voluntarily get into a roller coaster.
The crazy thing is the brain activation
pattern in both cases would be the exact
same. That is to say, excitement and
terror have the same activation pattern
in the brain, except of course for one
key brain area, the amygdala. The
amydala maintains the stress threshold.
That is the amydala decides whether a
stress is excitement or if it's terror.
And guess where the highest
concentration of testosterone receptors
in the brain is? The amygdala. If
testosterone is high, the amygdala
increases this stress threshold, meaning
that you need to be in a really, really
bad situation in order to feel stressed.
If testosterone is low, then the stress
threshold is low. So, even a mundane
stress would feel terrifying. Naturally,
higher testosterone means that you're
likely to take more risks and do cool
[ __ ] because you're no longer afraid.
Here's the paradox. Testosterone causes
you to pursue more pain in search of
reward, but also dulls the pain. So, it
is the case that you can endure more,
but it doesn't even feel like you're
enduring more because it almost becomes
fun. So, Tim Ferrris has this question
that he likes to ask when he's
confronted with a difficulty. What would
this look like if it was easy? The
question I prefer to ask is, what would
this look like if it was fun? It's a
very powerful question to ask if you are
an entrepreneur or a pre-ontrepreneur.
But it's not so simple because in this
mechanism we see another feedback loop.
Testosterone causes action and action
causes victory and victory generates
testosterone. But also low testosterone
causes fear. Fear causes inaction,
inaction causes failure and failure
leads to low testosterone. It's one of
those things where to he who has more
will be given and to he who has not more
will be taken. This is a vicious cycle
that exists and must be broken out of by
force. To do this, you need action and
you need knowledge. So, let's get into
the tactical stuff. What biomarkers
would you need to get tested to see if
your health is on track as a man? For
testosterone, we would need at least two
metrics. Total testosterone and free
testosterone. Most of the testosterone
in your body is not freely floating.
It's not in an activated state. In fact,
only 2% of the total testosterone is
freely available. And that's ballpark
numbers. Obviously, the rest of
testosterone is bound tightly to SHBG,
which is the spherical protein, which is
sex hormone binding globbulin. As the
name suggests, it doesn't just bind to
testosterone. It binds to all sex
hormones like DHT and to a lesser extent
estrogen. To be clear, SHBG is not the
enemy. It's not that SHBG is trapping
the testosterone and preventing it from
acting. It's actually a transporter.
It's a wonderful molecule. In fact, we
need SHBG to transport the testosterone
across the bloodb brain barrier in the
in the brain to carry out its functions
on the amygdala. However, stress,
xenoestrogen exposure, or heavy metal
toxicity can cause SHBG to bind to too
much testosterone. If your free
testosterone is less than 2%, then you
need to take action to start liberating
this bound testosterone. So, what can
you do? Boron supplementation can help
with this. Just make sure that you pair
the boron with iodine because boron is a
grogen. Quick note, if you're trying to
calculate the percent of free
testosterone in your lab report, here's
something that you'll run into. Because
the concentration of total testosterone
is so much greater than that of free
testosterone, most lab reports will
report the scores in different units.
So, make sure you do your unit
conversion correctly before you
calculate a percentage. Another useful
biioarker to get would be SHBG itself.
If you're in the 55ish range, you're
good. If not, then SHBG optimization
comes first. SHBG is downstream of
insulin, estradiol, and thyroid. So,
you'd want to look at those biomarkers
first for clues. Now, the thing is
testosterone on its own doesn't tell us
much about the overall health of the
body. It's actually a lagging indicator.
So, I have created a custom blood work
panel of more than 52 biomarkers
including testosterone and free
testosterone through our industry
partner, Alta Labs. I have linked this
in the description. It's the most
cost-effective panel of its kind. You
can verify this for yourself, but
unfortunately it's only available in the
US. If you join Crusade Cohort,
interpretations of these blood tests
will be included as a part of your
membership. I will personally go through
your results with you. Now, what gives
me the credibility to do this? I'm not a
medical professional, but I do hold a
certification in functional blood
chemistry. Now, let's get back to the
big question. What testosterone range
should you aim for? Here's my stance.
Don't aim for a number. Aim for a
percentage increase. The reason I say
it's better to aim for a percentage
increase rather than a number to hit is
because everybody's receptor sensitivity
is different. So, one man's 400 might
actually beat another man's 600. So,
what are some benchmarks? There are no
standard industry benchmarks for men who
are trying to actively increase their
testosterone. What I can share with you
is what I've seen from my own practice.
If you're below 200, you can see the
biggest boost. you can actually get a 2x
increase in testosterone just because
there's more room to grow. Right? If
you're in the middle range of 200 to 600
nanogs per deciliter, you can expect to
see a 50 to 100% increase. If you're
already above 600, you're already doing
great. You can aim for a 20 to 50%
increase. I will of course share with
you the tactical advice on how to do
this, but first a word from our
sponsors. Me, I'm the sponsor. So, I'll
keep this quite short and I'll keep this
to the point. I am a specialist in only
one thing. I specialize in getting guys
out of a rut to move them towards their
dream goals. This is my full-time job. I
love doing it. I've gotten quite good at
it. I've helped more than 10 guys just
like you achieved their dream
transformation in just 110 days. This
was me right after surgery. I had lost a
lot of muscle over the 2 years. I was
determined to get it back. And this was
me after joining cohort zero. I have a
long ways to go, no doubt about that.
But I have the systems to ensure my
success. Alex had one goal. He wanted to
join the army, but they would not let
him because he was overweight. 3 months
into cohort zero and he's reached the
lowest weight he's had in 5 years. Jaden
had one goal. He wanted to get strong.
In 3 months, he won gold in his
powerlifting competition. Kuba had two
goals. To overcome his binge eating
habits and to start a business. 3 months
into cohort zero and he's in the shape
of his life and just signed his first
three clients. Now cohort zero has just
ended, but cohort 1 is under
construction. If you're a man with big
dreams, then I can help you make these
dreams into a reality. Applications to
cohort 1 close in about 5 days at the
time of this recording. I'd also say
that 50% of the slots have already been
claimed during the pre-launch, but not
to worry, this is not a first come,
first- serve basis. This is based on
fit. I will link to my website in the
description. There's a short video on
there that explains the mechanism of how
this all works. You could potentially
take that mechanism and try to apply it
by yourself. That's fine by me.
Transformation is what I'm after. It
contains some very interesting
frameworks that are outside the scope of
this video. It describes the interesting
and very important interaction of the
hormone profile with the big five
personality traits. This is the cutting
edge of my research. So, you're going to
want to watch this to get a sneak peek
of what's coming to give you that
massive advantage. Now, let's get back
into tactics. So, when it comes to the
high leverage action steps to increase
testosterone, what do you need to do? I
asked this question to you, my audience,
and you answered correctly. Basically,
it's three things: recovery, exercise,
and nutrition. If you think I'm going to
give you some crazy new hack like icing
your ball sack or taking some scam
supplement, then you are going to be
disappointed. The hardcore truth that
nobody wants to hear is there's only
three big levers on testosterone. It's
nutrition, exercise, and recovery. Then
you have three smaller levers, which is
sunlight, social status, and sexual
success. If you're expecting some kind
of crazy esoteric hack method, then you
are looking for entertainment and not
outcomes. On this channel, there is no
entertainment. There's only outcomes.
Excellence is the fundamentals done a
thousand times. That's what we care
about. That's what I care about. And
that's what you should care about as
well. But then again, if it was so
simple, then why do so many men not have
the results? Why do they not have the
energy, the physique, and the sex drive
that they want? There is a secret hiding
in plain sight that I will now reveal. I
have drawn a triangle of health on this
piece of paper. Exercise, nutrition, and
recovery. Now, I have a question for
you. How many elements make up this
system? Think about it for a second. If
you answered three, you are mistaken.
There are six. Health is a system and
each of these connections two is a part
of the system. Each of these big three
interact and co-interact with each
other. If you add in the small three,
quickly it becomes a web. And this is
the web that men will find themselves
stuck in. The elements of health are
simple, but the interactions are
complex. Let me give you a real life
example to drive this point home.
Imagine a normal guy who looks a little
bit chubby as he gets to his 30s. He
cannot any longer see his abs and the
girls aren't checking him out as much as
they did when he was in college. So,
what he wants to do is quite
straightforward. He wants to lose some
fat. He wants to gain some muscle. He
wants to get back to his college
physique. Great. So, he starts going to
the gym. And what does he find? He finds
that he's hitting the weights. He's
putting in the reps, but doesn't look
any better week after week. What he
doesn't realize is that his increased
calorie burn is actually causing him to
snack more. So his benefits of his
exercise interact with his nutrition and
not in a good way. In the end, he
doesn't lose any fat because the
benefits of exercise are counterbalanced
by his downfall in nutrition. Learning
from this, our guy says, "Okay, let's
start with the diet instead." Now he
cuts his calorie intake, but this tanks
his metabolic rate. Now his baseline
metabolic rate is low. It doesn't have
the energy anymore to exercise. Now he's
feeling stuck, feeling like [ __ ] So he
goes back to his old habits. They say
old habits die hard. But why is this?
It's because old habits have a feedback
loop. Now the third time he tries to
combine exercise and diet, but the
stress from his lifestyle change is
causing effects on his sleep. And we
know that fat is lost when you sleep.
Muscle is gained when you sleep. So it
ends up just looking more or less the
same. week after week and he gives up
assuming that he is too old to make any
substantial change in his life. Now this
story is a hypothetical right? It sounds
like a hypothetical because it is. But
some variation of this story is what's
keeping you stuck and that is not a
hypothetical. Some feedback loop is
responsible for keeping you where you
are. This goes beyond fitness by the
way. There are feedback loops that are
keeping your bank account looking
exactly what it's looking like. There
are feedback loops that are keeping you
single. I'm serious. So think about
this. If you are stuck at anything in
life, it means that there's a positive
feedback loop which is keeping you
there. If you're a guy who's bad with
women, probably means that you have a
mindset that's making you bad with women
and your being bad with women reinforces
that mindset. So this is an example of
course of another feedback loop that
keeps you stuck where you are. So
whenever you are stuck, you must
investigate the system structure. So the
solution of course to something like
this would be a systemsbased approach
which just so happens to be my
specialty. Going back to that
hypothetical which I constructed out of
nowhere, if you are that chubby guy
who's trying to lose some life chub,
you'd have to focus on recovery to blunt
the cortisol spikes. You'd have to focus
on hypertrophy to blunt the insulin
spikes. You'd have to focus on stress
management to blunt the epinephrine
spikes. You'd have to focus on
consistency to blunt the dopamine
spikes. Hard to say spike so many times,
boys. If it seems complex, it doesn't
have to be. You just need the right
systems. First, like I said, boys,
sleep. It's when you sleep that
testosterone is produced, when muscle
growth happens, and when growth hormone
is released. Sleep is when fat loss
happens. Sleep is when your body height
increases, assuming you're in the right
age for this. Sleep is when you cash in
the efforts made during the day. If you
don't get good quality sleep, 8 to nine
hours, you're basically deciding to
forego the rewards from the effort that
you made during the day. Yes, sleep
optimization is a big topic, but let's
hit it with the big five analysis. The
big five rule states that 90% of the
results come from the top three actions.
So, what are the top three actions that
lead to good sleep? Action one is the
light environment. You need to fix the
light environment if you're going to get
good sleep. So, how do you do this? You
are going to wear a silk sleep mask when
you sleep. This will keep out the light
from your eyes. Second is to get
yourself these blue light blockers. Now,
I'm not an affiliate. I don't make any
money by promoting this company, but I
found a lot of benefit from having
these. So, not all blue light blockers
are created equal. And this is the final
boss of blue light blockers. Yes, it
looks weird. Yes, it looks like
something out of Mission Impossible. No,
I would not wear it in public. But it
works. It's shaped in this weird way and
it's shaped such that light doesn't get
in from the sides and it's super dark
tinted and it's completely red so
nothing but red wavelengths get through.
High leverage investment. Shout out to
Elijah from the Austin Growth House for
putting me on these. Now the third is
optional though recommended is to get
programmable lights in your home like
like the Philips Hue lights. And what
these will do is you can program them to
turn red at a time that you set. So I've
set mine to turn red at 6 p.m. Works
great. reminds me that I need to stop
working to wind down and focus on
recovery mode. Action number two,
nutrition. No food 3 hours prior to bed.
Food right before sleeping messes with
recovery. Also, I would say no water 3
hours prior to bed. Now, this is not an
exact science, but it helps me because
if because if I don't follow this rule,
I almost always end up waking up to go
to the bathroom. And I hate this because
it disrupts my sleep, right? So, food
and water. You need to increase the time
between you consume food and water and
your actual bedtime to improve your
recovery. Action number three,
temperature. Take a quick shower before
you sleep. It can literally be less than
60 seconds. Hell, it can be just 30
seconds. Just expose yourself to water.
You don't even have to, you know, use
soap and shampoo and do a whole hygiene
routine. This is not for hygiene. It's
more so for the body temperature reset.
It's a thermal reset. So, you've
probably heard this before that you need
your body temperature to cool down for
better recovery during sleep. Powerful.
All you got to do is step into the
shower, blast yourself with cold water,
and doesn't have to be actually cold
water. It can actually be a warm shower
as well because regardless of hot shower
or cold shower, the t the the surface of
the body will actually lose heat through
evaporation of the water. So, this will
cause a cascade of blood flow changes
that will allow your body to quickly
adapt and change its state. So hear me
out and understand this carefully. A
shower, no matter what the temperature
is, allows you to be more adaptable
thermally. So either from wakeful to
sleepy or sleepy to wakeful. So I
actually take two quick showers during
the day. One in the morning to go from
sleepy to alert and once an hour prior
to bed to go from alert to sleepy. If
you implement just these three
techniques, you're going to achieve 90%
of sleep optimization. In the cohorts,
how we implement sleep optimization at
the expert level is by giving everybody
an aura ring. This way I have
minuteby-minute control or I should say
access to your bio data. Pair the fact
that in the cohort I have access also to
your nutrition and your exercise. Using
this I can triangulate the perfect
health transformation for you. Now going
to the third key aspect of health which
is exercise. There's research that shows
that lifting heavy in the five to eight
rep range can boost testosterone
receptor sensitivity. There's also
research showing that I don't give a
[ __ ] The truth is doesn't matter. The
only thing that matters is intensity,
progressive overload and consistency. So
consistency is a real king because you
can train intensity and progression. You
first build consistency. And where does
consistency come from? Consistency is
downstream of enjoyment. So find a
workout style that works for you and
just stick with that. The best training
modality is the one which you enjoy.
Make it fun, make it social, make it
intense. Personally, the gym, just
standard weightlifting makes the most
sense for me because I can see the
fastest results. The past 2 years have
been difficult time for me health-wise.
I took two joint injuries back in 2022
at the end of 2022 and my health issues
flared up out of nowhere in 2023. had
severe breathing issues to the point I
couldn't even breathe with my nose at
all. The most I could do in the gym
because I was completely out of energy,
my testosterone profile was destroyed,
my hormone profile was destroyed, was
maybe 10 to 20 minutes on the treadmill.
Then I had to get surgery done which
again put me out of the gym because of
course if you lift weights after a
surgery you can rupture blood vessels.
Now the final aspect of health which is
nutrition. Now this can be a huge topic.
We can talk about the gut microbiome. We
can talk about parasites. We can talk
about so much more. But this would be
its own course. Instead, I will focus
again on using the big three rule. So,
what's the big three on nutrition?
Number one is to avoid seed oils. This
rule automatically changes food choices.
It means that you choose the grilled
chicken at Chick-fil-A instead of the
fried. See, you don't have to be rigid
with this. Right now, I'm not saying
Chick-fil-A is where you should go to
get healthy food. I'm just saying that
if you're going out as well, you can
make better choices. This is one of
those high leverage rules that have huge
downstream effects. Now, you may not be
able to eliminate seed oils completely,
but you don't have to. You don't need
perfection to see results. Just need to
aim at minimization. Simple rule, high
leverage. The second rule, rule number
two is the carrot and egg rule. I used
to have this habit of snacking a lot
between meals. If I'm doing research for
a video or working on business, whenever
I get stuck on something, whenever I get
frustrated, I would make a beline to the
fridge to grab something. Now, I've
tried using discipline and willpower to
stop this behavior. But I always had
mixed results. Now, I have this simple
rule that I always follow, which is I
can snack anytime I want. No guilt
associated, but I can only snack on
carrots or boiled eggs. Now, I like
carrots and boiled eggs, but they aren't
addicting in the same way as packaged
goods generally are. Besides, it's
nutritious. You can't go wrong with
eating too many eggs or carrots. Well, I
mean, you can, but that's very unlikely.
Carrots will bind to toxins and remove
them from your body. Eggs, of course,
are eggs are amazing. Eggs are nutrition
grenades. So, simple rule, high
leverage. Rule number three, chew your
food completely before swallowing. This
is an interesting one because it has
immediate as well as long-term effects.
In the short term, chewing your food
longer and waiting for it to be
completely mushed before swallowing it
aids in digestion and of course the
nutrition absorption, meaning that
you're going to get more nutrition per
volume of food that you consume. But the
long-term benefits are actually the
biggest lever. If you chew your food
fully, you will reveal the full flavor
profile of that food that you're eating.
It means that unhealthy food of any
kind, packaged goods or if it's fast
food, whatever, will lose its appeal to
you. Why? Because as you are chewing
this food completely, you're giving your
taste buds the time to actually examine
what's in the food. So foods that's
engineered to be nutritious by adding
MSG will no longer be able to play that
trick on you because your sense of taste
is actually quite good. It just needs
time to fully absorb and give that
information to the brain. Giving your
taste buds time to assess the food makes
the food taste bad if it's unhealthy
food. And at the same time, actual whole
foods like steak and potatoes will not
decay in taste as you chew. In fact, new
flavors will be unlocked. This single
rule will lead to lifelong changes in
decision-m. I want to mention this
before we close out. The knowledge of
these tactics are useless without
implementation. Put these to work. Make
the sacrifices. If you don't sacrifice
for your dreams, your dreams will become
the sacrifice.