so why would you want to read a science
fiction series full of gigachad super
soldiers rampaging in the Galaxy
fathered by these Gene Titan demigods
who are all ruled by this massively
overpowered psychically able Emperor on
the surface level well it's fun it's
enjoyable to read these stories they're
complicated plots interesting Mysteries
to solve and you have stories of Duty
strength and honor also you have stories
of treachery debauchery and degeneracy
plus your over laying all this on a
system of warfare and strategy so all
these things are extremely appealing to
me I loved all this stuff so it makes
perfect sense for me to read it that's
the surface level though on the deeper
level it asks the fundamental questions
of society meaning and personal life and
that's the reason why you would ever
read fiction you read literature and
fiction because that's the way you get
at deeper truths for example what role
does faith and religion play in a societ
Society that's gravitating more and more
towards science are there domains where
science is irrelevant and what is
Brotherhood anyway what is loyalty is
loyalty just Blind Faith or is there
some kind of cognition some kind of
judgment required even for loyalty then
what's the correct balance of power of
government should government be
perfectly rigid and enforce all laws at
all times or should government have some
ability for individuals to have freedom
and what if that freedom comes at risks
then of course course the Aesthetics the
aesthetic understanding is very
overlooked in the modern world the
modern ethos states that it's always
function over form and quite often
you're left with neither function nor
form so it's very important to cultivate
an understanding of the Aesthetics and
indeed this was something which almost
every single civilized culture taught
their students taught their young men
this series The Horus heresy has the
epicness the greatness The Valor of
something like The Iliad or the Odyssey
it brings those great works of Homer
into the modern and in fact into the
science fiction realm and I've read dead
in the ODC and I see these parallels
between them it's beautiful it's able to
discuss the greatest philosophies for
example when is it appropriate to show
mercy and when is it appropriate to show
complete Relentless War I will see the
Galaxy freed once
more so what the hell am I talking about
like let me Orient you because obviously
this channel is is not a 40K L Channel
anything like that so the Horus heresy
is a book series which takes place
within the Warhammer 40K universe and
this is a massive massive Series this
book series is more than 50 books long
can you imagine that like you would
think that the Harry Potter series was
long because it had eight books Horus
heres's
550 books but luckily you don't have to
read all of them to make sense and I'll
give you basically the best of the best
books within the Horus heresy so you can
enjoy them and get value from them
without literally reading every single
book
from the Skies of Terror to the galactic
Rim I'm going to tell you right now that
this is a vast and crazy detailed
Universe which I love but it might be a
lot to get into in the first place I
understand that's a huge barrier to
entry that's fine ignore the barrier to
entry it's literally fiction so don't
overthink it just jump into the book
series exactly in the order which I give
them and you'll be fine like the level
of detail in this series is staggering
there's
20 there's 18 there's 18 Legions each
Legion has their own different strategy
of War each Legion has their own
Aesthetics their own color scheme and
everything each Legion has its own
Primark which is like the leader of the
Legion and each Primark has their own
backstory their own character Arc and
everything so it gets really complicated
real fast but luckily each book only
usually deals with one Legion at a time
so first let me give you the absolute
Basics that you might want to know
before you get into the series first
thing which like really got me
interested into this into this universe
is that humans aren't like the weakling
spe species where all the other aliens
have better technology than us in this
universe humans are the big ones the
humans have the biggest empire which is
ridiculous completely inverting what
most science fiction universes have and
the first book of the series starts off
with Humanity on the ascent humanity is
growing across the Galaxy so get that
this science fiction universe is Galaxy
spanning like the entire Milky Way
galaxy is within the purview of this
universe so when I say the Imperium of
man I'm talking about like this Imperium
owns the whole galaxy and there are
other aliens but they've kind of been
pushed into the sides and at the center
of this massive universe is Earth our
same Earth which is in this universe
they call it Tera and in Tera there is
the Emperor the Emperor of mankind and
this kind gentleman has created 20
primar Prim marks are like demigods and
the emperor himself is practically a God
but he creates these Prim marks which
are massively powerful fate bending
Destiny wielding massively overpowered
super soldiers and using the gene seed
from each Primark you can create Space
Marines which themselves like stand
twice the height of a regular man and
are massively powerful like each single
Space Marine would be as strong as the
most elite soldier of any other universe
and the most important thing for me is
the aesthetic sense there's no
minimalism in this universe everything
is to the max the artwork is over the
top it's beautiful it's detailed it's
rich in a world when most science
fiction universes or any kind of
universe tries to go for minimalism or
realism 40K goes for the opposite we go
for the maximum level of detail
possible so now let's jump into the book
list and if you have a book in mind that
I don't include just put in the comments
so book one we have of course Horus
Rising so this book series like I said
is 50 books long right but there's kind
of like mini series within them so it's
kind of like clumps clumps of books
which go well together and you kind of
have to read them as a chunk without
skipping in between so the first chunk
like the opening Saga of this Horus
heresy starts with Horus rising and you
absolutely should read the first five
books one after the other the first five
books are Horus Rising false gods Galaxy
in Flames Flight of the eisenstein and F
Grim so you need to read all these five
to get started with the series they're
all really great books and you'll enjoy
them so getting right into it right so
Horus Rising Horus Rising so there's a
Primark named Horus who is the name of
the entire series Horus heresy and he's
important because he is the leader of
the traitor primarch so I mentioned
there's 18 primarch some of them turn
bad it's a civil war so the Horus heresy
is a civil war absolutely brutal man
like this series is the distillation of
all civil wars in our own human history
you start off with a bad side almost
being justifiable in their reproach and
then slowly the world the universe
deteriorates piece by piece and you're
left with nothing and no side really
wins because both sides are destroyed
almost starting off with Horus Rising so
our boy Horus he was appointed by the
Emperor as the leader of all the
primarch and at this point all the
primarchs are good none of them have
fallen so the first three books Horus
Rising false gods and Galaxy and Flames
details the fall of Horus and how he
turns against his father so Horus is the
chosen son right he's the favored son of
the emperor and he knows it he is the
most beloved he is the highest praised
primarch among all the primarch and
everybody's jealous of him but the thing
is this gets to his head when the Empire
leaves the Crusade so all the primar are
basically at war with the Universe At
Large and they're doing this huge thing
called the Great Crusade and the emperor
leaves the emperor leaves and this means
that the Crusade is no longer the most
important Focus for the Emperor or by
extension mankind so at the same time
Horus becomes a leader of all the
primarchs but he also loses meaning in
the Crusade itself so when a man loses
meaning in life he can do two things he
can look within himself get on
self-improvement read way of the
superior man by David daa and start
doing meditation and gratitude
journaling and all this stuff and become
a better person theyel his own talents
right this is not what Horus does Horus
grows bitter and resentful and a series
of events happen with treachery within
his own Legion which pushes him slowly
across the edge into embracing the
powers of chaos and you got to think the
primar are the leader of each Legion but
each Legion has thousands upon thousands
of Space Marines and some of them will
go loyal to the emperor and some of them
will won't be loyal to the Primark so
Horus has to kind of eliminate V section
of his own Army in order to make it
loyal to him so this book is truly about
Brotherhood and loyalty it's about
ethics and it's about sacrifice strongly
recommend you need to smash out the
three first books and before we go into
the next book I got to say that these
first three books detail something
called the istan 3 atrocity which is a
massacre and this is not really a
spoiler because anybody who's in 40K or
wants to get into it knows of this event
and it's very very compelling brutal
next book is Flight of the eisenstein
also a mustre because this details how
horus's treachery and the treachery of
some of its traitor Brothers gets word
to Terra and lets the emperor know so
that the Loyalists are kind of starting
to prepare for this Invasion this one
has less Mass scale battles but it kind
of Narrows the scope to a single
Battleship and the actions of A Few Good
Men highly recommend it's a mustre and
then we have number five F Grim this
details the fall of the Primark fulgrim
and this book is about excess so as we
develop oursel we're on the path of
ascent we're improving oursel we're on
self-improvement we're going to the gym
improving our bodies and seeking some
kind of perfection at what point does
this become obsessive and at what point
does the pursuit of perfection lead to
its opposite that's the philosophical
point which kind of comes out in the
book fulgrim fulgrim is a Primark of
perfection he is the perfect swordsman
he's the perfect battle tactician he's
also a man of art he's also a man of
learning learning so what happens when
his love for music and art and culture
goes to the extreme what happens when he
achieves Perfection but he doesn't know
what to do next and how this can drive a
good man mad that is the story of
fulgrim book number five completely a
highly recommended then we skip over
book six and go into book seven so the
first five books kind of contain
themselves they're kind of their own
thing and then you can jump straight to
book s book s stands alone it's a book
called Legion by Dan ABN and Legion is
about the alpha Legion so Alpha Legion
is one of those I said there's 18
Legions right so there 18 Legions one of
them is the alpha Legion Alpha Legion is
the master of Espionage trickery having
double agents spycraft all this stuff so
Alpha Legion books are a treat because
Alpha Legion books are usually
structured in a kind of like a mystery
like you don't know what you're getting
into and you really don't know what to
expect chapter by chapter a legion is no
different Legion is a mystery book
disguised as a war book and it details
some very important plot points for the
the Horus heresy it details why the
alpha Legion which is ostensibly for the
emperor goes against him so is the alpha
Legion a traitor or a loyalist well even
after you read the book you might have
questions then we skip over book eight
battle for the abyss we skip over book n
mechanicum we skip over book 10 tales of
heresy skip over 11 and then we come to
12 a thousand Sons by Graham McNeil this
is the Magnus the red book this is the
Thousand Sons book and this is one of my
favorite Legions so the thousand suns
are are special Legion it's a very small
Legion but one of the most powerful if
not the most powerful because almost
every single soldier within this is a
Space Marine but also a psycher Space
Marine psychers in this universe are
basically individuals who can draw upon
the power of the warp in order to do
magic basically they can shoot out
lightning from their fingers they can
read the future the powers of the warp
are used in many different ways you can
use it as a weapon you can use it as a
strategy in any case the thousand suns
are very powerful magic Legion and their
Primark Magnus red is one of the most
powerful Primark and he's 100% loyal to
the emperor but then there's an event in
this book which happens where Magnus
feels betrayed by the emperor there's
this Council called the Council of nikea
which is very reminiscent of the actual
real world example the Council of NAA
happened in the city of NAA in the Roman
province of bethia in 325 ad and the the
Christian the church was in crisis
different Bishops believed different
things and it was up to the emperor to
decide what was Christianity and what
was heresy and this is exactly what
happens in this Horus heresy book The
Emperor has to decide whether magnus's
use of the warp was allowed or it was
heresy and here's the thing the emperor
himself is one of the most powerful
psychers to ever have lived so for him
to say that using psychic powers was a
heresy was very hypocritical and this
book is about the pursuit of knowledge
how much knowledge is good and this is a
problem that we actually facing in
society right now the internet exists
and we have so much knowledge at our
disposal at what point does it stop
being helpful and of course we having ai
ai allows information synthesis to
happen at a very different way than it
ever happened before what are the Perils
of this technology and more deeply this
is about epistemology does there exist
something called forbidden knowledge is
there knowledge that is so toxic that is
better that we don't even know it and
even up to this point so Magnus feels
betrayed by the emperor and he is the
most powerful for Primark but even
though he feels betrayed he is still
100% 100% loyal but he is arrogant
because he's so powerful and he is
himself a psycher so he thinks he knows
everything Magnus is the champion of
knowledge and because he thinks he can
even see the future his own level of
knowledge becomes a handicap Horus and
the forces of chaos are able to trick
Magnus into doing something very wrong
indeed basically Magnus goes against his
father's dictate that all psychic
energies are supposed to be heretical
and Magnus has has the best intentions
in mind and yet he makes a mistake so
terrible that at this point the tide
shifts so until this point the Imperium
still could have won at this point
there's still a bunch of loyal Legions
and the emperor himself could take the
field plus he had his whole custodes
Legion which is one of the most powerful
Legions there is and at this point the
emperor could have absolutely won the
war outright by going and killing Horus
himself but because of magnus's mistakes
caused by his arrogance in his own
knowledge now the tides have turned and
the traitor really are in the ascendant
highly recommend one of the best books
in the series and after this book you
immediately jump to Prospero Burns so
Prospero Burns is not the exact next
book in the series but it continues
story-wise it's the next book right it's
not the next book in terms of
publication but in terms of story it is
so jump from thousand suns directly onto
Prospero Burns because what happens is
because the emperor thinks that Magnus
has turned traitor even though he hasn't
he sends one of his other Legions the
Space Wolves to destroy the Thousand
Suns
the Space Wolves and the Thousand Suns
both are loyal at this time and they're
brought into conflict simply because of
arrogance misunderstanding and of course
manipulation by outside forces so in the
Thousand Suns we see the Thousand Suns
perspective of that war and in the
Prospero Burns book we see the space w
side of that war it from Reading from
both perspectives is really cool because
both sides genuinely believe that they
are doing the right thing but at the end
both sides are badly muled and the only
real winner is cha and Horus himself so
the Imperium cops of fat L on this one
highly recommend both books then we skip
over book number 13 and we jump to book
number 14 the first heretic by Aaron
diky Bowen this book is about the word
bearers Legion the word bearers and
their primar lurg guard were actually
the first to fall it wasn't actually
Horus Horus was the leader of the
traitors yes but lorgar had fallen
decades before Horus ever did and this
this was also a mistake by the emperor
so the emperor had a strict rule that
nobody should worship him as a God but
lurar he really wanted to and he
absolutely did he was building temples
and converting entire planets to the
worship of the emperor and the emperor
really didn't want worship because he
believed that worship fueled by Blind
Faith is what gives chaos its power I
haven't really talked about chaos but
and that's a philosophical discussion
for later so when the emperor realizes
that lorgar is creating a whole new
religion based on him he punishes lorgar
you know that saying you should always
praise in public but punish in silent
well the emperor did not get the memo he
punishes lar he humiliates him in front
of his brothers now understandably lar
is pissed the [ __ ] off and he wants to
take revenge he's in a very bad State
because the man who he believed to be a
God has treated him so poorly now he's
bitter he's resentful and this
bitterness and resent was co-opted by
the forces of chaos to turn him to their
side I mean amazing book about ethics
about what's true and what's false and
what's good and what's bad because these
things may not align perfectly and then
we go so this okay so remember I said
that these books kind of Clump up as
story lines after reading first heretic
you go all the way to no no fear book
number 19 so you go from 14 straight to
19 no no fear is a classic no no fear is
about the ultramarines legion the
ultramarines are led by their Primark
Rabe Gilman and what happens here is RO
rute gilan was there when the emperor
humiliated lorgar so basically lorgar
was humiliated in front of rute by his
father so he carries a lot of resentment
against his father but also for Gillan
for being there and in fact Gilman's
Legion was used to destroy one of his
most important cities and his own Planet
so he has a lot of anger towards Gillan
and of course lar is siding with Horus
so Horus basically commands lar to
destroy the ultral legion at this point
the ultramarines don't know what's going
on they don't know there's a heresy at
play completely oblivious so both
Legions are amassing at this planet
called calp and at Cal they are getting
ready for an invasion of the Orcs which
are completely different zenos race but
there are no Orcs because this whole
thing was a setup and lorgar's Legion is
basically ambushing the ultramarines
legion and they completely have
advantage of the element of surprise
they open fire on the friendly
ultramarines and decimate them but you
see the ultramarines are no joke this is
a legion based on real life Roman Empire
so they had discipline they have tactics
they were very Resolute and they could
change their tactics on the Fly and
really respond with Breakneck speed and
they did they fought against the word
bearers even though they were at a
disadvantage but the word bearers
started unleashing demons so the word
bears are the masters of the warp they
were able to control not even control
but just Co up the darkest sides of
chaos and unleash these demons and mon
monsters from another realm which at
this point the ultramarines didn't even
know they existed so now they're
fighting a whole different type of enemy
which they never encountered before but
by God they are the ultramarines and
they don't give up so they find new
tactics to defeat these demons on top of
their traitor brothers and despite the
fact that the war bears were going to
annihilate the ultramarine religion
they're able to regroup and escape to
fight another day and that day comes the
next book called book number 24 betrayer
by Aaron demsky Bowen this book is the
avengeance of the ultramarines the
ultramarines see an opportunity to
attack the word bearers and there's
another Legion called the world eaters
Legion and their Primark angron angron
is a living weapon so each of these
primarchs have their own skills so for
example ruti gilan is the master of
strategy I had mentioned before Horus
Horus is the master of the Tactical
strike another primar that we mentioned
Magnus Magnus is the master of magic and
the warp then we had lorgar who is the
master of mass psychology we also
mentioned the primar fulgrim he is the
master of Art and Perfection but angron
is the master of war and single combat
so angron is no joke to go against on
top of that lar was also with him but
the ultra Marines a strong and powerful
Legion so they decide to attack the
world bearers and the world leaders at
the same time and that is the story of
this book betrayer and this is a book
about friendship and Brotherhood more
than anything because this book really
Narrows the scope to two Warriors to
arel tal and K both very well-written
characters and these are the bad guys so
it's a really cool book because many of
these books you're always rooting for
the good guys to win obviously but in
this book the stars of the show are the
bad guys and it's a really cool other
side take on this narrative 28 here we
go 28 introduces you to the white scars
Legion this book is called Scars by
Chris R and the white scars Legion has
been all the way in the other side of
the Galaxy so all the [ __ ] is happening
in the middle of the Galaxy Horus is
here he's trying to kill the Imperium
the imperi is trying to fight back on
the other side we have gilan and what
happens in the previous book is Gilman
kind of gets trapped he's not able to
come to the rescue of his father and on
the other side we have the white scars
Legion who can come but they don't know
what's going on they've been so distant
from the rest of the universe that they
don't know who's good and who's bad
they've been fed lies that the emperor
betrayed Horus and the Horus is a good
guy they don't know what to believe and
this is another book about epistemology
how do you trust the information to you
so the primarch of the white scars jagon
is a very well- written character he's
very normal like all of the Space
Marines and all the primarch are
autistic to the level 9 man they all
have big egos take drastic action all
the time without thinking jagat tyon is
a very reasonable and calm Soul so when
he sees conflicting information he wants
proof before he can proceed he's very
reasonable so in this book we see how a
reasonable primarch actually behaves and
jagon is a master of speed his entire
entire Legion is around speed speed
speed like they attack fast and they
withdraw and they attack and they
withdraw so it's a very different type
of fighting style than any of the
legions that we saw before so it's cool
to see a different take on strategy so
highly recommend book 28 Scars by Chris
ra 36 36 is path of Heaven Again by
Chris Rait this is a continuation direct
continuation from book 28 scars so
finished scars and the very next book is
path of Heaven by Chris ra and this is
the conclusion of the white scars Legacy
white scars like I said were trapped in
the other side of the Galaxy and there's
traitors all over the place and then
there's Tera they need to make it
through all the traders to get to Tera
and this is the book which shows you how
they do it and this book is about
sacrifice man there is a scene and a
story arc in this book which is
absolutely brutal this book is about
when you have a higher goal what level
of pain are you able to go through in
order to make that higher goal a
possibility even if you never see it so
very powerful very drama IC book The
skip over 38 you should also read book
39 petoran of Dorne so petoran of Dorne
is when the Traders are really close the
Traders have reached the soul system and
they're attacking Pluto which is of
course the outer ring of the solar
system defenses and this has your
Primark rogal Dorn so rogal Dorn is the
petorian of Tera which means that he was
appointed by the emperor himself to
fortif five and hold the salt system and
rogal dor is Master tactician himself he
is the master of Siege craft so he has
transformed the soul system into an
absolute nightmare to attack he has
fortified everything and we have another
primarch in this book named alarius of
the alpha Legion and You' have met
alpharius already in Legion and this
time he's attacking the outer parameters
of the Soul system in order to get to
Terror so we have a face off between
extremely cunning and crafty Primark the
literally the Primark of treachery
alarus and against the most like
stern-faced loyal guy rogal Dorn so
highly recommend book 39 petoran of
Dorne 41 is another solid one master of
mankind by Aaron demsky Bowen so I said
the emperor is at the center of
everything right but this is the first
time we actually see him in action in
master of mankind so remember when I
said Magnus [ __ ] things up and then
the emperor couldn't get off his ass and
go and actually fight Horus this is
where we find out what actually happened
so Magnus he had a foreshadowing of
horus's betrayal so he breaks his
father's orders of not using magic and
he uses his warp power to teleport
himself all the way from his planet of
Prospero all the way to Tera to inform
his father but in doing so he
accidentally breaks all the shields his
father had so the Father the Emperor of
mankind he of course guarded his Palace
both with physical walls but also
psychic Wards and Magnus is a very very
powerful psycher so it's only him in the
entire galaxy who could have broken
through so Magnus was actually coming to
warn his father about heresy and in
doing so he destroyed destroys those
psychic Wards in order to get to his
father but because he's broken those
psychic Wards now other forces can also
get to his father so at this point
Magnus had destroyed the emperor's
project and the emperor had his own
battle to fight within Tera itself
because demons were coming into Tera and
the emperor had to manage that full time
and so he couldn't take the battlefield
himself and master of mankind details
the story of that battle and that war
very cool because you can see the
emperor in action you see the custodies
and you see a hella powerful demon
called draenen and the philosophy behind
this demon is interesting so this is the
demon of the first murder so we didn't
really talk about chaos at all until
this point so the idea of Chaos in this
universe is that there is a metaphysical
realm on top of the Physical Realm which
is completely governed by emotion as
beings in the Physical Realm die could
be humans could be xenos their pain and
suffering bleeds into this imum so the
alternate reality and in this alternate
reality it people's suffering can turn
into cognizant life forms and the echo
of the first murder so the first time a
human being killed another human being
that caused an emotion to be formed in
the warp and this emotion very small at
first but as murders started happening
more and more throughout the entire line
of human history this demon become
powerful and more powerful at the end
you have this Mega demon which is strong
enough to kill custodies so it's a very
interesting philosophical take the idea
that one sin may not be that much but
compounding that sin year after year
leaves you with a demon which can outdo
yourself so very cool book very
interesting philosophical sides master
of mind kind book number 41 highly
recommend at this point there you have
it boys that's the Horus heresy reading
list and if you want the whole overall
reading list cuz obviously I don't read
just fiction then I have the reading
list Link in the description below and
this reading list will contain things
like self-improvement topics philosophy
history business and L contains the top
20% of books I've ever read in my
[Music]
life