is stoicism holding you back let me ask
this question in a different way has
anything great ever been achieved
through stoicism has stoicism inspired
great art or great architecture has it
fueled great warriors has it fired
passionate love stoicism is the
internet's favorite philosophy and let's
see if it lives up to the hype most
people don't know this but stoicism
shouldn't be considered a philosophy but
more so a strategy and if you don't
understand the difference between the
two then stoicism can actually hold you
back from your true potential stoicism
in its purest Essence is if you can do
something about it then go right ahead
if you cannot do something about it then
you have to accept it and move on this
can be expressed in the form of a prayer
give me the courage to control that
which I can give me the strength to
accept that which I cannot and give me
the knowledge to tell that difference
this shows the greatest strengths of
storis it's Simplicity but also its
greatest weakness the flaw in stoicism
lies in the third sentence give me the
knowledge to tell the difference I think
this is where stoicism really falls
short and I'll explain by looking at the
history not just of Marcus Aurelius the
stoic Emperor but also of Lucius aurelan
the restorer of the world everybody on
this side of the internet knows the name
of Marcus Aurelius the great emperor of
Rome who ruled with Justice honor and
Duty around 200 ad we are aware of the
book meditations which is his personal
diary which serves as the gateway book
in into stoicism Marcus aurelus can be
considered a true embodiment of the
Greek ideal of the philosopher king when
I was in Rome last year I was walking
around in the city and I saw this
massive marble column there was no crowd
around it there was no hype around it
there's no information panels around it
and and even tourists didn't really
bother taking pictures of it but I knew
what it was it was the column of Marcus
Aus it shows in its carvings the many
Battlefield triumphs of Marcus Marcus
had to fight brutal Wars against the
germanics in the north the parthians to
the East and of course he had to face
the antonine plague this plague did more
damage to the Roman army and the economy
than any enemy on top of this Marcus was
in constant personal pain he was not a
very healthy man he had some kind of a
chronic illness or perhaps it was just
the stress of his duties as the emperor
soon after Marcus aelius died the Empire
started to crumble there were 40
Emperors in just the next years and we
got a new emperor every 2 years in
contrast Marcus ruled for 20 continuous
years after Marcus we had Commodus
Marcus's [ __ ] up son who was so messed
up in the head that he literally did
this he rounded up some guys who are
handicapped so people who had lost their
legs and he put them in snake costumes
and he made them wriggle around and then
he proceeded to beat the [ __ ] out of
them with a club yeah so messed in the
head then we had carala who was a great
Soldier but he does a lot of damage to
Rome by De de basing the currency and
giving all the gold to the generals then
we had elagabalus who literally was a
prostitute he literally prostituted
himself to his guards and his soldiers
he even got the doctors to give him a
sex change operation which they refused
to do but still like this was the kind
of Rome that it became after the reign
of Marcus and this is why Marcus is
remembered with a lot of respect because
in his Reign things were actually pretty
good but now the currency was worthless
the military was weak and demoralized
people had lost any trust in the
government and the religion was
corrupted and this was the Empire that
Lucius aelan took control of about 100
years after the death of Marcus Aurelius
this was an Empire of degeneracy Decay
and Corruption the people of Rome were
driven mad by drinking water from lead
pipes rampant uncontrolled immigration
meant that the original Roman stock was
being replaced and global cooling was
happening that was destroying grain and
food production on top of this new rival
Powers were getting stronger we had the
polymarine Empire to the east led by
Zenobia who is apparently a certified
hottie according to the historical
record and we have the new threats in
the north the gods and the vandals in
the west we had the gallic tribes today
we talk about the decline of the us and
we talk about inflation eating our
savings we're talking about China
getting stronger and stronger we talk
about all this stuff but it's all
happened once before and much worse this
was the Empire that Lucius took control
of and yet Lucius was able to bring
bring the Empire back to its former
glory in Just 4 years so who was this
Lucian aelan and why am I hyping him up
let's look at his origin story Lucius
was not born into Power he was not in
line to the throne by a long shot he was
a regular and listed soldier who was so
damn good at his job that he rose up the
ranks and eventually became a general
then the emperor himself this should
have been impossible a rational man
couldn't have done it but IUS was not a
rational man a rational man controls
that which he can and accepts that which
he cannot a rational man would have
looked at the state of the Roman Empire
in 270 ad and decided that this dumpster
fire could not possibly be controlled
this was a fallen Empire and just 10
years ago Emperor Valyrian was captured
by the Persians imagine how [ __ ] up
that situation is that's as though the
president of the United States get
captured by China like that's an
unbelievable thing but that is what
happened to Rome Emperor Valyrian was
captured by the Persians tortured made
into a foot stool and skinned alive
According to some references the
rational man would have taken the path
of stoicism the best I can do is slow
the decline and push back the end times
but there's a thing Lucius was not the
rational man he said [ __ ] it we ball and
he did ball in 4 years he managed to
undo about 100 Years of corruption
military defeat and stagnation that's
the mindset of a winner now let me make
sure you understand the greatness of
this man he destroyed the alamani the
gods the vandals and the sarmatians and
the jangi in the north then he took all
his forces to the east crushed Zenobia
and the pal Marines and then he went to
the GIC Empire in the west somewhere
along all this he also commissioned the
building of the aelan walls around Rome
that still stand today he even fixed the
currency system and reversed inflation
by moving back to the true gold standard
imagine the balls it takes to do that
and all of possible because he was
completely consumed by the vital energy
this was a man who ran on electricity
this was the Man Against Time able to
harness the destructive power of the
Roman cavalry charge but also the
creative power of the Roman industry and
it couldn't have done this if he was a
stoic and now you think I'm going to be
misrepresenting stoicism because I don't
understand it well let's see let's paint
the best picture of stoicism that we can
stoicism is the wisdom to know that
there are things outside one's control
in Marcus ais's meditation he talks
about the only thing you can really
control is the internal you can only
control the self and this idea of
Virtues or virtue as we would call it
his idea was at the end of the day the
only thing that matters is being a
virtuous man doing the right thing no
matter what the pressure or The
Temptations to put it simply stoicism
says control that which you can but have
the strength to accept that which you
cannot however to do this you need the
knowledge to know the difference the
thing is you don't have that knowledge
and this is the main flaw of stoicism
you don't know what's within your
control if Lucius aelan looked at the
Hard facts the evidence and the rational
arguments he would have concluded that
the Roman Empire was beyond doomed he
would have resorted to a defensive
mindset and that is exactly what
stoicism is it is a defensive mindset it
was because Lucius took the offensive
that he was successful it is because he
had irrational Faith rather than cold
logic that he could do the impossible
even today Elon Musk is he a stoic
absolute Ely not I just finished reading
his book his new biography by Walter
Isaacson and I am blown away by the
impossibility of musk's achievement if
musk looked at the world as a cold and
logical place if he looked at it in fact
as an engineer then he would not have
been able to build SpaceX or Tesla let
alone both at the same time stoicism as
a life philosophy cannot lead to great
success stoicism is focused on the
internal not the external this is
literally the core tenant of St ISM put
forward by Zeno himself but here's the
thing focusing on the internal does not
drive change Blind Faith irrational
optimism and pure passion are what Drive
change let me explain this in a slightly
different way if you're learning boxing
and you're getting really good at
defense in the ring you have your chin
down you have your elbows up because you
obviously don't want to get clocked in
the face and to be fair this strategy
works you minimize the damage but you
will never win with a pure defense
strategy you will never win in order to
throw a punch you have to put down your
defense for a second and risk getting
punched in the process stoicism is a
shield everybody has times in their life
while they think things are hopeless
they say when it rains it pours and I
get it sometimes all you can do is stand
and take the punches sometimes all you
can do is just use the mental Shield of
stoicism and say this is just outside my
control I'll just accept it for what it
is and do my duty and my point isn't
that stoicism is bad or useless far from
it it's highly useful my point is simply
that it is one strategy a defensive
strategy that makes sense in special
circumstances while things are genuinely
outside your control one example is just
death people die family members die
friends die pets die and there's nothing
you can do after somebody is dead there
is no hope in this case there is only
acceptance another example is the things
in the past you cannot change the past
no matter how powerful you are it is
truly outside our control Faith and Hope
cannot change it the only way forward is
acceptance but other than the past and
death there is a lot that is within our
control it is better to assume that
things are within our control we as
humans have a bias towards the status
quo we are not risk-seeking creatures so
we must actively seek to push oursel
into thinking that we have more control
than what our logical brain tells us so
I am not willing to stoically accept the
world in which I I'm born into so let me
drive passionately towards the future
that I want let me feel the pain of
existence as a gift he who can
experience the deepest sorrow can rise
to the greatest Heights I know I'm going
to get a lot of comments saying well
stoicism doesn't tell you to be passive
and that's technically true but stoicism
doesn't get you fired up it doesn't have
any aggression within it stoicism is a
defensive mindset that's just the truth
of it and even if you read the original
works of epicus it is a defensive
mindset it does doesn't have Fire Within
it and it made sense for the Greeks and
the Romans because those men had so much
Fire Within them that you kind of needed
something to place a damper on it to
kind of control it our men our modern
world does not have men of great fire
it's quite the opposite we're we're just
normally passive so we need the opposite
we need the fire we need a worldview
that actively rages against passivity
and stoicism simply does not do that
even now you might think that I don't
fully understand stoicism and so I
criticize it but I do understand it my
point isn't that stoicism has some
logical flaw in fact it doesn't have a
logical flaw it's actually the perfect
philosophy and there in lies the problem
the human mind is not a computer if the
human mind could process if then
statements if the human mind was a
perfectly logical machine then stoicism
would be the ideal operating system if
humans had perfect knowledge of our own
capabilities and the full knowledge of
the externalities then stoicism would be
the perfect algorithm but that is simply
not the case stoicism should be used as
a last resort strategy when everything
is going bad too many young men snuff
out the Fire Within them because they
think it is virtuous to Bear the burdens
placed upon them I know the ideas which
I'm sharing in this video kind of go
against the common wisdom of the
masculinity space but the history of
philosophy actually supports my view
Roman stoicism gained strength when the
Empire had crossed its peak was in a
Time of decline it would be historically
accurate to say that Roman stoicism was
born in an era not of Hope and growth
but of stagnation and decline also
stoicism works best in a society that
tells you exactly what your duty is
because if your duty is St in stone you
might as well deal with it the best you
can in Roman times if you were the son
of a baker then you would learn how to
bake if you were the son of a cobbler
you would know how to make shoes if
you're born a slave then tough luck you
might as well get used to it cuz you're
going to die a slave you could see here
how stalis would be an amazing
Philosophy for the time when you really
cannot do much about your surroundings
or your circumstances stoicism is the
best but here's the thing stoicism
teaches you how to Bear heavy loads but
does not teach you what loads to Bear
now coming back to the initial question
is stoicism cope again we look at
history epicus was a slave he had zero
control over his life and he needed a
cope senica was not technically a slave
but he was in the court of Nero so he
was a subject of the random whims of a
Madman he had zero control over his life
he was exiled at random by Nero he was
executed at random by Nero he needed a
cope but what about Marcus aelius he was
an emperor of Rome surely he is the
opposite of a slave well not so Marcus
Aurelius was a slave to his position he
couldn't quit he couldn't even take a
break 20 years of Relentless work man
not a single weekend right every second
of every day was devoted to legal
procedures endless Warfare plagues Civil
Wars and famines he did not have freedom
now it seems that I'm being critical of
Marcus in this video but nothing could
be further from the truth the strain and
the stress that Marcus aurelus faced
would have broken any man and if you
look at the successors of Marcus you
have the proof communist was a lunatic
kacala was a sadist El gabis wanted a
sex change operation so the fact that
Marcus could bear the burden of office
is an impressive impressive feed but
let's be clear Marcus Aurelius lived his
entire life on the defense he didn't
have a choice his health was poor and
his Empire was crumbling the main point
is you do have a choice you are not an
emperor of Rome you don't have to bear
the responsibilities of being an emperor
you don't have to worry about making
decisions that cost millions of lives
you don't have to live on the defensive
as Marcus did is my personal belief that
Marcus Aurelius had he had better health
would have not taken stoicism up and he
would have been less like senica and
more like Caesar he clearly had the
ability but he didn't have the mindset
and the reason he didn't have the
mindset is because he didn't have the
health that's why I keep telling you
health comes first and that includes
mental health you probably heard of
meditation before or even tried it maybe
you saw results and maybe you didn't I
have a unique meditation style that
nobody on YouTube has talked about this
is the esoteric meditation protocol one
of the principles of esoteric health is
that the body and the mind are one and
it is meaningless to train one without
the other based on this principle I've
created this protocol which I've been
using for years at this point the
standard meditation and advice of
sitting around focusing on breath takes
too long to see results and that's why
you quit cuz you don't see results quick
enough but I have fixed this problem I
will teach this meditation technique in
the next video so if you'd like to
subscribe you do have that option in
fact I have created a whole Community
called a 30-day brain reset it contains
a 30day long course a day byday training
to reset your brain this is the
technique that allowed me to gain
Traction in life for the first time it
allowed me to break through my
addictions helped me get better social
skills made me a better decision maker
and even gave me the skill at Sports and
exercise and boxing I a very strange
medit ation technique and you'll
understand what I mean when I actually
talk about it more if you like the idea
of being able to reset your brain for
less than 10 minutes per day then
there's a link in the description below
which is going to take you to that
Community right now it's practically
free so best time to get it is literally
today coming back to the history of
stoicism the word stoicism comes from
the word stoa which were these corridors
in Greece where philosophers will meet
and share ideas but where does the word
stoa comes from it comes from the Proto
indoeuropean root sta which means firm
but it is the same roote that gives us
the word stasis which means to never
change to stagnate and so we come to
another flaw with stoicism which nobody
really talks about the common wisdom is
that emotions are bad men should be not
emotional men should be rational and
logical and indeed stoic but does this
describe the greatest men of history
Napoleon Alexander Ashoka Caesar shivaji
aurelian Justinian and even in more
times Washington Hamilton and even today
Elon Musk none of these men were
particularly stoic they were moved by
their Titanic emotional energy it was
the power of their emotions that allowed
them to lead their men in the first
place they acted on their emotions and
were driven by their emotions they made
terrible mistakes also because of the
emotions the very forces that made them
a great man also were in some cases
their downfall and here's where the
virtue of stoicism lies stoicism cannot
drive a man forward but it can stop a
man from slipping backwards sometimes
stasis is not a bad thing it matters
where you are if you're happy where you
are then stoicism is the perfect mindset
but for me I want to shake things up I
want to see what can drive a man
forwards and I think the best answer is
Faith just as stoicism is The Shield
that protects you faith is the sword
that strikes out this can be faith in
God but it can also be faith in one's
own ability it can be faith in the
possibility of a great future and this
is what I believe in