Attention chatting. It has come to my
attention that some of y'all don't know
how to cut a pineapple correctly. This
was me. Few weeks ago, I decided to cut
my first pineapple on YouTube. I decided
to see how to cut a pineapple. What I
discovered was lies. Lies upon lies from
big pineapple giving you incorrect
pineapple cutting techniques. There is
only one correct pineapple cutting
technique. And I shall reveal this
secret to you today. I will tell you
what most pineapple amateurs do not
know. First, we do start with cutting
the head off. Next, we do in fact cut
its ass off. Next step also is commonly
known. We cut it in half. Here's where
the changes happen. Here's where the
highly esoteric pineapple crafting
techniques come into play. A lot of
pineapple amateurs,
what they do is they try to remove this
core and then try to slice the pineapple
up in different ways. Wrong. They don't
know what they're doing. What you do now
is you chop this,
chop this, and then instead of removing
the core with a diagonal slice, you
instead
remove it using two slices at right
angles to one another, thereby removing
the core, extracting this pestilential
piece of pineapple that cannot be eaten
by human beings, leaving behind as much
pineapple
bold as possible.
Then you slice that in half. Now you
have these segments of pineapple and
then you extract its armor, revealing
the succulent insides of pineapple. But
the secret to good pineapple carving
starts even before you start carving the
pineapple. You got to choose good
pineapples. And that begins by looking
at its exterior. You're looking for a
nice golden non-green outer surface.
Sometimes there would be like sugar
leaking out. That's actually a good
sign. What you're doing is you're
looking for some compressibility, but
not much. And of course, the smell. If
your pineapple doesn't smell like
pineapple, it's just not ripe enough.
You need to give it more time. Then you
do the same square
indents out of all these pineapples.
And once you do this, you will be
rewarded by the gift of the gods
themsel, the Hawaiian royal pineapple
from the dough plantations themselves.
Most pineapples you probably had are
from a can.
And even if they're not, they probably
have this weird prickly sensation which
they create in your mouth. This is
caused because pineapples have this
enzyme which in them within them which
basically kind of eats some part of your
skin as you're eating them. It's a it's
a it's almost like a digestive enzyme.
This is what causes that prickly
sensation. But pineapples which are
fresh don't have this. So, if you can
get fresh pineapples, which you can get
in some places only, Latin America and
Hawaii, then you are in luck and you
have been blessed. All the armor has
been separated. Now, we got some hiding.
And that, my friends, is a pineapple
completely carved up in a matter of
seconds. Now, you can choose to chop
them up into chunks. You don't really
need to. All you need to do is grab one
of these as they are and let's do a
taste test.
A a ripe fresh pineapple doesn't have
that segmented crunchy feeling that a a
canned pineapple or a unripe pineapple
might have. It has the same texture of
something like a mango where it just
your teeth just sink into it, but has a
flavor profile of pineapple. So, if you
have the opportunity to visit the
glorious Pacific Island of Hawaii, one
thing you must do is enjoy a Royal
Hawaiian pineapple.
I go.