non-sleep deep rest is a 10 000 years
time tested practice called Yoga Nidra
science has finally caught up and I'm
going to share with you my personal
protocol and this is like a guided
meditation so use it as a tool for
whenever you need a dopamine recharge
phase one
the setup find a comfortable and quiet
space where you won't be disturbed for
the next 25 minutes you don't need an
alarm because I will tell you when to
come back turn off any distracting
devices or noise around you and lie down
in a position that feels comfortable
close your eyes gently and tune in to
the Natural rhythm of your breath
there is no need to control or change
anything just let it be as it is
phase two
the body scan
now let's begin a body scan
start from the top of your head
gradually moving to your toes as you
focus on each part of your body let any
tension or stress Melt Away feel the
weight of your body on the surface
literally feel the weight of your heels
your calves glutes shoulder blades and
head on the surface you're literally
going part by part
you're going from your top of the head
and going to your forehead eyebrows eyes
nose
mouth
neck
your shoulders
upper chest
lower chest
[Music]
your belly
your biceps
your triceps
your forearms
thumb
index
middle finger
ring
and Little Finger
and each part of your body which I've
mentioned you are going to
allow them
to relax
[Music]
then
we come
to our waist
will relax
our genitals will relax
[Music]
our dick will relax our balls relax our
quads our hamstrings our glutes
our knees
our calves
our heels
the base of our feet
and our toes
phase three mindful breathing
turn your attention to your breathing
feel the rise and fall of your chest
with each inhale and exhale
if your mind begins to wander that's
fine just bring your focus back to your
breath
Place one hand on the belly and one on
the chest to really feel the in flow and
outflow of air through your body foreign
[Music]
meditation
embrace the present moment
let go of the thoughts of the past and
the future
if thoughts or feelings arise that's
fine just acknowledge them without
judgment and return to the breath
for the first few minutes just lay or
sit in silence it's fine allow your body
and mind to enjoy the Deep state of
relaxation
let your body sink into the surface
beneath you you'll continue in this deep
relaxation State recharging your
dopamine until I say so
[Music]
foreign
you've done a body scan if I dressed
you're breathing and you've addressed
the voice in your mind your body and
mind and spirit are now at rest
and I am personally happy they have
taken the time to do this for your body
and mind
[Music]
stay in this deep state of relaxation
and I will wake you up when it's time to
go
[Music]
foreign
Awakening when you're ready gradually
bring your attention back to your
surroundings wiggle your toes your
fingers and gently open your eyes
remember this state of peace and
relaxation is always within your reach
even in the most busiest of days it
barely takes 20 minutes
thank yourself for taking this time for
your body I hope you find a deep sense
of calm and relaxation now you may
return to your day fully recharged and
ready for Conquest