your brain functions exactly like this
tub of water so everybody has a dopamine
level this is their Baseline dopamine
you see this water level right here
everybody has waves of dopamine this is
completely normal it's healthy and in
fact the waves in dopamine that's what
allows you to actually pursue goals in
life and even be happy from the goals
that you pursue however when you have a
massive shock like how por or any other
addiction can cause you some of the
water will Splash out of this tub and
actually decrease your dopamine Baseline
level that's why addicts of all kinds
are not only miserable and sad and
depressed but also they struggle with
any kind of goal Pursuit you've
literally depleted their happiness
molecule You' have literally depleted
the molecule which makes them actually
do anything that's why they're so
unproductive it's not that they're bad
people it's literally that their brain
has been damaged by the addiction of
course I keep on saying they but it's
not they it's us it's you and me we have
addictions of our own it's us who are
struggling with these things the
information which I'm going to give you
in this video will destroy any addiction
that you have permanently and if it
doesn't come back to this video and give
me a dislike that's how sure I am that
this video is going to change things for
you when your mind has a desire your
dopamine level is going to go up and
here's the interesting thing as soon as
it goes up is actually going to go down
below Baseline so this is your Baseline
Baseline of dopamine so when it goes
down when you have a valley that's
actually when you have an urge to move
or perform an action this is what most
people don't know it's actually the
valley which causes pain and causes you
to take action literally causes movement
when you are in a dopamine Valley your
body literally wants to move towards the
goal that you're thinking of so for
example example say here I think of ice
cream there's a place not too far from
here called Freddy's and they have
really really good soft serve ice cream
they serve it in a waffle cone with like
chocolate and everything and I like the
vanilla bean flavor a lot so even
thinking of that I have a little bit of
saliva forming in my mouth even though I
don't have any food near me that's the
power of our mind right I'm thinking of
that ice cream that's caused a spike in
my dopamine and then that Spike
immediately reverses and now I'm in a
valley a declined level of dopamine this
makes me want to go and acquire that ice
cream and if I did go get that ice cream
my dopamine would go again up to
Baseline and hit that Peak and then it
would fall again back to Baseline and I
can continue my day so this is me
actually acquiring
the ice cream and so what happens with
por or any addiction is the same thing
you still have the thought of por which
I'm just going to say p your dopamine is
going to go up and then fall down you're
going to be in pain this is going to be
your urge to actually go and watch
that's going to create you to actually
take action maybe pull out your phone
your laptop whatever it is and your
dopamine is going to go high but it's
not going to be like this is when you
when you watch p and you actually nut
that level of dopamine is going to be
massively high and when it crashes it
crashes all the way down and it doesn't
return to Baseline it stays low so
you're still stuck in this goal-seeking
mode so maybe you go and watch some
point again maybe you exceed Baseline
but then you're going to plummet even
lower and this time when you come up
your Baseline is even lower and then
you're still in pain you're still in the
goal-seeking mode and then you watch
again your dopamine sinks and your
Baseline is even lower now you're
absolutely [ __ ] cuz this is the kind
of dynamic which messes your prefrontal
CeX your brain is literally fried
because of this mechanism right here I'm
going to show you exactly the tools you
need to defeat this mechanism and break
the addiction forever now of course
self-control is important but let's put
the blame where it actually lies the POR
industry and the media literally know
how this system works and they have the
audacity to sit and cry about Mental
Health awareness week when they are the
ones who created the problem in the
first place the media not only
normalizes this filth but also
sexualizes every single damn thing think
about it like this 50 years ago the
media pushed cigarette smoking a lot of
young kids got into it like 15 14 13
year-old children got into it are you
going to blame these kids for getting
into smoking because they should have
had more self-control are you going to
put the blame are you going to put the
corps of these young people at the feet
of the media and the smoking companies
and the rotten scientists who propagated
incorrect sence saying that smoking was
correct these are the people who are to
blame not the people who are misled by
the media this is not about self-control
this is about using self-control to
defeat the psychological operation
that's being inflicted upon you for
example you might have heard this claim
that masturbation prevents prostate
cancer that's not true it's completely
BS so I've actually gone and read those
studies and it's very shoddy science
they use a bunch of surveys to come up
with this silly concept that it reduces
prostate cancer I don't trust it at all
imagine this there's only one or two
studies which even show this they're not
very good studies and media took these
two studies and then blew it up to the
point where almost everybody you ask
they think that masturbation is good for
you because it prevents prostate cancer
and it doesn't even factor into the
account nocturnal emissions so a healthy
human being a healthy human man if he
doesn't have sex and ejaculates he still
has a means to relieve that pressure the
body will literally ejaculate excess
semen at night when he's sleeping that's
completely healthy that's not Point
that's not masturbation but that's not
even a single factor in these studies
and the media still had the audacity to
go ahead and fill the minds of young men
to think that porn and masturbation is
actually good for them well it's
completely not the government should
have banned this Fil A long time ago
think about it the government's always
out to encroach upon your civil
liberties but no but PA is a free speech
issue we need to ban porn before the
Advent of AI generated porn and virtual
reality porn these two Ai and VR is
going to destroy it's going to destruct
the minds of young men and young women
if we are not careful about it you see
free speech is for the furthering of
political and scientific ideas which are
not commonly accepted P does not
contribute anything to science or
politics I don't know why it's
considered a free speech issue and then
of course I know what you're thinking
you're thinking well even if you ban
point it's not actually going to be
eliminated from the internet so what
think about this fenil and other harmful
drugs are banned that doesn't mean that
the these drugs Fentanyl and other drugs
are not available they have not
eliminated them but the band still is
effective in making it difficult to
access these drugs that's why we have
these banss in place we know the science
is very clear that porn is very very
detrimental to the health of young men
and women and yet for some reason it's
completely legal and even there's a
whole industry making money off this
filth if you have any pro porography
thoughts in your head I guarantee you
it's been implanted into you through a
psychological operation you must must
defeat the scop and when you do the buge
eyed mle men the snively bureaucrats and
the villainous media who think they run
this place they will fear you when you
open your eyes imagine a future in which
our children our sons and daughter live
in a world where porn is a thing of the
past and even whatever remnants of porn
still exist on the internet they can
just ignore it because their mental
health and spiritual health is so high
that to them it looks like absolute
filth which is exactly what it is they
will use use science observation their
own intuition and philosophy to find out
what is true and what is false this is
the vision I have for the future and you
shall see it pass this is a
multi-generational psychological war and
you are their worst nightmare po drugs
alcohol addictions cigarette addictions
and even social media addictions attack
the prefrontal cortex this is the center
of control in your brain this is
essentially the seat of stoicism in your
brain and that is what all these
addictions directly attack so think
about this everything you lose against
your addiction your prefrontal cortex
takes a hit and becomes weaker your
dopamine levels and lower Baseline which
makes you more susceptible to losing
again literally this stuff makes you a
loser at a molecular level now that you
understand the enemy I'm going to give
you the weapons to fight them so listen
closely this is the part which is going
to destroy your addictions permanently
so the example with the ice cream I gave
you earlier was a little bit simplistic
I'm going to go into finer details cuz
that's where you have leverage that's
where you can break the addiction so
we're starting off again we're just
going about our day and we think of the
ice cream all right we think about it we
don't actually acquire it this is
causing the spike in dopamine and like I
said is going to give you a fall in
dopamine and now of course when you
think of something and you get that urge
to get something you don't immediately
have it there's often a path of events
which you need to follow in order to get
it for example when I think of the ice
cream and I fall into this crash the
first thing I need to do is grab my car
keys so as soon as I grab my car keys I
have a little peak of dopamine that's
right and then I have another Valley of
dopamine so I'm actually deeper than I
was before and then I get into my car
that's another step towards the goal
right so I have another peak in dopamine
and another deeper Valley of dopamine
then I get to Freddy's which is the
place where I love getting their ice
cream when once I get there and see
their board I see another thir increase
in dopamine and another fall and then I
actually order the ice cream get another
Peak another fall I actually get the ice
cream another Peak another fall each
step of the way I'm getting into more
and more pain and see how far away I am
from my dopamine Baseline that is how
difficult the urge is to control
essentially that's how less resistance
you have basically speaking it's very
very difficult for me at this point to
not eat the ice cream it was easier back
back then when I just had the thought so
when I'm here and I finally get the ice
cream and I take my first Big Lick
massive massive spike in dopamine go all
the way past Baseline and then because
I'm not addicted to ice cream you know I
enjoy ice cream but I don't like go
crazy about ice cream with time I'll
just come back back to Baseline and I'll
be back to normal and that's the end of
the story for ice cream but it's
different for porn when it comes to porn
so I'm putting big p for for I get the
desire to watch it I have the spike I
have the decline and what do I do maybe
I pick up my laptop I get that little
Spike of dopamine and that sends me to a
new Valley maybe I open a browser new
Peak New Valley maybe I type ww. new
Peak New Valley maybe I type
www.p new Peak New Valley maybe I
finally go to the dreaded website and
then I have another Peak and another
Valley and what happens here is the
difference when you watch por and
literally nut that is the ultimate
dopamine release because in prehistoric
times that was a good thing you know you
want to impregnate a woman to further
your literal children further your
literal ancestry further your literal
lineage so of course you get a massive
surgeon dopamine far above anything
which ice cream can give you right so
instead of just stopping at the ice
cream Peak you actually go way way way
higher and then when you crash you crash
really bad and here's the difference
between like actual real sex with a
woman you love versus poor if you have
sex with an actual woman you love and
you ejaculate that's fine you'll come
back to Baseline because that was a
productive activity and your body knows
it with P you are obviously dissatisfied
with what you got that means when you
come back you're actually not at
Baseline you're below Baseline and now
you're in trouble cuz you're below
Baseline your brain is still thinking I
still haven't acquired the goal I still
haven't had the result which I desired
so what do you do you might actually
have a new urge that's right this is
where the problem starts you have a new
urge and a new Valley now what happens
you're in the goal Pursuit mode again
but this time it's worse because this
time you're at a lower Baseline than you
were before and now you're really now if
you have the same Cascade of events
you go down down down and then say you
watch Point again and you have a new
Peak this peak is going to be actually
lower than the previous Peak and this
time the valley is going to be even
deeper than the previous Valley ever was
and then you're again lower than
Baseline This Time by a huge margin and
then this of course will continue and
you're at this point cuz you're going to
go down this hill this is going to go
worse and worse and worse and every time
it happens going to be harder and harder
for you to resist the temptation now
your question should be how do you fix
it how do you break the addiction well
I'm going to show you right now so how
do you get rid of your porn addiction or
any addiction forever this is how you do
it so let's understand addiction again
so first you have an urge you get the
dopamine Spike you fall below Baseline
and then smaller Peaks happen as you get
closer and closer to the goal and you
have a massive Peak when you hit the
goal and because it's an addiction you
never really come back to Baseline and
you repeat this cycle again and again
until you basically ruin your life where
is this cycle the most vulnerable think
of that where is the cycle the most
vulnerable you don't really have any
control about when you get the urge
because you know your mind just throws
an urge at you and it's not in your
control you actually have the most
control in the first Peak this is where
you strike because think about it until
this point you don't really have any
control you cannot control what thought
comes into your head you can only
control what you do about those thoughts
so until here we have no control but we
do have our first line of control in the
first Valley so what is the first Valley
the first time you feel pain and you
have an an urge to move and perform an
action towards your goal that's when you
attack so when you have an urge to watch
and you have an urge to pick up your
phone that's when you strike or when you
have an urge to go go to your laptop
that's when you strike you literally say
with your mouth you say the word no you
say it with courage with boldness like a
military commander you say no you don't
have to yell it you don't have to
whisper it you just say no and you
shortcircuit it right in this spot when
you have the first incling of movement
or action towards that goal that's when
you destroy it you say no and you don't
take another step towards that goal
because if you take another step what
happens you go back into the spiral and
you're stuck in this spiral forever
right you Short Circuit the entire
mechanism by attacking it when you first
get a sensation towards action and what
happens if you break it right here what
happens if when you have an urge to pick
up your phone and go to the browser or
pick up your laptop and go to the
browser and you say no what happens then
if you take nothing else from this video
get this when you're in a valley if you
give it time you'll come back to
Baseline pretty quick in like 5 minutes
you'll come back to Baseline so when you
get the first urge to get your phone out
and you say no you literally have to say
the word no alloud so that you can hear
it because that signals to your brain
you hear the word no you hear a command
you giving yourself a command you give
the command no and you don't do anything
you literally stay sitting you don't do
anything you literally say no and just
stay put and don't do anything for 5
minutes if you do that your dopamine is
going to raise up back to Baseline and
then you're just back to Baseline you're
fine if you're at Baseline you're good
there's no urge at Baseline and then you
just continue at Baseline until another
thought comes into your head maybe you
know like in 5 hours or something
another time your brain is like hey hey
maybe you want to watch por and then you
get another Peak and you get another
Valley and again at that point when
you're picking up your phone you say no
and then you short circuit it again you
just return back to Baseline so you
don't have this Cascade effect you just
have a peak a valley and come back to
Baseline that's all that happens so if
you do this for long enough you just go
Peak Valley Baseline Peak Valley
Baseline you destroy your addiction you
straight up destroy your addiction for
the rest of your life because your brain
has learned your brain has learned that
this is not a reward worth seeking and
that's it you're done you'll never be
addicted to it another time in your life
ever again I've given you a semester's
worth of knowledge with regards to
dopamine circuitry how do you absorb
this information so it's not the value I
provide to you it's not the value I
provide it's the value you absorb you
need to absorb the stuff which I gave
you otherwise there's no point you
aren't going to actually implement it
this is what I want you to do I want you
to go to the comments and literally do a
homework assignment the homework for
today is think about the last time you
relapsed or last time you lapsed on
whatever addiction you have and I want
you to analyze the steps you took before
your addiction got the better of you in
the framework of this dopamine circuit
which I showed you and analyze what was
happening so literally I want you to
write a paragraph saying step by step
what was going in your in your mind what
you physically performed and what was
going on with regards to dopamine and I
I will go ahead and grade you I will
come to the comment section and grade
your homework if you do this I guarantee
you you've understood this concept well
enough that the next time a urge hits
you you have the upper hand you can
attack where it is weak and that is how
you defeat addiction forever if you do
everything I told you and you still go
back and watch then I want you to come
back and do this give me a dislike give
me a dislike and then in the comments
write down how you fail like exactly
autistic level detail how you failed so
that others May learn from your mistake
and understand this the dopamine circuit
is not a bad thing the dopamine circuit
is actually the best part of your brain
it's the it's a center of motivation the
center of happiness and this is what
actually gives you massive success and
happiness in life this is the circuit
which they literally hijack and ruin
your life the dopamine system is
actually a learning system so imagine
this you're back in caveman days and
you're feeling hungry you have a spike
in dopamine and then you have a dip in
dopamine what do you do then you go
outside the comfort of your Village and
you see that there's deer dropping so
you see deer tracks that gives you a
small spike in dopamine and then you
have a deeper Valley maybe you see the
the leaves rustling or the grass is
moving another a spike because you think
maybe the deer is there and then you
have another a deeper Valley now you're
getting anxious you're getting pain you
want to hunt that deer right then you
pull out your bow you're aiming at what
you think is the deer you have another
Peak cuz you're thinking you're going to
succeed and then you have another Valley
and then you see it you see the deer and
you let the arrow go and the bolt gets
it right in the neck success that's a
peak and a valley then you go and
confirm that you got the deer and then
you take it back to your village massive
massive success massive release of
dopamine all your brothers are you know
patting you in the back great hunt great
job all the women in the village are
like oh that's a good Hunter maybe I
need to date him and then of course the
village Elders are like okay good good
good job like you're a young guy but you
succeeded in the hunt congratulations
and then what happens you get the
success uccess your reputation has
increased your essentially your wealth
in the village has increased and then
because it's an Adaptive experience
you'll return to Baseline nice and slow
you'll come back to Baseline and then
maybe this time your Baseline is
actually a bit higher than it was before
so instead of the effect where you have
a lower Baseline than before maybe this
time you're actually higher and the next
time you do this you actually better
maybe you don't have to go through every
single step to get the deer next time
you see the wrestling boom you got the
deer that way you're actually increasing
your Baseline every time you hunt and
get better and better at hunting that's
how you learn and perfect a skill your
dopamine circuit actually helps you
perfect skills but nowadays what happens
nowadays what happens is you get your
phone you see some dumb B to working on
Tik Tok and you have an urge you go to
porub you freaking what's some and then
your dopamine drops and then you do that
again your dopamine drops again and
again until you're completely brain dead
your prefrontal cortex is fried you're
basically lobotomized slave you're
basically a cator this is the mental
prison which they've built for you and
think about it like this if you were a
prison Warden and the inmates were
getting a bit unrestful you know they're
getting a little bit Rowdy right what
would you do you cannot just use
violence because if you and like the 10
other guards you have go out and try to
fight the inmates you'd lose because
there's like 10,000 of them what you
might want to do instead is resort to
chemical and psychological warfare maybe
first you destroy the inmates dopamine
systems using psychology and maybe then
you prescribe to them anti-depressants
and mess up their circuitry forever and
then maybe you make money selling them
anti-depressants which don't fix the
cause of the depression they only mask
the symptoms there are quite a few
tactics and weapons in the bag of
chemical and psychological warfare but
you have some weapons too literally the
sun is your ally in my esoteric sleep
guide I I briefly talk about how the Sun
boosts your dopamine levels but now you
have a pretty good understanding of the
dopamine circuitry so what the sun does
is actually very very remarkable when
you get out in the morning this is
especially effective in the morning you
wake up obviously you brush your teeth
drink your electrolytes go to the
bathroom and then what you do step out
into the sun expose your eyes and skin
towards the Sun not necessarily looking
at the sun just towards the Sun and this
is going to recharge your dopamine if
you get good sleep that's already a
powerful dopamine recharge but then you
look at the Sun and your dopamine level
your Baseline dopamine level is at a
whole new level and you a different
person than you were the previous day
and not only that when you get out into
the Sun that literally stimulates your
pineal gland which is the center of
sexual energy for any man or woman for
that matter if you take nothing else
from this video understand how to break
your addictions and then go out into the
sun that's all I have to ask you that's
literally all I have to ask you are
there any supplements you can take to
fix your dopamine system absolutely not
there are fools out there prescribing
supplements to fix your dopamine systems
don't do it because you don't want
another dependency when you're trying to
fix your dopamine instead invest some
time in ex exercise literally resistance
training or cardiovascular exercise is
going to up your Baseline dopamine I'm
not talking about Peaks and troughs I'm
talking about literally increase in your
Baseline and the higher you can get your
Baseline man the more success you're
going to have literally success in
literally everything business money
women whatever you want it comes from
your Baseline dopamine and what's
another way cold showers do actually
work they do generally increase dopamine
for about 6 hours it's not like a
permanent increase in dopamine but you
know 6 hours is not bad like you have 6
hours of extremely productive time after
your C shower in the morning just to
drill this into your head how do you
break an addiction you break the
addiction as soon as you feel an urge to
move and act towards that goal which
could be smoking a cigarette could be
drinking alcohol could be watching porn
could be any number of things as soon
soon as you feel an urge to move and
perform an action you literally say no
you say the word no nice and loud and
firm and clear and then you just sit
down or you just continue doing
something else you literally do not
entertain the slightest movement or
slightest action towards that goal and
you will come back to Baseline and do
this three or four times five or six
times seven or eight times how many
times it takes and your addiction
literally your brain chemistry and
rewiring is going to change and you'll
never be addicted to that substance
again do you want to be a part of my
conspiracy here's what I want you to do
hit that share button but don't
necessarily share it with anybody if you
want to that's fine but what you do is
you copy the link which you get from the
share button just copy it because
YouTube doesn't know whether you shared
it with somebody or not YouTube just
thinks that you have shared this video
that think that makes YouTube think that
this is a banger video and that means
it's going to shove this video into the
faces of other men just like you and I
know that this video is going to destroy
their po addiction as well this is how
I'm waging psychological warfare back on
them and you can help me by doing this
and I will end with a visualization just
close your eyes and hear these words you
are their worst nightmare imagine a
legion of men resistant to psychological
operations and completely maxed out on
on their testosterone such a force
cannot be reasoned with cannot be
bargained with or defeated you are the
Vanguard you are working on your dream
project but it's difficult you don't
know how to proceed you're at a bit of a
dead end you have some kind of knowledge
Gap you don't know how to navigate and
you feel a sensation that you haven't
felt in a while a base desire for
instant gratification you've not watched
porn in months and haven't thought about
it in weeks it wouldn't hurt right it
wouldn't hurt to take a quick break
surely in fact it might make you even
more productive right you feel a
sensation to move your mouse cursor
towards the browser tab but before even
a single millimeter of movement a sound
escapes your mouth almost involuntarily
a single syllable crisp and clear
leaving no doubt as to its meaning no no
you do not yield you do not break you do
not move the dopamine death spiral that
used to rule your life life is weaker it
grows weaker every time you refuse to
feed it it is not dead yet and will try
again to ins snare you but your dreams
are too important and you spit in its
face you are finished with such
trivialities you have a legacy to build
discipline is