me quite a few times why I join the Army
if I'm so against big government well
easy answer to that is have you heard
this phrase when a girl
says um you know when a girl's in Rock
Bottom she'll say f it I'll be a hooker
when a guy hits Rock Bottom he says f it
I'll join the Army it's an old joke but
it's true so what happened was I had
just finished well I was in the PHD
program and I
had found out that the PhD wasn't for me
and this was very disappointing to my
parents I disappointed my parents twice
in a row so what happened was I was
during my PhD program I realized that
what I was doing it for was for that
steady paycheck and for the status that
it conveyed if you were a university
Professor you would have status you
would have a steady paycheck I would
have made my parents proud if you know
anything about Asian parenting it's a
lot of comparison like oh your kid did
this you know my kid actually did this
my kid Works in Microsoft my kid Works
in Amazon and when I told my parents
like I didn't want to be a professor I
didn't want to do a science job that was
a second blow to them the first time I
was like I don't want to be an engineer
second time I was like I don't even want
to be a scientist and I dropped out of
the PHD
program and what I found was I didn't
know what to do I was looking for
Brotherhood I was looking for meaning I
was looking for purpose I wanted to
belong to something greater I wanted to
have a greater
purpose and
I looked at the options that I had I was
like you know soldiers get a lot of
respect they're not the highest paid but
they get a lot of
respect they get a lot of status and I
always love the idea of surgery because
I'm very much into military history I
like you know I could do this I'm
physically strong enough to be a soldier
I can surely track the code and I signed
up I enlisted and you know what it
actually worked it's the thing for the
first three months of training I loved
it I genuinely enjoyed basic training
which is a weird thing to say for
anybody who has been through that I
genuinely enjoyed the first three months
CU I actually had status I had status
because I was one of the older guys in
my platoon and a platoon is 50 soldiers
more or less I had status in my platoon
and I had status because I was a little
bit older I had more you know Real World
experience as it was and I kind of knew
what was going on and I was like a solid
you know four years older so of course I
had a bit of respect right even the
drills like the drill sergeant even they
treated me a little bit differently than
the average 17y old 18yar old who was
trying to
enlist and I let it get into my head I
wanted to be a leader and I was I was
actually good at that job I was able to
control and command and lead from the
front and I remember this with extreme
detail there was a obstacle course so of
course there was an obstacle course
right so they divided the platoon into
two halves and the side of them who got
me they rejoiced and the side who didn't
get me they were in despair because I
was seen as an asset literally the guys
wanted my presence there not because I
was the fastest or strongest or biggest
or the meanest but because they knew
that I could lead them to Victory and I
did I loved it man I had status I had
respect of my peers and it was going
great and I wanted the PG position so PG
is Platoon guide it's just a fake
position to be honest it's basically
you're the leader of the platoon for the
duration of training and the drill
sergeant appointed me as a PG about 3
months in that's exactly what I wanted I
made the wow to make my platoon the best
performing platoon in the entire company
company is for platoon
usually and on the same day that I got
appointed PG Platoon guide I was fired
from the job for the stupidest reason I
I don't remember what it was I think
like my flag patch was like slightly
crooked or something stupid like that
and I was fired from the position that I
had worked so hard to get and I had so
many Big Dreams
for I resented that genuinely I resented
that I I hated the arbitrariness of the
army so much and you know that wore off
after a couple days but I had to look at
the Army's training protocol in more
detail and I realized it was a terrible
protocol the Army does not want Warriors
doesn't want to train Knights doesn't
want to train leaders because if you
wanted that kind of system what you
would do is You' have a caraan stick
type system right you would incentivize
good behavior and you would punish bad
behavior that's not what happens in Army
basic training what happens is arbitrary
punishment you do the right thing get
punished you do the wrong thing you get
punished you don't do anything anything
you get punished you try to put your
best foot forward you get punished there
is no Rhyme or Reason it's just the
whims of the drill sergeant who's in
charge on that day and I realized this
is not a mistake this is by Design This
is not a bug in the system this is the
feature because the US doesn't want
Warriors they want peasant soldiers they
want mindless ctors who would just do
their bidding and fight Banker Wars and
bleed for the Saudis they don't want the
soldiers to think for thems they don't
want to have incentives for
self-improvement they just
want punishment given arbitrarily to
break the Mind down such that it's just
Mindless obedience that's what they
really want and I realized this I was
like God damn it I signed a contract now
I'm stuck in
this and you know I had joined the army
for many good many good reasons but I
had joined the it also for the sense of
Duty Brotherhood you know
masculinity and truly a bit of status
and I didn't have any of those
things I like did I just make the worst
mistake of my life but it wasn't all bad
wasn't all bad it's because of
this had these little notebooks not
exactly this one but it looked kind of
like that it's these waterproof
notebooks called right in the rain
notebooks anybody in the military knows
exactly what I'm talking about these are
notebooks which are waterproof so you
can write in them even if it's like
pouring outside so these little
notebooks I carried them everywhere I
went and if you know anything about the
military there's this concept called
hurry up and wait the idea is man it's
annoying as hell the idea is there's
periods of intense activity where it's
go go go there's periods of absolute
boredom where they're given no commands
and you don't know what to do you're
just sitting there most people wasted
that time but not me I use that time I
was journaling I was writing I didn't
know how to journal at the time it's a
skill that you can Master but I didn't
do that right but I had time on my side
I had 8 months of absolute monk mode on
my side nobody has this luxury but I had
this luxury I had eight months of my
life where I had zero internet zero
Instagram Zero YouTube zero Tik Tok zero
anything I didn't have the news I didn't
have the phone call to call anybody
including my parents I didn't have any
kind of internet and
complete isolation right only thing I
was allowed to have was one religious
text I chose the bhagwad Gita to take
with me which is an ancient religious
text and of course other guys had Bibles
I borrowed their Bible there are some
guys with Quran I borrowed the Quran as
well and what I learned was you must
find your duty and do that Duty and
Destiny takes care of itself and it's
written in different ways but all the
religious text have this message I was
like okay fine that's well and good but
how do you find your duty how do you you
find your purpose and that brings us to
the topic of today the LSD method which
I shall instruct to you which is the
literal method which I used while in
training to figure out my purpose and
really when I came back out of training
that was my comeback you know till then
I was I was stalled I did my engineering
degree didn't go anywhere I didn't want
to be an engineer started my bio Master
bio PhD actually and that didn't go
anywhere got a masters and you can't do
really anything with the biom Masters
biop PhD is prestigious right but biom
Masters like you can be a community
college
professor what is that pay no
status who wants that right what my
thing so until that point it was just a
bunch of false starts and stops and
failures I'll call them that I'll call
them failures but not after that you
know after I got done with training it
was different life and I'm going to show
you this exact method find your purpose
find your duty after that you cannot
fail because even if you're failing at
your duty but you're making the attempt
that's still a success it's only a
failure when you're doing the wrong
thing even if you do the wrong thing
well it's still the wrong thing so what
happened exactly in my story so I was in
basic training I was you know
disappointed in my ability to be a
leader I was kicked out of that position
and I had to be sat there contemplating
what to do how to improve because I knew
that if if I at the end of basic
training I didn't have a vision for
myself then I would be in the same exact
position as before I joined no vision no
Direction
nothing so I started journaling with a
specific intent of making my vision my
dream future that's how I came up with
that 9f framework so you might have seen
that video the 9f framework is the best
Vision framework to create a high
definition image of what you want the
future to look like such that you
actually achieve it so if you haven't
watched that video it's a requirement go
and check out the 9f framework video
it's
entitled I don't know I'll put in the
description right so it's basically a
video which Paints the picture of what
you want your life to look like and
after doing that framework I was like
you know Army is never going to get me
there it's not Army is not about freedom
and time Freedom Travel Freedom it's not
about abundance of money it's about
obedience and that wasn't
me so I realized my path was going to be
different I had to do something
different I wanted to
create something create products sell
useful products and make a difference in
people's lives I realized this but I
didn't really know how to do it but
that's the good thing about this method
is you don't have to be perfect in
finding your duty and your purpose you
could be kind of right and you can
course correct to eventually find that
thing which is correct perfect for you
so once I got done with basic training I
created my first business it's not this
business and I'll talk about that later
I'll give you first the actionable STP
the straight up exact actionable steps
and the protocol which is the
LSD method so this is a 3-we framework
all right L is week one s week 2 and D
is week three L stands for listen so who
are you listening to you are
listening for divine inspiration you are
listening for divine inspiration but the
problem is your mind is blocked your
mind is blocked by conditioning and
there are three kinds of conditioning
the first is Parental conditioning I've
talked about this a little bit before my
parents vision for me was to be an
engineer their Vision was so powerful
and so real in their hearts and Minds
that I absorbed it I didn't even think
twice I didn't have
to but it wasn't the vision for me it
wasn't the vision for me so at some
point I had to have that difficult
conversation be like hey Mom I don't
want to do this this is not my thing Hey
Dad I can't I don't want to this is not
my destiny and I want you to have this
difficult conversation especially if you
are from any kind of Asian household you
probably have a strong bit of Parental
conditioning I want you to have the
difficult conversation before you have
to have it right at some point you're
going to break and you're going to be
like I need to have the conversation
right now don't wait for that go and
have that conversation as soon as you
can to chart your path for the future
tell them that their vision for you is
not your vision for you and that you
have to go your own way the second kind
of conditioning is social conditioning
and what's going on here
is depending on your race or gender
there are expectations placed on you if
you are brown expect you to work in like
Microsoft or Amazon Google or if you're
lower income gas station right gas
station is the
common
stereotype or they have other
expectation if you are white they'll say
you're privileged anything you achieve
is because of systemic injustices on
other races you're privileged if you're
black they'll say oh you poor oppressed
Soul we have to coddle you and and we
have to give you all this free stuff
that's the only way you're going to
succeed there's no opportunity for you
if you're women they'll say Hey you have
to be a girl boss you know you have to
make six figures if you want to be a mom
you're being oppressed you're being
brainwashed by your husband imagine
you're a woman all right you're a girl
and in your heart you want to have kids
you want to be a
wife if you try to do that you'll be
ridiculed for that and I have a lot of
compassion for women in our society
all these stupid stupid podcasts try to
antagonize men versus women women are
and men are this and that's not
true most women have a duty and a
purpose just like you and I but they're
even more brainwashed even more
societally conditioned than we are it's
actually harder for them to find their
purpose than it is for us so I have a
deep well of empathy for all women
either in my life or just strangers I
encourage you to see it from their point
of view as well
at least for us as men you know money
status property that's what Society
wants us to get and that's kind of what
we want anyway so at least there's
some Parallels for women it's the
opposite what they truly want and what
Society wants them to want are going in
opposite directions it's worse for them
than it is for us that's two kinds of
conditioning there's another one but
before that I want to talk about how you
can destroy this conditioning and this
is the part of the contemplative walk so
gentlemen of older times they had this
habit of going on leisurely strolls in
the park all right it wasn't for cardio
wasn't for exercise wasn't for Fitness
it was for the mind it was
cognition I want you to be outside if
possible if it's too cold then I
understand you can walk inside indoors
instead you can pace around your room
you can pace around your hall when you
are walking especially in nature when
you don't have an agenda in mind you you
don't have your phone on you you just
have a notebook and a pencil you are
going to be receptive to divine
inspiration also you're going to be
receptive to the conditioning the
aspects of your conditioning are going
to pop out at you and that's when you
can confront them and you can trace them
back to how you got that thought or that
conditioning and when you trace it back
that's how you destroy it if you have a
limiting belief of you know I'm ugly I
can't get GRS all right you have that
belief creat it back so like oh that one
girl in like sixth grade she said
something funny about my face and that's
the reason I have this insecurity
destroyed right contemplative walks is
for contemplation you are going about
your stroll without an agenda in mind
specifically so that when thoughts come
up you are able to address them as a
mature
adult the Third Kind of conditioning is
chemical conditioning and you are not
going to be able to solve this with
contemplative walks chemical
conditioning is the effect of parasites
emfs of course estrogenics on the human
nervous system you know there's a study
which shows
that as testosterone levels increase in
men their political beliefs change how
bizarre is that why should
political inclinations have anything to
do with a hormone in the body what's
going on over there is the way your
hormones interact with your brain
determines your Big Five personality
traits and your Big Five personality
traits have a huge impact on what your
self-perception is and that has a huge
impact on what your political leaning is
but also just in general what you think
you're going to be successful at so now
that's a big topic onto itself like how
do you avoid estrogenics and everything
so I will keep that topic aside for a
later
lecture but just make sure you're
cognizant of that aspect
once you do that that's the week one
that's the homework for week one
basically and then you go onto week two
which is search so when you're in the
search phase which is week two you are
going to actively be Plumbing the depths
of your mind to find out your core
memories I want you to ask the question
when you are left unsupervised as a kid
what is it that you spent your time on
for me answer is easy reading I loved
reading then I loved stories I loved
learning new words I enjoyed the art of
reading I read anything Science History
I I wouldn't even understand it half the
time right I was a kid but I would read
it for the pleasure of reading and
different kids have different
inclinations some love to draw some love
music some like to run around for no
godamn reason they just like to run the
reason I bring that up is because I'm
going to share with you the five types
six types of intelligence and you're
going to be able to relate your core
memories as a child with what kind of
intelligence you have and that's going
to give you a hint as to what your duty
might be the five kinds of intelligence
first one is linguistic or word-based
intelligence that's me I have a
word-based intelligence I am good with
words either speaking them or writing
them reading them that's my thing and a
example of a Duty for people with a
linguistic intelligence would be
something like I want to write
life-changing essays which improve
people's Soul an example of somebody in
the public domain who has a linguistic
based intelligence is Jordan Peterson
very good with
words another type of intelligence is
logical and mathematical
reasoning this I have it to some extent
but it's not really my main form of
intelligence so logical and mathematical
reasoning an example of a Duty for this
kind of person would be I want to solve
challenging mathematical problems to
improve the advanced ment of science and
technology that could be a possible Duty
for that kind of person example of
somebody in the public space doing
this Ben Shapiro to be honest I don't
like him I don't like his message I
think he's regardless he is good at
logic though he's very good at taking an
argument breaking down into competent
parts and disproving them that's his
whole thing so that's an example
of logical or mathematical reasoning
another type of intelligence is musical
and for example we have people whose
duty is
to improve the human soul or Elevate the
human soul using Music These are people
who get Melody tune Harmony this is not
me at all like I'm not that skilled at
music can't keep a beat for to save my
life right it's not my thing but it
might be for you another type of
intelligence
is spatial Visual and
spatial visual spatial intelligence is
basically when you can take a 3D object
and you can manipulate it in 3D space an
application of this is like fighter
pilots when a fighter pilot is flying
his plane he needs to have a
threedimensional
understanding of of the space otherwise
going to get killed that is one example
Joo willing has extreme spatial
intelligence he was a a Navy SEAL
operator right so you need to know you
know where your fire team is in real
time in 3D space that's visual
intelligence so find out which kind of
intelligence you have and that's going
to give you a hint as to what kind of
Duty you might be given because
everybody has a different type of
intelligence and they're uniquely suited
to doing one job better than everybody
else to find that it helpful to know
what kind of intelligence you do have
all right so that's your search phase
once you've destroyed your conditioning
you're going to go and search for your
duty your meaning in life and that's
your week two main task once you are
done with that you're going to go on to
week three and of course I forgot to
mention one of the most important types
of intelligence is social intelligence
and a great example of this is
Hamza so an example of a purpose you can
have if you have social intelligence
is I want to end men's addictions with
pornography by having empathy and
understanding of their condition Hamza
has this and even though it may not seem
like the most monetizable form of
intelligence you know clearly it hasn't
stopped him so any kind of intelligence
that you have can lead to amazing
results so long as you give it the
chance and you actually apply yourself
to your duty apply yourself to your duty
and Destiny takes care of itself then we
move on to the third week which is do so
you found what potential purpose you
could have you have to actually execute
it for a week to get feedback from real
life so here's the thing if you're 18 to
25 man you're young bro you're in the
search phase like your job in life is to
find out what your job in life is you
know your purpose is to find your
purpose 18 to 25 don't sweat it be
receptive be understanding that you are
going to find your purpose and you are
going to solve this problem for yourself
all right so don't be stressed allow
inspiration to find you where when
you're in the DU phase you are actually
taking action if you chosen
entrepreneurship of any kind to be your
vocation that's what you want to do cool
if you have chosen entrepreneurship
solve a problem that you have in real
life could be something dumb the first
business I started was a robe business
you know how like Hamza wears bath robes
right so this was before
Hamza my first business so the problem
which I was having was I would I would
like wearing robes in Winter I thought
there really cozy really comfortable
enjoyed them
right but when you try to go and do
dishes or something the sleeves always
get wet and if you're too warm you can't
really roll up the sleeves of your robe
because they'll just flop down so I was
like you know what if I had a robe which
I had a a loop and a button I just pull
the sleeve up and then Loop and button
it in place so that it stays up and you
have a sleeveless
robe not a great Innovation right but I
was like you know I really want this
product and I made the product it was
kind of a product cuz I just got it
you know cheaply made in China it was
completely 100% polyester so I didn't
even use it myself wasn't the product
which I envisioned but all that I could
afford so when I got done with Army
basic training I had a bonus the Army
gives you a bonus so I had 16,000 cuz
it's actually a $220,000 bonus but they
taxed it to bits and it's just 16,000
did you get in your hand and I took
5,000 off that I was like I with this
$5,000 I will either transform it into
$50,000 or I will burn it
completely and I burnt it that business
was a flop all right didn't go anywhere
I ran Facebook ads I ran Instagram ads I
made sales on Shopify and when you get
that first ding on Shopify as a
notification that somebody bought your
stuff man it's a dopamine Rush unlike
anything else so I was selling these
things and then of course Co happened so
the shipping times expanded from 3 weeks
to like 3 months so that in itself was a
death blow to my business but another
thing happened the iOS update so anybody
who's listening who has an Ecom business
probably had PTSD flashbacks from the
iOS update so in one day the ad costs
went like 3x or 4X because of this
update and yeah business freaking died
all right died I didn't lose money but I
didn't like at the end I didn't have any
to show for it right I didn't have
product I didn't have money
it a dead business but I loved it I
wouldn't change a thing about it the
things I learned making that business
showed me something about myself I enjoy
creation I enjoy creating products I
enjoy marketing them and that's what set
me up gave me the confidence to actually
create this content so so long as you're
in the right direction of your duty
you're always winning there's no way to
lose cuz if you lose it's just data that
you can use for the next win so that's
why finding a purpose is that important
you stop losing once you find
it then of course I start the YouTube
channel KCC which is my private
Community launched to $30,000 in profit
in the first month of creation
so all that came from those difficult
months in Army basic training you don't
have to join the Army in order to find
your purpose I've given you the exact
system which I had to learn through that
challenge through that struggle through
being the wrong place the wrong
time with those struggles which I had to
deal with you don't have to do any of
that I'm giving you the wisdom free of
cost but even so once you complete these
three weeks of finding your purpose you
have begun to execute that's week three
you begun to execute on what you think
your purposes so in your search phase
you might come up with two or three
things which you think is your purpose
in week three you choose one of them and
proceed with it if you don't like it you
have to give it 21 days all right 21
days to make your decision as to whether
you're going to pursue this thing or not
for example this live streaming I don't
know if it's going to succeed I have no
way of knowing but I'm going to do it at
least for 21 days right at the end of 21
days I'll have the actual data do I like
it do I enjoy it do I wake up in the
morning excited to do this and of course
the audience reception that's important
too I'll only learn this if I do 21 days
off it so that's your du phase it could
be 2 3 weeks could be more if you decide
that you haven't found the right thing
that's not your purpose that's not your
duty that's fine just repeat listen
search and do again and you do this
again and again until you find something
that's actually clicking with you
because For the First Time in human
history you have the permission to do
what you want you have the permission to
do as you please and make money doing it
so if your talent you know your duty
your mission was to prepare the best
food ever you want to be a cook you want
to be a chef you want to be an artist in
the realm of culinary
Cuisine you don't have to go you don't
have to go to Color inary school you
don't you can make a business around
making food from the comfort of your
home Tik Tok Instagram or blogs there's
a million ways to monetize your talents
from home if you so choose all right
that's you have the freedom in most of
human history you couldn't really do
what you wanted cuz if you didn't work
in the factory like your family would
starve right it's not the case anymore
you have a limited window of unlimited
opportunity which you must use at
present today is the 31st of
January in
Hawaii it's the starting of the Year
2024 is about to begin you have 365 days
in that year Well actually 366 I believe
because it's a leap
year you 12 months in that year I want
you to sacrifice well not even sacrifice
but utilize 3 weeks off that year which
has 52 weeks in all to really dig into
this method I want you to listen for
divine inspiration I want you to search
your childhood memories for the kind of
intelligence that you have from that I
want you to create three to five
different different purposes or duties
that you think you might have and then I
want you to execute on one of them to
see if it's the right one if it's not
that's fine you move on and you repeat
the cycle again and you try different
things until you find your thing I said
before that 18 to 25 is the search phase
you have unlimited opportunity to search
for the right thing even if you're older
doesn't matter it's never too late to
find out what your purpose is in fact
I'd go so far as to say the older you
are the more important it is to find
your duty because you have less time to
fulfill it now all right kind of morbid
but that's the case if you're older and
you're watching this is more important
than if you're younger that's the
hardcore truth of it you have less time
you don't have much time left bro all
right next
thing there's a concept of resistance
all right this is a concept which I
haven't really discussed much it's a
concept which I came across in the war
of art by Steven pressfield which is a
book that we as a collective in col's
country club we read this and the idea
behind behind this book is there's a
force called resistance there is the
divine inspiration which pulls you
forward to your destiny to your duty
there's an opposing Force called
resistance which wants to thwart you
wants to stop you wants to push you away
from your
duty and you know you can use that to
your advantage how it's because
resistance only appears when you are
trying to pursue something that actually
matters to you if you don't actually
care about something there's going to be
no resistance for example Le if you're
trying
to work in a coding job because you want
to have money resistance will give you a
free pass you won't feel any kind of
compulsion to not do it you'll be bribed
into doing it that was me I wouldn't
feel a lot of resistance doing
Engineering in the first few years
because I was just going with the flow I
was just doing what my parents told me
resistance occurs when you're doing
something which you actually called to
do for example
starting on YouTube I wanted to do this
for years and I was working with Hamza
right I realized he was following his
purpose and making a beautiful business
for himself and I could surely do the
same but took me a year or so since then
to actually get started why because of
resistance the resistance was telling me
that my parents will you know watch
these videos and they'll say something
about it my friends from high school or
friends from college are going to know
that you're on YouTube and that put me
off for the longest time so what made me
change that is because I realized that
the performance of your duty overrides
everything for two reasons first is when
you're following your duty and you're
doing the thing which gives you purpose
you're going to be the best at it and
it's likely that you're going to make
more money in a month than they make in
a year following something which is not
their purpose and the second piece of
this is of course a deeper reason when
you're fulfilling your purpose purpose
you're doing your duty on a day-to-day
basis doesn't really matter doesn't it
doesn't sting you the resistance happens
before you make the plunge after you
take the plunge there's no more
resistance because you've crossed the
Threshold at this point I'm not afraid
of anybody stumbling across my YouTube
channel even if they know me from like
childhood or something I don't care if
they have something to say about it
doesn't matter to me I'll make more than
them I'll live a more fulfilled life I'm
more freedom than then I can do what I
please it's my duty and my destiny it's
not anybody concerned apart from mine
all right so I want you to have that
kind of mindset do your duty at the cost
of anything and anybody all right your
duty comes first
the other thing which I wanted to
mention is the idea of
self-perception all right there's this
idea that success is a lag indicator of
self-image that is to say your
self-image is always going to lead your
success so if your self-image is behind
your success you're going to fail so the
question is how do you improve your
self-image it's a good it's a good
question the answer is you brainwash
yourself and I've been brainwashing
myself I've been reading this book
called psycho cybernetics and I've been
incorporating those techniques into my
daily life in order to be able to do
this very live lecture I've also use the
method of Mind rehearsals to try to do
these things so I had this limiting
belief that I needed editing right I
needed editing I needed to make a couple
edits for the videos worth watching and
I had this limiting belief that I would
have to say a sentence three or four
times to get it right and then chop out
all the bad takes and then I would have
a good video but when you're on live
call like this you don't have that
luxury I'm doing YouTube on hard mode
right now there is no background music
in order to boost average view duration
there's no cool little AI images to hit
you with dopamine in order to make you
stay the only thing I have right now is
my presence whatever Charisma that I can
muster my storytelling skills and of
course the content and the value that
I'm providing in the video if any of
these core things are failing then I'm
not going to get the viewership that I
want it's literally that simple there's
no crutch that I can rely on and I had
this limiting belief that you know it's
not for me guys like Hamza he can talk
for like 3 4 hours and he still makes
sense he's still coherent he's still you
know making a good video like you know I
couldn't do that I couldn't do that but
I started to brainwash myself into the
version that I will manifest into in 3
years time so I I visualize what I would
be like in 3 years when I've already
done a whole bunch of live streams so
what's going on is let's say live
streaming or even speaking in public
right because this is public speaking I
am speaking in front of at least 10 10
people surely
so I have a certain skill level at
public speaking all right and that skill
level might be a six out of 10 but the
future version of me is going to have a
skill level of nine out of 10 if I
visualize and act as though I am that
person then my 6 out of 10 becomes seven
out of 10 why is that it's because I'm
more receptive more relaxed I am more at
ease with myself I'm okay with making
mistakes why because if I believe myself
to be a 9 out of 10 public speaker I
know I have the fundamentals I know I
have the skills if I mess up it's just a
one-off occurrence it's not going to
break my flow it's not going to impede
on my ability to
speak believing myself to be a 9 out of
10 speaker makes me a seven out of 10
speaker rather than a six but now the
question is like how do you actually
brainwash yourself what's the exact
actionable step autistic level detail
and that is going to be the topic of
tomorrow's video I'm going to make a
video tomorrow exactly same time it's
going to be live streamed it's also
going to be available as a recording of
how to brainwash yourself for success in
2024 so here's the thing I'm aware that
I'm making mistakes in this call which
is fine I'm 100% okay with it it's
literally my second attempt I'm not
going to give myself a hard time about
it because I feel like or I am embodying
the spirit of a nine out of 10 speaker a
nine out of 10 speaker isn't thrown off
by one word misspoken or one story which
didn't hit the point as hard as it
should doesn't matter n out of 10
speaker has that kind of confidence so
tomorrow I'm going to teach you how to
brainwash yourself for success of course
it doesn't have to be public speaking it
could be literally anything I don't know
playing the guitar talking to women so
brainwashing yourself is the elite
technique on how to talk to
women without these thoughts these
nagging thoughts which sabotage you but
of course you know that's tomorrow's
topic so let's not get into it too
deeply today today I have homework for
you so you think these lectures are free
no sir I demand a fee I demand a fee for
these lectures that fee is the homework
which I'm going to give you right now I
want you to go for a contemplative walk
like I described earlier in this lecture
I want you to go for a contemplative
walk ideally it's outdoors but of course
not everybody has a luxury of living in
beautiful Hawaii like I do so I
understand it may not be possible but go
for a walk inside your own room
literally Pace in your own room and I
want you to have zero distractions no
phone no Internet your computer switched
off your phone Switched Off you have
something to write with you have your
pencil and your paper and you're going
to write down any thoughts which come to
you if they're negative thoughts they're
limiting beliefs I want you to trace
back where they came from so that you
can destroy them and if if if you feel
the divine inspiration then that is a
blessing take it
seriously write down that feeling of
divine inspiration you might just get an
idea just out of the blue like a
lightning bolt it's just going to shock
you it's going to be like damn that's a
good idea I can do that I can succeed at
that write that down as well I want you
to do that homework and this is what
you're going to report to me if you're
in colle Country Club you've already
joined you've already paid you're a
you're member right I know you in that
case I want you to go to the challenges
section and write down what your thought
was could be a negative thought that you
destroyed or it could be a positive
thought from divine inspiration and you
write it down I'll come in there give
you feedback if it's relevant all right
if you are not in my private Community
it's fine do the same exact homework but
in the comment section when I upload
this record this live stream as a
recording that is your homework for
today tomorrow's lecture is going to be
how to brainwash yourself for success in
2024 and if you missed yesterday's
lecture that was a lecture on how to
master any skill I have a system called
the magic hourglass method teaches you
how to master literally anything so once
you you have your purpose good how do
you actually get good at that purpose
right for for for that content
yesterday's lecture I'll have the tile
pop up for that tomorrow's lecture is
how to brainwash yourself so the idea
behind these lecture videos is basically
give you a tool set a tool kit
of success in general right I'll of
course go doing lectures on health I'll
do stuff on supplements I'll do stuff on
nutrition as well but all that is
peripheral to the Core
importance of Duty and purpose so I'm
going to go grab my camera I'm flip it
around I'm going to look at your
questions and see if I can't answer them
for the next 5 minutes and then we'll
close out for today appreciate your time
and I will see you
tomorrow let's see if I can't turn this
around all right
bet I can't see the chat did I not
enable chat today
yeah okay you saw here boys 100% proof
that I am actually yeah I don't
think chat are
enabled or maybe I just don't know what
I'm doing
no I I I can okay so alza says my
mission struck me like a lightning
recently took me 3 months to finally
find it what was your mission
man you can't just leave us like that
Bernie sandal says will you be bringing
back cooking to tutorials I will but
likely on my second channel so
immediately after this lecture is given
right I'm going to jump onto my second
Channel and I'm going to work out I'm
going to do it on live stream so that my
intensity is held accountable and I will
also be doing cooking and other stuff
like that on live chat all right so
that's the answer for that and then we
have
Andreas Killa asks how old are you 28
all right so getting close to 30 at this
point
ala also says even if your duty won't
make you money fast it's still more
worth overall that's true and it's quite
likely that you will make money all
right don't have the limiting belief
that if you're following your duty that
you're not going to make money quite
often the opposite is true all right
keep that in mind cool I will of course
answer questions in the comments as well
so when this is uploaded as an actual
video feel free to ask it there all
right boys I'll see you in the next one
have a nice day