toothpaste is a scop to the toothbrush
is what does most of the cleaning you
actually don't need toothpaste and if
anything the toothpaste is actually
harming you and not helping you you see
toothpaste is highly abrasive it wears
down the enamel and that's what actually
causes cavities later down the line you
may have wondered what the caveman did
before the invention of toothpaste and
toothbrush and mouthwash and all these
things you might wonder what the animals
do how do they survive without brushing
their teeth well firstly even if you
look at the records it turns out that
the pre-agricultural human beings so the
people who were hunters and gatherers
their teeth and their bones was Far
stronger than anything we have as modern
humans and in fact it has been a steady
decline in bone and tooth quality since
then till now let's go back to
toothpaste real quick this one is sodine
it's in the name sodine right it's
supposed to help with sensitivity does
it so when I took out toothpaste from my
life and fully embraced the esoteric
Health movement I found that my teeth
were actually stronger and wider than
theyve ever been before the biggest scam
is charcoal toothpaste so charcoal
toothpaste is actually more abrasive
than your normal toothpaste you should
never be using charcoal toothpaste next
thing is the Stannis fluoride so there
was actually a toothpaste back in the
'90s called floristan pring gamble
announces Crest toothpaste with floran
one of the first toothpaste which had
well Stan is fluide so should you have
fluoridated tooth
it's exclusive fluoride compound world's
greatest weapon against Decay I already
made a video about fluoridation in our
water you can make your own decision as
to whether you want fluoride in your
toothpaste for me it's a definite no so
no fluoridated toothpastes for me there
do exist toothpaste nowadays which are
low abration and fluoride free if you
want to use those do go ahead I think
they're good products I personally have
chosen to use a tooth powder instead of
a toothpaste and I will link in the
description below to the tooth powder
which I use and and looking at the brush
you need to use Ultra Soft Ultra Soft
not just a soft Ultra Soft Ultra soft
brush and a low abrasion toothpaste or
ideally a low abrasion tooth powder you
should not be using the conventional
pepsodent cold gate all that BS
toothpaste all that's doing is probably
increasing the chances of cavity not
decreasing it so how often should you
brush your teeth the standard two times
a day is fine once in the morning once
at night but I always pair my
toothbrushing with oil pulling oil
pulling is a esoteric oral hygiene
method which you may have never heard of
before what you're doing is you're
taking olive oil or you can take coconut
oil is fine and you swirl it around in
your mouth and then spit it out after a
couple minutes so there's bacteria in
your mouth right when you're sleeping
bacteria are growing as you go about
your day you have food bacteria are
growing it's normal but bacterial cell
walls are made of lipids oil is made of
lipids so oil pulling is an ancient
technique which essentially it doesn't
necessarily break down cell walls but it
absorbs the bacteria and you spit it out
you get rid of a lot of the bacteria and
then did you know that Listerine
complete scop so Listerine was actually
a floor cleaner what they did is
completely marketing it's not anything
to do with signs they realized that they
weren't able to sell in a floor cleaner
right so they realized that they could
Rebrand and resell Listerine as a
mouthwash no tooth Bas can kill germs
the lerin does so they invented the term
h Tois which you might know as bad
breath they invented it look at this
they had TV commercials they had
newspaper commercials and they made this
thing a fear in people's mind but
something's gone wrong it was
psychological operation nothing wrong
with the Martin's marriage that lisine
couldn't fix it was a psychological
pressure in people's mind they made it
seem as though everybody you have bad
breath and that's why people don't like
you you have bad breath that's why your
social interaction suck you have bad
bread that's why you're not attracted to
women you have bad bread that's why
you're not attracted to men and they
used you're in security to push a floor
cleaner as a tooth and oral hygiene
product don't use Listerine it's garbage
and then look at the ingredients list in
line well or any Big Brand mouthwash
it's trash for one thing it has many
different kinds of different alcohols
what these do is they dry out the mouth
and decrease saliva production if you
know anything about how the mouth
microbiome works you know that you don't
want alcohol in your mouth cuz it kills
off the good bacteria in your mouth
that's one thing but the other thing is
the alcohol actually dries out your
mouth and decreases saliva production so
saliva contains Calcium and phosphates
you need those to rebuild your teeth you
need those for healthy enamels but the
lisin actually counterproductive right
it actually the more lisin you use the
more you feel like using it cuz you use
lisine your mouth becomes dry you think
you need to use lisine again in order to
fix that so it's a amazing thing for the
company which makes the stuff but it's
terrible for you another thing you need
is a tongue scraper this one is a
plastic one there are bamboo ones and
like other ones wooden ones I would
probably suggest those this is the one
which I had so tongue scrapping is very
important you need to do this once a day
ideally twice a day is very simple just
after you brush your teeth take the
tongue tongue scraper and then just pull
it across your tongue very gently cuz
you don't want to damage your tongue and
then just you know wash your mouth and
clean the tongue scraper and everything
and a lot of bacteria a lot of odor
comes actually from the tongue not the
teeth themselves so if you're neglecting
your tongue scrapping that's probably a
lot of where your mouth odor issues come
from then of course we we have flossing
this important this is non-negotiable
get yourself a bunch of uh these
toothpicks or you know floss picks I
guess you can call them and try to get
the ones with narrower strings and just
put them between your teeth and make him
go all the way to the gums clean out
every single day at least once at night
you don't need to do in the morning but
at night you should be doing it no
excuses so the reason why they added
fluoride in the water at least the
official reason why they added added
fluoride in the water is to help your
teeth so what's going on here what's the
scientific mechanism behind this so what
happens is as as sugars wear away in the
teeth so I mean fluoride is a scam from
the start right because they added high
fructose corn syrup to everybody's diet
which caused the tooth decay in the
first place and to fix this they added
fluoride into the water they should have
addressed the corn syrup issue but they
never did that so the sugars wear away
the tooth enamel and fluoride is
essentially there to replace lost enamel
but fluoride is not the actual chemical
which is supposed to be in our teeth yes
fluoride is more resistant to corrosion
but the teeth are supposed to be made of
calcium and you can get calcium from a
variety of sources the best way to get
calcium a good amount of calcium highly
bioavailable calcium is not through
freaking supplements supplement industry
is a scam I mean not every single
supplement is bad right but most
supplements are not bioavailable to
human being so most supplements are just
a waste of your money and if anything
it's more risk than they word and it
comes to calcium eggshells boy so I know
you saw I know the the hook of this
video was the eggshell right I was
eating the egg whole like with the
eggshell that's legit legit look it up
right now eating the eggshell is
actually very beneficial best source of
calcium for your body it's been done for
thousands of years like it's not new
it's ancient wisdom and that's what the
esoteric Health movement is about is
unearthing ancient wisdom combining it
with modern science and delivering it to
you in an easy to understand format then
there's some stuff which can stain your
teeth you have coffee tea wine they'll
stain your teeth they won't necessarily
damage your teeth but obviously you
don't want your teeth to look yellow and
gross right so what you do is after you
drink wine coffee or tea or anything
like that or any sticky sweet substances
you need to address the issue
immediately you need to go to the
bathroom wash your mouth at the minimum
ideally brush your teeth with just a
brush you don't need toothpaste like I
said before or you can do oil pulling
you need to do one of these things like
you at least need to address it you need
to at least wash with water so I brought
up before how did the cavemen and
animals how do they survive without
having their teeth rotting at age 15
right so one thing is saliva again
cheese milk meat dairy product products
all the esoteric food substances you
know even vegetables vegetables which
have fiber especially they all stimulate
saliva production and saliva essentially
remineralizes and reforms your teeth
stronger so this is again a diet issue
if you have a bad diet if you're
drinking soda having candy all that
garbage then you're not going to have
good teeth surprise surprise right so
fix your diet use the methods which I
told you and you'll have much better
oral hygiene I guarantee you I swear to
God I hope you're not using like five
gum or any of those stupid bubble gums
and chewing gums instead here's what you
should use the most effective which I
found is cloves so I don't know if you
know what cloves are cloves are these
little spices they look like little they
look like little torches
almost so cloves just put them in your
mouth and swirl them around chew them
because they have these little barbs
almost they get into your gums and
behind your teeth Etc and they clean it
out if you have a clo in your mouth and
the other example or other option is
mastic gum Mastic gum is not the same
thing as your modern industrialized
chewing gums mastic gum is actually
legit it's it's a sap which grows from
an actual tree so it's completely
organic so Mastic Gum also stimulates
saliva production it's another way you
can use to remineralize your teeth and
fight against bacteria fight against bad
breath and now that you've learned some
esoteric ways to fix bad breath perhaps
you want to learn about how to fix your
breathing so if you don't fix your
breathing if your oxygen intake isn't
sufficient you're going to be lethargic
you're going to be slow you're not going
to be productive so if you want to know
about how to fix breathing how to not
suffer from allergies throughout the
year you need to watch my video about
fixing your breathing using esoteric
Health methods