what if I shot your dog would that be
insignificant all these nerds bro Neil
deGrasse Tyson Bill Nye Richard Dawkins
Stephen Hawkins all these guys they
always talk about the cosmic
insignificance of everything they talk
about how we're just one more species
one more evolved ape among a million
other species in the galaxy and I said
you know a thousands thousand stars
there's a thousand thousand planets and
just one more species and everything is
so insignificant but that should be
inspiring and that should help us
improve our species for some reason I
call it BS completely on this regardless
of what they say we should focus on what
they will actually do their actions
speak louder than words and that's true
for anybody including scientists if I
decided to walk into Stephen Hawking's
room and shoot his dog
yeah yeah still right it's all right
kind of yeah where was I
um if I walked in this room kicked him
off his wheelchair and shot his dog
using Stephen Hawking would talk about
Cosmic insignificance no because for
every person their own life and the
lives around them are of course
significant and perhaps we don't want to
be so negative speaking about harm done
to others perhaps we want to speak about
the positive
a few weeks ago there was an old woman
trying to carry up a heavy suitcase up a
flight of stairs and I saw this and
without even thinking about it I just
picked it up took it up the stairs it's
just a few stairs and you know I went
about my day without really thinking too
much about it but now when I consider it
I realize probably nobody saw my act of
kindness as it were and even I myself
would have forgotten it but perhaps to
her
the act of kindness was quite
significant because for her that
struggle was quite a struggle and my
gesture of kindness made her day
so just because there are stars in the
sky and planets that revolve around them
is it fair to say that such acts of
kindness are insignificant just because
they're scaled down
I disagree and I think that if you look
into your soul and into your bones
you'll find that even the smallest acts
of kindness are as significant as the
birth of our universe
all right