I have four tiny sentences in my brain
that trigger automatically to reset my
thought pattern make me more present and
delete anxiety in my daily life this
video is about the voice in your head
there's a voice in your head which is
the internal monologue the internal
narrator this is the voice you hear when
you're reading a book this is the voice
which you debate with and this is the
voice which helps you making complex
decisions to my surprise some people
don't even have this voice and not to my
surprise most people have a terrible
relationship with this voice but a few
people do have a good relationship with
this voice use it as a tool and as a
partner to make better decisions and
think through complex ideas and in
general improve the quality of their
life I going to help you join this
special group most people don't know
this but your relationship with that
internal voice that mind voice is a key
driver in your happiness and well-being
but also your attractiveness and even
your productivity at this point we can
agree that happiness doesn't coming from
having the most money the most most
number of cars the most number of
or anything like this but at the
same time we not ready to give up
everything go and live in a monastery
and live in complete seclusion we need a
functional mindfulness a kind of
meditation a kind of mindfulness that is
with you throughout the day as
responsible for destroying negative
thoughts without taking us off our focus
into actually achieving the things that
we want to achieve many YouTubers have
talked about the Flow State a state in
which your mind kind of goes blank
you're completely in the conscious
you're working really hard at your
project or maybe you're doing physical
activities like a sport this is not
about that this is a functional
mindfulness while you're not meditating
you're not in a flow State you're just
going about your regular life many
people even very wise people assume that
the voice in the head is kind of an
enemy kind of something which you need
to suppress or delete in order to live a
fulfilling life I don't see it this way
I see it as a tool as an ally as a
partner but that being said it's not
your Ally and you don't really control
it like a tool if you ever had trouble
sleeping because of racing thoughts you
know exactly what I mean literally I
dealt with this for years I would lie
down ready to sleep I did my nighttime
routine and everything and I couldn't
fall asleep because the voice in my head
would be saying that if I didn't get
good sleep tonight then the next day is
going to suck and the weird thing the
irony is I would have been able to sleep
if my voice wasn't cycling and reminding
me of how my life was going to be
if I couldn't sleep it was completely
dysfunctional this is an example of a
maladaptive voice in your mind but it
doesn't have to be like this there's
amazing book called the happiness
hypothesis by Jonathan ha who's a friend
of Jordan Peterson he talks about how
the subconscious mind is vast like an
elephant and you're like the rider on
the neck of the elephant technically the
rider is in control of the elephant but
any given time the elephant could just
take him put him on the ground and stomp
him this metaphor is actually quite good
because that is how a rider really rides
an elephant the rider of an elephant
must have a good relationship with the
elephant the elephant has to trust him
plus he needs to have the the skills of
his trade and the tools of his trade in
order to actually control his elephant
in this video I'm going to give you the
tools to take your subconsciousness from
an enemy to your friend I'm going to
give you a total of just four very short
sentences and I'm going to teach you how
to train your mind to use these
sentences the way it works for me
because I've been training it for years
at this point is when my mind falls into
a rabbit hole into a vicious cycle one
of these thoughts will automatically
trigger and break me out of the cycle
the first one of these magic sentences
is stop and let it go and I say this in
my mind in a kind of like a humorous
light-hearted manner you know stop and
let it go and this plays in my mind
whenever I get stuck or I'm hung up on
something from the past I regret from
the past for example there was this one
Hazel eyed girl who I fumbled years ago
at this point but I still have hangups
and regrets about this so whenever I do
catch myself thinking about that and you
know what I could have done different or
something like this immediately my mind
will come up with the thought just stop
and let it go go cuz you know I can't do
anything about that anymore that ship
has sailed so all I can do right now is
stop and let it go before I give you
these other three sentences I want you
to understand how this works I didn't
come up with all these four sentences at
the same time and I didn't practice them
all at the same time I did one at a time
depending on what was necessary in my
life at a time in my life in which I was
really really hung up about this girl I
would practice stop and let it go of
course it doesn't only work for that one
situation it works for multiple
situations but it was created for that
purpose if you have constant hangups
about the past whether it's a girl or
something else it doesn't matter you'll
just hit it with stop and let it go and
if you practice this enough times it
becomes automatic and whenever you find
yourself in that recurring rabbit hole
that recurring never- ending cycle a
vicious cycle your mind will
automatically trigger that sentence stop
and let it go and your mind will simply
detach you'll be back to the present and
you'll be able to reassess and then you
know move on to other things this is a
huge benefit to to mental health I don't
know why more people don't talk about
this but if your problem isn't getting
hung up on the things of the past but
rather it's hyper optimizing the present
and the next sentence is for you the
next sentence is a question it's do I
care and the tone of this is kind of
dismissive it's like do I care and I use
this when the circumstances I'm in are
not ideal to my perfect standards for
example if I go to the gym and I haven't
brought my water bottle you know so it's
not perfect I can still work out but
it's not perfect in situations like this
my brain instead of making this into a
big deal instead of overthinking it I'll
just hit it with do I care and quite
often I don't care so I'll finish my
workout regardless and then go about my
day if you're the kind of person who
overthinks trivial inconveniences this
is an important sentence for you and
this works amazingly well in social
situations for example if you make an
edgy joke around people who aren't
really your friends and you're later
you're thinking about like how you
shouldn't have made that joke and nobody
really laughed and you're feeling kind
of cringe kind of discomfort from that
memory of the past hit it with do I care
and the fact of the matter is I don't
care about the opinions of most people
so there's absolutely zero reason why I
should be hung up about cringe things or
uncomfortable things which I've done or
said in the past in front of these
people I don't care so I ask myself the
question do I care and if I don't then
it's an easy way to let it go so this is
also something which I practice in order
to be less socially anxious you need to
be able to recover from situations in
which you are kind of socially awkward
so if I ever get a memory of myself
being socially awkward do I care and of
I don't care so I move on pretty easily
understand this these sub routines right
these special sentences which I'm giving
you for me they trigger automatically as
soon as I get caught in a trap if I'm
overthinking about this awkward thing
which I made automatically the thought
will pop in my head do I care and I let
go of the burden I'll get let go of That
Awkward thought and this is hugely
beneficial for my overall well-being and
just happiness in general the next
sentence is what is done is done and
this is said with a tone of arrogance
and finality it's like what is done is
done and you use this when you're
thinking about decisions which weren't
optimal what I mean is if you have ever
made decisions and you found that your
decisions weren't perfect which
everybody has made bad decisions and
you're constantly having thoughts of I
should have done this because of this or
I should have done this cuz I should
have known better Etc then you got to
hit it with what's done is done the
truth of the matter is quite often it's
better to make a bad decision than not
making a decision at all in fact they
teach this to every single army officer
serve across time and across space from
the Cavalry commanders of Napoleon to US
Marine Corps every single officer is
taught that sometimes you just got to
make a decision and then work with it
rather than just sat there and getting
shot at so everybody has made bad
decisions that's fine you have to rise
about the occasion and keep moving and
making new decisions because that old
decision is already gone that fork in
the road has already been crossed you
cannot look back and be hung up on
things because that's actually a worse
position just moving on and making new
and better decisions so you got to hit
bad decisions which you've made which
you're having regrets about with what's
done is done Own It move forward another
use for what's done is done is when you
know you have to do something but it has
a strong level of resistance or
uncomfortableness while going through it
for example when I made my video the
anti- addiction video the video which
teaches you how to break free from porn
addiction forever it was a very awkward
video for me to post I knew the video
was good in fact I think it's the best
video on this topic on the planet and I
say this with zero arrogance I say this
with knowing the facts of my trade I
still felt quite uncomfortable releasing
that into the public because think about
it do I want to be talking about such a
sensitive topic and this can be searched
you know as this available on Google
people can find this so it's a highly
awkward decision to make but I knew what
I must do I knew it had to be done so I
found myself kind of catastrophizing you
know I was I found myself kind of hung
up on this I wasn't able to click the
make public button on the back end of
YouTube so finally I decided my moral
and principles are in alignment I should
just hit the button and then deal with
the consequences so I hit it I've made
that video public what is done is done
and I'll deal with the consequences when
they arise and again I want to remind
you you don't need to practice all these
four sentences at the same time in fact
you shouldn't do that you can only
practice one sentence in your
subconscious at any given time I'll
write these four sentences in the
description below but you should only
focus on one at a time find out which
kind of mental block you're facing the
most which kind of rabbit hole which
kind of endless cycle you're falling
yourself into and then use the correct
sentence for that destroy that
particular thought cycle and then move
on to a different sentence if you need
it and if you don't need all four maybe
you just need two of them that's fine
you have to customize everything which I
give you for your own life circumstances
and the last sentence is stop and come
back and this is said with a tone of
command you're commanding yourself stop
and come back this is used when you're
having cycling thoughts about the future
if youve ever worked in code like you
ever tried to code a program you'll know
what's an endless loop it's a loop that
you you kind of messed up the
programming a little bit so when you hit
run the program just runs again and
again and again and again forever and
most programs will have a manual kill
switch as soon as you hit it the program
stops running and then you can fix it
and some programs even have a feature
which if it detects an endless loop
it'll shut down by itself and say you
need to fix this and that's what stop
and come back is for me for my mind
whenever I'm catastrophizing when I'm
making cyclical thoughts about the
future you know this could go wrong
visual call this go wrong this is going
to go wrong this is going to go wrong
I'm thinking about the future in the
cyclical way that's when I'm hit with
the Stop and come back so the first
sentence I give you was stop and let it
go that's about the past when you have
things in the past you can't control it
because it's already in the past you
stop and let it go when you have
thoughts about the future you're trying
to figure out what's going to happen in
the future and how best to handle it and
you're just going around in circles you
got to say stop and come back this is
going to help you break the cycle come
back to the present and then actually
reassess the situation and then move
forward I suggest that the four
sentences which I've given you use them
exactly word for word I've given you
because if you heard me say those words
so many times in this one video that
they already have a resonance in your
mind they already have some kind of
connection with your subconscious you
might as well just build on those
practice those and use them whenever
you're having cyclical thoughts what I'm
teaching you is essentially a meditation
technique called labeling I've taken
that technique and made it more
practical so it say you can use it even
when you're not meditating so what
you're essentially doing like if you
look at what's going on is when you have
a cyclical thought pattern your mind
instantly recognizes that labels it and
as soon as you label it it becomes
powerless and inefficient and so you can
keep it aside and then you can get back
to actually what you're doing do this
enough times and the labeling process
and the shunting off process becomes so
efficient and effortless that you have a
genuine Improvement in the quality of
your life because you aren't spending
any time at all stuck in Endless
thoughts