reality punishes those who deny her and
Fortune blesses those who act with
boldness and have the furthest Vision
having a good mental model for how the
world really works allows you to make
better decisions in real life and allows
you to see business opportunities when
others only see Darkness studying human
nature is the first step in creating a
personal brand so this collection of
books is not a theoretical collection it
is not for your reading pleasure this is
a series of very practical and
intelligent books these books are
designed to peel away the darkness
allowing you to see with more
understanding we've study human nature
and reality itself from the perspective
of History economics biology and
morality we'll start off with the book
The sovereign individual by the authors
Davidson and reys Mong this is a book
that predicts this book is full of
interesting predictions and if you look
up a online review of This Book You'll
see that people are amazed by the
prediction of such trival things as
smartphones and the gig economy these
are distractions these are not the key
predictions of this book you see most
non-fiction writers who write about the
future are often coward they'll shy away
from making predictions or if they do
make a prediction they'll cover it in
caveat so that the prediction itself is
without fangs without any skin in the
game but not so in this book the authors
are bold they go ahead and make what
they think is the best possible
prediction based on the knowledge and
information which they have and here's
the thing making predictions is risky
because if they come wrong then you look
like a fool so I have a lot of respect
for this book just for making those
predictions making them with boldness
and support their predictions with facts
and the actual logical structure which
leads them to make those conclusions the
real frightening prediction that the
book makes is regarding the fragility of
the nation state it says that the nation
state will always try to find itself in
a war because a war serves to better its
own interest even at the expense of the
citizens paying its taxes a nation state
according to the tenants of this book
will do anything to perpetuate a
pretense of holding power it goes so far
as to say that nation states will
encourage and forment War in order to
maintain their whole and happened just a
few years after the release of this book
I'm not making the claim that was an
inside job more so what I'm saying is
was used by the nation state to gain a
level of tyrannical control over its
population marks the day the old ideals
of the United States die in the new
modern surveillance state was born do
you know what the Patriot Act is well
but that's a topic for a different video
hundreds of thousands of loyal
courageous and Brave Young Americans
were funneled into the wrong war in the
wrong country in order to perpetuate the
power of the nation state and these
young men they went and fought for what
purpose to enrich the Saudis to enrich
the bankers and investors to enrich the
weapons complex the book which was
written back in the 1990s actually
predicts this and says how the mega
political structures of the modern state
will incentivize this kind of behavior
and this book goes completely against
the status quo political thinking which
states that the nation state is the the
culmination the Apex of human political
achievement in fact Francis fukuyama who
I personally met as a very well-known
historian and political scientist
actually calls this the end of History
this book says no this is not the end of
history and terrible darkness and
potential hope lies in the near future
so is this book a perfect predictor of
the future absolutely not and the
authors don't claim that to be the case
in fact the first chapter of this book
is an utter flaw the first chapter goes
on into the whole year 2000 crisis thing
about the Y 2K bug which never really
materialized so no this book is not a
perfect predictor of History it's first
and foremost a book about mental models
how you can use observations and facts
and connect them in a logical faction to
make predictions about the future this
book is not the rambling of Mad Men this
is a very precise book which lays out
why the authors believe what they
believe and you can choose to reject
their logic or Embrace their logic
that's up to you the book does not hide
its internal working so the book's
titled the sovereign individual what
does this mean this refers to the idea
that in the future individuals will have
massive power which they never had
before and this book was written more
than 25 years ago and it's coming true
isn't it look at Joe Rogan for example
Joe Rogan has more loyalty and more
viewership than literal Legacy companies
of the past like CNN or MSNBC a single
man has more influence that a whole
media conglomerate this was not possible
20 years ago this was a prediction that
came true and now in our day almost
seems natural it seems normal but you
have to understand how remarkable This
truly is from a world which completely
revolved one this Mass organization and
an industrial society which only relied
on mass production we're going to a
different form of economy where
individuals are massively valued and
production of higher quality at a
smaller scale is becoming more of the
desired state but trust me when I tell
you this is not a book about hope this
book is not blind to human evil this
book predicts rivers of blood if you
were to look at what's going around the
globe right now you would say that those
rivers are already flowing this book is
of course about sovereignty so
sovereignty means the ability to have
the freedom and liberty to control their
own destiny a Sovereign Nation is
essentially a nation which is not a
slave to another Nation a sovereign
individual is an individual who is not a
slave to Any Nation so the norm the
common understanding of nationhood is
you're born into a country you're likely
going to live your entire lives in that
country pay taxes to the country then
die
there there's really no choice in the
matter but going forward what you find
is individuals have that choice highly
productive and talented individuals will
find that if they live in a country
which doesn't treat them right a country
which is taxing them too much or whose
government is standing for values which
they no longer stand for or is betraying
the citizens by going to meaningless war
and wasting their tax money all these
would be reasons for talented
individuals to say I'm out I'm going to
go where I'm treated best and this is
already happening and this is only going
to ACC accelerate more especially with
regards to another prediction which this
book makes this book predicts that a new
form of currency will arise a form of
currency that's immune to Taxation and
inflation by the government through
which individuals can carry out
transactions without the need for Fiat
and one could say that this currency has
arisen in the form of Bitcoin but
Bitcoin is a scam is it not the whole
crypto industry is a scam right well
this brings us to the second book on
this list the Bitcoin standard by saaden
a mood these are actually two books
Bitcoin standard followed by Fiat
standard it's SQL but I just lumped them
together as one book because they really
tied together so I have to tell you this
that the Bitcoin standard is not about
Bitcoin it is first and foremost about
the nature of currency about money
itself it helps you distinguish between
the difference between money currency
and wealth and this book was suggested
to me by a seven fig businessman by the
name of Robert Oliver very talented
individual and I'll link to his channel
in the description below so this book is
not a bought Bitcoin it is about the
nature of currency and help you answer
the question if the government can just
print how much of money it wants why
does it tax you so much it's honestly a
very scary and Sinister book in the
sense that it it shatters your beliefs
about how money works and how the world
actually works it shows how dark the
system really is it shows you how the
system of federal debt slavery truly is
and you've probably seen this statistic
that the world is trillions of dollars
in debt you know the US is billions of
dollars in debt whatever is death to
whom right that's a question which you
have to ask and this book does a
phenomenal job of answering it I will
probably make a whole video on this
topic it's fascinating and dark if you
want to get ahead of me and get a even
richer understanding strongly suggest
the Bitcoin standard and the Fiat
standard by saine AMU and indeed it
talks about how the US dollar is covered
in blood and gore and it talks about
that most Sinister of organizations the
Federal Reserve the book builds nicely
upon the foundations of the sovereign
individual these books work really
nicely together one was written back in
1990s and makes predictions about the
future and the Bitcoin standard is
written pretty recently and looks back
and talks about what recent changes have
happened so it kind of brings you up to
date and the Fiat standard was I think
released just last year so it's very
much up to date as to the technology of
money and makes predictions about how
we're going to look at this going
forward next 10 to 20 years but indeed
this book is first and foremost about
human nature like I promised it shows
you how the incentive structures created
by the miny system that we have truly
shape every aspect of society and you
know me I love to understand my history
and in my previous video about the Roman
Empire and its demise and what we can
learn from it I talk about the
debasement of currency I tell you that
debasement is essentially the old term
when you add base metals to gold in
order to water it down for the
government to create more money but
doesn't really create more money what it
really does is creates more Fiat token
the common term for this used by the
Gremlin verminous macroeconomists is
called quantitative easing and these
folk will tell you that a slight amount
of inflation is actually good for the
economy it it promotes business growth
it promotes investment but you know what
this is actually just marketing speak
imagine if they told you hey your tax as
a citizen is 40% but you know if we
increase the tax by another 10% it will
actually be good for the economy would
you believe them or would you start
drawing the pitchforks this book helps
you understand the truth behind the lies
it makes you understand why big business
big media and the government say the
things that they do it starts to make
sense for the first time and one could
excuse the Romans Dian didn't know
perhaps that the debasement of currency
would have such terrible Downstream
effects he didn't know perhaps that the
price ceilings that he enforced would be
calamitous but we do know it now we have
the data in place we understand how the
economy works we understand how
incentives structures work but that's
the thing the government's incentives
are not the same as a citizen incentive
and this is because of the nature of the
currency the nature of the currency fiat
currency is such that the government can
basically print how much it wants and
this touches everything even your food
quality so understand this this is
actually from the book the government's
ability to print money gives it the
ability to fix interest rates so what
the government did was it lowered
interest rates what does that mean it
allows businesses including fors to take
big loans why is this a bad thing this
is surely a good thing if farmers can
take loans they can probably produce
more food but this is a market
Distortion what I mean let me explain
really clearly right so when the
interest rates go low and big loans are
available for purchase the big farmers
can claim massive loans because they
already have a lot of capital and a lot
of assets which they use as collateral
and they use these massive loans to
scale up their operations to a crazy
level driving the prices extremely low
small farmers who cannot have access to
such big loans cannot do this and even
though their quality of produce might be
higher they're driven out of business
now all that's left in the economy are
these Mega farms and mega corporations
which are pumping out very very cheap
food but at the cost of nutritional
density so because of this Distortion in
the market now you have food which is
extremely cheap if the only thing you
meant by food was just calories so yes
in the United States calories are
extremely cheap but nutrition becomes
expensive in a natural economy this
shouldn't be the case you shouldn't have
calories going in One Direction and
nutrition going in the other direction
but because of the nature of government
subsidies enabled by the fact that the
government has Fiat money to print you
have this disgusting situation where
people are fat and they're obese but
they're obese and fat because they're
malnutritioned it's ridiculous this is a
clown World which is enabled by the
currency that we use so strongly suggest
reading this book to understand this at
a more granular level and indeed here's
the most Sinister part
the nature of our money system
determines the morality of society as a
whole why is this so savings right you
earn money cool you save it in your bank
account you expect the money to stay the
same because you put $10 in surely it
should stay $10 and in most of human
history Not only would it stay it would
actually increase but not in our
inflationary environment when you store
$10 the next day it's 9 the next day
it's 8 every day your value of money is
decreasing in your savings account so
what does this mean from an incentive
structure point of view what does it
mean according to human nature what it
means is if people believe that saving
is pointless because it is because of
the nature of the money then they're
more incentivized to spend in the
present instead of looking into the
future building Legacy instead of
planning 10 20 30 100 years into the
future people are forced to think hey
the money is not going to be worth
anything I might as well spend it the
monetary system incentivizes instant
gratification over delayed gratification
this is one source of degradation of
morality is just how we perceive time
and this neatly brings us to the topic
of morality and brings us to the next
book which is the Righteous Mind by
Jonathan hate and this is a truly
brilliant book it breaks down why humans
behave in the moral way that they do it
discusses moral decision- making and
this it does it in such a brilliant way
in a very simple and easy to understand
way they break down morality into five
pillars the pillars are care fairness
loyalty Authority and sanctity and it
turns out this explains why left leaning
folk and right leaning folk don't ever
succeed in talking to each other people
who lean left they only use two of these
pillars they only use care and they only
use fairness and the folk on the right
more conservative folk these guys use
all five pillars they use the first two
which I mentioned but they also look at
loyalty Authority and sanctity and this
book is critical because understanding
each other and having rational decisions
brings Society together and prevents a
division division is not helpful for us
as people division is only helpful for
the powers that be me personally I
definitely lean more conservative I
certainly do not mean I support the
conservative party those are two
different things trust me I just tend to
lean conservative in my value I care
about all these five pillars I care
about giving care to folk who need it I
care about fairness and Justice I care
about loyalty to the group I care about
deferring to Authority where it makes
sense and I care about the sanctity and
morals of the society but some of my
family members and friends they lean
left they reject the idea of morality
based on disgust and Purity the idea
that if it doesn't harm somebody else
then it's Justified to do while I
disagree with this at least I understand
their perspective and indeed this book
shows you basically a prediction of how
politics is progressing and shows you
how the divisions sewed into society are
the perfect Seam for manipulation cuz
these folk the politicians they
understand these tactics they understand
how to pull these levers of Morality In
order to make us do what they want so
you have to take control of your own
morality and have a deeper understanding
of why your moral intuition your moral
compass works the way it does so that
you are being manipulated by outside
forces my personal belief is that
disgust is a powerful piece of the moral
compass if I find something disgusting
happening in society something really
irritates me and disgusts me I don't
have to be sat there analyzing the moral
logic in order to find the objective or
subjective truth about morality in order
to reject it I believe if something's
disgusting that grounds enough for me to
reject it but regardless it is very
interesting that when people have so
many different views and beliefs and
moral structures that we can come
together as a society and even though
each individual has its own Survival at
its core even then we as human beings
can act in a tribe and this is not a
trivial point this requires explanation
and and this is where the final book The
Selfish Gene comes in this is the book
which literally coined the word me in
this book the author Dawkins literally
says we need a name for the new
replicator a noun that conveys the idea
of a unit of cultural transmission or a
unit of
imitation MIM comes from a suitable
Greek root but I want a monosyllable
that sounds a bit like genan I hope my
classicist friends will forgive me if I
abbreviate me meme to meme if it is any
consolation it could alternatively be
thought of as being related to memory or
to the French word m it should be
pronounced to rhyme with cream I'm sure
he didn't foresee how that word meme
would eventually get its own life but
this book is a controversial one just
because Dawkins is controversial see
Dawkins became famous for his obnoxious
atheist propaganda more than his actual
work in biology and this is kind of sad
because it's kind of cringe but luckily
this book doesn't have a lot of that it
just is a pure Biology book and indeed
it is fundamentally a book about
genetics if you don't understand
genetics at a fundamental level then you
do not understand human nature the
previous book analyzes human nature from
a psychologist perspective Dawkins
approaches it from a biology and
ecologist perspective it goes into
questions like why is a man's strategy
in the dating market so much different
than a woman it answers questions about
how many Traditions arise in the first
split like for example why do most
societies consider it okay for men to
sleep around but when a woman does it
it's just completely Haram and why some
societies think it's Haram for both
sexes fascinating stuff if you have any
interest in biology then this is
absolutely must read and it does go into
the dark topic of parasites which trust
me that is going to be something on this
channel which I discussed the
manipulation of parasites on indeed the
human psyche is something which I have
become more understanding of that indeed
is the next stage of this channel I
discuss the really troubling rate of
infections of parasites in humans even
in First World countries and I will
slowly share with you piece by piece how
to defeat this at this point I hope you
already understand the dangers of
xenoestrogens good that's the first step
but it is by no means the last step it
is my pleasure and privilege to bring
you this information about health
optimization which the big governmental
bodies simply have no interest in doing
finally I'll say that this reading list
to give you is just a tiny fraction of
my esoteric reading list so there's a
link in the description go to my website
you don't have to give me your email or
anything you'll find the total list the
full list and you can pick and choose
whatever appeals to you and if you're
interested in reading and you want to
take your reading to the next level not
only reading stuff but also discussing
it with like-minded peers then
potentially my private Community is open
for right now we're taking new members
at this time and these members have
access to all my courses so this is
something you're interested in then
there is a link in the description below
so what books do you think should belong
on my list put in the comments your
favorite books about the nature of
reality and human nature itself