When Michelangelo was 17, he was
obsessed about cutting open human bodies
to see what was inside. This was despite
the fact that this was a crime
punishable by death in Florence at the
time. If you're struggling with fear and
uncertainty about the future, then this
is the video that you need to watch to
understand what is possible when a man
decides to bet everything on himself.
Our story starts when Michelangelo turns
15. And what he does is he does these 2D
sculptures in marble for his local
church. As he's doing this, his talent
is of course recognized and he gets a
first big commission of a 9-ft tall
Hercules statue. This is the first 3D
model he's done and certainly the first
lifesize model that he has done. So a
project above his threshold, above his
comfort zone, certainly he takes on this
project and he do does something
important. He creates a clay model of
the Hercules as he envisioned it. But in
doing so, he realized he doesn't
actually have the skills he needs. He
doesn't understand how the weight
distribution works, the way the muscles
should tense and relax to make that pose
possible. So, he needs to upgrade his
skills. He needs to learn how human
anatomy actually works. And at the time,
there was no resources that could teach
him this. There was no professors he
could go to, no books that he could
read. He needed to create the body of
knowledge needed to pull this off and
the money situation. This made it even
more challenging. So the commissioner
who asked him commissioned him to make
this Hercules did not pay for the raw
material. So he didn't have the marble
to begin with. So he had to go and buy
his own marble which was at the time and
now very expensive.
So Michelangelo has been saving money
for the past 2 years trying to save
every single penny that he can and he
saves up a total of four gold Florence
the currency at the time. So 2 years of
savings, four gold Florence, spends it
on a big block of marble without having
ever done that kind of a project before.
That's the kind of man who bets on
himself. Now he doesn't have the skills.
He doesn't have savings anymore. His
father was adamantly against this
project. Why? Because it's risky. The
father was like, "Hey, you should just
go into the family business. Just do
what's tested. Just do the thing which
is safe." But Michelangelo was not
comfortable or he wasn't he wasn't
willing to take that path. Instead, he
did what was not comfortable. He bet his
life savings and has his marble. Now,
the skill issue. How does he address
this? He decides that he needs to
understand the underlying mechanism of
what makes the skin take the form that
it takes. Michelangelo didn't understand
what it took to make a truly lifelike
sculpture with the veins and the muscles
and the tendons and the ligaments
actually in place with the correct
amount of strain. So, he had to dissect
human bodies. How does he get them?
Well, he couldn't access the dead bodies
of the rich because these graves were in
uh family graves and these were well
protected. He couldn't access the graves
of the middle class folk simply because
well they had these elaborate rituals
which which they would bury them and he
was afraid to incur some kind of curse.
He would be limited to the corpses of
the beggars and the orphans, the
unwanted corpses of Florence. So he
would go at night into the charity
hospital and into the morg snuck in and
he would carry this candle. When that
candle starts to go out, it means his
time is up and he needs to leave in in
case he gets
discovered. So every night for months,
he's dissecting bodies. He's taking
notes. He's making sketches.
Michelangelo at the time was more
experienced, has cut up more bodies than
actual anatomists and more morticians of
the era. He put in more reps than the
actual professionals of that field. He
has even cut up all the animals. Every
single animal that is known in Italy at
the time, he had cut up to try to
understand the
musculature. So once he returns to that
clay model now, after months, if not a
year of training and looking at the
actual insides of the bodies, he finally
understood what he needed to do. He
understood how the weight balance of
that clay sculpture worked. He
understood what ligaments should be
taught, what should be relaxed, which
muscles would be uh acting as he built
out this
Hercules. Then it's the time to take
that clay model and make it the 9 ft
marble model. And he still doesn't have
experience with this. So he makes a
grave mistake. He starts to chisel away
the parts of the marble that you don't
need because you're first trying to
create the overall sculpture, the
overall structure of the statue before
he puts in the fine details. In so
doing, he goes way too narrow on the
neck. What you're supposed to do is
leave a good amount of marble around the
neck so that any tremors going from
above below the body to the above
wouldn't just break the head off. But he
didn't know. So he went too deep. As
he's sculpting the shoulder musculature
of the Hercules, he realizes that the
tremors were traveling up the neck and
kind of shaking the head. But luck would
be with him and the head did not fall
off. Hercules kept his head and
Michelangelo kept his commission. He was
able to sell that piece for 100
Florence. He invested four Florence in
and got a 100 out, 25x return on his
investment. But that's just the
beginning of Michelangelo's career. In
fact, this is the most crudest of his
sculptures. He would go on in the next
four years to sculpt the Pieta and this
sculpture whole new level. And for this
sculpture, he's paid 400 gold Florence,
100x his initial investment. Now, it
would be easy to assume that
Michelangelo was just born a genius. And
maybe he was, but nobody can deny that
he put in the reps. and not just any
reps, but the kind of reps that nobody
else was willing to put in. In fact,
even the tools, he didn't have the tools
needed to pull off what he pulled off.
So, he had to design and invent his own
tools in order to do the sculpting that
he did. So, to recap, Michelangelo
starts off without the skills. Not just
that, but he doesn't even have the
knowledge base required. So, he had to
go out and create the knowledge base. He
had to create the encyclopedic knowledge
of human anatomy to actually pull off
the sculpture. Didn't have the
knowledge. Didn't have the tools. So he
had to design the tools. In the modern
time that we live in, is there anything
comparable? For almost every project
that you ever want to do, the knowledge
base already exists. You want to create
a e-commerce store, there's courses out
there. There's YouTube videos. All the
knowledge is already out there. you want
a career in a big company software
company and in Amazon the process for
getting into those companies is actually
well documented and you can just follow
that probably will get in all the
problems all the knowledge based
problems are solved except for the ones
which are at the absolute cutting edge
of physics like how do you build a Mars
colony now that's a problem which hasn't
been solved yet but that too might be
solved in the years to come the tools we
have all the tools we would need to
start a business or any other pursuit.
We have the tools in place. If you want
to start a website, website builders
exist. It's not like in 2001 where you
had to kind of work on WordPress and
create your own website. You can just
drag and drop. Email senders exist. If
you're trying to create a physical
products company, there are
manufacturers out there who will work
with lowQ, which is minimum order
quantity, and help you get your first
prototypes out. So, all the tools exist.
So, what's stopping you? There's
absolutely no reasons except the fact
that you feel like you need permission.
That's I think the core part of the
Michelangelo story which resonated with
me which is he decided to act and take
these bold actions without the
permission of his father. When we grow
up, one of the core and if not the core
authority figure in our lives is our
fathers, sometimes our mothers. If
you're young, start disobeying your
parents more. Do it early. Do it a lot.
do it when you don't feel comfortable
doing it. Now, coming back to the story
of Michelangelo, he sets his sights on
his next project. He comes to know of
this legendary massive block of marble
40 ft high which was left abandoned in
the courtyard of a church. Now, he he
talks to this church and what's happened
is this this marble was actually damaged
by previous sculptures. So, it was an
imperfect piece of marble, massive,
bigger than anything he had done before.
But he gets the commission and this
legendary piece of marble is what's
destined to become the David. Again,
another 10x jump from where he was
before in terms of the skill required to
pull this off. If you look at the David,
you the details are insane and you'll
miss them if you don't know what you're
looking for. David's hands, one of them
is holding the sling and the other is
left limp by his side. The hand which is
holding the sling, you'll notice that
his veins are not visible. But the hand
which is by his side, his veins are
popping and quite quite visible. This is
exactly what would happen to an actual
human being in a state of arousal with
the hands in this position. So by the
fact that when he was 17, he was
dissecting the bodies and understanding
how the circulatory system of the human
body works. He was able to understand
how blood would flow in an actual human
being and replicate this in marble.
Another great example, the statue of
Moses, which was upon the Pope's tomb
that he was commissioned to
sculpt. This the figure of Moses has his
hand like this. There's a small muscle
on Moses's forearm which is engaged.
That muscle is only ever engaged if your
pinky is flexed. Most sculptors would
not know this, but Michelangelo did
because he put in reps and not just any
reps, but the exceptional reps because
he could just do things. At this point
in his career, Michelangelo has
established himself as one of the
greatest. He's now in competition with
the old master himself, Leonardo da
Vinci. And then his prestige improves
even more because Pope commisss him to
paint and design the dome of St. Peters
and of course the Sistine Chapel, the
painting of the Sistine Chapel. So he
was a sculptor, right? He doesn't know
how to paint. So he develops a whole new
skill set of painting. And of course he
created the masterwork of God creating
Adam. He creates the he also does the
wall of the 16th chapel which is another
masterwork. But in so doing he takes on
sacrifice. Painting a ceiling very
difficult. He's working for 18 hours a
day in this position looking upwards.
And the strain that this puts on his
neck actually makes him go blind for
months. His his health almost never
recovers. When I see the struggles and
sacrifices of some of the greats, I find
that my own struggles and sacrifices
seem childish in comparison. For
example, me and Marlin, my cameraman. We
filmed one and a half hours in the cold
and the rain and we tried to make this
video about the big five personality
traits. It was a cool video and it was a
good take. We were satisfied with our
work. But when we head back home to edit
it, we found out that the audio wasn't
there. It wasn't recorded. All that work
in the rain, uh me trying to speak and
not really able to articulate my words
because it was so cold, our hands were
numb, but it didn't matter cuz the audio
wasn't there. So, we had to do
everything again. And guess what? That's
what Michelangelo had to do as well.
When Michelangelo did his first version
of the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel, he
found out that the paint was literally
molding. So he had to scrap the entire
project, redo all his work, and in fact
even invent new paints that wouldn't
mold. That's the level of dedication and
sacrifice it took for Michelangelo to be
great. And that's why it's inspiring to
me. You see Michelangelo, this guy who
is 17 years of age, he already knew what
he wanted to do and is willing to go at
to whatever lengths it took to make this
dream happen. I share this story because
my clients exemplifies the idea of you
can just do things. He didn't seek
permission. He didn't seek validation
from others. And validation from others
didn't even matter to him because his
standards were so high that others
standards were irrelevant. If he met his
own standards, then he would be good.
Nobody could really impeach him for
anything less. I think at this point in
the video, you understand that art and
the aesthetic experience is important to
me. It is. And we always hear this news
that AI is going to destroy art. AI is
going to replace artists. But it doesn't
have to. If you are an artist, you can
just desire to do things. You can just
make art. And if you are a businessman
or a consumer of art, you can just
choose to support those artists. You can
just choose to buy art instead of AI
slop. You can just do that. You don't
need to buy into the narrative that X is
happening. One of the things which I
want to succeed in before I die is
dedicate $1 million to creating
humanmade art. real art which has a
human and emotions behind it. I'm going
to display on the screen some of the
artworks which I've commissioned. First
artwork, the artist imagines Romans to
be in medieval armor. That's such a cool
concept. I really like it. The second
artwork, he describes or depicts the
crusader knights as they were. The
knights hospitaler, the knights templar,
the knights of Jerusalem and the knights
Tutonic. The third artwork, the
Renaissance uh Papal States artwork.
These are the warriors who guarded the
papacy. I've also commissioned two new
artworks. One of the glorious Spartans
in bronze defending the gates of of uh
Thermopoly. And the final artwork which
I've just commissioned is the samurai
warriors. And why do I do this? Because
again, I think a society would be a
better place with more actual art in it.
What I want to do is for 2026, I want to
create a calendar with 12 different art
pieces commissioned by the same artists.
If you're interested in following this
project and being a part of it, then
there's a form in the description below.
Give me your email and then when this
project is finally brought to fruition,
you'll be the first to learn about it.
Imagine the calendar, right? It has 12
epic art pieces and then a blurb about
each of these warrior types written by
me. To bring such a project to life
would be something that only I can do
because only I am interested in art in
this specific way. So this allows it to
be a part of my legacy. When I die, I
can look back at the things I've done
and this calendar would be one example
of a time where I spent my time and
resources in making society more
beautiful. If you feel that society is
not as beautiful as it was in history,
then it is your moral duty to fight
against the decline in beauty. So join
me and let's make society beautiful