acrylamide is formed when you microwave
your food and if it sounds toxic that's
because it is you have to understand
that the human body is not just a
biochemical machine it's also an
electrochemical Masterpiece most people
don't know this but the signals from our
brain is not transmitted to the rest of
our body through electrical pulses like
in a wire but rather through a system of
ion channels and electron pumps and
these store up energy in the form of
concentration gradients and they
basically use that to transmit a pulse
through a series of long cell called
neurons and all this relies on ions like
calcium sodium and potassium and that
brings us to our video sponsor element
now I'm kidding with you man but
the thing is these ions these charged
particles are influenced by
electromagnetic radiation I talked
earlier about the formation of
acrylamide in our food when you heat it
in the microwave but even before that
let's talk about improper shielding so
if you ever listened to music on your
Bluetooth headphones while you're using
a microwave oven you might have noticed
that there's interference or even
disconnection
from your device this is proof that the
radiation is not shielded properly that
is to say electromagnetic radiation is
leaking from your microen and we can of
assume that there's no problem here
there's no Health effect but what if
there is but talking about the food
again so let's talk about another
observation you probably notice that
when you heat food a microwave like some
parts of it are ice cold when other
parts are super heated this is the
problem which causes the formation of
these toxins so because some parts of
the food are heated to an extreme degree
there's chemical reactions which start
which cause the creation of acrylamide
and other toxins so when it comes to the
issue of the electromagnetic shielding
the solution is pretty clear just step
away from your microwave when you're
using it simply stepping away from the
microwave is going to drastically reduce
the electromagnetic radiation that you
actually incur and if you're like four
five steps away from your microwave
that's far enough but the acrylamide
issue is a little bit more complex it
depends on what food it is how long
you've been heating it for and how you
actually heat it so first thing Heating
liquids is mostly fine heating water
milk coffee I have no issue with that
and the reason behind that is because in
liquids the particles are free to move
so as you're heating them in a microwave
there's convection currents which form
which kind of move around the water move
around the liquid and no part of the
liquid gets super heated and so there's
no formation of toxins but now when it
comes to food especially carbohydrate
rich foods so what's going on is this
extra heat this excess heat causes a
reaction called the mord reaction and to
be fair mord reactions are very common
in cooking and I'm not at all saying
that this reaction is always to be
avoided searing a steak or caramelizing
the top of a Creme Brule that's all a
form of mad reaction so basically when
carbohydrates and amino acids are
subjected to extreme heat you have the
potential to create acrylamides so don't
heat carbohydrates in the microwave for
too long and before I even get into that
heating the microwave is not by any
means the only cooking process or only
heating process which causes the
creation of toxin
far far worse is deep frying in seed
oils so if you have french fries and you
deep fry them in seed oils that's far
more contaminated the toxins than taking
a potato and baking it in the microwave
oven so if you were to make fries by
frying it in Tallow that's fine but if
you fry it in seed oils it is not fine
and the reason comes down to the
stability of the fats saturated fats
like Tallow are extremely stable they
can withstand quite a bit of oxidative
stress seed oils on the other hand are
unstable they have double bonds these
bonds can break down through oxidative
stress and this causes the oils to
become toxic and I have a whole video on
seed oils already created so if you want
to watch that for more information
please do so I'll link to it in the
description or even have the card pop up
as an end screen at the end of this
video the story of seed oils is a
disgusting story of corporate greed and
government subsidy I'm simply not okay
with putting industrial lubricant into
my body despite what government
organizations and the American Heart
Association which is a scam organization
have to say about the topic now coming
back to to microwaves so don't store
anything on top of the microwave because
it will be affected by the radiation so
I went to my mom's house a month ago and
she had Vitamin D supplements on top of
the microwave and I just picked it up as
the microwave was running I was just
heating some coffee or something and I
felt that it was warm like really warm I
realized that this vitamin D supplement
was essentially going through hundreds
of cycles of heating and cooling every
time this microwave was switched on so
Vitamin D supplements are kind of BS
anyway the soft gel tablets that it come
in it's filled with seed oils and the
fact that my mom had placed it on top of
the microwave and subject it to
countless cycles of heating and cooling
made that toxic so I tossed it out
immediately and speaking of Vitamin D
supplements all I have to say about that
topic is if you need Vitamin D
supplements for example if you are in a
cold region and you don't get a lot of
sunlight during the winter months
especially if you're dark skinned like I
am then it does actually make sense to
have a supplement for vitamin D but not
the actual store-bought capsules instead
go for cod liver oil from a company that
actually gets their sourcing from
non-toxic fish the one which I use is
called Green pasture I've recommended it
before so I personally have been cutting
down drastically on my use of the
microwave oven I've instead started
using the convection oven so what you do
is just take your food put it on your
ceramic plate set the convection oven
for 375° f let the thing preheat and
then you put your food in for about 10
to 12 minutes you can absolutely put
multiple plates of food in there if
you're eating with your friends or
family so what if you have no option but
to use a microwave oven for example if
you pack your home food food and you
take it to work and you handly have the
option of a microwave oven what do you
do so here's some tips I can give you
first make sure that you aren't leaving
the food in there for more than 1 minute
so you can put the food in there for 1
minute and then take it out Stir It flip
it move it whatever it is and then put
it back for a second minute so that the
heating is more even and it doesn't
cause the creation of these toxins and
second obviously I'm not going to insult
your intelligence you already know not
to use Plastics in the microwave oven so
let's just leave it at that and here's
another thing so on this channel I've
always taken the science of things but
I've also always looked at the context
the history of stuff so when you look at
the microwave and you realize that the
biggest impact it had is not the
toxicity it's actually the social impact
it had an impact on the family structure
the family tradition so when I was a kid
there was no option of a microwave oven
the food was hot when it was prepared as
soon as my mom had the food ready she
would call us down me my father my
sibling we would join her and have a
dinner together the microwave oven
changes that it makes it such that
people can have their meals
independently they can just go grab
their food from the fridge heat it up
and have it at their own time this
concept of having meals alone is not
human it's not natural the microwave
oven has pulled families apart by
destroying a central family tradition of
having meals together and this happened
at the same time as when both parents
had to work in order to make ends meat
and children spent far more time in
their penitentiaries which they call the
public school system instead of playing
and enjoying nature being with their
parents being with siblings and friends
but I suppose that's a topic for a
different video I do absolutely want to
make a video on the education system and
how to essentially deprogram the wiring
which they gave us so here's a challenge
to you if you're so invested in
improving your life and avoiding toxins
the first step you can do to really make
your life better is to fix your family
relationships call your mom call your
dad call your grandparents actually
schedule a reminder on your phone like
for for real this is a high Roi task
schedule a reminder on your phone for
every single week you talk to your
grandparents and parents at least once a
week Imagine the health benefits that
they're going to receive their stress is
going to go lower which genuinely has
physiological effects on their body the
most honorable things you can do is to
take care of your parents and honor your
ancestors and that's far more important
than being scared of a microwave of them