if the human race was to go extinct
because of an alien invasion a super
volcano earthquake explosion an
incurable place an Intergalactic Civil
War at least that's kind of cool it's
not ideal but I'd be okay with it
because at least we went out fighting
and now imagine if mankind was to go out
because we literally couldn't reproduce
we couldn't do the one thing the one
thing that all of our ancestors managed
to do if the human race was to perish
just because we couldn't have kids
that's kind of pathetic you might think
the real problem is overpopulation
because that's what they want you to
think understand that the entire
propaganda against having children
is a psychological operation it's a
psyop the academics the elites and the
media think that humans are a curse on
nature they think we are a Cancer upon
this planet well the question becomes
what do you do with the cancer exactly
you might seek to kill it in one of many
ways you might seek to poison it and
make no mistake we are being poisoned
and let's look at the statement there's
too many people on this planet as Jordan
Peterson would say that's the most
implicitly genocidal statement you can
possibly make because what do you do
with a statement like that there's too
many people on the planet well what do
you do about that exactly do you
genocide them force them to have
abortions or perhaps you don't want to
get your hands dirty so you just shame
them into Oblivion you shame people into
not having kids you shame them into
living a life that's subpar because of
your false ideology it's more important
than ever now to understand what's in
our environment what's actually
poisoning Us and how to actually
mitigate these toxins I want you to
answer some questions why has sperm gone
Fallen by almost 50 percent actually
more than 50 percent in just 50 years
years why has the rate of miscarriage in
women almost doubled in the past 50 to
60 years why has the level of
testosterone in men fallen so
drastically over the past half decade
why has the age of puberty among women
kept decreasing that is to say girls are
hitting puberty earlier and earlier
every single year all this points
towards severe endocrine disruption in
our entire Society the clothes we wear
the food we eat the water we drink all
have been poisoned to one degree another
this is unacceptable to me hence this
channel the question then becomes can we
fix the Damage Done To Us well
absolutely yes we can fix the damage the
mainstream narrative is that in
developed Nations people are having less
and less kids because they choose not to
it's because women are more educated and
they rather work rather than have kids
that's the narrative that's been fed to
you they say that because of this
progress this amazing progress that
women don't want to have kids and this
is actually good for the environment
it's good for humankind I call [ __ ]
on their entire ideology what's
happening is a lot of people who want to
have kids are not able to because their
reproductive systems have been
systematically poisoned luckily for men
it's a little bit easier for us to fix
ourselves you see men produce sperm
throughout their entire lives almost so
if you take a man and you separate them
from all the toxins within a few months
despite firmative produces is going to
be healthy again however the truth for
women is a little bit more harsh which
means it's more important for women to
take care of themselves women are born
with a finite number of eggs which means
that when these eggs get damaged there's
no easy way to replace them while it is
more important for women to safeguard
their bodies against endocrine
disrupting chemicals it's also important
for men I don't want men to watch this
and think they're okay and they're
immune from the harm done by edcs that's
not the case all I'm saying is it's
easier for men to recover than it is for
women and think about it we have a
significant Advantage going into this
While most men and women have no idea
what's going on and they're getting
systematically poisoned you and me we're
working on ourselves we're working on
educating ourselves and safeguarding our
bodies from these toxins which means
that me and you are going to be some of
the most virile men on the face of the
Earth and if you're a woman watching
this you're going to be one of the most
hormonally balanced women out there
you're actively getting our hormonal
systems back online in 10 years Imagine
by the average men and women are going
to be and where you and I are going to
be another psyop is this whole men
versus women type of dynamic which
they're forced upon us this is not
organic this is not natural it is never
men versus women it was always men plus
women against the problem you know
there's this ancient Greek myth the
Greeks thought that the gods created
humans as a conglomerate as man and
woman in one body these beings these
proto-humans were so powerful that even
the gods were afraid of them so the gods
of Greece they split them into man and
woman so that they would be forever
powerless and they could never oppose
the gods very interesting very
interesting how that parallels to our
society today men and women are more
atomized than ever before separated they
distrust each other which makes both men
and women far easier to control by those
who see themselves as Gods the question
of course becomes are they poisoning us
intentionally or is it just some fluke
is it just because of corporate greed is
just because of a consequence of
industrialism and nobody actually knew
what the hell they were doing well of
course that's a possibility but the
truth is it doesn't really matter at the
micro level so in your level literally
what you can influence around you your
family and friends at some level it
doesn't matter if there's a huge
conspiracy or this is just the act of
the Invisible Hand of economy the
actionable steps remain the same then
that's Key Don't bind to ideas which
have no actionable steps that's
pointless focus on what you can do get
it done fix your own hormonal systems
help your friends and family and then
we'll discuss what we can do at a
societal level the situation is not as
hopeless as it seems you see nature
itself is on our side the universe wants
us to win if we spend the time to get
ourselves hormonally healthy and rid
ourselves of psychological operations
this is actually a problem that solves
itself literally evolution is on our
sides all those people who say it's bad
to have kids fine let them not have kids
let us who are invested in Tradition let
us who are pursuing virtue let us have
kids and our kids will be higher quality
than theirs our kids will be smarter
stronger wiser more intelligent and more
resilient than their kids we will
out-compete them at a genetic level so
we don't have to fight some kind of
ideological war when it comes to
psychological War we actually have the
upper hand time is on our side biology
is on our side
but when it comes to the chemical war
time is certainly not on our side we are
losing the chemical War get this there
is birth control in your water women who
consume birth control they peed out
those molecules are not destroyed those
molecules find themselves in the water
filtration plants which recycle the
water send it right back to your homes
then we consume literal birth control
molecules birth control is obviously a
hormonal inhibitor women who are on
birth control have the same menstrual
cycle as a woman who is pregnant now
think about this very carefully young
girls are being prescribed birth control
before they even hit puberty just so
that they can clear up their acne on
their face if you know anything about
young girls and even young boys they'll
do anything for appearance sake right
they'll do anything to not appear
blemished and ugly in high school high
school is freaking brutal it's it's
completely understandable the young
girls would accept putting birth control
into their bodies in order to remove
acne they don't know any better they're
young and their parents have been told
that it's healthy by the fraudulent
doctor prescribe this stuff it's
actually FDA approved to use birth
control as an acne prevention system
which is insane instead of using natural
ways to clear your skin they're asking
you to take birth control Instead This
should be criminal and yet it's
completely normalized and even later in
life a woman who's taking birth control
actually has her taste in men altered so
women who is on birth control right get
this women who are on birth control
prefer more feminine men in fact it's
even worse than that women on birth
control actually prefer men who kind of
look like their siblings most women who
are on birth control don't even know
this is happening no surprise then that
women who come off birth control in
order to have a child with their husband
realize their husbands are actually
dweebs and choose to leave them this
kind of mass medication and mass
altering of biological imperatives is
evil and yet that is the norm men and
women of virtue are not to be split
about by meaningless psychological
operations rather they should come
together and create a bulwark create a
wall behind which to raise powerful
children these children will be better
than us in every way they will be
hormonally intact and they'll be
psychologically resistant this is what
they fear and for good reason