the esoteric electrolyte Elixir this is
how you make it you need
honey you need table salt you need
potassium citrate you need magnesium
malate so you have three ions you have
the Magnesium you have the potassium and
you have sodium that makes a good
electrolyte but you also have some
simple carbs from the honey and you have
some protein from the collagen all
together it makes this the superior
electrolyte Elixir now you could make
something similar by using these Made
For You packets from lmnt it's fine but
it is kind of expensive and I do use
them but it's up to you if you want to
use that or not so first you have your
water and I hope you're using an RO
filter I hope you're using a distiller I
hope you're using at least a charcoal
filter something to purify your water
because you should not be drinking the
water straight from your TAP so you take
your water take some magnesium malate
it'll come with a spoon and you just
want to use half of the spoon which they
give you so it's about half of a
tablespoon just a little bit of
magnesium melon Just A Pinch maybe a big
pinch but you know I mean
then we have sodium chloride which is
just your regular table salt I have pink
salt you can use any salt doesn't really
matter so long as it's sodium chloride
half a teaspoon half a teaspoon of
sodium chloride
and then you have potassium citrate this
one you're going to use less of so not
even half a teaspoon you're going to use
one quarter of a teaspoon and even the
spoon which they give you is really
small so if I use use the spinach they
gave me so one small thing of potassium
citrate
so three ions and the ratio which I Told
You So sodium chloride magnesium malate
can be about the same and a little bit
less about half of those quantities for
the potassium citrate and that's a solid
electrolyte Foundation you can change
these ratios depending on what you need
but that's a more heavy topic which I
don't really need to go into this is a
solid electrolyte when you're starting
from scratch this is perfect you don't
need to overthink it and then we have of
course the collagen the collagen is an
interesting supplement it's definitely a
supplement which I recommend so collagen
is found in of course a lot of foods
chicken skins is a great source of
collagen any skin is a good source of
collagen because collagen is good for
your skin so collagen is one of the
primary proteins which make up our skin
so the more collagen you have in your
skin the more healthy more Vitality more
glow you'll have in your skin so this is
easy to drink it's just like water just
like water with salt but it has also
some protein so if I am not able to make
my esoteric eggnog Elixir which is
superior to this to be fair because it
has healthy fats as well the esoteric
eggnog Elixir takes time to make though
don't be afraid of carbs my guys I know
the keto Community has kind of
criminalized eating carbs it's the
refined carbs and the high fructose corn
syrups which mess you up not all carbs
are bad like honey is great I'll just
add half a tablespoon of honey to my
electrolyte drink and I did Heat this
water so this water is room temperature
I put it for 30 seconds in the microwave
that's going to allow the salt and the
Honey to dissolve in the water and the
collagen too and there we have it the
perfect the ultimate the esoteric
electrolyte elixir