wiim Phoenix is too old and is also kind
of ugly to play Napoleon Napoleon was
known for his Aura of command the fact
that he could inspire people to line up
to die for him and most importantly
Napoleon was young that's what has set
him apart so much from his
contemporaries his story and his Legend
are so alien to the modern bugman that
he tries to humanize Napoleon but can
you humanize a force of nature the
entire aim of this movie was to say that
Napoleon was nothing more than a loser
sing for a mid who just happened to be
at the right place at the right time
they want to say look here man your
great general of History was nothing
more than a [ __ ] and a sexual deviant
the only reason he had any ambition was
because of sexual frustration they want
to say that if he attained Glory it's
only because of his entrapment with
women either his wife Josephine or his
mother how the Barbie movie had more
masculine energy than Napoleon but fear
not this video EX exist to correct the
flaws of this Dreadful movie most people
don't know this but Napoleon was a man
out of his time and I mean that even in
the context of his own life Napoleon was
a great man in modern times people of
his own time were shocked into
submission by seeing a meteor in human
form or they were seduced into following
him as he had the aura of Destiny about
him but instead of focusing on such
higher Concepts as Destiny they could
have instead just focused on his
military achievements they could have
focused on his ability to inspire Fire
Devotion and maddening loyalty they
could have focused on his military and
economics reforms they could have
focused on his ability to bend entire
armies to his will whether his own or
his enemies they're going to focus on
his victory at yena or his maneuvering
at borodino but no instead they just
focus on Josephine 60% of the movie is
freaking Josephine and this is the most
boring and uninteresting part of his
life Napoleon could have been such a
phenomenal movie this could be the movie
that defined the genre of historical
films going forward but instead they
chose to make it a shitty be drama they
could have at the very least shown off
the opulence of the French Court they
could have shown off the architecture of
that time but no they chose to put this
gray blue filter on the entire movie
makes think the entire movie looks kind
of cold and dreary it's almost like they
want us to believe that the past was as
dark and dismal place this is not true
there was far more Beauty in the past
it's only now that our art is polluted
and our architecture fails to create any
kind of inspir ation in us so let us
look at Napoleon more closely and let us
use history and philosophy to guide us
into understanding the story Napoleon is
an example of a real life superhero he
was the manifestation of the spirit of
the French people I have a belief that
Napoleon was the Avatar of the French
people at that time he embodied their
pride and tactical Brilliance and
Amplified it to the maximum but he also
Amplified the sexual freedoms let's say
of the French people so when I say
Napoleon was a man of the people I mean
this very literally he was the
personification of the French population
at that time their entire hopes dreams
and frustrations came to be in the
embodiment of this one man and this
happens quite a few times in history
Caesar was the embodiment of the
tyrannical and hero worshipping aspect
of the Roman people and Ashoka was the
embodiment of the Hindu and Buddhist
philosophies brought to rule of course I
do not expect a modern Hollywood movie
to ponder on these deep topics I do not
expect them to be able to place so much
agency in their own characters all
protagonists especially if they are male
are made to be almost mentally
handicapped in order to make them more
humanized and more believable for
example the latest James Bond they
literally gave him PTSD for no reason we
watch Bond as an archetype and that's
exactly the case with Napoleon Napoleon
is to be seen as an archetype he's to be
seen as a force of nature not a man we
want to draw inspiration and draw power
from him but instead we have this of
course this goes against the Hollywood
narrative this is why Napoleon fails
while a movie like 300 shines of course
a movie like 300 will never be made
again because it shows the ravening
appetites of well-trained men and thei
doesn't even mention Napoleon's Marshals
how dare they make a movie about
Napoleon without talking about his
General his Marshals Marshall nay Murad
berad do aino and davu these were
celebrities in their own right these
were men who were praised across France
as much as Napoleon was and we don't
even get a mention of their names
instead we get a 60% of the movie
dedicated to Josephine the does
Napoleon's success come from his highly
talented generals and Marshals or does
it come from the source between
Josephine's legs the movie doesn't talk
about how Napoleon knew his soldiers by
name he would go among the ranks among
the lowest ranked soldiers know them by
name know their family history asked
them about their daughters asked them
about their hopes and aspirations and it
wasn't just simple Soldiers the greatest
artists of his time writers poets would
orbit around Napoleon like planets
around a star but the movie doesn't even
attempt to explain this magnitude and of
course Wen Phoenix is the complete wrong
choice for the lead role for this movie
Napoleon was not a crusty old looking
dude who looks like he needs a shower we
need a handsome young youth a man of
power and Charisma who looks as though
he could inspire people to follow him
onto death I nothing against JP as an
actor is just that he looks broken and
worn down which makes sense for movies
like Joker where he was phenomenal does
that make sense for Napoleon because
Napoleon was not broken he was a man
above his peers I could imagine a
situation where men are following Wen
Phoenix's character into battle is so D
and uncharismatic but speaking of which
the battle scenes were pretty cool they
showed only two battles they only showed
aitz and waterloop and both the battles
felt really short almost like the
battles were the interruption from the
main story line which is Napoleon and
Josephine still the battles were good
I'm going to give credit where it's due
the Battle of ostritz was really cool
it's cool to see how Napoleon sunk his
enemies by opening up the Frozen lake
under their feet using cannon fire
there's also a scene near the start of
the movie where Napoleon uses grape shot
against his own French citizens and this
is how the director should have undercut
the hero Narrative of Napoleon see I
don't think Napoleon was a good guy
Napoleon was not the good guy if you in
fact if you wanted to show Napoleon as
the villain of the story you could
absolutely do that you are more than
free to show Napoleon as capricious
tyrannical over ambitious evil even you
can absolutely make Napo to be seen as a
nemesis of mankind this is all a
reasonable approach what is not a
reasonable approach is to make him seem
like a bumbling idiot who only cares
about and he only has success because he
was at the right time and right place
this is not reasonable so that scene
when Napoleon opens fire on his own
friends people this is historically
accurate and this does show what length
Napoleon would go to achieve success but
the scene was cut short and doesn't have
the impact it should have had see if you
wanted to show Napoleon as a conflict
icted figure an egomaniac and as a power
hungry Tyrant you absolutely could do
that and that would be a legitimate way
to show Napoleon was not somebody to
emulate that's fine but instead they
show him as a puppet [ __ ] to his wife
Josephine and the movie also did one
more good thing it showed the irony of
the French Revolution so the French
Revolution for those who do not know was
a revolution in which the monarchy of
France was deposed and replaced by a
people's Rule and this went just about
as well as you'd expect the people's
rule was even more more brutal and
bloody than the monarchy ever was so the
monarchy was a strict hierarchy and when
the people's rule came to be they tried
to make it as though everybody was equal
and there was perfect egalitarian
society didn't quite happen like that
and this led to many ironic moments for
example when Josephine's son not
Napoleon son Josephine had a son before
Napoleon he asks Napoleon for his
father's sword as a memorabilia and
Napoleon explains that citizens aren't
allowed to hold weapons in this New
France and this reminded me of the soku
i period in Japan as soon as power was
Consolidated in the hands of a few the
first thing which they always do is to
confiscate the Weaponry of the citizens
this is a very common tactic which all
tyrants use so understand this the
freedom of the American people is not in
the First Amendment but rather in the
second but speaking of the French
Revolution the American Revolution was
actually happening at a similar time so
why did the French Revolution fail so
abysmally while the American Revolution
succeeded is because of one man and this
brings us to the theories of history and
that one single man that One Singular
man was George Washington there are two
views of looking at history one is the
great man view of History this says that
great men singular men at the
appropriate times basically dictated the
course of history the opposite view the
Marxist view is that grand socioeconomic
changes is what drives history and any
of these names from history you know
Napoleon Caesar Alexander Etc these are
just leaves upon the stream of History
this notion I reject history is made by
individuals the fact that the American
Revolution did not follow the same
trajectory as the French Revolution
comes down to the actions and ethics of
that one man General George Washington
he was a man who was entirely
uncorruptible and he chose by himself to
abdicate power rather than hold it for
himself on the other hand the movie
shows Napoleon to be a bumbling idiot
who just happens to luck out every now
and then but this is completely
inaccurate Napoleon was not at the right
place at the right time he made the
right place and the right time so
Napoleon failed you say Napoleon didn't
achieve what he set out to and he got
exiled yeah in fact he got exiled twice
and even in here there is a Learning
lesson after his disastrous campaign in
Russia speaking of disaster campaigns
the movie completely neglects to mention
his campaign in Spain they completely
don't even mention that Napoleon sent
his armies to Spain of course that's a
story onto itself so Napoleon met with
some serious opposition in the Iberian
Peninsula got to askap really but we
don't want to talk about that that we
just want to talk about Josephine
apparently in this movie and this is so
pathetic man Napoleon's generals were
such charismatic leaders on their own
right each of them was a crazy character
and each of them were so different from
each other you could create an entire
movie about each of Napoleon's Marshals
but no they weren't even mentioned by
name instead 60% of the damn runtime was
given over to Josephine Josephine's only
contribution to history was to be a [ __ ]
but even in defeat there are learning
lessons to be had Elba was a small
little fishing Village it was an island
and they exiled Napoleon to basically be
in confinement over there and you know
what they retired him when Napoleon met
with defeat in Russia and came back they
gave him 2 million Franks per year to
just go and retire in Elba he could have
literally just gone to Elba lived his
life out and relaxed but no he was a man
of Titanic energy there was no such
thing as Stillness for this man instead
he actually took control of the island
of Elba and developed it so El was just
a random sleepy little fishing town but
after Napoleon came he modernized that
little village the same little sleepy
town which was existing in that same
exact state of stasis for probably
hundreds of years now became a modern
Village because of Napoleon's presence
and his or of command his ability to
strategize his Ambitions for his people
around him that's what I mean when I say
a single man can make all the difference
this man literally couldn't stop himself
from developing and developing the
people around him and then he Escape I
say I am
Napoleon I am Emperor Napoleon escaped
from his Exile from the island of Elba
and came back to the French Mainland and
every single Monarch in Europe
collectively [ __ ] themselves at his
arrival the French monarchy so what
happened was when Napoleon was deposed
they reinstalled the French monarchy and
this French monarchy sent Army after
Army to destroy Napoleon before he can
come to Paris and they all failed
because as soon as they saw the man who
they fought for and who fought with them
they wouldn't be able to fire upon Him
rather they would actually change their
size they would defect and they would
join Napoleon and there is a scene about
this in the movie but it's so brief it's
almost forgettable this is the aura of
Napoleon man this is the thing which
neolin is known for his Aura of presence
and command the idea that he could go up
to an army and say hey boys I know you
know me I know you recognize me I fought
by you in every single battle that we
were in
why would you point your guns towards me
why not join me let's take France back
and make it great again that was what
Napoleon stood for and every Army did
defect they joined Napoleon instead of
the armies destroying him each Army made
Napoleon stronger and stronger until he
had built up well he didn't rebuild his
entire Army right but he built up a
decent enough force and every other
Monarch in Europe had to combine forces
to deal with Napoleon he was outnumbered
something like 3 to1 or something like
that something terrible this this movie
does a terrible job of showing why
Napoleon inspired such levels of
devotion it doesn't even try to explain
it and this is the Mystique this is the
challenge the director has completely
missed out on the challenge of Napoleon
the idea of Napoleon and Josephine and
him being a cockold and other that's the
easy way out that's the easy and boring
and lame part of Napoleon's life which
is very easy to portray in a movie The
Challenge is to portray Napoleon's
Charisma the challenge is to portray
Napoleon's power of inspiration how do
you do that on the screen that's a real
challenge the movie completely fails to
deliver upon the vision of the loyalty
and Brotherhood within the French army
and of course their allegiance to the
emperor of France Napoleon and so for
all these reasons I give this movie a
one French bare skin hat out of five if
you enjoyed this it's more than likely
that you'll enjoy my review on movie 300
a movie that some people think is
historically inaccurate but is actually
completely authentic to the mindset of
the Greeks at that time or perhaps you
would want to watch my review on the
Barbie movie which ironically is more
masculine than the Napoleon Movie I'll
have these tiles pop up shortly go ahead
and watch if you so please