I'm a simple man if it's good enough for
wice Gera it's good enough for me I've
been schoning raw eggs for the past 2
years or more one raw egg in the morning
one raw egg at night and on top of that
I'll have hardboiled eggs with the shell
on and this is exactly what Bruce Lee
did so you see these shells are pure
calcium and they are massively
beneficial for tooth Health by tooth
sensitivity issues are completely gone
but you say what about the Sal Manilla
risk what about food poisoning if you
schlunk them raw and what about the bio
deficiency a lot of people might have
heard that if you have raw eggs it's
going to cause biotin deficiency and I'm
going to answer all these questions and
more in this video you see most people
don't know this but Factory farmed eggs
come from a result of animal torture
these Factory farmed they starve these
birds for weeks on and stress them out
they start losing their plumage so their
feathers and this is a process called
forced multing and after this they
manipulate the artificial lights to kind
of stress them more and make them think
it's always daytime so after this forced
molting period which is torture on its
own they're laying a lot of eggs per day
and really big eggs so from a
productivity standpoint from an output
standpoint it makes sense which is why
it's legal in the US this practice is
completely illegal in India UK and the
EU it's no surprise that these highly
stressed diseased chickens are laying
eggs which have bacterial contamination
this is the same story as with cows if
you pump cows full of hormones and
destroy their immune system then of
course their milk is going to be
contaminated requiring pasteurization
but coming back to eggs it's not the egg
itself that's the danger it's not the
egg itself that's toxic it's more so the
farming practices so I'll prove this to
you in Japan right in Japan it's
actually very very common to have eggs
Raw it's a part of their regular
breakfast they'll just take an egg raw
break it over some rice and that's
breakfast there's not this huge hysteria
or fear around raw eggs there and the
reason is that they have better
standards and for that reason I do not
fear food poisoning risk with with eggs
because I'm purchasing the best quality
eggs there is this is pasturised non-
GMO egg so these H have been living
their best life out in nature eating
insects small lizards they get carrot
they get all kinds of different stuff
and they're healthy chickens living out
in the sunlight so these eggs have a lot
of vitamin D and because they're not
immune compromised these eggs don't have
the same level of risk as a lowquality
factory farmed eggs that being said
should you consume wrong eggs I cannot
make the decision for you and I don't
make any recommend recomendations in
this
video also you got to think about what
the chicken themselves are eating if
your chicken is grain Fed so you're
buying lowquality eggs grain fed chicken
are fed with basically low quality corn
and lowquality soybean both of which are
likely contaminated with zaa which is a
mold estrogen and of course soy contains
phytoestrogens so you're eating an
estrogen bomb if you're eating
lowquality egg on the other hand if
you're eating high quality eggs like
what this is you're getting the best in
terms of B vitamins protein literally
everything which brings us to biotin raw
egg whites can create a biotin
deficiency a lot of you might have heard
that if you eat eggs Raw it's actually
not that good for you because the egg
albumin it contains something called
avidin which is a protein and this
avidin it it binds to Biotin and biotin
is a B vitamin it's very required for
the body for healthy functioning and the
idea is because it's aidin is binding to
biotin it doesn't get absorbed by our
stomach our digestive system I should
say and therefore cooked eggs are better
than raw eggs because avidin is
destroyed by the process of cooking but
this doesn't really track because
cooking only destroys up to 60% of the
avidin in eggs anyway so even if you do
cook your eggs you're still getting 40%
of evidence so cooking isn't even that
effective as destroying evidence and
also biotin deficiency is very uncommon
especially in fact it's impossible to
get a biotin deficiency if you're on an
animal-based diet unless you have some
kind of genetic predisposition so no
you're not going to get biotin
deficiency because you eat raw eggs now
the concern around salmonella or food
poisoning that's fair enough that's a
risk assessment that you have to make
but the concern around biotin deficiency
is not realistic in my opinion that
concern only exists if you're schoning
like whole cartons of raw eggs every day
and the thing is you can see biotin
deficients coming it's not like a
surprise event biotin deficiency you're
going to lose skin quality you're going
to lose hair quality and my hair and
skin quality have only gotten better
with time but I'm sure that I don't have
any kind of bioin
deficiency and if you choose to have raw
eggs when should you have them I
personally have them one in the morning
and one at night before I sleep so
that's right I have Incorporated a small
breakfast into my routine I've
experimented with different things I
found that one fruit usually a kiwi plus
one raw egg works
amazingly now is there any benefits of
raw egg versus cooked eggs no I don't
think so it's just a matter of
preference for me at least so what I'll
do is it depends okay first off it
depends how you break the egg because
that's also a massive counter to any
salmonella risk so I'm going to show you
that and like I said it's just a matter
of convenience I don't want to take out
time to boil an egg or make an omelette
sometimes in the morning I just want to
get my nutrition in Fast and I really
try to minimalize my morning routine as
much as possible literally it's three
things first Sal second sunshine and
three shower so literally wake up of
course use the bathroom go outside get
some sunshine into my eyes come back in
have some electrolytes and third go and
have a shower it doesn't even have to be
a cold shower just a regular shower will
do and then I'll come to my kitchen
schlank an egg have a kiwi and my day
starts I should also say especially in
Winter you want to incorporate eggs in
your diet for the Vitamin D benefit of
course you're always choosing pasture
raised and you're never going to have
your regular store-bought styrofoam
[ __ ] eggs again in your
life so how do you break an egg easy do
not use a fork to smash your eggshells
do not use a sharp corner to break your
eggshell because what happens is when
you do that the fragments of eggshell
will actually shoot into the egg and
could potentially contaminate the egg or
at the very least now you have a sharp
piece inside your mouth so much better
way to do it is just a FL flat surface
so like this table take the
egg brisk tap you'll have you'll have
like a what do you call it like a
depression right you'll have a
depression the membrane behind the shell
is still intact so it's not going to
leak at this point so you have the
depression you just bring it over your
um you know your cup whatever it is use
your thumbs to just divide the egg and
it'll pour out and you've basically
minimized any chance of the egg touching
the the shell cuz it's usually the shell
if it contains any bacteria it's going
to be on the shell not inside the egg so
my shell did not really touch the
albumen doesn't really touch the yolk so
we have pure egg albumen and yolk in in
this cup and it's just a matter of
schlunk it's just like a taking a
shot there we have it Egg Long right so
how much time did that take maybe 30
seconds at most and then I'll have a
kiwi or a banana but whatever your fruit
you choose make sure that you actually
wash it well with either 10% salt
solution or apple cider vinegar 10%
solution so that any of the pesticides
and insecticides are removed from the
surface of the fruit so cholesterol
which eggs have cholesterol cholesterol
is what transforms into either
testosterone or cortisol or a a number
of different hormones but let's talk
about these two I want to bias the
formation of testosterone over cortisol
and having a small little breakfast in
the morning lowers your stress and
allows your body to do just that on top
of that eggs are important for another
reason so eggs contain sulfur and sulfur
can bind to and neutralize Unbound iron
in your blood this is important because
you don't want Unbound iron in your
blood it's a whole different topic of
course it has to do with heavy metal
toxicity but if you want a full course
like a full course on every single detox
topic imaginable everything from emfs
all the way to parasites and of course
xenoestrogens and everything else then I
do have that course ready down
below and speaking of eating eggs with
the shell on is this something worth
doing yes but this is after hard boiling
and that's because you're actually
eating the shell and the shell could be
contaminated so yeah you absolutely want
to boil the shell before you eat the
whole thing and how often should you eat
the Shell with the egg at least once a
week just eat the whole damn egg it's
not that bad you can you can eat this I
mean like this one is not boiled
obviously it's just from the carton but
if I boil this egg I will smash it I'll
smash it whole with the shell for the
calcium benefits 100% legit Bruce Lee
did it all the time if it's good enough
for Bruce Le is good enough for you and
me