if your brain feels like this then you
have brain rot you struggle to focus on
productive things but very easily slip
into bad habits I'm telling you this
right now you will lose years of your
youth if you don't fix this right now I
will give you an ancient technique that
I unlocked by reading old text and the
biographies of snipers there are more
than 150 guys who are doing this
technique daily and they are seeing some
really cool results so this will work
for you 100% of the time I have used
this technique as a an engineering
student to increase my focus to get
better grades I've used it to Do
genetics research as a biosciences PhD
student and I've even used this to be
more accurate with the M4 rifle as a
soldier in training at Ford Benning
Georgia this technique shows results
from day one and it is not like the
standard meditation techniques that
takes weeks to get into the best part is
it's kind of fun to do and it has a
clear way to track your progress I will
provide you all the resources you need
I'm not going to be gatekeeping any of
my knowledge brain Rod happens when your
brain circuitry is compromised by
external over stimulation porn video
games and doom scrolling can do this
every time you do an action the neural
circuit Tre associated with that action
are strengthened so there's this vicious
cycle that keeps you trapped forever you
can literally observe your ability to
concentrate go down you can feel the
level of self-respect you have go down
you can even feel your intelligence and
creativity fall off a cliff but there is
a way out not only can you push through
all this [ __ ] you can actually
strengthen your brain in the process and
come out smarter and more more
intelligent more creative and more
resilient you can come out with better
control of your behavior and even the
manner of your speech you can emerge
from this with creativity and
productivity that you need to change
your life the human brain is the most
complex single entity in the known
universe and perhaps the most remarkable
thing about it is its ability to change
the most common advice given to guys who
are stuck is just go to the gym bro and
you know what that's actually really
good advice physical effort cuts to the
mental [ __ ] going to the gym and
seeing your body transformed shows you a
new way plus when you start going to the
gym you want to optimize your diet to
maintain your gains so you start eating
cleaner this further declutters your
brain however there's a weakness in this
method and I've seen this in myself and
clients and friends and the weakness is
that the ego built upon just physical
growth is fragile and a small setback
can send you back to your old Baseline
I've experienced this myself getting fit
does wonders for the mind but the
progress can be set back by even a small
failure one girl Rejects you and you
feel inadequate again not only that but
you start getting new anxieties what if
I'm not big enough and you'll start even
creating new copes I'll ask her out next
month when I'm bigger you never get big
enough to match your self-image this is
body dismorphia what you want is a
robust mind the kind of mind that does
not take damage from failure in the
ideal case we want an anti- fragile mind
that actually get stronger with failure
I don't think you can get there with the
gym alone another popular approach is
that of meditation meditation also works
the benefits are legit you get
measurable results you can feel your
mind becoming immune to setbacks you
start making better decisions as a
strategist and the most fun part is you
gain new social skills well technically
you don't gain social skills it's more
that you can actually apply the skills
that you already had because you're more
present but I mean you get the point
right but even meditation has a weakness
well the first weakness is that it takes
so long to get results you can go months
without feeling like you're making any
progress but the other is if you force
yourself to meditate you'll quickly
associate meditation with pain and soon
as life gets in the way you'll just quit
because you haven't got any you know
positive feedback from it we all know
that meditation works but how many
actually do this on a daily basis not
many and that's because it's a hard
habit to get into and an easy Habit to
fall out of I believe this is because
meditation Focus entirely on the mental
and I disagree with this approach one of
the key principles of esoteric health is
that the mind and the body are one it
follows that training one without the
other is flawed it is from this
realization that I started experimenting
I needed a technique that could see
results from day one so there's no
chance of quitting before I see results
I needed a technique that doesn't take
more than 10 minutes per day and will
give me a tangible power boost
throughout the day I got this technique
by studying military history and tactics
in almost every biography I read about
The Life and Adventures of elite modern
soldiers there's one commonality the
importance of controlling heart rate and
bread and this makes sense because the
modern Battlefield is not a place place
where you need to be the most physically
aggressive it's about Precision movement
and communication it requires clear
thinking and overall awareness think
about modern Weaponry even with a
standard issue M4 even with a simple Red
Dot site you can reliably get rounds On
Target from 300 M away and it's not
about how hard you squeeze the trigger
obviously it's about how stable you can
keep the Red Dot on the Target and this
requires breath control if you don't
have control over your body your own
physiology then you're going to miss
your Target because even a millimeter of
deviation of the Gun Barrel can cause
several meters of deviation at range the
second component is spatial awareness
you need to be aware of the peripheral
vision to be able to detect new targets
so the fundamentals of Modern Combat are
breath and spatial awareness so it
should be a zero surprise that the
military trained soldiers especially
snipers and operators on these aspects
this is the technique that I'm going to
share with you right now I'm going to
present to you the esoteric meditation
protocol I'm going to explain how it
works and provide you the exact guidance
you need to see results as you know one
of the core esoteric Health principles
is that the mind and body are one this
means the protocol must train both in
the same session so how does this work
we divide our 10-minute session into two
parts the first is the stress test and
the remaining 9 minutes are minutes of
spherical awareness the stress test is
to activate your sympathetic nervous
system your fight or flight response and
the spherical awareness part rapidly
cools you down into the parasympathetic
state which is your relaxed State this
process is similar to what a swordsmith
uses to temper his blade first the blade
is red hot but you immediately plunge it
into cold water this rapid cooling is
what actually strengthens the blade and
so it is with your mind so we heat up
the Mind using this stress test and then
we rapidly cool it down using spherical
awareness in order to strengthen the
mind let me explain in more detail so
what is this stress test it's is doing
the maximum amount of push-ups that you
can do in 1 minute why push-ups well
easily you can do push-ups basically
anywhere your room the airport School
literally anywhere you don't need any
kind of equipment to do it but here's
the catch it's not the specific number
of push-ups that you need to do it's
that you need to do as many push-ups as
you can in 60 seconds this means that
the difficulty scales with your level of
experience for a beginner maybe you can
only push out like 10 push-ups right but
those 10 push-ups would be challenging
if you're an expert maybe you can get 50
push-ups total but I guarantee you the
last 10 push-ups are still going to be
very painful and challenging so it's an
equalizer the last few reps are always
going to be a mental Challenge and
that's the point the the pain and the
honesty of hard physical work is just
what cleanses the mind and removes any
silly little depression or anxiety that
might be residing in your brain but
naturally this calisthenic workout is
going to give you a stressed state which
is the point your breathing will be
heavy your heart rate will be elevated
and that kind of state is not associated
with meditation at all traditional
meditation is all about the mind it's
all about relaxation and being calm
however the stress state is the kind of
condition you'd be expecting if you were
in combat a sniper would need to be able
to rapidly bring himself from the stress
State back into this parasympathetic
relaxed state in order to take the shot
and that's what we're going to be doing
the second phase of the esoteric
meditation protocol is spherical
awareness spherical awareness is a
technique that trains spatial
intelligence gymnasts and martial
artists use this technique to increase
their canes thesia which is um it's a
fancy word for the awareness of your
body in 3D space very cool technique
especially for self-defense with or
without weapons also very beneficial in
Social environments because allows you
to read micro Expressions at a
subconscious level and get the feel of
the room if you know what that means the
spherical meditation part is difficult
to explain with words it's a more
experienced thing it's like it's like
trying to explain how to ride a bike by
just talking about it it's not feasible
there's a part of it which you kind have
to do in order to experience in order to
learn so I will upload another video
which is a full guided meditation on how
to do spherical awareness so after you
finish this video go to that and
practice it for yourself to see the
benefits the esoteric meditation
protocol gives you results from day one
but the results only compound and you
can see a step change in the benefits
after the first week for this reason
I've created this 30-day challenge in
order to keep you consistent a
day-by-day training that will guide you
at every step I will do the push-ups
with you I'll will guide you through the
spherical awareness process I've built
out this course to deliver a new module
every day so you can maintain your
consistency it's like a video game that
unlocks new levels as you finish the
previous one it will be as though I'm
with you training and meditating it's a
challenge to do any good habit for 30
days but having a new module drop every
single day gives you a sense of
progression you can see in this
community that people are sharing photos
of their progress tracker there's even a
7-Day Hall of Fame for those who have
been consistent for 7 Days the last time
I showed this off there was only 60 guys
in here now there's more than double
many new members have started to engage
in this weird but simple meditation
protocol right now it's practically free
so if you're thinking of joining the
best time is literally today link is in
the description