the 8020 rule states that 80% of the
outcomes come from 20% of the causes it
works in theory but I found it hard to
use in practice the promise of the 8020
rule is that if you could figure out
just the 20% of the stuff that actually
matters you can get away by doing just
that however it's not that easy it's
hard to know what 20% is the right 20%
for example let's take any complex task
let's say I want to make a YouTube video
what's the 8020 on that is it the title
is it the thumbnail the hook is it the
camera is it the audio is it the actual
words I say is it my camera presence is
it the topic that I choose all of these
seem important if I was to impose the
8020 rule which of these would represent
that magic 20% that gets the result I
don't know I'll use another example
let's say we want to get into shape we
need gym membership we need maybe
supplements better food better sleep
like I can make a long list of things
which you need to get the physique that
you want the purpose of the 8020 rule is
to reduce complexity I think it does do
a good job of that except that I needed
a little bit more structure before I
could personally take the actionable
steps required to get outcomes at the
end of the day I only care about
outcomes I do not seek to entertain you
or even educate you I'm going to share
with you a quick and easy mental model
that serves me better than the 8020 rule
does I use something called the 93 rule
or simply The Big Three rule the 93 rule
states that 90% of the outcomes come
from the top three causes so another way
of stating it would be what three sub
problems do you need to solve in order
to solve the main problem let's do some
examples let's say I want to create a
YouTube video what three problems do I
need to solve it's going to be packaging
script and topic there are other things
to be sure like audio or video quality
but without these three nothing else
matters and here's the cool part The Big
Three rule is inherently hierarchical
and you can use it recursively I'll
explain what I mean by that what this
means is now you can hit the sub
problems with the big three Hammer again
to reveal these smaller sub problems
which you can now solve what's the big
three on packaging oh it's thumbnail
it's title and the hook cool we can
solve those there's tutorials on YouTube
to make good thumbnails titles and hooks
what's the big three on the topic Choice
well again it's timeliness its
importance and its relevance to the
audience you can research and fix each
of these in order to solve the main
problem suddenly the strategy the action
steps become more clear to you because
you've broken the problem down into
manageable components now I take zero
credit for this rule I'm not sure when I
started using it but hey I thought it
was useful so now I'm giving it to you
you can even apply the big three rule to
behavior what's the big three on camera
presence okay it's eye contact it's it's
Clarity of speech and perhaps it's also
hand gestures right each of these is a
trainable Behavior each of these I can
train somebody to replicate now let's
apply this technique to an even bigger
question what makes a good Lifestyle the
triangle of lifestyle is health wealth
and relationships the big three on
health is nutrition exercise and
Recovery the big three on wealth is
going to be income investment and
spending the big three on relationships
is going to be friends family and female
attraction you can solve wealth if you
increase income increase investment and
decrease spending you have solved
relationships if you build friendships
have family ties and build female
attraction but now you're thinking well
it's easier said than done right exactly
I never said it would be easy I said it
would be simple those are not the same
things but the good thing is the big
three rule allows you to break things
down until you have a clear actionable
step so let's go into health I said the
first of the big three on health is
nutrition but what's the big three on
nutrition in other words what three
problems do you need to solve in order
to solve 90% of nutrition well you need
to answer what to eat you need to answer
how much to eat you need to answer when
to eat if you solve these three problems
you have solved nutrition let's do
another example what's the big three on
exercise it's consistency Progressive
overload and injury prevention if you do
these three you're good you'll 100% see
results if you just focus on these three
aspects of exercise now let's go to a
different part of this what's the big
three on income I'm a business owner so
for me it's going to be Marketing sales
and delivery as in I get people to see
who I am that's called marketing I show
people that I can solve a problem that
they have that's called sales and I
actually solve those problems that's
called delivery if I do do just these
three things at a high level I'm good I
don't have to worry about income if I
execute on these three aspects of income
at the same time if I [ __ ] up on any of
these then I'm screwed the big three
rule is derived from a method called me
which was created by the world's biggest
consulting company called McKenzie it
stands for mutually exclusive
collectively exhaustive let's talk about
the mutually exclusive part mutually
exclusive means that there are no
crossovers between the sub Parts when
you break down the hole in the ideal
case each subpart is its own problem
that does not interact with other
problems now this isn't always perfect
for example if you break down Health
into nutrition exercise and Recovery you
of course know that a bad diet can
affect exercise and bad exercise can
affect recovery just because there are
some crossovers doesn't mean you can't
use the rule just be smart and try to
minimize not eliminate these
interactions the second part is
collectively exhaustive collectively
exhaustive means that if the subp parts
of the hole are added up they represent
100% of the hole this is where the big
three rule diverges from the traditional
me method the traditional me method
requires that the hole is broken down
into as many parts as it takes until we
can be sure that the parts can be added
up to recreate the hole for the kind of
Consulting work that mckenzi does this
makes a lot of sense but for what we are
going to use this for we don't need all
the parts let me explain this is because
most complexity follows a power law
distribution meaning when you start
breaking down a problem the first chunk
represents a very large part of the
initial problem the second chunk might
be big as well but it is smaller than
the first the third chunk is a bit
smaller but still significant the fourth
chunk the fifth chunk and so on are
going to be smaller and smaller and
smaller they're going to matter less and
less so I'd rather focus on the big
three that I need to get right and then
I can move on to the smaller problems me
requires you to get all the chunks but
the big three rule requires that you
find just the biggest three chunks
that's the difference even so there is a
potential problem that you will face how
many recursions of the big three rule do
you need to do now what do I mean by
that when we had health as a complex
topic we broke it down into nutrition
exercise and Recovery when we broke
exercise I broke it down into
consistency Progressive overload and
injury prevention but even these are too
big there's too much complexity it
doesn't lead to an actionable step we
need to keep breaking it down we break
it down until we reach actionable steps
for example let's break down consistency
what is consistency it means essentially
you're working out for weeks and months
and years if we break that down we
realize we're already consistent with
many habits we brush our teeth every day
we shower every day and most of us pull
up Instagram or social media every day
here's the cool part all of these are
learned behaviors you learn to brush
your teeth consistently because your
parents provided you the accountability
when you were little we shower
consistently because we don't want to be
seen as a smelly person in other words
we want hygiene to be a part of our
identity we get on Instagram
consistently because the app is designed
in a way to inject a reward into our
brain if we apply the big three
consistency breaks down into
accountability identity and reward now
we have something we can work with now
we have the ingredients to create a
system that delivers each of these now
we have something that we can bring
change not only to ourselves but to
others is using such principles that I
have created Crusade now coming back to
the big three rule why does it work as
Julius Caesar said DV day at impera
divide and conquer essentially The Big
Three rule allows you to divide and
conquer your problems in the same way
that Julius Caesar divided and conquered
Gaul which as you know culminated in the
Epic Siege at Alysia when Caesar was
besieging the GS he was in turn besieged
by the GS it was a double encirclement
there was the GS in the center Caesar
surrounded them and then he himself was
surrounded by a huge Army of GS in this
terrible position where you have enemies
on the inside and the outside Caesar
decided that there was three things that
he could not let slip otherwise it all
goes to [ __ ] number one was the
fortifications of the Legion if the
walls broke the legion would be crushed
number two was the supplies if Caesar
didn't have supplies we didn't manage
Logistics he would be killed by
starvation instead of Spears the third
was the morale of the troops Caesar
himself led the charge in the fighting
because he knew that his presence would
light the troops on fire and they would
not back down so long as he doesn't back
down if you read the GIC Wars Caesar
used the big twe rule be like Caesar
sadly we are 2,000 years too late to
join Caesar's Legion but hey you might
be in time to join mine if you found the
big three rule useful you need to apply
it now so you can learn it forever try
to apply the big three rule to something
in your life right now in the comment
section so I want you to comment below
your big three analysis of any topic
that you choose let me even give you
some quick examples to show you how wide
we can go with this stuff what's the big
three on driving a car safely well it's
going to be going to be control it's
going to be attention and it's going to
be the speed at which you drive what's
the big three on looking good in your
clothes well it's going to be fit for
obvious reasons it's going to be the
quality of your clothes again for
obvious reasons and it's going to be
congruence as in the style should be
congruent with your persona I wear well
ironed polos I wear high quality wi
necks I wear black jeans I wear
accessories like my Seiko alpinist I
wear my personel sunglasses you know I'm
going for a classy sophisticated look
which makes sense for me because that's
how I want to present myself to the
world that's what resonates with me
you'll never catch me in oversized
t-shirts or Street Wear it's not that
that's wrong it just means it's not
congruent with my style regardless we're
getting off topic let me give you the
homework here's the homework for today
I'm going to drop a list of topics in
the comment Bonus Goes to the most
useful breakdown and the funniest
breakdown and remember if you do not
sacrifice for your dreams your dreams
become the sacrifice