so who is gay
[Music]
first they call them crazy they called
him a lunatic they called him a liar
then they called him a racist I transfer
a homophobe it's not funny but
regardless of the other crazy claims
that he has made over his long career
the fact is they did turn the frogs game
and if you're lucky we might be able to
see a gay frog today the same chemical
atrazine that turns to Frog's gay well
it doesn't even just turn them gay it
actually turns them trans it messes with
their reproductive organs and mutates
them and destroys them that same
chemical atrazine is actually present in
your drinking water too so get this
atrazine is actually 100 percent banned
in the European Union so the EU banned
it completely but not in the U.S in the
U.S atrazine is the second most popular
herbicide right behind glyphosate which
is Roundup which is probably just as bad
as atrazine U.S we don't really care we
just say [ __ ] it so if you think I'm not
a frog and I don't care about the
environment
well you're a dumbass atrazine is in
your water supply and it has very
similar effects on humans as it does
with frogs
so they actually did experiments with
mice embryos and they found that my
embryos literally die when exposed to
atrazine and then they did other studies
with show Hall atrazine affects humans
and unsurprisingly it's highly toxic to
us literally atrazine is an estrogen so
which means
that it competes
with testosterone and tanks your
hormonal Supply and of course you know
the testosterone is an important well
it's the most important
hormone for a young man's health
literally this is what determines your
mental health it determines your
motivational levels
so if you find that you have no energy
you have no motivation and you have no
discipline it could literally be a
hormonal issue it's not a moral issue
you know what I mean like it's not
because you're a bad person or you're a
lazy person literally you have poisons
in your water
that are turning you unmotivated and
undisciplined
there's no way I think I can make it
let's go
this is about to be a challenge
in this self-improvement community on
YouTube we often talk about things like
meditation and journaling and all this
stuff which is obviously these are good
habits right
but making money
Etc always a good habits but
think about it you're literally fighting
an uphill battle against your body every
single day as long as you're being
poisoned by these substances in our
environment so I believe the first step
in self-improvement is actually a detox
not a dopamine detox but an actual detox
removing toxins from your body now
you're going to think I'm some kind of
liberal hippie type person it's not the
case
I think America is sadly divided on many
issues and one of those issues has
become environmental toxins you know and
this is stupid
both conservatives and liberals should
agree
that the environment is a critically
important part of our well-being as
humans and we being the stewards of this
planet have a moral duty
to upkeep our environment and of course
even if you're being selfish literally
having a good environment is important
for our own well-being
you think I can make this
I don't think I can make this
I'm gonna try
okay almost there
we're gonna go
okay I wasn't in that bad I know I was
so scared that's crazy so think about it
you're on self-improvement
you're doing all the important things
all the good things meditation Etc but
you're still not seeing results and
every day is a challenge and there's no
momentum that's actually not how it
should be if you think about it
self-improvement
should be the most natural and easy
thing for a man to do this literally
should be programmed in our genes to
self-improve but it's not the case
because our hormonal systems have been
hijacked by these artificial
environmental estrogens which literally
destroy our motivation Drive happiness
our sex drive and our drive to make
money and have success in life
so you might ask well is this scientific
is everything which I'm saying true well
yes and I'll link the studies down below
and it's not a secret scientists have
been talking about the effects of
atrazine and other estrogenics on the
environment and on the human body for
quite some time now but we've just
decided as a society to ignore
the call you know everybody in the
so-called masculinity space they all
talk about how you know civilization is
ending and it's all because of feminism
or it's all about socialism
etc etc I think this is a mistake I
think the bigger problem which kind of
goes under the radar
is literal toxins in our bloodstream
think about it is is an ideology in a
half-baked ideology could have more
impact on our success as a civilization
or actual poison in our bloodstream and
this reminds me of this one thing I read
about the Roman Empire as it is
declining there was more and more
instances of people being mad you know
Madness and you would call that mental
illness today you wouldn't call it
Madness today and it was on the rise
because of many reasons but one reason
which historians have come to is because
there was lead in Roman pipes so the
pipes which Romans got their water from
had lead in it and of course the Romans
didn't know that lead was toxic so they
didn't see the connection between lead
in their pipes and increase in the cases
of Madness and mental illness in their
City
so are we in a similar position today
then where we're barely understanding
the effect of microplastics and
environmental estrogens on our
bloodstreams and maybe 100 years from
today we'll look back and think oh these
you know 21st century people they
they're literally poisoning themselves
and complaining about feminism when the
Real Enemy was actual toxins in their
environment that's why I really fear
we're missing
what the real problem in society
actually is is literal poisons
This Is Where It Starts literally this
feels where the atrazine comes to so
this is a cornfield slash a soybean
field and there's literally acres and
acres and Acres of soya and corn fields
in the midwest in the USA and also other
places I'm sure
and it's here that tons and tons of
atrazine is dumped and finds its way
into our water supply and causes the
feminization of men and you think I
might be making this phrase up or
there's some kind of manosphere phrase
not the case the term feminization of
men is a scientific phrase which actual
scientists use it's a real problem it's
a real phenomenon which is taking place
in our world today and people like to
blame Socialism or feminism like I said
but I would put the blame first on
environmental toxins literally found in
fields such as this
so the question now is of course what do
you do about it you aren't going to stop
atrazine use you know people have tried
and failed in places like Europe yes
they have successfully banned it and
have banned it for years but in the US
the I mean it's not like people don't
know about it so understand this this 40
50 60 studies showing that atrazine is
harmful for plants and not not plants
animals and humans Etc but
there's one study
which actually paints a positive picture
of atrazine says that the estrogenic
effects of atrazine are not Direct
and if you look at that one study which
I'll cite down below you'll find that
that study has been funded by syngenta
that study was funded by syngenta which
is one of the biggest herbicide
companies on the planet and of course
there's a conflict of interest there
isn't there so very suspicious that the
one positive study and even that's it's
not actually positive it just says that
the effects are not direct and that
state was funded by literally the
company which makes this stuff so it's
not like scientists and politicians
don't know that atrazine hurts us
in fact of course U.S lawmakers know
that European lawmakers ban this stuff
so they know it's harm harmful
just the U.S politicians don't seem to
kill a farm which is a different problem
altogether so it's up to you to take
matters into your own hands what can you
do about it you need to buy yourself an
RO water filter so reverse osmosis Ro
you can literally purchase this on
Amazon and install it yourself or if
you're you know if you have enough money
you can get a really good system and
have it installed in your home in any
case you need some kind of filtration
system in your home to protect yourself
and your family it's not a matter of
opinion you need one and you need it
yesterday or you have an alternative you
can get yourself a water distiller and
distill water in your home and then you
know
re-mineralize it and then drink it
that's also an option I will link down
below I'm not an affiliate or anything I
don't get any money from promoting these
products this is my job I'm going to
give you the means I'm going to give you
the information and then it's up to you
to act on it and actually protect
yourself from these toxins and that I
believe is the first step in modern and
21st century self-improvement it's not
meditation it's not mindfulness it's
literally literally saving yourself from
these toxins which are poisoning your
bloodstream right now
do you think
that duck is gay
no bro that duck has a girlfriend think
about that that duck has a girlfriend
and you don't bro
there he goes there he goes as you know
I do literally read every single comment
oh yes I promised that I'll show you a
gay frog today
so if you see a frog what I'm gonna do
I'm gonna catch him I'm gonna show him a
picture of a male frog and if he reacts
he's gay
laughs
thank you Jen for editing this video