Porn actually boosts your testosterone.
However, the boost is only 10% and the
prolactin spike that you will inevitably
receive will crush any testosterone
boost. So, prolactin is the hormone of
postnut clarity. It releases right after
your nut to shut down your sex drive.
So, prolactin is actually designed for
this. It's literally designed to clamp
down your ambition, clamp down your
energy, and destroy your momentum. This
is the hormone that makes you feel
empty. Why would such a hormone even
exist? It's because it serves a valuable
purpose. If you're with your wife or a
woman who you can expect to be your
wife, then this is the chemical of pair
bonding. It makes you feel empty because
it allows her to fill you up with her
presence and warmth. But of course, the
problem is if you're with somebody who's
a rando who you're just hooking up with,
or worse, what if she's just pixels on a
screen? then the emptiness will not be
satiated. The emptiness will not be
filled. Instead, the emptiness will
consume you. People think that the
opposite of testosterone is estrogen.
But this is not true. The opposite of
testosterone is prolactin. Just as
testosterone makes effort and taking
risks feel rewarding, prolactin makes
effort and risk feel painful. If you
spike your prolactin without anybody to
attach to, then it leads to a cascade of
negative emotion and a depressed hormone
engine. So, here's the rules. Zero
tolerance policy on porn. You need to
release some steam. I get it. Just don't
use porn. Use your imaginations like
your ancestors did. If you are married
or have a girl, consciously reduce sex
to two to three times a week. Now, that
is to say, you're making yourself the
scarce resource. You will have a better
sex life and so will she. If you decide
to abstain completely, you will
experience nocturnal emission. It means
that you you're going to have dreams
which will take care of business. This
is normal and should happen once a month
or more. Generally speaking, you want to
minimize prolactin unless you are in the
special circumstance where you are
expecting to be a father. This is one of
those times where testosterone should
not be the dominant hormone and instead
the peaceful hormones like serotonin,
oxytocin and prolactin should take over.
In fact, prolactin does this. It nukes
dopamine and it nukes testosterone. Why?
Because in combination, these two
hormones can cause a man to seek out a
new partner. Not ideal behavior for a
new father. Prolactin also upregulates
serotonin, which causes a relaxed and
blissed out state. quite common to see
in new parents. Now, I'm going to make a
controversial scientific hypothesis. My
belief is that people can tell if you
watch porn or engage in meaningless sex.
We know that we have as humans a
pheromone system. They did an experiment
with which took a large number of men
and women who were in long-term
relationships. They wanted to see if
these women could identify the t-shirts
of their partners using their nose.
Turns out they absolutely could. And the
crazy thing is women could identify the
correct t-shirt even without the smell.
So what they did was they they washed
these t-shirts multiple times to destroy
the actual smell molecules. So indeed
the women didn't say they smelt the
t-shirt to be like their partner. They
just said they felt an inner voice or
feeling that it was the case. In other
words, women could detect their mate at
a subconscious level. We also know that
chemical signaling is all too common in
nature. The mere presence of a sexually
mature male in the presence of young
females of a given species will cause
the young females to reach puberty
faster. The presence of a novel male
near a pregnant female can cause a
spontaneous miscarriage. So I make the
following hypothesis. If a man has a
high prolactin spike paired with low
dopamine and low testosterone and high
cortisol, this hormone profile signals
to a human female that he is well, he's
already pair bonded. He's going to be a
father, so there's no point in her being
attracted to him. So essentially, if you
are consuming porn, if you're jacking
off a lot, to be more blunt, you are
telling your females around you that you
are not receptive to them. Essentially,
you'd be putting out signals of a
stressed, pair-bonded father rather than
a stud actively looking for a mate. So
if you want a real woman in your life,
you must reject the virtual ones.