every video game has a skill tree that's
because they want you to know how to
progress through the game and actually
get better and have a visual
representation for how you have
progressed through the game you usually
start off the game having no skills no
points no experience but as you go up
and you reach the late game you become a
force of nature so I've always wondered
what a skill tree for real life would be
and what I'm going to show you right now
is the skill tree which I've been using
since 2018 this skill tree is going to
contain nine metrics and these nine
metrics are going to allow you to do two
things first it's going to show you a
snapshot of your life as it is right now
and with it you're going to be able to
create a high resolution image of your
life in one year and 10 years time so
you actually have a destination that you
can have a direct plan towards so this
is the tool that you're going to use to
create your one-ear plan and does it
work absolutely it works I've been using
it since 2018 gives me a high resolution
image of what I achieved in the past
year and gives me a clear Focus as to
what to do the next coming year the way
the this works is there are three inner
vertices which are the core of this
framework and the very first one is of
course Health it's Fitness so I'm going
to go ahead and draw a dumbbell here to
symbolize Fitness there we go and what
do I mean by Fitness I don't necessarily
mean get jacked as possible I am talking
about vitality and vigor and energy in
life I'm talking about having the energy
and drive and mental resilience to push
through any obstacle and actually
achieve your goals I'm talking about a
baseline level of Health which goes
throughout your life I'm talking about
hormonal Health which is the basis for
strong physical body and also a clear
mind of course that is a topic onto
itself but that is really the first
metric which gives you access to the
second metric which is finances so often
time our first goal is to make money
this is backwards you need to First have
the mental bandwidth to think about how
to make money you need to have the
physical endurance to actually do the
work required to to make money so you
start off with Fitness and use that as a
resource towards building your wealth
and the second metric is the dollar sign
which is finances so basically your
Baseline for Fitness is can you see your
abs and do you have a score about 500
and the Baseline score for finances is
if you're making $110,000 per month
that's your Baseline if you want to
achieve more than that awesome if you
have this and this dialed in then you
have unlocked the New Frontier which is
freedom with a baseline of health and a
baseline of finances you know have
access to Freedom I'm going to try to
draw an eagle here let's see how well
that comes out there we go Eagle as a
symbol of Freedom so let's recap a
little bit this is your tier one let me
actually write that down so tier one has
three components which is Fitness
finances and freedom and when I'm
speaking of Freedom I'm specifically
talking about time and geography Freedom
a reasonable ability to travel where you
want and a reasonable ability to work
when you want and you'll notice that all
the comps of tier one are completely
depending on you you don't really need
anybody to give you permission or give
you even help you can achieve all these
by yourself you'll have all the
resources available online to learn how
to do any of these things you can refer
to my earlier videos on how to have the
perfect nutrition I even have a
nutrition course at this point but once
you've done that then you start making
money when you have freedom and when you
have finances you are able to serve your
family this could be your parents or it
could be your kids if you have any so
with freedom of time and with actual
financials you can serve your family
they put down the symbol for family just
a cute little genealogy chart so you see
how this is like a skill tree right you
unlock Fitness that allows you to unlock
finances you unlock finances that allows
you to unlock loock Freedom when you
unlock freedom and when you unlock
finances you have the ability to unlock
family and when you have Fitness and
when you have freedom that's when you
are going to make your best friends at
this point you have the ability to build
a fraternity A brotherhood so with
freedom and fitness you'll have the
respect of others you'll have the
respect of men just like you and with
that respect you build fraternity I'm
going to try to draw a handshake if I
can and that is our second tier 2 metric
so tier two we have family fraternity
and the third one when you have a degree
of fitness and a degree of finances you
are now attractive to females for the
first time you can unlock the feminine
so you have now access to a new skill or
new metric of embracing the feminine
aspects of life that means it could be a
wife it could be a girlfriend not sure
what that is for you but it's only after
you unlock these two that this tier
really becomes accessible but you see
this is still incomplete there is
another tier which is missing from this
a tier that's grander and greater than
anything on the diagram so far this is
tier three and you'll notice that in
tier two you're depending on other
people family requires interaction with
other people fraternity requires
interaction with other men the feminine
requires interaction with women whereas
tier one was mostly just yourself tier
three is interesting back cuz it
involves others but truly it's a inwards
journey let's start off with finances so
finances when you upgrade this to tier
three looks like this it is the
foundation it is the Legacy that you
leave behind this is beyond just making
money this is the thing which you leave
behind when you die this is the thing
that you'll be remembered for this is
the foundation you will create create
something you'll create something that
endures past your life this could be a
work of art it could be a book series
that you write it could be YouTube
videos for all I know it could be a
business it could be a physical
structure this is a thing which gives
you immortality this is the foundation
this is the tier three this is above
just making money and the same way you
can level up your game with Fitness so
Fitness is basically having a high level
of testosterone a high level of Fitness
you have end you have muscle cool but
there's a level above that and it's
called flow when you are doing a
physical activity which requires your
100% concentration and it requires a
level of skill that you are at the
periphery of your ability that is to say
like if you're playing tennis and you're
playing with a guy who's just slightly
better than you if you really push
yourself and you can match his Pace you
are in a flow State and Flow State
doesn't have to be physical Flow State
could be artistic for example a writer
who's really writing an essay which is
very difficult for him at the edge of
his ability to communicate that could
leave him in a flow state if you're a
public speaker and you're giving a
speech about a difficult topic you're
trying to communicate a complex idea you
could be in a flow state so flow state
is basically your physicality but it's
accelerated to the highest possible
level so your flow state is when you're
pushing your ability so hard that
there's a real risk of failure and to do
this you need to get really good so this
is not just your Baseline anymore this
is when you are truly building a art
form out of your body this is flow I'm
not sure how to draw a wave I'll try
okay that's my best approximation of a
wave looks like garbage I know but hey
the best I can do at this point and that
is your upgraded form your upgraded tier
of fitness and the same way you can
upgrade your freedom as well what you're
going to realize is even though you've
achieved so much there's still going to
be an inner layer of fulfillment you
still need to achieve so we complete
this the second item in tier three is
flow and the third is fulfillment that's
what you get when you upgrade Freedom
I'm going to draw myself meditating and
the thing here is I have not achieved
this right I don't really know how this
feels like but I but I've had glimpses
of it when you're truly satisfied with
your accomplishments in life that's when
you have a feeling of true fulfillment
and that is your tier three so this is
tier one the inner triangle tier two is
one step accelerated and tier 3 is even
more broad even more deep now the
question is how do you use all this
framework to create your actual one-year
plan and the answer is you will create
yourself a table and on the table you're
going to have the current state and
you're going to have your desired state
I'm going to use these as prompts to
write about your current and desired
state so you'll go ahead and start with
tier one your Fitness financials and
freedom write down your current state of
Fitness so for me I'm about 1 70 fairly
lean that's going to be my current state
my desired state so I'm going to write
my current state I'm going to write my
desired State my desired State is1 180
at the same level of leanness so that's
my desired goal at the end of the year
regarding finances my current state is
10K per month my desired state is 30k
per month regarding freedom I actually
very happy with my progress over the
year so you can also use this to assay
your past Year's performance over the
past year I've built out this YouTube
channel I've built courses I've built a
community and to achieve full-time
status on YouTube in a year that's a big
achievement in my opinion so I'm very
happy with my progress towards Freedom
so I'm going to write my current state
of Freedom how much freedom I have right
now and then my desired state in the
same way I'm going to go to tier two
right now my family I don't really
support them as much as I could the
desired state is I've retired my parents
so that's my desired state for family
regarding fortunity over the past year I
created a private Community a paid
private Community called the Country
Club and that gives me a sense of
fraternity with my like-minded peers
however I want to take this to the next
level I want to do in-person events with
them so that would be my current state
is KCC as it is and my desired state is
to incorporate Live Events and right now
that's all the metrics that I'm going to
focus on for the next 6 months I'm going
to focus on just these I'm just going to
focus on Fitness finances freedom family
and fortunity once I'm comfortable in
those metrics then I will progress on to
embracing the feminine the foundations
of my legacy achieving the Flow State
and achieving fulfillment because like I
said this is a skill tree you cannot
focus on everything at the same time you
have to go Peace by peace and yet
there's actually one component which
I've purposely left out until this
moment because I only want to share this
with those who have stuck with the
entire video at this point the final
component is Faith and you can interpret
faith in the way that you want the way
that it works for you but at the
foundational level this is Faith in
oneself This Is Blind Faith blind faith
in your destiny that no matter what
happens that you have a destiny to
fulfill you don't need any signs you
don't need any justifications you don't
need logic you don't need reason this is
meant to be blind faith and that is at
the center of it all I'm going to draw a
crown to represent its importance this
is the most important tier and you can
start off your journey and you can
sustain your journey only once you have
a degree of faith in your success before
you achieve anything thing and there we
have it boys that is the skill tree that
is the
9f framework I can actually help you a
little bit more so regarding nutrition
and fitness specifically I'm going to
provide you the esoteric food pyramid
which really gives you an understanding
of what nutrition really looks like