so at this point I hadn't even seen a
machine gun with my own eyes let alone
heard one so I hear the machine guns
going off and I see the Tracer fire
arching over my head and I feel my heart
just drop it's the craziest experience
so this was Army basic training so they
had heard this all the trainees into the
this huge goalie I didn't even know what
it was at the time but now looking back
it was actually a trench the same way a
trench would be in like World War one
and on the other side of the field there
was two machine gun turrets well
actually got two there's probably many
machine gun turrets they had this
machine gun called The M249 I believe no
no these were m240s they had the full
m240 so the way it works is the machine
gun fires five rounds and then it Trace
around then five rounds and then a trace
around so that the machine gunner knows
where the rounds are landing so we could
see these Tracer rounds all over us and
then we hear our drill sergeants whistle
with this this long metal whistle the
same kind which they would have used in
like World War one this is a training
exercise it was called Nick at night is
what we called it it's night
infiltration course and I see so it's
night infiltration course at night kind
of redundant but redundancy is what the
Army is about not gonna lie so there we
were we were we were crawling a low
crawl it's the most uncomfortable way
you could possibly get across a piece of
ground you're literally face first on
the ground completely flat not even your
legs can come up you have to just crawl
and you have your weapon you have your
helmet you have body armor you have
freaking your canteens you have all this
kit on you and you're just trying to get
forward and so much effort for even
moving a few inches and they had made it
like it was a beach they had made it
like Sandy and and Gravelly so it was
terrible like we were we were ripping
skin off our
um elbows and shins as we try to get
through this patch of land so this was a
simulation exercise they wanted to show
us what it would have felt like to be a
soldier in World War one being told to
rush the other side the sergeant
whistles and they're gonna get out
trenches we have to start going so this
was one of the most memorable
experiences I have from Army basic
training in this video I'm going to
share some of those experiences and also
make something called a mango lassi one
of my favorite drinks of all time and
this is actually going to be the best
mango lassi video on YouTube and this is
a new Cooking Channel so you're welcome
so what do we need to make the mango
list you need milk and notice that this
is a glass bottle of milk why glass
because Plastics contain tablets and
tallets will leach into your milk and
that will make the milk essentially
toxic it'll poison your testosterone
production poison your hormonal
production and even if you're a woman
watching this salads aren't good for you
either it messes up your hormones as
much as it messes up any males hormones
and then we have some five percent Greek
yogurt so five percent is as much as you
can possibly get it's very fat filled
very highly calorie dense very
nutritious and very creamy so it adds a
good amount of flavor then they have
honey this is the really good quality
honey so when you're looking for honey
the best is to get local honey from a
local farm so this is what that is if
you aren't able to get that at least
look for raw and unfiltered the best is
unheated if you can get unheated honey
that's the best possible then we have
heavy whipping cream this is not an
essential ingredient but if you have it
then good for your red it'll taste
better it'll make the texture better and
then we have vanilla extract another
unconventional ingredient in this
mixture and of course we have the mango
chunk so you also need something to
measure with so what we do is well get
back to the Army Stories the best part
of army training especially looking back
is that for six months of your life no
it's more like seven months of your life
you're literally literally forced into
the most extreme monk mode you've ever
heard of no phones no internet no books
nothing just pure single-minded focus on
the training now don't get me wrong we
goofed off quite a lot but even then
there was no internet there was no
distraction there was no porn there was
no drugs there was no alcohol there was
no smoking so every possible sin that
you can imagine all the addictions of
modernity removed for seven months of my
life and I do believe that that
catalyzed some of my later successes so
first thing we need Greek yogurt so how
much Greek yogurt do we need we need one
cup of Greek yogurt so regarding
quantity right I'm gonna do a one is to
one is to one so I'm going to use the
same amount of yogurt as I'm going to
use of milk as I'm gonna use of heavy
whipping cream you can obviously adjust
these quantities depending on how much
you're making right so that's about one
cup a little less than one cup to be
honest another memorable memorable event
in my army training was the first time I
looked at the sky wearing night optic
devices so nods night optic devices
basically you know the movies they have
the Green Vision that you can see at
night first off those are actually
amazing pieces of Kit if you look at the
sky wearing nods you will see how many
stars there actually are because it's
obviously very sensitive to light right
so if you can see say you know 10 000
stars with your naked eye you'll see a
hundred thousand stars with if you're
using your Night Vision Optics and it's
beautiful looking at the sky through the
night optic vision is one of my favorite
little stories from the from the Army so
we have about one cup of the Greek
yogurt more than sufficient go ahead and
put that away
but trust me when I tell you not every
single experience in army training is a
good one for example there's something
called land nav so Land Navigation I'm
adding one cup of milk more or less so
none of these quantities have to be
exact by the way so land nav is when
they put you into this nasty ass Forest
so I did my basic training at a place
called Fort Benning Georgia and trust me
you don't want to go to freaking Fort
Benning Fort Benning is the home of the
Infantry it's where the Infantry is
trained and it's the worst it's the
absolute worst place on the planet it's
hot it's humid the forest literally
stinks there's so much decomposed
material on the forest floor it's just
nasty man the worst part is the spiders
man so there's big ass banana spiders so
the spiders like this big bigger than my
hand probably like wide big boys big
spiders they're everywhere like every
single two trees there's two trees
there's a freaking spider web between
them and a big old spider sitting right
in the center and this is a nasty nasty
Woods not the kind of nature like I like
nature but not this kind of nature you
know what I mean disgusting Woods big
ass spiders and it was hard to do land
nav so land nav is basically they give
you a map they give you a compass and
they give you a protractor and they give
you like a pen to Mark stuff and they
give you points on the map like you have
to go to these points and each point has
a number I needed to take the number
down so that when you come back you can
show your drill sergeant the number and
prove that you in fact found all the
points so during the daytime it's all
really hard because we have to go
through all these dense Woods trying to
avoid the spiders as much as possible
and then still find your points through
these swampy lands and there's like
actual snakes there was copperheads and
I've seen a copperhead in the in the
wild and it's just nasty and difficult
to get through terrain but it was hard
during the daytime in the night time it
was it was the worst I was trying to get
to a point at night and I remember
distinctly you use something called a
red lamp or a red lens when you're going
through the forest at night it's just a
red light flashlight and by the way
you're not actually allowed to use it at
night so during night land now it's
pitch black no light allowed nothing
allowed because you're trying to be as
stealthy as possible right so when I
turned on the red lamp just briefly to
see what's around me I see a hundred
thousand beady little eyes staring back
I didn't realize it but I was in the
center of those huge huge spider web and
if I had taken 10 steps forward I would
be drenched in spiders I still have that
memory it's disgusting immediately I was
like I don't care what the drill
sergeant says I am not walking through
there to get to my point so yeah I got
penalized but man I am not walking
through freaking spider nests so then we
add our heavy whipping cream so this is
going to be about 3 4 of a cup and
that's our mixture hopefully it's all
fits in here we'll we'll find out I
guess so I'm gonna go ahead and pour it
all through
there it is and yeah it all fits it's
good but land now wasn't all bad on
another night or maybe it was the same
night me and two other friends who I'm
not gonna name obviously because of
confidentiality reasons me and them we
we were doing land now we're trying to
find our points and we find this opening
in the forest all right we find this
huge opening in the forest so Fort
Benning Georgia is densely densely
forested so an opening in the forest is
is pretty uncommon for some reason this
huge patch of land had no trees had no
vegetation whatsoever it literally
looked like the surface of the Moon
completely Barren it was like Sandy and
gray for some reason I'm not sure why so
one thing we lose as adults is our
ability to play we don't do things just
for the sake of doing things you know
everything we do is calculated
everything is strategy everything is
tactics everything is for a goal when
you're a child you play just for the
sake of playing and during a brief
period very brief period of my time in
the Army basic training I actually got
to play so me and my two friends found
this weird Landing Zone like place in
the middle of nowhere in the middle of
Georgia's worst woods and for whatever
reason we it all got into our heads like
this is such a cool and interesting
place and we just played you know we
just ran for no reason we threw stones
for no reason we were jumping and acting
out the moon landing it was like we're
just frolicking for the fun of it and I
will never forget those moments we also
did other stupid things but those are
confidential and the armies where I
learned that you can sleep anywhere some
of the best sleep I've ever had was
literally curled up in a black trash bag
on the forest floor because it was
freezing and I slept like a baby right I
was still I still had my backpack on
because if they told you to go you need
you need to move so best sleep ever
sleeping with my backpack on in a trash
bag on the floor of a forest and then
also like even in the barracks right
you're not allowed to sleep in the
barracks at all if they find you
sleeping in the to get if I catch you
sleeping it's game over so you have to
be very stealthy with your sleep people
will sleep in the bathrooms people will
sleep under beds all kinds of things
some of the best sleep I got was
literally on the ground flat on the
ground with a rolled up t-shirt as a
pillow and I was knocked out for like
hours because we're just so tired all
the time and then we cannot forget to
add our honey so how much honey am I
adding I will add a good two solid
tablespoons of Honey because I don't
have a problem with honey I know it's
sugar but sugar isn't necessarily bad
for you it's the processed refined carbs
which mess you up I mean I'm not saying
go overboard with it right a little bit
of Honey isn't going to hurt you though
and then we start to blend it hopefully
oh my [ __ ] god
or damage control
so it already tastes really good
already it's nice refreshing drink
very flavorful this is just Frozen
mangoes you can use frozen mangoes
normal mangoes you can use whatever you
want
I got it strong mango taste which is
exactly what I want I'll actually add
some more mango so how much mango am I
adding I'm adding about a big handful of
mangoes and a splash of vanilla essence
this is not something you'll find in
traditional Indian recipes this is
something I added because it tastes good
and then we'll give it one last blend
and we are ready to serve another thing
I really disliked about the army or
basic trainings especially was the fact
that there is group punishment so what
group punishment is if one person messes
up the philosophy is everybody else
messes up too I understand where it's
coming from right if you're actually on
a battlefield and one person messes up
literally everybody could get killed so
I understand the philosophy but in
practice what happens is you may have
zero control over what somebody else is
doing but everybody gets punished for
the actions of one person and the fact
of the matter is some people just don't
care right some people just don't care
about doing well in the training
environment and they will keep messing
up because they simply don't care and
everybody else gets punished it's very
demoralizing you know you want to have
control over your destiny and that's
what actually helps people improve and
grow in life is when you feel that your
actions either bring your Rewards or
punishment but in the Army especially in
the basic training environment what I
found is it doesn't matter how good you
want to do or how bad you're doing the
end result is you get punished for
everybody else's behavior and you only
have so much control over what other
people are doing as a trainee you are
not going to be able to tell other
trainees what to do because they aren't
going to listen to you right somebody
wants to be a [ __ ] bag they're going to
be a [ __ ] bag I found this extremely
demoralizing I did my best in training
for the first few months and after that
I I wanted to give up because no matter
how good I did there's no reward
whatsoever it's only punishment and
that's not the way you set up a good
trading system so obviously I don't have
the authority to change anything about
training whatsoever so there's no point
in me even saying this but if you end up
going to some kind of army training then
expect unfairness if you do good you
won't be rewarded for it if you do bad
you'll get punished for it if somebody
else does bad you'll still get punished
for it so it's very demoralizing I don't
like the culture I don't like the logic
behind it I think you should get
rewarded for doing well but that's just
how it is and serving my extremely
esoteric
mango Lessie here we go look at that
Perfection ladies and gentlemen we have
the perfect summer drink finally they
have some sun here in the Midwest using
a metal straw why because we want a
white Plastics is that right and then
how does it taste
so good it's hard to communicate taste
or video right but this stuff is just so
good it tastes like you're drinking a
mango it's amazing you gotta try it I
know you guys like my esoteric eggnog
recipe this tastes even better than that
if possible now it's not as good in
terms of nutrition as the eggnog recipe
because that has eggs and it has fats
but this isn't that bad either because
it still has fats from the milk and
heavy cream and the Greek yogurt Greek
yogurt is a power ingredient so this is
a very healthy drink now the honey and
the mango make it very carbohydrate Rich
makes it very sugary so if you wanted to
you can just decrease the amount of
mango and honey and make it more
nutritionally optimized but it's up to
you right if you want to go for taste
like how I did then enjoy it own it