I woke up from a dream I saw a Pakistani
man wearing a bathrobe emerging from the
sky and he looks at me and he whispers
you are the Adonis now no one is going
to replace Hamza cuz Hamza that you see
on screen is not the entire Hamza the
Hamza off screen is extremely logical
extremely intelligent and on screen
Hamza leans into his emotional
intelligence he leans into his
relatability I'm not trying to say that
Hamza is being disingenuous or dishonest
I'm just saying Hamza has different
aspects of his personality and depending
on what he's trying to communicate and
who he's communicating with he has the
emotional ability to regulate his
personality in that way HS of being as
intelligent as he actually is he knew
exactly what he was doing when he
inspired you to make your YouTube
channel to start your YouTube Journey
but I am here to tell you that you will
most likely fail so what am I doing here
I'm trying to make myself some eggnog in
the next 5 to 10 minutes I'm going to
tell you why your YouTube channel is
going to fail and hopefully make myself
some amazing eggnog along the way for
those of you do know eggnog is a protein
Rich fatri amazing testosterone boosting
drink so long as it's made correctly so
eggnog is a Christmas tradition and you
know people like me from India we don't
really celebrate Christmas so I learned
it from a friend so Hamza sells the idea
that all you need to succeed on YouTube
is radical honesty consistency and
sharing your journey through your own
self-improvement I don't think that's
true cuz nobody cares about your
self-improvement journey bro nobody
cares about your noof fap Journey man
okay so you were struggling with porn
addiction and drugs and whatever it was
and then now you go to the gym and now
women finally wants to talk to you
nobody cares that story has been done
Hamza has a monopoly on the
self-improvement Journey of breaking
drugs and bad habits and becoming Adonis
so if you are trying to do the same
exact thing as Hamza you are going to
fail you cannot out Hamza Hamza
understand if you're doing a
self-improvement type Channel then Hamza
is your enemy Hamza is the competition
that's the guy you're trying to take
views away from and you were not going
to succeed I guarantee you Hamza has
some serious advantages in the space
firstly I've already talked about how
Hamza is intelligent more intelligent
than you think he's also very well
spoken he has an amazing camera presence
he's also relatively handsome and he's
also jacked you might know the first
video of his that actually blew up was
his aesthetic body transformation video
so he was already jacked before he got
big on his channel he used that as a
leverage and as a advantage to grow his
masculinity Channel because of course if
you want to build a masculinity Channel
you better be looking masculine he's
also perfected his storytelling skills
and if Hamza worked on storytelling
skills for years before he got as good
as he is right now so when you are
trying to start a self-improvement
journey that's the guy who you're
competing with so what am I doing here
I've added myself one cup of whole milk
I'm going to do half a cup of what's
called heavy whipping cream this has all
the fats so ham tells you this idea that
if you are just two steps ahead of the
guy who you're trying to to help then
that's enough and that person can learn
from you I disagree with this imagine
you're learning boxing right do you want
to learn boxing from the guy who just
has one more year of experience than you
in boxing no you don't you want to learn
boxing from a champion you know you want
to learn boxing from somebody who's
actually been in the ring and has won
some competitions you want to learn
boxing from a guy who knows how to box
and same's true for self-improvement I
have no problem with learning things
from Hamza because he has been on the
journey longer than I have that's why
his content sells you on the other hand
you barely started why would other
people who want to listen to your story
and the idea of relatability so Hamza
tries to paint himself as a relatable
character and he does a very good job of
this but understand that relatability is
not a virtue in itself just because
you're relatable doesn't mean I want to
watch your content Andrew Tate is a good
example of this he's not relatable at
all what color is your guy Ander Tade is
an aspirational type motivational
speaker he's in prison now he's highly
controversial regardless of what you
think about him the fact is he did a
excellent job of promoting you know
hyper masculine character but not being
relatable but rather by being an
aspirational figure for a lot of young
men and I was reminded of this idea from
Jake Tran that people will watch you
people consume content if you provide
them an unfair Advantage if you're
trying to create a channel on YouTube
you need to be providing something that
nobody else can provide providing an
angle that nobody else can compete with
and also giving your audience something
that's going to give them an advantage
in whatever they're pursuing so I'm
going to go ahead and separate these egg
yolks from the whites so what I'm going
to do is catch the yolks and let the
whites just go through my fingers and
separate them that's the easiest way I
know to separate the eggs from the
whites if you have a better idea feel
free to add that to the comments I'll
call you out and of course everything
I'm saying to you is true for my channel
so I cannot continue to use hamza's name
to get views and likes and comments the
fact is that's simply unsustainable I
need to be providing you value which is
independent of Hamza I need to have a
different Edge and provide different
value so that I'm not competing with
Hamza well I already know what that is
for me I'm a biologist and so I know a
lot about nutrition and health I'm going
to create this channel around boosting
your testosterone because my view is
that even before mental health hormonal
health comes first my view and you might
disagree with it is you fix your
hormonal health and your mental health
fixes itself and so does your physical
health see hs's framework is you fix
your mental health first and that's the
cause for improvement across your life I
don't disagree with that but my view is
hormonal health comes even before that
so in this channel you're going to learn
cooking skills you're going to learn how
to make yourself highly nutritious
testosterone boosting food while you
pursue your self-improvement my take on
this is completely different from
hamza's I've never seen Hamza cook
anything I also have military experience
so I can share stories from being a
machine gunner in the US Army and that's
something completely different which
Hamza is not able to do these things
these experiences my journey and my
unique knowledge about hormones and
testosterone Etc give me an edge which
Hamza doesn't have gives me a
competitive space in which I'm not
competing directly with him and then
there's the issue of
commitment so you want to get your egg
whites whisk that you can kind of see
these Peaks forming that's perfect so
the issue of commitment now you might
think commitment is the same thing as
discipline and you might say I'm
committed to YouTube I'm going to make
three videos per week commitment is not
the same thing as discipline for example
I'm committed because my video editor
Jan I've committed that I'm going to pay
him full-time salary for 3 months and
that means I'm going to have to use his
skills that means I have to produce the
videos to justify his pay so I'm
committed my money is already committed
to this purpose that in my opinion is a
higher level than just straight up this
discipline all right I'm going to put
this milk mixture on the
heat hopefully I don't focus on this and
let it boil over but we'll see so
commitment is not simply this iron mind
idea all you andate types are going to
be like iron mind I'm disciplined I can
[ __ ] be committed no commitment is
also about creating success Frameworks
success structures in your life which
help you to do the things that you want
to do for example my gym has this unique
feature hats off to them I commit to
being at the gym at a certain time at a
certain day and if I don't check in at
the time they actually find me $5 yeah
$5 is not a lot but that $5 commitment
gets me to the gym when I promise I'll
be there that's an example of a success
structure that keeps me going even if I
don't feel like going all right just
going to wait for this milk to start
steaming all right so I don't want to
get my milk to a boil I'm going to stop
when it just starts steaming right
that's when it's going to be perfect so
I've gone ahead and added my whisked egg
whites to the milk now I'm going to go
ahead break these yolks mix them up a
little bit yeah there it is add it in
blend this mixture and of course you
have vanilla extract which you don't
really need for this recipe but I do
think it adds a little bit extra taste
so I've been giving you discouragement
for 10 minutes straight I've been
telling you all the reasons why your
YouTube channel is going to fail at this
point if you decide that perhaps you
need to wait for a little bit longer
until you find that edge and then come
back to YouTube then you have my
understanding if you instead decide that
you're going to go for it anyways that
you think you're ready and you're going
to do YouTube regardless of what I've
said just now then you have my respect