Jeffrey's finally got a girlfriend. Oh.
Oh. Oh no. Oh no. Oh no. Jeffrey, she's
texting other guys. You've got to
confront her about this, man. You've got
to go speak to her about it. Oh no.
Jessica's using one of the 10
manipulation tactics. Don't fall for it,
Jeffrey. Don't fall. No. It's too late.
He believed her. And now she's getting
pounded by one of the guys she was
texting, but she told him that he's just
a friend. Jeffrey, don't fall for these
tactics. Jeffrey, didn't you know that a
lot of girls these days are using these?
Adonis
Adonis does not fall for a puny female's
manipulation tactics. Now, he knows that
there are good women out there. One by
one, Adonis deflected all of the
manipulation tactics so that he could
find a good woman. This is how men need
to live today. What are the best and
worst manipulation tactics that women
use today? In this video, I'm going to
rank 10 of the most popular, most common
manipulation tactics that women are
using in modern dating. I'll be ranking
them from S tier all the way down to F
tier. And inside of this video, I'm
going to crown one of these manipulation
tactics as the best one, S plus. And I'm
also going to crown one of these as the
worst, most silly. Like, if you fall for
this, you're just an idiot. Fminus tier.
Let's start with the first manipulation
tactic. Crying. This has been a
manipulation tactic that women have used
for literally the existence of human
beings. And this is how it goes. She
does something to upset you. You are
upset. Since you're upset, she's upset
and now it's about her. She literally
will hurt you. Let's say, you know,
she's texting guys and you see it.
You're upset. Then she'll cry saying,
"Oh, but I've upset you and now it's
about her again and now you're the
asshole."
So, of course, where do you think we're
going to put crying in the in the rank
of the manipulation tiers? We're going
to put it down low. We'll give it an F
tier. But here's where it gets
interesting. For the second manipulation
tactic, I'm going to change it slightly.
How about crying socially? So, not just
crying between you and her in private,
but let's say she starts crying in
public, or let's say she starts crying
and then posting about it on social
media. Suddenly, that harmless act that
you could kind of look at as like the
act of a little girl who's trying to
make you feel bad, suddenly she's now
getting basically everyone on her side.
If you're with a girl and she starts
crying about something, okay, it's
pretty normal, fine. But if she cries
and then posts about it on social media,
she's going to get so much extra support
on her side because you as the man will
instantly look like the bad guy. The
same in public as well. Look, if you
guys are out in public and let's say
she's done something to upset you, but
then she cries in public, you look like
the [ __ ] So, I'm going to put crying
socially higher on the list. I'm going
to put it in the C tier. And I want to
teach you quickly how can you overcome
this form of manipulation. Don't take a
woman's tears that seriously. There's a
phrase which is called crocodile tears,
which basically means when a woman's
crying, but she's literally using it as
a form of manipulation to make you feel
bad or to get people onto her side.
There's an Instagram reel, I think,
maybe hopefully we can find it for you,
where this girl, she's like crying on
the phone to her partner, you know,
she's like arguing with him or whatever,
and her friends are like sat in bed
recording her. She's on like the
loudspeaker speaking to him, you know, I
can't believe you you you've hurt me
like this. And when she realizes her
friends are recording, she turns to her
friend who's recording and goes like
this. Like, you know, like she's like
laughing happy and then goes back to
pretending that she's crying again. And
her friends are like laughing because
they know that that's her personality.
And a lot of girls are like this. They
literally will show you what seems like
pure genuine tears, but they don't
actually feel that bad. They're doing it
to make you feel bad. The way you
overcome this form of manipulation is to
not take her tears seriously. Women cry
for like everything these days, bro. A
girl will cry because she's kind of
stressed. She'll cry because she's kind
of hungry. So then, if she cries because
of some [ __ ] that's happened in your
relationship, it doesn't mean that you
should actually take it more seriously.
You should not allow that to change your
perspective of anything that's happened
in your relationship. And another thing,
as a society worldwide, we need to do
this. If you see a woman crying about
her man, be aware that it could be a
form of manipulation. There's a
statistic that literally blows my mind.
You know what it is? Let's say you're in
a relationship with your girl. You're
both at home. If she attacks you, like
I'm talking, she literally physically
grabs you, scratches you, attacks you,
and you call the police. When the police
arrive, if she has tears on her face,
you are more likely to get arrested.
Even if you've got blood on you, her
tears are more believable than your
blood. That's a real statistic. If you
are a victim of domestic abuse, you are
more likely to get arrested yourself if
she is crying. Think about that for a
second. If you call the police, you call
them, you they literally heard your
voice, they asked your name, you call
the police saying, "Oh my god, my
girlfriend's going crazy. She's just
attacking me. She's grabbed a knife."
They'll come over. Statistically, you
are more likely to get arrested than she
is as long as she's crying. Think about
how crazy that is. Cuz when the police
come, they're [ __ ] idiots, right? Of
course, bro. The world is sexist, not to
women, but to men. When they come and
see the little girl who's crying,
they'll see you, the big aggressor, and
blame it on you. This is why us talking
about manipulation is so important. And
I know this seems like a goofy video,
but you're seeing my point now of like
this video is actually quite purposeful
for us to speak about, isn't it? Let's
talk about the third manipulation tactic
that women are using, and it is lying.
Lying is manipulation because a woman
will make you believe that reality is
different from what it is. You don't get
the human right of being able to feel
and base your decisions on reality just
because she's maybe a bit embarrassed
about something that she's done. And the
reason why lying is such a powerful
manipulation tactic, especially when
women do it, is because most men do not
know just how much a woman would lie. If
you've ever been in the situation where
you've had a girl compulsively lie to
you, you might have like had your
perception of the world destroyed,
thinking, "I cannot believe a girl who
loves me could lie that much to me." As
men, our word is kind of like our bond.
It's our our honor. We say what we mean.
For girls, especially feminine girls,
it's not so much. And so because of
that, I'm going to put lying pretty high
up. I'm going to put it in the B tier.
I'm not putting it all the way to the
top. The reason why is because feminine
women are not exactly liars. They're
talking about what they feel like in the
moment. The problem is most men don't
really relate to that at all. And so
when she tells you, no, that guy I was
texting, no, nothing's happening. I'm
not interested in him. The reason why
she's saying that, even though it's
technically not true, cuz she was
interested enough to reply to him, is
because right here, right now, when
you're in front of her, you're giving
her attention. you're confronting her,
she doesn't feel like she's interested
in another guy. She can say, "I love
you." And she means it, but 10, 20
minutes from then when some guy from her
past texts her, her emotions can change
just like the wind and she can go from
loving you and just be only thinking
about you to suddenly getting a huge
surge of emotions when maybe some guy
from her past texts her or, you know,
you haven't replied to her for like an
hour or something. And so more and more
guys are kind of understanding like a
feminine woman is kind of like extremely
chaotic and untrustworthy in some ways.
And this is just the nature of a
feminine woman. And it's a hard thing to
deal with because you would expect
whatever a girl says to you is what she
actually means, but it's not. It's what
she feels right now, which is subject to
change every 2 minutes. So, we've got
lying for the Btier. But now, there is a
different form of lying, which is way
higher on the tiers of manipulation, and
it is something called trickle truths.
Trickle truths is like lying, but on
steroids. And this is how it works.
She'll tell you a part of the truth.
Like she'll tell you something which is
in the direction of the truth, but just
enough to upset you, but not enough to
really piss you off and make you end
things with her. She'll tell you that
because you're close to finding out the
full truth. And hopefully she makes you
believe the situation wasn't as bad as
it actually was. And you can imagine the
number one scenario in which a woman
will tell you trickle truths is when she
tells you how far she went with another
guy that she was cheating on you with. I
remember last year I had a girl come
over to my place. I had seen her a few
times and she told me that she had been
married before, you know, this point.
And it was quite interesting cuz she was
still fairly young. She was like 28
years old. And so I asked her, "Oh,
that's crazy. You were married. Like,
you know, what happened?" And she said,
"Yeah, he wanted a divorce when he found
out that I cheated on him." And I was
like, "Oh, that's crazy. What did you
do?" And she says, "I kissed another
guy." And I instantly because I knew
about Trickle Truth, I said to her,
"Listen, it's me. You can tell me the
truth." You know, I was playing like the
sort of like cool guy. I said, "You can
tell me the truth. You didn't just kiss
that guy, did you?" And I swear to God,
this is what she did. And she looked
like she went, "No, I [ __ ] him as
well."
Her husband, bless him, had the balls
that when she told him that she just
kissed this other guy, he still wanted
to get divorced. But a lot of women will
literally go all the way like they'll
cheat. They'll get pounded maybe even
multiple times, but they'll tell their
man it was just a kiss. Oh no, no,
nothing happened. We just went on a date
but nothing happened. They'll tell you
something like, "Oh yeah, he just kissed
me." Instead of saying, "Yeah, he [ __ ]
me three times in the night." Because
they want you to just be able to get
kind of pissed off, but not enough that
you actually kind of, you know, sus
everything out. My first girlfriend did
this to me as well. I still remember
this. This is probably what made me
jaded for [ __ ] years. I went to
surprise her one day and I went over to
her uh accommodation like you know we
were students in university and I even
got inside of her flat like one of her
flat mates opened the door for me and I
knocked on her bedroom door and when she
opened she was like shocked to see me
and I literally I just knew for a fact
there was like someone hiding underneath
the bed or someone was here cuz I could
tell she was just like guilty. So I'm
subtly you know cuz I don't want to show
all my cards. I was like subtly kind of
like checking if there's any [ __ ]
guys here but there wasn't. But my gut
feeling was just there though, like she
could not be trusted. You know, your gut
evolutionary like animal instinct was
just telling you like some bullshit's
happening. Eventually, I noticed that
she was on her phone and she had been
texting a guy and I asked her like,
"Who's that?" And she said, "Oh,
nothing. It's just like a guy from back
home. He was just asking me how
university was because she had just
moved here." And I knew that she was
kind of lying about something. So, I
asked her, "Have you had sex with this
guy before?" And she said, "No. What?
No, not at all. No, it's just a friend.
He's just asking how this university
was. It's it there's nothing, you know,
we're just texting. That's it. No,
nothing at all. My gut instinct didn't
change. I kept on pressing her on it and
said, "No, tell me the truth. Have you
been with this guy? Like, have you
kissed him before? Have you done
anything with him? Tell me the truth."
She's like, "No, what happened? Come on,
relax. You're just getting crazy. You're
just, you know, you're being insecure
now. You're just being angry about
something, whatever." She kept that up.
I swear to God, this was for about an
entire day. I kept like, you know, it
felt so awkward. I was sat there
overinking. She was telling me to just
calm down, whatever. And I said to her,
I just gave her the ultimatum. I was
like, "Listen, I know you're lying to
me. If you lie one more time, I'm going
to walk out the door. You will never see
me again. Tell me the truth." And she
says, "Fine. Yeah, we used to send nudes
to each other." That already broke my
heart. Cuz that's cheating, right? If a
girl used to send nudes to a guy, now
she's texting him again whilst she's in
a relationship with you, that's
cheating. So my heart was already
broken. But the gut instinct didn't go.
So then I felt trapped, like I should
have just walked away. I should have
just ended the relationship. But it's
like I felt like this massive need to
know all the details. So I start
speaking to her more. Okay, when did
that happen? Tell me. No, you didn't
just send nudes. You've hooked up
before. You've like kissed each other
before minimum. She's like, no, no, no.
Like we've never even done it. We
literally just like, you know, just a
few pictures. No, it was years ago. No,
no, no, no. This goes on for literally
the next day. The whole day, I'm
literally stressed. I can't even sleep
properly. I'm just thinking about it. I
should have just left, of course, but
like, you know, you feel like this need
to know everything, right? And I kept on
asking, kept on asking. I'm like,
"Listen, I give another ultimatum. If
you don't tell me the truth, I'm just
gonna leave. Just tell me, please.
Please, you're you're breaking my heart.
Just tell me. Like, something's
happened." And she's like, "Okay, fine,
fine, fine, fine. We we we we had sex
once, but it was with a condom."
My heart [ __ ] tore in half,
bro. I named my future children with
this girl. I lost my virginity. Like, I
did everything with this girl. She was
my first everything, right? She says
that it was like another tear in my
little fragile heart and still the gut
instinct didn't go away. For days we're
on this like on and off kind of
relationship where you know I feel
terrible but when you feel terrible you
run to the person who you've got a
loving attachment with even though
they're the ones who who are making you
feel terrible. So it was almost like
self harm where I was like I felt [ __ ]
I felt so like hurt and I kept on
staying with this girl. Kept on asking
okay is that it? It was with a condom.
It was just once. Okay, you know but I
didn't really believe her. I kept on
like just thinking about it, whatever.
Eventually, I I was so stressed that I
literally went back home for a few days
cuz I just didn't want to be in like
university. I didn't want to be next to
her. And I remember I still remember
this so perfectly cuz I was 19 years
old. It was like December in uh 2017 or
to 2016, like my first year of
university. And I was in the my garage,
like, you know, back home in my family
home. I was in my garage where we had
like a little weightlifting setup. And I
was sat on the bench. I still had the
same gut instinct that she wasn't
telling me everything. So, we're on
FaceTime together, and I said to her
once again, I said, "Listen, tell me the
truth. You're still hiding something. I
need to know the truth. You're killing
me. I'm so stressed, but I need to know
everything. It wasn't just once, was
it?" She's like, "No, it was like, it
was just the mistake. You know, it was
before I ever met you and whatever." I'm
like, "Just like, I don't believe you.
Tell me the truth." And she goes, "Okay,
it was lots of times."
And I said, "How many times did you use
a condom?" And she said, "None of them."
I still remember cuz I was on the phone
with her like this and I went I put the
phone like this so she couldn't see my
face. And I went
like that. Do you know that was like
cheating because she was texting a guy
that she had been intimate with
beforehand while she's in a committed
relationship. That's cheating. That's so
wrong. But the reason why this hurts so
much is because she just trickle truth.
She dropped little truths over time. She
like dripfed the truth. And when someone
does that to you, it makes you literally
go insane because you know that if you
keep [ __ ] aggressively asking them,
keep asking them, keep asking them, keep
asking them, you'll get more and more of
the truth. Someone who tells you the
truth just straight up, they might have
hurt you. You kind of know where you
stand with them. A lot of men are like
that. Like this is why like like men are
often more respectful than women because
a lot of men, not all men, but like a
lot of high-standing masculine men who
you know they're not cowards, a woman
could ask him, "Have you ever cheated?"
And he'll say like, "Yes, three times."
He'll say it straight up like that. And
that that doesn't mean he's a good
person, but the very least he's not like
lying and drip feeding it and whatever.
When a girl does this to you, it can
quite literally drive you insane because
one, you're getting all these hurtful,
you know, realizations that she's been
cheating or she's been talking to this
guy, whatever. But two, you know that if
you press her hard on the issue in this
uncomfortable kind of conflict argument
that then you'll get more and more of
the truth. It leaves you like a
crackhead, like fening for the next bit
of truth. It's so utterly painful to be
in that situation and chances are if
you're watching this, you might have had
a time where a girl was giving you
trickle truths and it's so hurtful. Like
just asking a girl what's happened and
she's cheated on you. Okay, that's
terrible. You know, guys kill themselves
for that. But then her cheating on you,
lying about it, and then giving you
trickle truth. Just giving you a bit of
the truth over like a few days, over a
week. That's so painful. Like that
literally can drive you like mentally
insane. I probably still have like trust
issues. That was like, bro, that was 9
years ago. And I probably still have
some trust issues from that moment.
That's how much it can negatively impact
you when a woman uses trickle truths,
which is one of the most extreme
manipulation tactics. And that's why I'm
going to put this one in the S tier. And
if you're wondering, how do you beat
this? How do you overcome a woman who's
giving you trickle truths, please do
what I didn't have the courage to do,
just leave. Don't try and get to the
bottom of it. I know that for some
[ __ ] up reason, you'll want to know
all the details. Don't. You'll just
drive yourself insane. You'll destroy
her perception of you, which you know
you shouldn't care about, but still it's
like, bro, she'll just think of you like
some some crybaby little [ __ ] as well
who's like controlling and insecure. You
gain nothing from knowing all of the
details. The moment the bare minimum has
been hit for like a girl who's wronged
you, she's disrespected you, she's
cheated on you. Like, you know, the
moment I saw that she was texting a guy,
I should have just left the relationship
right there and then. I was literally,
bro, I was a good boy. I wanted to get
married. I wanted to be in love. I
wanted children. I'm not going to do
that with a girl who's texting other
guys and even has like male friends or
anything. And the moment I found out
that she had sent nud news to this guy,
even though there was so much more, I
should have just completely left the
situation, right? We have like this this
[ __ ] up thing inside of us that wants
to get all the details. We want to ask
all these specific, you know, details so
we can build up the picture in our minds
and it's bro, it's not going to help
you. You're not going to feel any
better. It's not going to like make it
easier to move on. The moment the bare
minimum has ever been hit for a girl to
be like ejected from your life, do it.
Don't stay around to argue. Don't give
her closure. Don't give yourself
closure. Ghost her from everything. And
then don't have this kind of like, you
know, annoyed feeling towards her. Have
this like shrugged shoulders feeling
which is like, "Nope, yeah, I'm not
really attracted to her anymore." That's
the biggest power play you can ever have
on a woman who wrongs you this much. The
biggest power play is not you arguing
with her. It's not you asking her for
all the details. It's not you trying to
convince her that she's a bad person.
Because those things will just make you
look bad because she'll just think, "Ah,
he's so insecure." The biggest power
play is literally you delete her from
everything, even block her so she can't
reach out to you. And if anyone asks, or
even if she asks you like, "What
happened?" You just shrug your shoulders
and say, "Ah, I'm not really attracted
to you anymore." You just say it like
it's a casual thing. That will hurt them
more than you getting in their face and
saying, "No, but you cheated." Because
you want them to admit, "Yeah, I've
wronged you. I'm so sorry. I should have
treated you better." But they're not
going to say that because a lot of these
women, the type of women who are using
this type of [ __ ] manipulation
tactic, they don't have the awareness to
notice value in front of them. They
don't have the awareness for that.
They're [ __ ] [ __ ] up, damaged
people who would hurt the person they
love this much. You're trying to
convince her that, you know, like you're
trying to say to her like, "Come on,
realize that you wronged me. Realize
that you hurt me." They're not going to.
And if she does, she's still going to be
laughing behind your back thinking, "Oh
yeah, he was crying about it." Whatever.
The biggest thing you can do, bro, just
[ __ ] go ghost mode. Shrug your
shoulders when her or her friends ask
you like, "Hey, what happened?"
Literally, just shrug your shoulders
like a little [ __ ] and just go, "I'm
not really into her anymore." That's it.
The next manipulation tactic is makeup
and filters. You know, when I was
growing up, I um the the filters that
were available for people to use was
like the dog filter on Snapchat. Like,
that's how old I am. So on Snapchat,
there was like this dog filter that
would give you like a dog nose and a dog
tongue and ears and it would kind of
like sort of um make your face look a
little bit smoother or whatever when it
was on your face. These days you can
literally use like Photoshop or these AI
softwares that can literally just make
you look hotter even not just on
pictures but even on videos as well. And
of course makeup has been doing this for
like hundreds thousands of years. It's a
form of manipulation because they don't
actually look like that. But when you
keep seeing someone in these Instagram
pictures or videos that they've kind of
magnified or you keep seeing someone
with makeup, your perception of them
kind of increases because they're more
attractive or you know they're trying to
be more attractive, then you're more
invested into them. You care about them
more than they actually should get from
you. I'm going to put this at quite a
low level of of manipulation just
because it's so common these days. Every
guy knows, oh yeah, like you know what
she looks like in makeup is not what she
looks like without makeup. And actually,
most guys are are thinking like, "Yeah,
I kind of like it when the girl's not
wearing much makeup at all, just because
it like it just feels more natural."
It's the same with if you see a girl
who's got all those heavy filters, you
can tell she's been using like those AI
software, whatever, to like change her
face on Instagram. It's actually a bit
unattractive and a lot of guys see right
through it, right? So, it's it's a weird
kind of form of manipulation where most
guys are not actually falling for it at
all. So, I'll crown this as the lowest
weakest version of manipulation, which
we'll say is the F tier. The next
manipulation tactic is the white dress.
The woman in the white dress is a term
that I came up with and it's referring
to a girl who tells you that she's a
good girl even though she's still a hoe.
This is probably a large part of the
female population, especially the type
of girls that you would meet. You know,
when you meet a girl who's very clearly
a hoe, you know where you stand. The
problem is when you meet a girl who
isn't very clearly a hoe and then she
says all the right things to you and she
tells you like, "No, I don't go out. No,
I don't really have male friends. No,
I'm not really texting anyone. No, I
don't like sleep around. No, I just want
a real relationship. I want to get
married and have children." She'll say
all these things which will seem so
attractive to you cuz chances are you'll
want a girl who's like that, but she's
still like the rest of them. When she
says, "I don't really go out," what she
means is, "I go out 10 times a year."
And in 20 to 30% of those times I get
pounded by someone. She's still a hoe.
Like she's still getting [ __ ] by like
two random guys per year. That's still
ho behavior. It's just that like, you
know, she probably has one proper hoe
friend that she's not as badass as. So
she kind of sees herself as like such a
highquality girl compared to her. But to
us, that's still ho behavior. The girl
who says, "I don't really go out. I
don't really party." Still goes probably
like once a month. The girl who says,
"Oh, I'm not really texting guys." I'm
telling you, you know this is true. If
you grabbed her phone and checked
Snapchat and Instagram, she would have
been texting like 20 [ __ ] guys in the
last month, right? She would have
responded to every guy who messaged her,
every guy who responded to her stories,
all these guys who wanted to [ __ ] her,
she's responding to all of them. She's
quite literally texting like 10, 20, 30,
40 guys every month. And these girls, if
you end up getting into a relationship
with them, I give you my word, they'll
still keep responding to all these guys
who are casually, you know, replying to
their Instagram stories or Snapchat
stories, which is basically a form of
cheating. So, you've got to be aware of
the woman who pretends she's wearing
like the white dress. It's like she's
wearing the mask of a good girl. And
this is actually a big form of
manipulation because more and more, mark
my words, girls are realizing what guys
like us want. You know, there's like a
very like stereotypical highvalue man
these days of the type of guy who's
going to the gym. He's on
self-improvement. He's going from
Jeffrey to Adonis. He's meditating. He's
learning about masculinity and
femininity. He's working hard so he can
provide. There's quite a lot of these
guys, you know, like our viewers
basically who are leveling up and we all
basically want the same kind of woman
who's very pure and she's not a
degenerate and she doesn't vape or smoke
and she doesn't have male friends and
she's not going out drinking. Well, more
and more girls are realizing this and
they're realizing how to trap guys like
us and what to say to attract a guy like
us. The problem is most of the girls who
are like this aren't actually like the
woman that you want. They're just
pretending to be. They've been passed
around the class in school and then
they'll say to you like, "No, I don't
really go out. No, I don't really party.
No, I don't hook up with guys. But she's
had like four hookups before. So, for
this reason, I'm going to put this form
of manipulation in the A tier. I'm going
to put it high up because I genuinely
believe most guys in the world, even our
boys, would actually fall for this.
Because, think about it. Before
self-improvement, before I got you onto
this path from going Jeffrey to Adonis,
you were probably struggling with
dating. You weren't really doing so
well. You didn't really have girls who
were like actually genuinely into you.
You know, you had girls who would reply
on your messages, but like not many who
were actually into you. You get on
self-improvement. You level yourself up
and suddenly you get more options. The
problem is the first girls you attract
when you're on this journey. They're
still kind of like blatantly hoes. They
smoke. They vape. They use Tik Tok.
Whatever. So, you don't really take
those seriously. When you get to a
certain point, you'll start to meet
girls that you'll literally say the
words like, "Oh my god, she's perfect.
She's an 11 out of 10. She's not covered
in tattoos. She doesn't vape. She
doesn't go out all the time and you'll
start to like delude yourself into
thinking like, "Oh my god, she's so
good." Just because she's better than
the absolute Jessica's. The problem is
she's still not that great. She's still
going to go out for her friend's
birthday party and she's still going to
dance on like on some [ __ ] guy's
groin when she goes out. She still
replies to 20 guys per month. That's
still ho behavior. Of course it is. Just
by the sheer quantity, that's like such
low quality girl behavior. The problem
is that's probably the highest quality
girl that's been into you. so far. So,
your brain starts getting all deluded to
think that she's perfect when actually,
bro, she's still like a 6 out of 10. So,
how do you overcome this form of
manipulation where a girl's pretending
to be a good girl to you? Never ignore
your gut instinct. You'll pick out some
things that she's mentioned. The fact
that she's not a virgin, the fact that
she's had one hookup before, the fact
that she says, "I don't really go out."
The fact that you've seen her go out to
clubs and parties. You've seen people
tag her in those kinds of environments.
You've heard of her being in a party.
You've seen her smoke before. You've
seen her texting other guys. You've
you've glanced at her phone when she
uses it when she's on Snapchat to see
that she's got like streaks with like
five guys and she's got like 10 unopened
messages from guys. Never ignore those
signs. Those are still the signs of a
girl who's still a hoe. She's not
actually a good girl. The problem is if
you ever confront her about this and
say, "Hey, you know those those things
that I've just seen, you know, you you
say you're a good girl, but those aren't
the traits of a good girl." She will
gaslight the [ __ ] out of you. She will
manipulate you and get angry at you and
call you insecure and say, "No, what?
You're crazy. Yeah, I'm just replying to
some guys. It's not that big of a deal.
No, it doesn't mean anything. No, it's
not." Oh, that male friend. No, he
wouldn't [ __ ] me given the chance. No,
he wouldn't. Oh, this and this and this.
No, it's not that bad. Whatever. You
don't ever actually speak to a girl
about this. Never communicate these
things. You know how everyone in the
world will tell you like, "Ah, men need
to learn how to communicate." No, no,
no, no, no. You never communicate this.
You never communicate that you think a
girl isn't high quality because it will
never end positively for you. She will
just tell everyone you're insecure cuz
you've hurt her feelings, right? You
never communicate this with her. You
just silently observe and the moment you
realize that she isn't your wife and
she's not the mother of your children,
which basically you'll realize within
the first conversation with these girls.
You have some standards and you just
think, "Fuck it. I only need to meet one
good woman in in my entire life. She
isn't it. That's it. Just leave her for
some other chump who's going to fall for
her lies. you don't fall for it, but
also don't argue with her. Don't try and
present all the facts and say, "No,
because if you were a really good girl,
you wouldn't have posted that kind of
Instagram reel and you know, I saw you
were texting those guys. Who are those
guys?" No. Like, don't argue with her,
bro. Cuz she's not going to look at you
and be like, "Oh my god, you're so
right. I'm actually a hoe." Whoa. Thank
you. I never realized. She's not going
to say that. She's going to be like,
"No, I'm not. You're insecure." She's
going to tell everyone you're insecure,
you're controlling, you're weird. So,
just you gain nothing from trying to
convince her to your way of thinking.
The moment you see it, you you act
respectful. You're like, "Oh, one
second." And you just never speak to her
ever again. I've got an interesting form
of manipulation here, and we're going to
call it with quotes. Caught me. This is
specifically for the guys who are now in
their late 20s. Chances are most guys
watching this, you've not really
experienced this, and you're not going
to for a few years, but let me just tell
you, okay, this form of manipulation
we're just going to call caught me. This
is when you're in your late 20s and for
the first time in your life, you're
starting to date women who are in their
30s. The problem is a lot of women who
are in their 30s are bitter and
resentful. The reason why is because
when they were in their 20s they were in
like peak attractiveness. They were
getting [ __ ] by all the guys that they
wanted. They were enjoying themselves.
But as they get to 30, 31, 32, 33, 4, 5
years old, they're noticing that they're
not as attractive. They're noticing that
for 10 plus years, for 15 years, guys
have been [ __ ] them without actually
like taking them out on dates, whatever.
And so these girls, usually around the
time that they hit about 30 to 33, they
get like this sense of resentment for
for men being like, "Yeah, all these
guys, they're not real men. They don't
actually caught me. They don't take me
out. They're just, you know, they're
like fake men. They're just little boys.
They don't they don't want anything
serious." So this girl, as a form of
manipulation, will start getting a bit
angry towards new guys that she meets,
saying, "Yeah, you're not a real man
unless you caught me. You're not a real
man unless you take me out on dates."
The reason why this is a form of
manipulation is because she's already
[ __ ] more than 10 guys for free within
a few hours of meeting them in the last
like 10 15 years of her life. Now, she
wants you to put in all the extra work
that the previous guys in her life never
had to do just because she's angry at
them and she takes it out on you. If
you're watching this right now and
you're young, you're like a teenager, if
you're in your early 20s, you probably
have never experienced this before, so
you can't really relate. But I'm just
kind of telling you this as like
something you're going to experience 5
to 10 years from now. And if there's any
older guys who are watching this, like
late 20s or even 30s, they'll be nodding
their head thinking, "Holy [ __ ] Hamza's
got balls, cuz this is exactly so
[ __ ] true. Courting a woman basically
means being a gentleman, putting in
effort, taking her out on dates, paying
for the date, opening the door,
whatever." And there's nothing wrong
with that, by the way. I think that's an
awesome thing. That's what I would do as
well. The problem is courting a woman
who is in her 30s, who has given her
body to over 10, maybe even 20, 30 guys
who didn't court her. Why would you be a
clown? Why would you take a girl
seriously who's literally been [ __ ] by
more than 20 to 30 guys who just kind of
casually met her, [ __ ] her within a
few hours of meeting her, didn't pay for
anything, didn't open the doors for her,
didn't treat her like a lady, whatever,
and now she's telling you, "No, you have
to put in more work." Even though she's
older, she's less attractive, her value
has literally diminished, and now she
wants the highest price. It logically
makes no sense. But with a woman's kind
of like aggressive, bitter kind of
attitude. Some guys fall for it and they
think, "Oh, well, you know, like
courting and you know, being a
gentleman, like those are the things
I've wanted to do." Yes, sure. But
you've wanted to do that with like a
beautiful 21, 24 year old woman who's
like super happy and she's polite and
respectful and she hasn't had much of a
sexual past. You don't do that with a
girl who's already had her fun and now
she's realized like, yeah, like, you
know, she's not as attractive. Like, a
woman objectively is less attractive
when she's in her 30s than when she's in
her 20s. Now, there are exceptions to
the rule. There is a girl who's wasn't
very attractive in her 20s, but then she
had a glow up, whatever. Okay, sure. But
in general, for most women, they will
have fun in their teenage years, fun in
their 20s, and it's only once they hit
about 30 to 33, that's when realization
will hit them and think like, "Oh [ __ ]
like I've got to have children soon, and
you know, I should get married soon
because it's kind of embarrassing. I'm
still 30 and I'm still getting like
[ __ ] by all these random guys. Why
don't all any of these guys want to take
me seriously?" Well, yeah, because you
[ __ ] like 20 guys in the last like 5
10 years, right? And and so now, of
course, no guy wants to take you
seriously. Why would Why would you want
to go take a girl on a date that is now
35 years old? She's older than you. She
She might not even be fertile anymore.
She might not actually be able to have
kids anymore. She's got four
ex-boyfriends. One of them's in prison.
She's [ __ ] 20 to 50 guys in her life
so far. Why would you want to take this
girl on a proper date? Of course, you
wouldn't. But of course, this girl will
be angry at you and she'll say these
gaslighting sort of manipulation terms
of like, "Oh, yeah, but a real man
would." If you're really into the
traditional relationship, but then you'd
caught me like a traditional masculine
man would. And you might fall for this
form of manipulation because you're
thinking, "Oh, yeah, well, I am like a
masculine guy, and you know, as a
masculine guy, you're supposed to
provide. Yeah, you're supposed to
provide for a highquality woman, and
these women are not high quality." Now,
there are certainly high-quality women
who are in their 30s, but they're all
married. By nature of being a
high-quality woman and also being above
30, she is going to be married. Of
course, she is. It's just by like the
objective law of the [ __ ] world. If
there is a woman who's high quality, a
man is going to marry her. If you see a
woman who's above 30 and she's not
married, it's because basically men
around the world have decided not to
marry her. And you should probably
think, "Oh, yeah, there's a reason for
that." Now, of course, this girl will
say, "No, because it was my my choice."
No, it wasn't, bro. I guarantee some of
the guys that she's been in love with,
she would have been happy to marry them.
Of course, just use your [ __ ] brain.
used like just common sense. If she's
above 30 and she's not married, it
wasn't because she made the choice. It's
because no man actually wanted to marry
her. Of course, it was. Don't fall for
the the lies of these women when they
act like, "No, I bring all the table and
I'm the one who's decided to stay
single." Okay. And now you're begging
guys to to court you and to take you on
a date. It doesn't seem to me like
you're the one who's decided to stay
single. If you're like trying to tell
guys like, "Yeah, you've got to take me
out on a date and stuff." No, you're
just [ __ ] miserable to be around. So,
I'm going to put this in the lowest
category, F minus tier, because if you
fall for this, you're a [ __ ] idiot.
By all means, bro, courting a woman and
being a gentleman is a good thing, bro.
By all means, if you want to be like a
gentleman, if you want to learn how to
like, you know, go on a date where
you're being so traditional and
masculine and you pay for the date, you
pull her chair open, you whatever. Okay,
those things are sweet. But do that for
a girl who deserves it. Do that for the
beautiful girl that you meet who's who's
similar age to you. Maybe she's younger
than you. She's 21 years old. Let's say
you're 18, she's 18. She's a virgin.
She's never been touched. Okay, that's a
high quality woman. You go take her on a
date, you're being lovely. You don't do
that with a girl who's 30 plus, who's
literally had 20 plus [ __ ] inside of
her. You don't caught a girl that's had
multiple hookups before. Because if
she's ever had a hookup before, she's
basically shown the world what the price
to her body is, and it's not much. So,
you're a fool. Imagine there's another
guy who got a massive discount, and
you're like, "No, I'll I'll pay full
price." Like, you just be a chump,
right? Imagine there's like a car shop
and they've sold the same car to some
guy for 10K. But then when you go to the
same shop 10 years later, the car is
older and they say, "No, 50k for you."
You'd be like, "Wait, what? Why is it
higher price? It should be literally
lower. It's been another 5 10 years."
That guy got it for 10K. It should be
lower price now. It should be like 5K,
right? And they're like, "No, because
you should have you should have come
earlier." You'd be like, "Okay, well,
I'll just go buy a different car. Why
the [ __ ] am I going like this car's old?
It's it's got high mileage. Why are you
going to charge me more for it having
more mileage? That doesn't make sense."
And imagine the store tries to gaslight
you. Actually, a car with higher mileage
is a good thing. You'd be like, "No,
it's not." Objectively, that is a
[ __ ] lie. Oh, no. No. Because we
could have sold this car last year, but
we just decided not to to because you
just wanted to. We didn't even want to
sell the car, actually, because I, you
know, the car is like a 10 out of 10.
And I am the table. What? Like, why are
you [ __ ] getting weird on me, man?
Like, why you spitting everywhere? Like,
what the [ __ ] wrong with you? You made
your choice. By all means, bro, be a
gentleman for a woman who deserves it.
But if she's had hookups before, if
she's literally been [ __ ] by guys for
free who didn't even take her on a date,
don't be the chump who now dates her
seriously. And and part of this is don't
fall for the scam of the real man. These
days, the term real man is used to
define a guy who has no backbone, no
spine, who basically treats a girl
better than she's actually deserved.
These women, like these girls who are
resentful, bitter, they're in their 30s,
they'll say like, "Ah, there's no real
men." What they're saying is there's no
chumps who will actually date me
seriously because everyone's got some
[ __ ] standards and they don't want to
date a girl who's already ran through
seriously. And bro, there's nothing
wrong with that. These days, you get
called a real man if you're a chump who
courts these kinds of women. You know
how there's a phrase like the nice guy.
The real man is a phrase now where these
girls are trying to gaslit us into
believing that you're a real man if you
like date these women. Seriously, I'm
telling you, don't [ __ ] fall for it,
bro. any guy who falls for this, who
dates one of these women, right? By the
way, if you're like 40 years old and
you're dating a girl who's 33, okay,
it's a bit different. But especially if
you're in your like late 20s, if you're
on this path, you're getting rich,
you're getting jacked, and some girl
who's like 35 years old, she slept with
20 guys before, she slept with 40 guys
before, and she's telling you like,
yeah, you've got to take me out now. You
should be thinking like, no, why the
[ __ ] would I do that? You've slept with
like 10, 15 guys who never took you out.
Why would I take you out? Why are you
saying it like this as well? So now I
need to tell you something about
yourself that maybe you've never really
thought of and everyone is going to
attack you for this. No matter how old
you are, you will always be attracted to
men.
No matter how old you are, you will
always be more attracted to women in
their 20s than any other age group. When
you're in your 20s, you'll want a girl
who's in her 20s as well. When you're in
your 30s, you'll still prefer a woman in
her 20s. Your brain might have just went
into like politically correct mode and
said no because they wouldn't really be
mature. I'm telling you that isn't
actually your belief. Don't fall for
what society has told you. That is not
your belief. For men who have not been
brainwashed by society, whether you're
20 or 60, you would prefer being with a
woman who's in her 20s. It's only these
guys who are like modern-day cucks who
are kind of like, "No, because she
wouldn't be mature. She wouldn't have
life experience." Life experience isn't
attractive to men. Like it's just bro
it's a masculine thing to want a woman
who's pure who actually doesn't have
much life experience because you want
her to experience it with you guys. Like
it's so weird. So many guys now like
they've been lied to that they fully
believe it where they're like no because
I wouldn't want a girl who's like you
know 23 years old because she's not been
ran through yet. I want her to have been
[ __ ] by four more guys before she gets
with me. What? Stop that [ __ ] If
you're in your 20s, you want a girl in
her 20s. If you're in your 30s, you want
a woman in her 20s. If you're in your
40s, you would still want a woman in her
20s. Don't fall for this [ __ ] where
where you think like, "Oh, but you know,
it feels a bit creepy." No, it's not.
She's a consenting [ __ ] adult. Don't
don't fall for any of this modern day
[ __ ] A woman in her 20s is going to
be more attractive to you even when
you're 50 years old than a woman who's
also 50. Don't fall for it, bro. This is
completely normal and healthy. People
will say like, "Oh, it's pedophilia."
It's like, what? So they're saying that
a woman in her 20s is still a [ __ ]
child then. So they're being sexist, not
me. If she's a consenting adult, if
she's above the age of 18, but I'm
saying like 20s because 18 is still
pretty young. But let's say, okay, 22,
24 years old, that is like peak
attractiveness for a woman, but also she
has such little like time that she's
been in on Earth, which means that, bro,
she's got less [ __ ] inside of her.
That's attractive to guys. Don't you
ever let anyone gaslight you into
believing that like a girl who's older,
who's [ __ ] more guys, is more
attractive than when like 10 years
before that point when she was like 24
and she had like one boyfriend before.
Don't let anyone lie to you and say
this. I It sounds maybe creepy, dirty
what I'm saying, but it's completely
normal. It's consensual. It's like
legal. It's it's absolutely like morally
fine for you to be, let's say, 38 years
old and to have like a 24year-old wife
or girlfriend. And you would prefer your
wife or girlfriend being 24 rather than
click your fingers and make her 34. And
the thing is, if you really ask, imagine
you've got like a girl, right? Imagine
you've got like a 35-year-old wife and
you said, "Hey, if I could click my
fingers and make you 24, would you want
me to do it?" She'd be like, "Yeah,
yeah, yeah, sure. 100%." Even she would
agree with it as well. And she'd be
like, "Yeah, I'd want to be younger as
well." And you say, "But what about the
life experience?" She'd be like, "No,
but if you could make me younger, that'd
be [ __ ] awesome." Women want to be
younger themselves. It's only when a man
has preference for a woman who hasn't
been ran through that then everyone's
like, "Ah, he's sexist. A he's a
pedophile." I'm not telling you to go
for a woman who's below the age of
consent, which is pedophilia. Okay,
that's that's wrong. Absolutely. You
will always want a woman in her 20s,
even if you're in your 20s, 30s, 40s,
50s. You know, for women, it's actually
not the same thing. For women in their
20s, they actually prefer guys who are
about 30 years old. For women in their
30s, they prefer guys who are in the
late 30s. For women in their 40s, they
prefer a guy who's about mid-40s. For
women in their 50, they prefer guys who
are 40 to 50. Basically, women's age
correlates to the man's age in terms of
their preference, but the man's age does
not correlate to the woman's age in
terms of their preference. There's a
study that found this, and the study
almost like broke the internet because
everyone was like, "Wow, all these guys
are like pedophiles, whatever." Which
basically got people to rate what age
they found most attractive of the
opposite sex based on their own age. So,
imagine they they interviewed a bunch of
men aged like 20 all the way to like 60
and asked them, "Okay, what age of a
woman is most attractive to you?" And
the age consistently from guys who were
20 years old to guys who were 60 years
old, the age they everyone rated was
like 21, 22, 21, 23, 21 all the way.
Even for guys who were like 50 years
old, they said like 21, which actually,
bro, it makes sense. But for women, it
wasn't the same. For women who were in
their 20s, they rated a guy who was a
little bit older, a little bit older, a
little bit older, a little bit older,
which makes sense, right? So you need to
know, bro, this is just normal. This is
how you feel. I hate the fact that
people are trying to like relate this to
something as extreme and as sickening as
like being attracted to a child because
that's [ __ ] wrong and disgusting.
Also, it's sexist towards women saying
that like you're comparing like a
[ __ ] 24 year old woman to like a
child. No, she's a [ __ ] grown adult
at this point. If you're 35 years old,
you'd still want a girl who's 24 years
old. If you're 44 years old, you still
want the 24 year old. don't lie and and
listen to like there'll be some like
cook little left-wing little [ __ ] in
the chat below and saying like, "Oh, you
guys are all weird. I'm 44 and I love
the fact that my wife has been ran
through." It's like, "What the fuck?"
They'll be like, "I wouldn't want a
24-year-old because she'd be immature.
So what? You'd want a girl who's older
and who has had more [ __ ] inside of
her. You want her to have experience
more of life without you. You know, she
can gain life experience with you by her
side. And that's like a beautiful
masculine feeling to want. Someone needs
to say this to you, bro. Men are
attracted to purity and youthfulness in
a woman. We aren't attracted to
maturity. We're not attracted to life
experience. We're not attracted to a
woman who's already had a lot of life
experience before us. We want her to
have life experience and maturity. But
with us, not before she meets us, right?
Don't let anyone gaslight you into
saying that this is wrong or it's
sickening or any of this [ __ ] that
people try and say. This is an
absolutely normal, consensual, legal,
completely healthy thing, which is that
if you're in your 20s, you want a woman
who's in her 20s. If you're in your 30s,
you still want a woman who's in her 20s.
The reason why it's important for this
part is because when you get old enough,
maybe late 20s, that's when you'll first
start ending up dating some girls who
are in their 30s, but never lie to
yourself. Just always know you'd still
prefer if she was like 24 years old.
That's the brutal part of like meeting a
nice girl who's like 32 because you'll
just think in your mind, man, like damn,
like she's probably had like [ __ ]
four, five, six, eight boyfriends. She's
had 10, 15 hookups. Most women who are
in their 30s has quite literally slept
with like 20 to 50 guys. Now, think
about it. If she started having sex at
17 years old, and let's say that she's
34, that's 17 years. If she only had sex
with two guys per year, which isn't a
lot, bro. Some girls do two guys in a
month, right? two guys per year. That's
34 guys that she's had sex with. That's
two guys per year. Even let's say if she
has sex with one guy per year, which I'm
telling you, bro, no girls only have sex
with one guy per year. She might have
had one guy for three years straight
when she was in a relationship. And then
she would have had one guy a month, she
would have had like four guys in 3
months, right? So, but even if it was
minimum, one guy per year, and she she's
been having sex from 17 now to 34.
That's 17 guys that she's had inside of
her. A lot of those guys wouldn't have
just been just one time, you know, 1
hour little [ __ ] It would have been
like a thousand sexual sessions with one
guy. It would have been 300 getting
pounded by the same guy. It's a lot,
right? We are not attracted to a woman
who's already had all these experiences.
And it's time someone actually says this
and normalizes it. We are attracted to a
woman who hasn't had that much life
experience before us and then she gets
it with us. That's what's attractive to
men. And don't you let any of these
modern-day little woke leftist weirdos
try and convince you otherwise. These
little cuck Jeffies, don't let them
convince you otherwise. So, this form of
manipulation, which is from the older
women telling you to date them
seriously, caught me. Or another phrase
for this same one could be be a real
man, which basically means to take these
girls seriously who have already been
ran through. They're past their peak
even though you're not. The only reason
why you'd fall for this manipulation
tactic is because you started to believe
the lies of like modern-day society,
which tells you that like, yeah, your
desire of a woman who hasn't had that
much [ __ ] inside of her is wrong and
it's evil. No, it's just completely
normal and healthy. If you just listen
to your own gut instinct, you won't fall
for this manipulation tactic. If you
fall for this, if you meet a girl who
you can tell is 33 years old, she's had
sex with 15 to 30 guys before, and she
tells you like, "No, you've got to
caught me. you've got to take me out on
dates, but you can just tell that she's
had hookups with guys before. So, she's
making you kind of invest more than she
did those guys and you actually do it
and you actually date this girl
seriously, then bro, it's like, come on,
that's pure Jeffrey level. So, we're
putting this at F minus. The next
manipulation tactic that a lot of women
and even society uses against men is
another quote, you're controlling. This
often happens when a guy is establishing
some pretty healthy boundaries. Like for
example, you don't want your girl to go
in an environment which is absolutely
obsessed with sex. Like for example,
parties and nightclubs. You don't want
your girl to post her body on social
media. In other words, you just don't
want your girl to act like she's single.
Women these days use this manipulation
tactic all the time where they'll look
you in the eyes and say, "Well, you're
controlling. You're insecure." The truth
is, you're not. You're establishing
healthy boundaries. A lot of girls talk
about boundaries these days, but when a
man establishes the boundaries, he's
seen as controlling. When a woman
establishes the boundaries, she's seen
as like a boss girl, you go girl kind of
mindset. But you're allowed to have your
own boundaries and values, too. And if
you don't want a girl to go out, that's
not controlling. That's just you saying,
"Hey, I don't want to date the kind of
girl who does that because it's not
attractive to me." But then when she
says you're controlling, it's a form of
manipulation because it can kind of
cause doubt inside of you to think,
wait, like, is this too far? What's the
way to navigate this situation? And the
thing is, the way to navigate the
situation is exactly what you did, which
is establish some boundaries. Say,
"Okay, well, I don't want to date a girl
who goes out to clubs, who's got male
friends, who's got all this stuff." The
problem is, most girls are just so
emotionally immature that when you've
established some healthy boundaries,
they'll just attack you for it. Their
friends will attack you for it. I had an
ex-girlfriend who still wanted to keep
going to parties and stuff where guys
would try and hook up with her. And when
I told her like, "That's not okay. You
know, it's boundaries. You shouldn't be
acting like you're single." She started
calling me controlling and told everyone
as well. And you know, like it kind of
feels bad when when everyone in the
social circle thinks that you're like
some controlling guy, but it's still,
bro, never back down. Your gut instinct
will always tell you the truth. You
don't want to be dating a girl who goes
out to these environments and and who
you even have to control. So, I'm going
to put this form of manipulation when a
girl calls you controlling around the
middle, like Ctier. And the way to
overcome this is don't actually even try
to like establish this boundary. You
know, like if a girl is going out and
you don't want her to, you shouldn't try
and change her. You should meet a girl
who already fits in your boundaries and
values. If you meet a girl who's
awesome, let's be honest, she's not, but
she goes out to these parties and clubs,
then she's not awesome. And if you have
to try and change her, it means that
she's not good enough. Then you should
just leave the situation as it is. You
should just leave this girl. You should
just think, yeah, like, bro, she's not a
girlfriend. She's not a wife. Your
wife's not going out partying and
dancing and grinding on guys and smoking
weed with them or some [ __ ] Your wife
isn't doing that [ __ ] It's not about
establishing boundaries. It's about
establishing that you've got balls and
then ending it with the girl. If you
have to establish boundaries like this,
you should just end it instead. If you
have to try and convince your girl like
please don't go out to the place where a
lot of cheating happens where you know
like like single people go, degenerate,
not even single, but just degenerate
people go, right? Like like clubs and
parties are for [ __ ] degen people.
Like actually degenerate little soulless
people, right? So if your girl's going
out, you shouldn't be trying to convince
her to stop going to establish your
boundaries. you should just end things
with her. The next manipulation tactic,
another quote, "He's just a friend."
This is when you catch a girl texting
other guys and she tells you like, "No,
he's just the friend. No, he's just
like, you know, he's the only friend
I've got. No, no, no, no, he no,
nothing's happened between us. No,
nothing would happen. No, he wouldn't
[ __ ] me. No, no, no. We're just
friends." This is such a common
manipulation tactic cuz women of today,
they crave validation and attention like
no other. And so they are accepting
messages and advances from all kinds of
guys and they delude themselves into
thinking that the guy who texts them
who's a bit of a beta male [ __ ] who you
know who's hasn't really put like his
sort of intention across they start to
believe that this guy is like actually
you know just a friend whatever. And the
reason why this is like a form of
manipulation is because she would
actually get [ __ ] by this guy more
often than not. The guy would [ __ ] her
given the chance more often than not.
But when she says he's just a friend, it
basically diffuses the situation and
makes you look like an [ __ ] Because
then it's the same thing about being
controlling or insecure, which is like,
okay, well, is she not allowed to have
friends? And then it puts you in this
kind of awkward state where you're like,
well, yeah, but like, no, but with a
guy, it's it's not the same thing. You
know, if he would [ __ ] you, then it's
not really friendship, but he hasn't
tried to [ __ ] you. So, it puts you in
this kind of like, you know, mental
overthinking bandwidth thing, which
fries your brain and you know that it's
wrong. There's a reason why it feels bad
when you see her texting guys. If you
see her texting some girl and you don't
feel anything about it. If imagine she's
hanging out with her female friend. No,
there's no guys. You don't get a gut
instinct that anything's wrong. If she's
the friend is like a good person as
well. It's not that you've got a problem
with her having friends. It's that
you've got a problem with her having
friends of the opposite sex because it's
unnatural. A lot of people, men and
women these days, like to act so
confident by saying like, "Oh, well, I'm
so secure. My partner can have friends.
You know, you guys are all insecure."
They're cucks. Like, you know, the the
the chair in the the corner of the hotel
room, those people sit on that chair and
watch their wife get pounded. The guy
who looks at us and says like, "Oh, you
guys are all insecure. My wife's got
lots of male friends." Yeah. She's going
to cheat with one of them. Think about
it. When a woman cheats, she doesn't
just like walk through the street, see a
guy who's hot, and quickly get [ __ ] by
him like in the alleyway. No, no, it's
not like random. A woman always cheats
with the guy that she's already speaking
to while she's in the relationship,
right? Like women especially, they don't
cheat spontaneously like a man cheats. A
man will cheat just given the chance.
Like if he's, you know, he's um doing
some work event in a hotel and he walks
through the corridor and just happens to
make eye contact with a girl, he'd [ __ ]
her right away. Okay, sweet. But the
girl cheats with the guy that she's
already been building up a bit of an
emotional connection with. 99 times out
of 100, if your girl is going to cheat
with you, it's with a guy she's already
texting. If that's so likely, then a
girl texting guys, it's not just a red
flag, cuz a red flag is an indicator of
danger. It is the danger. I am not in
danger, Skylar. I am the danger. She's
quite literally stringing these guys
along. And a lot of these guys literally
believe that they're close to [ __ ]
her and they will do when they want to.
Like, think about it. Another guy's
thinking about your girl, thinking, "Oh
yeah, she text me every day. He would
[ __ ] her." Like the situation to think
about in your mind is imagine she and
the guy that she's texting go on a night
out together and they drink. And imagine
they just end up back at either one of
their places, but they're friends.
Imagine if your girl starts flirting
with him, takes her clothes off, bends
over, looks back at him, and says,
"Please [ __ ] me. I'm so horny." Do you
really think that guy's not going to
just pull his pants down and [ __ ] her?
Do you really think that guy's going to
be like, "But wait, what about our
friendship?" No. He doesn't give a [ __ ]
about their friendship. He would do it
casually, just thinking, "Oh, yeah.
Well, even if we uh, you know, stay
friends, this is pretty [ __ ] awesome.
I get to have my friends with benefits
with this girl now. I've wanted to [ __ ]
her for so long. Every male friend a
girl has would absolutely do that. And a
lot of these girls will try and gaslight
you and say, "No, he's been my friend
for ages." He'd still [ __ ] her given the
chance. No, he's got a girlfriend. He'd
still [ __ ] her given the [ __ ] chance.
Don't you ever fall for this [ __ ]
where a girl will look to you and say
like, "Oh, well, you know, he's just a
friend and and it's, you know, it's
fine. It's not cheating. You're just
insecure." Whatever. Don't fall for it.
A woman speaking to other men while
she's in a relationship with you, it's
wrong and it's disrespectful. It's
completely disrespectful for you because
a woman who respects you will not be
texting other guys. The moment you see
her texting any other guys, you should
just end things right away. Not just
because it's a sign of cheating, but
also because it just shows you that
she's like a disrespectful person. Her
mother's probably a [ __ ] [ __ ] as
well. Her dad's probably a little [ __ ]
and she thinks that this is okay. She
comes from a household where it's okay
to be talking to like other guys and
basically stringing along options. But
if you were doing it, she would attack
you and gaslight you. So basically,
she's just like a [ __ ] low tier,
horrible little human being. This is a
big form of manipulation because look,
again, a lot of guys go crazy about
this. You know, I'm telling you, okay,
leave a girl who's doing this. But the
chances are if you're watching this and
your girlfriend's been texting guys, you
won't have the balls to leave her
because it doesn't feel quite serious
enough. Nothing's really happened just
yet. You kind of believe her and it's
all this vague thing of like they
probably would [ __ ] her given the
chance, but they haven't already. And I
just I just don't know. when she
promises me so so hard that nothing's
going to happen or whatever. If I tell
you you should leave a girl like this,
you probably won't. And this is why it's
a big form of manipulation. Because
look, if she told you the truth, which
was, "Oh yeah, I'm just stringing him
along. In cases you mess up, I'll
probably go [ __ ] one of these guys I'm
texting." That's the truth. That's
literally objectively, by the law of
probability, the truth. When girls are
texting their guy friends, they are
literally stringing them along because
they'll go and sleep with one of them
after they've ended the relationship
with you. That literally objectively is
what happens more often than not. the
guy that she goes to right after your
relationship ends or even before your
relationship ends, like she's cheating
basically, is a guy she's already
texting. If she looked you in the eyes
and told you the truth, like, "Oh yeah,
one of these guys I'll probably [ __ ]
after me and you split up." You'd be
thinking, "Okay, well that's literally
cheating then. You're entertaining the
conversation." You'd end. It's a form of
manipulation cuz she's like, "What? No.
No, I'm not. No, he's just a friend. No,
we just text casually. That's
disgusting, bro. I remember I was dating
a girl who I was surprised, right?
because she seemed like a good quality
woman to me. It was like that case of
like you know the woman in the white
dress and she went on Snapchat once and
I was like what you have Snapchat?
You're like 25 20 something years old. I
was just disgusted by it right away but
instantly I felt bad cuz I was like oh
man I'm probably going to have to break
up with her the moment I saw that she
had Snapchat cuz I was like I guarantee
this [ __ ] is [ __ ] texting guys. I
just knew it. Any girl who's got
Snapchat, especially when they're in
their 20ies as well, you know, if you're
like 16 years old watching this and your
girlfriend's 16, she's got Snapchat.
Okay, fine. But if you're in your mid20s
and you're a [ __ ] grown adult and
you're still using Snapchat, it's just
[ __ ] embarrassing. And so I saw her
on her phone. I was like, "Let me see
who you've been speaking to." And she
showed me and she had multiple guys she
had a streak with. And I was like,
"That's [ __ ] haram." Like that's
disgusting. And she was like, "No, but
they're just friends." I was like, I
didn't even want to hear it. I was just
like, "But you're texting other guys.
That's cheating." She's like, "No, it's
not cheating. It's not." I was like,
"No, but it is to me." And she kind of
went silent and and you know, it was
later on she actually said to me like,
"Yeah, I should have known that you're
the type of guy who it would have been
seen as cheating with." Basically, what
she was saying is, "I should have known
you've got a pair of balls." Unlike most
of the men in the world, most men would
have been fine with it. I should have
known that you wouldn't because I ended
with her and it's like she's she's
wanted to get back with me since that
point. And it's like, yeah, I stood up
for my [ __ ] self. Of course I did,
bro. It's not even about if she's
cheated with them or not, or if she's
going to. Just the fact that she's
texting other guys does not make me feel
good. If a girl makes me not feel good,
I'll end with her. Bro, you've got to
have like this big G, like this big dick
personality to be thinking, yeah, like,
bro, I'm a [ __ ] like I'm I'm gonna
have [ __ ] standards for myself. And
if a girl does something that makes me
feel horrible, I'm just going to remove
her from my [ __ ] life. It's her loss.
Right. For you, you should be nodding
your head with like a sense of ego being
like, "Yeah, I'm a [ __ ] future
millionaire. I'm going to have a 10 out
of 10 physique. I'm going to be like
Adonis. I'm going to be like the
ultimate man in the [ __ ] world. I
already have that [ __ ] I'm a [ __ ]
28-year-old millionaire kickboxer,
bodybuilder. I'm a [ __ ] leader of
millions of guys. If this [ __ ] isn't
going to show me the utmost 10 out of 10
absolute respect, she can go get [ __ ]
and go choose one of these male friends
to go hang out with in his [ __ ] like
2K a month [ __ ] little shitty home or
something. That's fine. Go [ __ ] yourself
then. If I want 10 out of 10 respect
from the woman who's in my life or not
at all. If she wants to go text other
[ __ ] guys like a little stupid little
child like on Snapchat, she can go get
[ __ ] by them. I don't give a [ __ ] I
do. I look like a [ __ ] little [ __ ]
to you that I'd be fine with that
saying, "Oh, but she's it's just
friends, whatever." No. So, you better
[ __ ] act like this as well. You need
a bit more of this aggressive energy,
not not to her, but just to yourself to
be like, "Yeah, bro. If a girl is
texting other guys, she is a
disrespectful little hoe." And you end
with her because you've got some
standards. And you don't end, oh, oh,
you're texting guys. You shouldn't be
texting. You don't try and convince her.
You just shrug your shoulders and say,
"Ah, you're not very attractive to me
anymore." That's what hurts them more.
This form of manipulation, I'm going to
put it in like [ __ ] low down, maybe
like Etier, because if you fall for
this, you're a bit of a [ __ ] [ __ ]
which many of us are. I've I've been
there as well when you kind of accept
the fact when the girl says it's a male
friend, whatever. Never again. Never
again. The moment you see a male name on
her contact list, on her [ __ ]
WhatsApp, Instagram, the moment you see
her texting guys, the moment you see her
liking a guy's picture, you're not
insecure. You've just got two testicles.
In the world of one bald men, you've got
two balls. That's it. In the world of
[ __ ] Cuck Jeff, you're an Adonis. Of
course, your standards are going to be
different. Everyone else will be like,
"Wait, what? You're getting pissed off
that she liked a guy's picture. Yes,
because I'm not a cuck. I don't sit in
that chair in the [ __ ] corner of the
room. I'm not a cuck, little Jeffrey.
And neither are you, right? So, don't
let anyone tell you like, "What are you
insecure, bro?" Bro, let them call us
insecure. We don't want to watch our
girl get [ __ ] by another guy. I'd
rather be insecure than be a [ __ ]
cuck. Right? So, [ __ ] these little
Jeffries. [ __ ] these cucks. [ __ ] these
hoes. [ __ ] all the [ __ ] all the
modernday guys who will try and say to
you like, "Oh, I'm so secure, bro. I'm
so secure. I don't mind if other guys
are flirting with my girl. It's like,
"Okay, go sit in the [ __ ] corner
then, you disgusting little weirdo."
Good girls do not have male friends. You
will never ever take a girl seriously
who has a male friend ever again in your
life. You are not a cuck. You are not a
Jeffrey. I have put you on this path to
becoming more like Adonis. You have two
balls. Whenever you're in doubt, if you
ever get into this kind of situation,
just take your hand like this, grab your
balls, and just count. If there's two
there, understand that you're not okay
with your girl having male friends.
You're not okay with her dangling a
crumb of [ __ ] to these guys who are
your competition. A relationship is like
a castle. You're the king of the castle.
And outside of the castle is the
barbarians who are laying siege. Like,
they'll just sit outside of the castle
and try and wait you out. And what you
want is your queen to be on your side
for you to strategize has to get rid of
those [ __ ] bastards out there. Most
modern-day women, they'll stand on the
walls of the castle and tease the
barbarians and talk to them and
encourage them to try and penetrate the
castle and and to take over the king.
That's disgusting. That queen should be
beheaded. She's not your queen. It's
better to be a king in a castle without
a queen than to have a queen who's
encouraging the barbarians outside to
overthrow you. That's disgusting. That
would destroy your self-esteem. You
never settle for the [ __ ] queen. never
settle for the queen who who strokes the
[ __ ] of the barbarians and leads them on
and dances sexy for them and talks to
them every day. Imagine that. Like
imagine you literally were like a king
of a castle and imagine right outside
the castle there's men who were trying
to take over but you you know the
castle's hard for them to get into so
they're just waiting outside and imagine
you realize that your queen has been
going out to speak to them every single
day having funny conversations with them
just encouraging them motivating them.
That's [ __ ] cheating. That's
cheating.
Don't fall for this [ __ ] This form of
manipulation, Etier. The final form of
manipulation
is a false
rape accusation. There's a story of a
young man named EMTT Till. He was a
black guy in America and he had a
relationship with a white woman. This
was hundreds of years ago and that was
extremely taboo like an inter
interracial relationship back in like
1800s or something. They were in love
with each other till one day some of the
town's folk saw them kissing
a black boy kissing a white girl.
They confronted her
and instead of telling them the truth
saying, "Yeah, I love him.
It was fine." She saves her own social
image because she didn't want to be
judged by them. And so she tells
everyone, "He forcefully kissed me."
They find him in his home and they beat
him and hang him to death. It's only
years, like decades later, that the
woman comes out and she says like, "Oh,
you know, it's been so hard for me. It's
been so hard dealing with what I've had
to deal with." And she basically admits,
"Yeah, she lied about the thing to save
herself from the situation." There are
hundreds if not even thousands of cases
like this where a woman will manipulate
the masses and she will try to convince
people that a man has wronged her and he
has raped her or sexually assaulted her
or abused her when actually he didn't.
Whether she did it for attention or she
did it for money. This happens so often
and it is the most extreme version of
manipulation that a woman can possibly
do. It's when she manipulates people so
seriously where she knows that that man
who the innocent man could be killed or
his life could be ruined. He could be
sent to prison for 20, 30 years. And
girls will do this just because they're
kind of pissed off at you. They'll do
this just because they feel like you
wronged them or you moved on too quickly
or they're just emotional weird little
creatures. I even had a girl say to me
once, I was with her and she literally
said, "Oh yeah, I've tried to accuse a
man of rape before. I swear to God, I've
never felt like that scared in my life.
There are demons out here, girls who get
like a sick kick from this. And they
don't do this with an evil smile on
their face, but they love to put
themselves in like this victim kind of
personality. Oh, another guy abused me.
Oh, another guy abused me. Be very
careful. If you ever meet a girl who
ever talks about being raped or sexually
assaulted before, it's usually never
worth doing anything with them just
because of the risk of like one, they're
usually just [ __ ] up in their head,
they usually damaged people. That's just
one thing. But two, the thing is they
might be lying. More often than not, it
seems these days when a girl says, "Oh,
I've been abused or raped." What they
really mean is they had consensual sex
with a guy that they realized was a bit
of an [ __ ] and now they've taken
consent back afterwards. The the way to
find out if a woman is a lying little
disgusting [ __ ] or not is when she
talks about being raped, be really
empathetic. Be like, "Oh my god, that's
so crazy." Like, "Did you go to the
police?" And when she says no, straight
away you see the red flag and you think,
"Oh my god, she's a dirty little lying
woman. Be careful." If she says, "Yes, I
went to the police. They got the
evidence. He's in prison." Okay, sweet.
That [ __ ] happens. She's a victim. Okay,
let's be nice. Okay, fair enough. Fine.
But more often than not, when a woman
doesn't go to the police, it's like what
happens so often is she'll have
consensual sex with a guy. Months or
years or decades later, she'll come out
and say, "Oh, yeah, he actually abused
me." Just turns out he's rich right now.
He's rich and famous now. Yeah, he
abused me 20 years ago. I've got no
evidence. I didn't go to the police back
then. There's no evidence. But yeah, he
did. And the world will believe her.
This happens to to guys who become
famous to rich. This happens to like
Hollywood celebrities. This happens like
in the me too [ __ ] that happened.
Basically, a guy will be rising up in
life and when a girl sees that, oh [ __ ]
he's got famous now. Then she'll go and
attack him and be like, "Yeah, yeah,
there's no evidence at all. It was 10
years ago. He abused me." No. If if that
was true, you would have went to the
[ __ ] police back then, but you
didn't. You didn't. You don't get to
bring up something that happened 10
years ago that you never reported as a
crime because it wasn't a [ __ ] crime.
It was consensual. It's just like, yeah,
he was a bit of an [ __ ] to you
because you were probably a bit of a
[ __ ] to him as well, right? But do not
fall for this [ __ ] bro. If a woman
shows you a police report, okay, you can
believe her. But don't fall for the
[ __ ] where a girl will be like, "Oh,
yeah. You know that famous guy? You know
that rich guy? Yeah, 5 years ago he
really abused me. Yeah, there's no
evidence at all. No evidence whatsoever.
But yeah, I'm a woman, so you should
just believe me. [ __ ] that. There are so
many cases. is I'll see if my editor can
just show you screenshot after
screenshot of just these false rape
accusations where girls will
consensually get [ __ ] by a guy and
then afterwards maybe because they feel
embarrassed by him or they had a
boyfriend or whatever they'll just say,
"Yep, you know, it was rape." And people
will believe her and she will literally
ruin a guy's life just to save herself
from a bit of like social shame because,
you know, she cheated on her boyfriend
with this new guy so it's easier for her
to say, "Yeah, he forced me." No, she's
just a [ __ ] But the problem is when a
girl makes this kind of claim, most
people, men and women, will instantly
just believe her, which is so wrong. In
the eyes of the law, you're supposed to
be innocent until proven guilty. But if
you're ever accused of rape by one of
these horrible little women, everyone
will see that you are guilty until
proven innocent. And even if you're
proven innocent, a lot of people will
just think you're guilty anyway because
they've just associated you and your
face with like, "Yeah, he's a rapist.
He's an abuser." This is the most severe
form of female manipulation. And if this
ever happens to you, I am so sorry
because I know for a fact like 50% of
people in your life are instantly just
going to believe the woman. Just because
she's a woman, you're a man, you must be
the bad person. Even if she's provided
no evidence, even if you've got
evidence, bro, it's the situation is
[ __ ] This is undoubtedly the highest
form of manipulation. S tier, S+ tier.
Now, just quickly, I want to give you
some advice here. If this ever happens
to you in the future, you you watch this
video right now just so you can mentally
prepare. This is how you save yourself
from this form of manipulation. Every
girl that you sleep with, even your
long-term girlfriend, keep proof, keep
evidence that the sex you had with her
and the time you had with her was
consensual. Let's say you're about to go
hook up with a girl, keep screenshots of
your text messages, screen recording of
your text messages. Whenever a girl
leaves your place, text her like, "Oh,
hey, it was a good night. Have a, you
know, it was thank you for coming over."
And when she replies and says, "Yeah, it
was fun. You know, have a good night."
Screenshot it. Record the the screen.
Show the entire thing. Keep all the
messages. You know how because these
days you can kind of delete a message
that you sent to someone. Keep all the
evidence. If you ever feel a girl is
like sketchy, like after you've had sex
with her, or maybe even you've not had
sex with her, but her behavior just
seems like kind of weird. Be open to
even recording like maybe the the video
or maybe the, you know, you can have
like voice memo or whatever. Just turn
that on. that proves that, you know, it
was consensual or whatever that like
nothing's happened. There was actually a
case I remember reading of a guy who
hooks up with a girl in a nightclub
bathroom. Like, so they're in, you know,
they're dancing in the club. They go to
the toilet, they lock the cubicle, and
they have sex in there. And the next
day, she said it was rape because she
had a boyfriend and her friends knew
that she had a boyfriend and her friends
might have told, you know, her
boyfriend. So, she's just said that guy
raped her. But that guy actually
recorded it on a voice memo where you
could hear her literally saying like,
"Oh, yeah, put it in me. Yeah, I would
like it." Whatever. And that saved him
from going to prison. Like she literally
called the police. She, you know, she
had evidence as well, right? Think about
how [ __ ] that is. She had evidence.
They took it to court, but his voice
memo literally saved the day. So just be
careful with this. I don't want you to
be like overly neurotic and be so scared
of girls, but you should actually have
like a bit of fear because you'd be
surprised. It's not always like the
obvious girl who will do this to you.
Sometimes they can seem like sweet,
normal people. So if you ever get that
gut instinct that something's wrong,
collect some evidence. In fact, you may
as well just collect some evidence for
every girl you're with because it takes
you, you know, 10 seconds to just
[ __ ] screenshot the messages or
screen record them. It takes you 5
seconds to just put on the voice memo
app when you're kind of saying good
night to her outside and, you know,
she's like, I had so much fun. You hear
you guys kissing or something. It
doesn't take much effort at all for you
to just capture a bit of evidence which
will be used in court and it might
literally save you one day. And this is
especially true if you are the type of
guy who you know for a fact you're going
to be [ __ ] a lot in your life. If
you're like the type of guy who, you
know, you're not going to ever hook up
with a girl, okay, fair enough. You
know, you're just gonna have a
girlfriend then a wife, sweet. But if
you're the type of guy who who wants to
or is [ __ ] a lot, 100% be capturing
this evidence. The highest tier men on
the planet, they literally take this to
an extreme level. They'll get girls to
sign forms and to record videos of
themselves saying that they consent to
having sex. You know, like some some
famous celebrities, rappers, whatever.
if they're about to sleep with a girl,
they'll quite literally have like their
legal team come in and like, you know,
speak to the woman and get her to sign
documents and everything because they
just don't want to risk it, right? Even
though that sounds crazy autistic or
whatever, when you really think about
it, it's like it's not that big of a
deal. Imagine you're like a famous guy
and your like team come in one day or
you know you've got some form, some
documents, or you get your phone and
say, "Hey, this is a bit weird, but like
I'm just going to record this." Hey, do
you consent to me [ __ ] you? And she's
like, "What? Yeah, I like to [ __ ] really
really hard. Do you want to get [ __ ]
really hard?" She's like, "Yeah." You
know what I It sounds a bit autistic,
but imagine if that silly, like stupid
little video saves you from getting put
into [ __ ] prison. Just be very
careful, bro, because if a girl ever
accuses you of rape just by how the
human brain, the collectiveness of
humans work, more often than not, most
people will believe her just because
she's a woman. It's just that crazy.
Even if there's no evidence, even if
it's ridiculous, like she'll say like,
"Oh, it happened 20 years ago." or some
crazy [ __ ] like that, most people will
just believe her. So, just be extremely
careful because women can ruin your
life. Think about it. A girl who loves
you can use many of these forms of
manipulation that we've discussed today.
A girl who loves you, she can literally
manipulate you to the point that you go
insane. Never mind a girl who doesn't
love you, who maybe even [ __ ]
despises you, thinks you're an [ __ ]
whatever. It's not crazy to say like,
bro, like girls ruin men's lives more
often than not. Like, if a man's life is
ruined, the probability of it being
because of a girl is pretty [ __ ]
high. It's like one of the biggest
reasons why like men's life is ruined.
And this video I I really feel I've done
like God's work here because we need to
highlight this to guys. Women have heard
so much throughout their lives that men
are dangerous. Men are this. Men are
that. But most guys haven't really heard
this. And if we speak about it as men,
it's always hushed and it's like, "Oh,
stop being crazy. Stop being insecure.
You're just weird. You hate women." It's
not that. It's just that you need the
same form of protection, too. I'm taking
a hit to my sort of like brand in some
ways and my social status when I make a
video like this exposing like what women
do to men because a lot of people will
see this and be like, "Ah, this guy
hates women. Oh, this guy's a weirdo.
He's talking about women like that." But
if this was a a video of a woman
teaching women how to avoid manipulation
and abuse, everyone would be like, "Wow,
that's so wholesome, right? It's when we
talk about it as like men who have went
through [ __ ] with girls. Everyone just
thinks of us as like we hate women." No,
of course we don't. I'm making this
video not so that you hate women and you
get scared of them, but that you can
find the girls who are manipulating you,
get them out of your life ASAP, so that
you can find the girl who's actually
genuinely a good person. That's why what
I want for you from this video. If you
want more advice like this, by the way,
the top link in the description is my
program, Library of Adonis, where I've
got hours and hours and hours of content
like this, some of which is even like
too controversial for me to post here on
YouTube. and you you would probably love
to join the community of guys who can
openly speak about [ __ ] like this. We've
got guys who come in there and they're
able to get support of like, you know,
the [ __ ] that's happening with some girl
right now. And so, it's a really
beautiful place for you to come into to
be surrounded by other guys on
self-improvement who are on the same
path as you. Jeffree to Adonis, do the
hard work, especially when you don't
feel like it. Wa!