I can predict your entire life with
these five scores. You were never taught
to understand yourself. Every device
comes with a manual. Every occupation
comes with a job description. But we
have never been taught how to understand
and use the mind that we've been given.
This is my biology lab where I spent
every day studying frog samples. On the
outside, I was succeeding. I was on
track to a secure career. My parents
were happy and I was literally paid to
study biology, which is what I was
passionate about. And yet, on the
inside, I was failing. I was lost. It
was about this time that I discovered
Jordan Peterson. I trusted him
immediately because of his credentials,
but also because he was willingly risk
his career for what he believed in. He
talked about this widely studied
personality model called the big five
matrix. He described how this model
would predict how much money you would
make, how long you'd live, how healthy
you'd live, and even how successful your
marriage would be, and what jobs you'd
be proficient at. So, when he launched
his Big Five personality assessment, I
was one of the first to purchase it. I
finished the assessment in about 20
minutes and I took it outside to read. I
read this test under that tree and it
changed my life forever. Within a week
of that test, I had quit my PhD program
which I had invested 3 years into. I had
walked into the recruiter's office and
began the process of enlistment. And all
this because of the power of that one
test. This is my understand assessment
from 6 years ago. The number that scared
me into action was my conscientiousness
score. This number meant that it would
be destined to be unfit, poor,
unmaraged, and basically end up a loser.
According to the psychological
literature, it's practically impossible
to change these scores. But I was
determined to take control of my life no
matter what it would take me. It took me
6 years, but I did the actions required
to change my CC score, and now I have a
personality that can effectively run a
business that serves hundreds. In this
video, I will share all that I have
learned. So, what even is personality
exactly? It's the frame of reference
with which we see the world. This is
what we use to categorize threats and
opportunities. People use different
words for this things like attitude or
mindset or character. But none of these
are studied. None of these have a
specific definition. And none of these
have predictive power. The big five
matrix is the only personality model
that has predictive power. What this
means is if you know the five numbers of
a person, you can statistically estimate
where they would end up. The big five
has five traits. And here are those five
traits. Let's start with a trait that
you recognize. Extraversion. We all know
people who walk into a classroom and
think so many opportunities, so many
stories that I can tell and so many
relationships that I can build. How many
people can I speak to? That would be
somebody high on extraversion. On the
other side, there's of course people who
walk into the classroom, don't really
want to talk to anybody. They see
threats rather than opportunities, would
rather go to the back of the classroom,
go to the corner, and hope nobody
interacts with them. when it comes to
conscientiousness. This looks like an
army general who's dealing with
logistics and personnel and deadlines
and enemy movements and has his handle
on everything despite the complexity and
has systems to make order out of the
chaos. That's high C. On the other side
of the spectrum, Los Ci, this looks like
a college student who's always missing
deadlines, always late to his classes,
finishes his assignments last minute,
studies for his exams last minute. And
that was me. That was me in grad school.
That was me 6 years ago. When it comes
to neuroticism, somebody high on
neuroticism is thinking of the in in the
mindset of what could go wrong, what's
the worst that will happen. And somebody
low on neuroticism is thinking well what
could go right? What's the best case
scenario? Now we jump to openness.
Openness is the trait of creativity.
Think musicians, think artists,
entrepreneurs, innovators, inventors,
people who are interested in ideas,
abstract thoughts in the aesthetic
sense. These are folk who want to
explore new things. They're interested
in fiction. They're interested in
stories and movies. And on the other
side, we have people who are interested
in doing one thing, right? And the same
way every time. Think accountants,
bankers, think nurses who have a
checklist to follow, doctors or even
surgeons who you obviously don't want a
surgeon trying to be too creative. So
jobs which have a checklist and a
correct way to do things, those kind of
jobs would rank low on openness.
Interesting things happen when you have
unique combinations of these traits. For
example, somebody like Musk who is a
genetic freak would be very high in
openness because he has an aesthetic
sense. He's obviously inventive and
creative, but he's also extremely high
on conscientiousness, which means that
he's able to put in the systems and of
course the repetitive work required to
bring his ideas into fruition. But you
don't need to have both of these extreme
traits in one person in order to
succeed. For example, Apple, one of the
most successful companies of all time,
was started by Steve Jobs and Steve
Wnjak. Steve Jobs extremely open. He was
very creative, had a clear sense of
aesthetics. However, he had completely
lacked conscientiousness to the point
that he wouldn't even shower every day.
Steve Wnak, on the other hand, very high
in conscientiousness, but maybe not as
creative as Steve Jobs. Together, they
were the powerhouse that fueled Apple in
the early days. Let's do agreeableness.
Agreeableness is the trait which
measures how compassionate you are, how
well you work in teams, and how
comfortable others feel around you. On
the extreme end of agreeableness, you
have folk who sometimes get taken
advantage of. On the other side,
extremely low agreeableness. You have
folk who come off as a dick even if they
don't intend to. Women in general are
higher on agreeableness than men are.
Now, here's a very important question.
What makes it that there are five
traits? And who decided what the traits
would be? The answer is nobody. No
scientist decided that there would be
five traits. It came out of the data.
And I'm going to explain how that
happened. Imagine I asked you
descriptive questions. How often are you
happy? Rate 1 to five. How often do you
smile? Rate one to five. How often do
you wake up every day feeling energized
and eager to start the day? Rate one to
five. Now, here's what would happen. If
you answer high for question one, very
likely that you answer high for
questions two and three. Same way if you
answer low for question one, you
probably answer low for questions two
and three, which means that these
different questions are linked in some
way. Now, you might ask a question.
Well, are these really three different
questions or is this one question asked
three different ways? And the answer is
if the answers to these questions
reliably predict each other, it means
that these answers cluster and they
reliably reflect something reflect an
underlying reality. And they ask
hundreds of descriptive questions to
hundreds of people over many many
behavior sets. And what they found was
these answers do cluster and they
cluster in five separate clusters which
are in fact the five traits of the big
five matrix. This is why I trust the big
five matrix. It was deduced and not
theorized. This is unlike other
personality matrices like the
MyersBriggs test which is just made up
by Meyers and Briggs. They sought the
data to validate their assumptions. And
here's the curious part. Corporations
love the MyersBriggs test and they hate
the big five. And that's because the
MyersBriggs test is constructed in such
a way that it makes everybody who takes
the test feel like a winner. This just
does not reflect reality. We know in
that in real life they are winners and
losers. And the big five personality
test actually predicts this. That brings
us to the very curious question. Are
some personalities better than others?
And we can only answer this with
something to judge personalities on and
that's outcomes. Do you believe that
some outcomes are better than others?
Would you say that earning a high
income, having a stable marriage, living
a long life, living a healthy life,
would you consider these to be good
outcomes? If you do, then you're saying
that you believe in good personalities
because some personalities
mathematically are proven to have a
higher likelihood of hitting those good
outcomes. But not all traits work the
same. For example, you can have a
successful career on whichever end of
the extroversion spectrum you end up on.
For example, a highly extroverted person
would absolutely crush it on a sales
team. A salesman is expected to be
social. He's expected to meet hundreds
of people. He's expected to play well in
a team. So, he needs to be high in
extroversion. If he wasn't, then he
would be drained and exhausted at the
end of the day. On the other hand, a
writer would actually be better if he
was low in extraversion. Why? Because a
writer needs to sit down alone in a room
and work on one task for hours on end
without companionship, without social
reinforcement. So if you wanted to
succeed as a writer, you'd almost want
to be low in extraversion. And same way
with openness, there's no good or bad
when it comes to openness. On the high
openness side, you see high-risk,
highreward strategies. What I mean by
that is while musicians, artists,
entrepreneurs, and innovators, how many
of these are actually successful? Not a
lot. Not a lot of entrepreneurs make it.
Not a lot of musicians make it. Very few
artists make their first dollar. So, but
the ones who do make all the money. So,
this is where you see winner takes all
type of games. On the other side, you
have things like accountants. You don't
need to be a famous accountant in order
to make money. Every accountant has a
stable career. So, the further you go on
the openness spectrum, the less stable
your career becomes, but potentially the
greater the rewards become. interesting
interplay which I hinted at before is if
you have high conscientiousness and high
openness, you can make some interesting
things happen. So, quick recap. Some
traits like extraversion and openness do
not confer a direct advantage one way or
other. They're just better for different
types of professions. Same with
agreeableness. It's hard to say that
high or low agreeableness is good or
bad. Most people would benefit by being
somewhere in the center. But with two
traits, conscientiousness and
neuroticism, there is actually a
direction that we want to go towards.
Almost everybody benefits by being high
on conscientiousness. This is the trait
that's tied with income. On the other
side, everybody benefits from being
lower on neuroticism because being no on
neuroticism predicts lifetime happiness.
So, quick overview. Agreeableness,
extraversion and openness, it depends on
your goals. There's no good or bad trait
when it comes to this. When it comes to
conscientiousness and neuroticism,
however, there are clear directions that
we want to go in, which is why this
video is going to be focused on these
two traits. But before we talk about
that, we have to discuss, well, where do
these traits even come from? What
determines how you fall on these traits?
Are you just born this way? In fact,
scientists did twin studies which
indicate that 50% of your personality is
genetically determined. But here's the
thing, this data draws from average
people who are not actively trying to
seek an advantage in life, are not
actively trying to change to to pursue
goals. So what does this mean? It means
people like you or I who are actively
seeking to succeed in life, actively
seeking to change oursel to confer
oursel an advantage. We might be able to
control way more than 50%. We might be
able to control 75% of our personality.
The scientific literature indicates that
people have these set points which are
set in stone and very hard to change.
However, wisdom is being able to stretch
past these natural inclinations and
knowing when to stretch. So, going back,
where does this personality come from? I
already said some of it is genetic but a
huge proportion of it comes from the
stories we tell ourselves. And where do
these stories come from? These stories
come from our experiences. These
experiences come from the outcomes that
are generated by our actions. So our
actions feed outcomes, feed the
experiences, feed the stories we tell
ourselves and feeds our personality. But
the personality also determines what
kind of actions we take in the first
place. Which means there's this feedback
loop. So some people are stuck in a
downward spiral where their actions
inspire a worse personality which forces
worse actions and there are those who
are on an upward spiral whose actions
improve their personality and the
personality improves their actions and
this is why life has winners and losers
and the big five personality matrix
predicts this. My journey started when I
saw that my conscientiousness score was
an eight single digit. What does this
mean exactly? Conscientiousness score is
a metric that measures how good you are
at making promises to yourself and
actually keeping them. What this number
meant was that 92% of people were better
than me at keeping their word to
themsel. And here's what the literature
says. Ccore, conscientiousness score is
a better predictor of lifetime earnings,
which is essentially the money you make,
IQ, creativity, or testosterone. In
other words, CC score is more important
for earnings than testosterone, IQ, like
literally the intelligence and creative
ability. This score indicates that I was
not going to make it in modern society.
Now, here's an interesting question. Why
would it be that CC score predicts
income even more than IQ? Well, here's
the answer. High IQ means that you can
probably make good plans, but says
nothing about how well you can follow
the plan. You need Ccore to actually
follow this plan. You can think of this
in terms of health. Having a diet plan,
even if it's not perfect, but actually
sticking to it is going to provide you
better results than having no plan or
having a plan and not sticking with it.
Have you heard the saying that an insult
only stings if it's true? Well, so it
was for me. The reason why the score
mattered to me so much was not because
the score was low, but more so how
accurately it reflected my life. I would
always promise myself that I would get
assignments done on time, that I would
be on time for classes, I would be ahead
of time in preparations for exams, but
it would just never happen. I'd always
meet deadlines last minute because I'd
be scrolling on my phone. I would be
looking at YouTube. I'd be distracted
instead of actually putting the work in
before time. I would always promise
myself that I would go to the gym, that
I would eat right, and I would try to
look better, become stronger. This just
never happened. I had the plan. I had
the perfect gym plan. It never
materialized. And even when it comes to
diet, I had the plan, but it never
materialized because I would just go to
Chick-fil-A or Panda Express. And when
it comes to addictions, I would promise
myself I will no longer watch porn. I
will stop after this one last time. I
would stop wasting time on video games
after this one last session. It just
never happened. I would continue to do
these behaviors. And every time you make
a promise to yourself and you break this
promise, you are informing your brain
that you are the kind of person who
breaks promises to themsel which is
literally what is meant by low CC score.
So it was not the score that scared me
in so far as it was the fact that I put
a number on my bad behavior. It is
particularly important because I saw the
comparison. I saw that I was in the
bottom 8% of of society when it came to
keeping my word. This is a terrible
place to be. This does not reflect where
I wanted to be. This personality score
alone would make it impossible for me to
reach the goals that I wanted to. To be
clear, the personality score is
downstream of my actions. So, I knew
that if I changed my actions, I could
change the personality score. This would
essentially increase my likelihood of
being successful in the way that I
wanted. I was desperate to change
everything. But I couldn't seem to do
it. I was stuck in this feedback loop
which seems to be self-reinforcing. One
of the things which Peterson said stuck
out to me which was they studied the US
army and they found that people in the
US army were
overwhelmingly high in
conscientiousness. So I thought well
either I would want to be within that
group to surround myself by
conscientious people and learn from them
or it's the training which makes them
high C which means that I would go
through the training. So one of the five
reasons I joined the US army was to
improve what my personality was. So I
had to join the army and I have those
systems imposed on me in order to
change. So more than half a year I made
my bed every day. I meditated every day.
I journaled every day. I exercised every
day. And I was completely divorced from
the internet. No internet, no
stimulation whatsoever. The most
stimulating thing that I could do was
journaling. And by doing these actions,
unsurprisingly, there was changes in my
brain. Now it's true that I had no
choice and the systems were imposed on
me rather than me using my willpower to
succeed. But it didn't matter. The
systems allowed me to change my actions
and this resulted in changing of my
personality scores. In other words, you
change the inputs, you change the
outputs. But to be clear, I'm not saying
that you need to join the army or you
should join the army just to change your
personality. There are better ways to do
this. And I also mentioned that this is
one of the five reasons that I joined.
What I am saying however is you need to
take a big irreversible decision in
order to actually change your life. Now
this could be an environment change. It
could be a location change for sure, but
it can also be the social environment.
who you surround yourself with. It's
easy to understand this by looking at
animals. Take the same animal which was
a wishes hunter, a powerful beast of the
forest, and you put him in a zoo and he
can barely even breed. So the question
is, in what ways are you in a zoo
socially, informationally, and
locationally and try to change those,
you can just change one of these and see
a huge benefit. So here's where I
started. So what does it say about me?
It says I'm low in agreeableness, which
was true. I wasn't the best at working
in teams, but I was independently
minded. Relatively high in extraversion,
which means I could do well in groups,
but not to a huge extent. Very low in
conscientiousness, which was of course
the problem. I couldn't hold a plan. I
couldn't keep my own word. High in
openness, which means I was very
interested in the aesthetic sense and
creativity. In fact, I'll prove it to
you. Check out my jacket. There's only
probably one of these on the entire
planet. I got this custom made in Italy
when I went there last year. And when it
comes to neuroticism, I was at a 42,
which is not the worst because it's
below 50, but it still means that I was
in a lot of mental pain. And here's what
I did to change this. You already know
that I joined the army in part to change
my personality scores. I also worked in
a tech startup which sold millions of
units of food preservation devices
worldwide. Over the past 2 years, I've
made 89 videos. This is actually the
90th video. Each of these requires idea
generation, organizing these ideas in an
orderly way. It requires the actual
filming. It requires editing. It
requires publishing. It's a complex
series of steps which need to be
completed 90 times. But the core of all
this was I had to make promises to
myself and actually keep them not for
days or weeks but for months and years
and you can do the same and these are
the results. So I retake the test just
last year about 6 years since the
initial test and this is what the
results are. Agreeableness is exact same
number literally three both times 6
years apart. So what does this mean? It
means I haven't really changed that much
in so far as it comes to interacting
with others. Extraversion 60 to 63.
Again, practically the same number. I'm
no better at handling crowds and no
worse. We leave conscientiousness for
suspense. Look at openness. It went from
89 to 98. A bump for sure, which means
that maybe I'm more creative and more
open to new ideas, more open to the
aesthetic sense. When it comes to
neuroticism, I went from 42 to 13. So, a
big dip in the average level of stress
that I feel on a day-by-day basis. But
conscientiousness, which is where the
biggest jump happened, I went from 8 to
90, which is a huge jump. In fact, you
could even argue that I haven't changed
that much as a person. Most of the stats
remain more or less the same. I just
became better at holding promises to
myself and maybe feeling a little bit
less anxious and neurotic on a
day-by-day basis. If you're past your
early 20s, the window of opportunity to
change your personality is shrinking
because your brain becomes less plastic
as you age. So now is the time that you
need to take this personality test. If
you don't know where you are, you cannot
chart the path to where you want to go.
So if you want to know where you are,
what's holding you back, and what you
need to do to succeed, you need to take
the big five personality test. There's a
form in the description below. If you
fill this and you're qualified, I will
pay for you to get this test done. You
probably see your peers at work. Some of
them, most of them even are probably
disorganized, not really on it, not very
conscientiousness, missing deadlines,
producing sloppy work. But at the same
time, you probably also see guys who are
locked in, who are producing highquality
work ahead of schedule. But overall, big
picture looking at society, it seems
that CC scores are going down. If you
speak to anybody in education, whether
it's in college level education or at
the high school level, they will all
unanimously tell you that something has
changed, especially post the pandemic.
So what does this mean? There's a golden
opportunity. Society will always have a
place for high C people. Either you are
a valued part of a team in a bigger
company or you're running your own
business. Doesn't matter. Ccore is
always an asset. So what does this mean
for you? It means you need to change
your actions. not on a short-term basis,
not for a week, but for months and
years, so that you can move your
personality scores and become the kind
of person who has the kind of success
that you want. This decade is the decade
of divergence. You choose whether to
sink or swim. Ccore acts as your life
raft and I'll give you more tactical
steps after I discuss Nore. If Ccore
will make you, Nore will break you. So
what is neuroticism exactly? It's a
level of stress you face based on the
level of threat in the environment. So,
I'll give you an example. Let's say
you're working for a company and there's
a rumor floating around of a mass
layoff. Should you be worried? Well,
maybe you should. But to what extent
should you be worried? That's what's
determined by neuroticism. Here's an
interesting thing. You don't actually
get to choose, at least on a short-term
basis, how worried you would be. Let's
think about the two sides of the
spectrum. On the high neuroticism side,
you might have one employee who's
absolutely freaking out, assumes that
they are going to be laid off, already
making a catastrophe out of this. On the
other side, you have the low-end guy who
sees this rumor, but doesn't care too
much. Either he gets laid off or he
doesn't. If he gets laid off, he
probably finds something else to do.
He's not going to die. So, that's why we
would rather be on the low side of this
than the high side. Like I said before,
none of these scores can be changed in
the short term. All of this only
responds to long-term repeated actions.
So, first let's clear the board. Now,
let's look at a case study of Alex
Eagle. Alexander Eagleman is a code name
for a member of my community who I've
been working with for past 3 months.
This is where he started. He started
with low agreeableness, relatively high
extraversion, low conscientiousness, but
still better than where I started. Very
high in openness, which makes sense
because he's a creative person. He's
literally a documentarian, makes
documentaries, very high in neuroticism,
which means he's in a lot of mental
pain. So, what did he do different in
the past 3 months to change these
scores? He was almost 100% consistent
with meditation every single day,
journaling every single day, and going
to the gym three to four times a week.
But what does this mean in real life? It
meant that he was more effective at his
job. He needed to produce a first cut of
his documentary for a wealthy client. He
estimated that he would take at least a
month to complete this project, but he
actually got it done in 22 days because
he actually had the systems and the
follow through to get done. After
being consistent and showing his brain
that he was a man of his word, this is
what we saw. The first thing is a small
jump in agreeableness, which means that
he's probably better at working in
teams. Extraversion also a little bit of
a jump, which means that well, he's more
comfortable in groups of people. His
openness score was already high and it's
only higher but this makes sense because
he was a creative person who was acting
on creative impulses to create creative
projects. Then we come to neuroticism
huge decline from 98 to 24 which means
that he's just in a better mental space
overall and of course the cherry on top
is a massive increase in
conscientiousness which means that well
he is a man of his word. But first I
need to give you a disclaimer. We are
using the big five matrix in a way that
it is not designed to be. The big five
matrix is not a coaching tool, is a
diagnostic tool. So using it in this way
might lead to exaggerations. We don't
really know for a fact if the change in
conscientiousness is as big as the
numbers indicate. My before and after
has a sixear span in between. So it
makes sense that a big change could
happen. Alice Eagle's before and after
have only three months span between
them. Which means that again this could
be an exaggeration but what does this
mean? It means that at least he went in
the right direction. That is not
arguable. So if his actions changed and
his self-perceptions change that means
his personality has changed. The key
thing to remember is you got to make
promises to yourself and actually keep
them do the right actions for long
enough your personality changes and that
feeds future actions and that is the
only way you have towards the success
that you want. But if you feel stuck and
you're not able to take these small
actions in order to change your
personality, it means that you probably
need to take a big action. If the small
actions aren't doing it, you need to
take a big action. And I cannot tell you
what this action is. It's just a key
core decision that you must make and
step across Rubicon in order to change
your life. You can do that for yourself
or you can get my help to do so. So if
you think you have low C or if you think
you have high N, you need to start
working on that yesterday. Fill out the
form in the description below.