Rub this on your shaft and thank me
later. This is magnesium lotion and when
applied to the shaft, it basically
guarantees morning wood. I learned this
from a bodybuilder friend who said that
applying magnesium lotion to aching
muscles alleviates muscle soreness. So I
had this brilliant idea in the name of
science of course. What happens if you
apply this down there? When I realized
that the effects were noticeable, I
suggested this to five of my coaching
clients and they too had similar
results. And so I bring this information
to you. Now to be clear, there's no
scientific evidence for this. There are
no papers published about this. This is
literally cutting edge. Why would
topically applied magnesium increase
erectile strength? I think this is the
reason. This is the cross-section of the
penile length. These two areas are
called the corposa cavernosa. These are
sponge-like tissues that when engorged
with blood cause the erection in the
first place. So if the blood vessels in
these tissues are blocked by
calcification, you will have less blood
flow into the shaft and therefore weaker
erections. We don't want this. So we
need to reverse calcification. This is
where the magnesium comes in. And we
know this for a fact that magnesium ions
can undo calcification. So the
hypothesis is that applying magnesium
topically seeps through in into the
shaft and causes a reduction in the
calcification of these blood vessels in
so doing improving the erectile
strength. Now the obvious question is we
don't want calcification. We want to
reduce the chances of calcification not
just in the blood vessels of the shaft
but just blood vessels overall. So what
causes calcification? Well, it's caused
by LDL which is called the bad
cholesterol. But then here again it's
not the LDL which is the culprit. It's
more so that damaged LDL is the culprit.
So what damages LDL? Well, when
polyunsaturated fatty acids get
incorporated into the structure of LDL,
it causes them to be more prone to
oxidative damage. Now, where the hell do
polyunsaturated fatty acids come from?
They come from commonly used cooking
oils, which the internet is now calling
seed oils, things like soybean oil,
groundut oil, any kind of fry oil
really. all of the things which are used
in basically all fast food restaurants
and even upscale restaurants unless you
specifically demand or ask that their
your food be prepared in butter or
tallow. Now, speaking of erections, if
you're below the age of 40 and you
aren't waking up with morning wood
basically every day, this might be a
sign of bad hormonal health. The first
step you need to take is get blood work
done. This will serve as a road map and
give you the next steps on what to do.
There's three key problems with getting
blood work. The first is you don't know
what biomarkers to get. The second is
you think it's expensive or you think
you need to go through insurance. The
third is well even if you get your
results back you don't know what the
results actually mean so you don't take
next steps. We can solve all these
problems for free. There's a form in the
description below that you'll fill out
and we myself or my team who are
certified in functional blood chemistry
analysis can help you out. When it comes
to magnesium this is not just something
that you can apply to your shaft. It is
also something that you can consume
orally. Magnesium comes in many
different forms. So first I have this
tablet form. I have this electrolyte
liquid form. I also have magnesium
lactate in a powdered form. So why focus
on magnesium? It's because practically
everybody is deficient. 15% are
chronically deficient and then 50% more
than 50% of Americans are below the
recommended dosage of magnesium. The
recommended doses of magnesium isn't
even that high. It's my personal belief
that a lot of heart disease in the US
can be reversed by supplementing with
magnesium. You may have heard of
different forms of magnesium. There's
glycinate, thrienate, citrate and so on.
I'll make all this very simple in the
protocol which I'm going to give you. So
in the morning just choose between
magnesium citrate or malate and take 400
mg. And at night again 400 millig of
glycinate or 3enate plus the magnesium
chloride lotion. You'll notice that the
average daily allowance is actually just
400 millig. So I take almost more than
twice of this. Now we have to talk about
how and where to apply the magnesium
lotion. Well, this video is about of
course the benefits to applying it to
the shaft, but it's not just the shaft.
You can apply this anywhere. It's just a
lotion. Specifically for sleep, I
recommend applying it to the base of
your feet. So, the feet are one of the
regions of our body through which we
regulate temperature while sleeping.
This is why a lot of people will stick
out one foot out of the blankets in
order to cool themselves down. Applying
magnesium lotion to the feet allows the
body to eject more heat because as the
moisture in the lotion evaporate, it
takes some of the heat with it. This
protocol is especially important if
you're physically active, if you're
going to the gym, but also important if
you are a knowledge worker, if you're
spending deep work hours getting work
done, and certainly you need to treat
yourself as an athlete of the mind. And
I'll leave you with a reminder that
being healthy in a sick society gives
you an unfair advantage. The first step
in seizing this advantage is to get your
blood work done. Use the link in the
description below. We can help you with
that.