[Music]
foreign
can do to you it won't go through you on
contact you just explode the M2 heavy
machine gun can send rounds at a rate of
600 rounds per minute at a maximum
effective range of 2000 meters and I
have the duty and privilege of using
this weapon and I also teach yoga
a harmless man is not a good man a good
man is he who is capable of Untold
violence but has the ability to keep
that in check a quote from Dr Peterson
of course Dr Peterson explains this by
quoting the biblical verse the meek
shall inherit the earth he describes
that the word meek in Modern English
means weak it means timid but it
describes how in Old English the word
meek meant something like a man who knew
how to use a sword but chose to keep its
sheathed unless he needed it it is my
belief that to have the ability to go to
war but choose to do so only when needed
is a mark of virtue but more importantly
I need to make lunch all these
vegetables are already washed and clean
and ready to go I'm making chicken broth
using a crock pot now a lot of you
probably think you know crock pot is
like what your grandmom uses no no if
you are going to the gym and you want to
do meal prep crock pot is the way to go
man I just put all these healthy
ingredients in here and in about four to
eight hours I'll describe how it's ready
and it smells amazing tastes amazing is
extremely good for your body
testosterone boosting ingredients I'll
teach you how to make this and also
speak about philosophy a little bit so
obviously you should train your ability
to perform violence go ahead do your
martial arts class you know go to
kickboxing go to BJJ do what you want to
do but you should also be honing the
other side of virtue which is having the
ability to have presence when you are in
communication with people having the
ability to empathize with people
understand others not only for your own
well-being but also in a business sense
to have the ability to empathize with
people and understand them is a first
step in creating a product that people
actually want to buy and coming back to
the carrots so carrots contain
beta-carotenes these are pigments this
is literally what makes a carrot orange
so these literally will become a part of
your blood and that's what will make
your skin look lustrous and healthy so
if you are on the looks maxing journey
and you want to look better carrots are
the way to go it'll make your skin look
healthy it'll give some pigmentation
some luster and then we have potatoes so
everybody should sell potatoes you know
it's like potatoes are bad for you it's
like no they're not potatoes contain a
lot of vitamin C vitamin A and the Skins
contain antioxidants so if you have the
ability don't get the yellow ones like
don't get the brown ones get the colored
potatoes like the red ones which I'm
having right here these are a little bit
better regardless potatoes aren't the
enemy
empathy presence and understanding are
also skills that you need to maintain
along with you know your Martial Arts
and Firearm skills Etc and these are
skills that you can generally get better
at and you should start probably with
meditation I know everybody talks about
meditation but no one gives you actually
what to do sit on your ass for 30
minutes but nothing happens I've been
there guys so before that garlic so
garlic I'm not even going to go into the
details of garlic garlic contains a lot
a lot of compounds complex compounds
which have been shown to have blood
purifying effects so what I do is just
get the skin off these cloves garlic
cloves I will take my blade and just
or you know just break them and toss
them in there I'm not going to spend the
time to cut them up doesn't matter
so I'm going to tell you exactly how
meditation works and while I'm doing so
I'm going to cut myself a tournament so
turnips are cruciferous vegetables the
same as cauliflower or broccoli and
these contain something called indols
i-n-d-o-l-e-s if you wanted to look it
up and indoors do not increase your
testosterone but they have an effect of
mitigating against phytoestrogens in
your bloodstream so even if they don't
increase your testosterone they actually
help increase the effect your current
testosterone level has on your body now
coming back to meditation let me Define
it for you to understand anything we
need to Define it first meditation is
the focus on an external stimulus at the
cost of the voice in your head let me
explain by the way mushrooms amazing
source of zinc magnesium selenium all
the things which your body needs to
synthesize testosterone I should remark
that when I say X increases testosterone
that doesn't mean that women shouldn't
eat them the fact of the matter is the
endocrine system in men is just better
studied and better understood than that
in women so I'm more comfortable just
saying you know this increases
testosterone but these same
micronutrient are obviously extremely
helpful for female hormonal production
as well so if you happen to be a lady
listening to this please eat your
mushrooms so meditation let me break
down my definition for you the first
part I said is to focus on an external
stimulus an external stimulus could be
anything oftentimes in traditional
meditation the external stimulus is the
sensation of your breath so you're
breathing but doesn't have to be it
could be literally anything for example
prayer beads so this is a what's called
rudraksha and you can get 10 prayer bees
on Amazon if you wanted to so all you do
all I do is focus on the sensation of my
thumb on each bead as I move it along
and as you know the fingertips are the
most sensitive parts of your body so
that sensation is very finely felt and
if you focus on that that could be your
meditation you don't necessarily have to
focus on the breath and for me I find
the beads meditation just easier to do
than breath meditation so this is
something you can try so focus on the
external stimulus that's the first part
you're focusing on the external stimulus
at the expense of the voice in your head
so your voice the narration which
happens in your head is ongoing the
voice in your head which is speaking
about the things that you're going
around you about thoughts for the future
regrets of the past the voice in your
head tells you the things that you want
to hear but it also tells you the things
that you don't want to when you focus on
external stimulus you force out the
mind's voice obviously this is not
something you want permanently you do
want your voice of the mind to help you
think however without meditation we
become over reliant on that voice and we
don't even know what it feels like to
have silence in our lives for this
reason meditation is indispensable
and say you don't have the time to do
meditation that's fine you can do a deep
breathing exercise instead which might
be easier for some people so literally
just breathe into your belly
and release it literally one breath has
a calming effect and I feel that
calmness even right now and this is not
some kind of gimmick to take a voluntary
deep breath has been shown to move your
body from a flight and flight response
to a rest and relaxed response so you
can use your breath the conscious
understanding the conscious perception
of your breath to mitigate the mode in
which your body is functioning all right
so what spices do you need to season
this thing I have a whole bunch of
spices here which me which I'm gonna add
but you don't need all of these I'll
tell you exactly what's optional first
I'm adding turmeric turmeric and Indian
spice known for many many different
medicinal properties it has like a mild
mellow taste next I have oregano which
is a white person spice so just little
bit does it then we have ginger and
garlic powder so ideally I would have
ginger garlic paste which you literally
just take Ginger and take garlic and
mash it up in your blender or your mixer
but I don't happen to have it right now
so I'm just going to use powdered
versions so what's optional here and
what's not the turmeric is optional the
oregano is optional ginger garlic paste
or gin ginger garlic powder I would say
you would definitely want to have it but
even that's kind of optional then we
have time so I also have some fresh
thyme which is also optional next we
have bay leaves which are also optional
but I'm going to add these after I've
already mixed it up because otherwise
this will break and there'll be
fragments of leaf in your food which you
don't want also optional then I have
some cloves I guess like three of them
optional what's not optional is salt and
all the mainstream media is going to
tell you salt is bad sodium is going to
give you heart disease no it's not salt
is essential part of a healthy lifestyle
and pepper pepper is also not optional
and you actually need more salt than
they tell you in general the mainstream
advice when it comes to nutrition is
kind of [ __ ] so you have to do your own
research and have your own understanding
about nutrition all right you're almost
done all we need is the chicken which
I've already washed so I noticed
something interesting meditation helps
me in kickboxing so when I am sparring
with a partner my best performance has
always been if I meditated before coming
to kickboxing I find that I'm present in
the moment with my sparring partner I'm
just able to judge his moves better I'm
not even thinking any thoughts in my
head I just move depending on the
situation I'm able to get my guard up
faster I'm able to throw punches faster
it's just so much more effortless when
you have an awareness and presence
instead of your thinking thoughts if
you're thinking I'm going to throw a
punch you already have that delay if you
think I'm going to have to block it you
have the delay but if you're meditating
and you're present in the movement while
you're fighting it's a different game
and then I spoke about yoga so what is
yoga and what is meditation in my
personal opinion yoga is the same as
meditation except that it's Dynamic so
yoga is dynamic meditation so instead of
focusing on the breath and sitting down
in a stationary position like you do in
meditation in yoga you're moving you're
using your body in real space while
having the same level of awareness as
you do in meditation so yoga in some
ways is even Superior to sitting down
type meditation which is why I have the
pleasure of being able to teach it at my
University remember the body is the the
interface between the mind and the
physical world your quality of life
literally depends on the quality of your
body don't neglect health no matter what
don't neglect hormonal health no matter
what make sure your mental health is tip
top shape and then you have a much
higher chance of business success so I'm
going to go ahead and add my chicken to
the crock pot and as I do so I want to
thank you for the immense growth of this
channel it's been crazy I had 25
subscribers at the starting of this week
and now I have more than five thousand
it's insane what you have done and the
credit of course goes to you and my
editor Jan for making this thing
possible I am loving the notion of being
able to create these stories and teach
you about food and nutrition and cooking
and being potentially paid to do so
that's just an amazing experience and
you've made this possible for me you
have my greatest gratitude and my
greatest thanks so what do we do from
here I've added my chicken wash my hands
because I need to add the olive oil
always get the extra virgin olive oil
try to pay a little bit more and get the
good stuff because most olive oil in the
markets is a blend of potentially rancid
olive oil which is not really good for
you also don't use seed oil no sunflower
oil no canola oil grapeseed oil none of
these at all in your diet extra virgin
olive oil is definitely a option you can
also use butter which I'm going to add a
little bit of butter to my cooking and
also if you noticed I did not remove the
skins from these chicken thighs and
there's a reason for this the skin of
these chicken thighs actually contains
the fats that we want it's the fats in
these meats that gives us the ability
our body the ability to create the
testosterone so I want to have the skins
on my meat now I'll try to write up a
how-to in a recipe and put in the
description for you guys to see but what
I do now is I need to kind of blend all
this up all the spices and the oil and
the food looks but you know I'm going to
eat it really going to
add myself
some vegetables from this
other video which I was making some
broccoli
and some cauliflower
so I sauteed these in butter and this
whole video I made doing this
so you can watch that and learn how I
made this so this is extremely extremely
good for you especially from a
testosterone building standpoint not
because broccoli and cauliflower can
help you make testosterone but because
they have indoors which are compounds
which reduce the effect of
estrogen in your bloodstream so this
whole meal right here with the protein
the fats the cats the potatoes mushrooms
broccoli and cauliflower
is a complete meal perfectly designed
for hormonal health and you know this is
going to be tasting amazing every
ingredient has been chosen by me for a
purpose
and
you know
I hope you get a chance to try something
like this thank you very much
foreign