all right boys quick video for you
showing you how to use strategy and
planning tools which I have behind me as
you know time is not the principal
resource from which all things stem
rather it is energy and strategy
everybody has time it depends what you
do with that time energy comes from
holistic wellness and health which I've
described in many other videos before
but today we'll take a look at strategy
I'm going to show you these two tools so
what we have with us today is first we
have this corkboard which is my progress
tracker everything gets tracked on here
each of these sticky notes represents a
video and as they progress the different
stages of creating a video for example
ideation then we have the actual
recording then editing thumbnails and
then uploading right so there's multiple
stages for each of these so this allows
me to have autistic level control and
tracking of the progress of each of the
videos which I'm working on for example
let's take this esoteric lucid dreaming
guide so this is a video which I want to
make I want to make a video on lucid
dreaming so it's just an idea at this
point but once I actually script it out
I will move it to this column once I
actually record it I'll move it here
once I submit it for editing to my
editor I'm going to move it here and
once it's actually done I'll move it to
the edge and that's the conclusion of
its uh Journey basically so it allows me
to have extremely intense tracking for
the multiple projects which I'm working
on you can see how it works for videos
but also works great for like if you
have multiple homeworks or assignments
or projects of any kind if you're a
coder and you are doing different coding
projects it works for that it works for
literally anything just use your
imagination it works best when all the
different tasks are the same like all of
these represent a video so the stages
are the same for all of them all videos
need to go through ideation scripting
recording and so on so it makes sense if
I had different types of projects then I
would have a separate board for each
type of project now we go on to this
side this is my cloud board or so I like
to call it it's just a standard
whiteboard what I'm doing here is I'm
clustering tasks so I'm bringing order
to chaos by clustering the task by
classification so for example I have
here my nutrition cookbook so nutrition
cookbook is something which I'm planning
to create I'm going to be including it
to my members in my private Community
the country club I'm also going to be
including it for whoever purchases the
esoteric men's nutrition course at the
time of recording that course is not
even out yet but it might be by the time
you're watching it so that course is
going to come with this cookbook but the
thing is the cookbook is not done yet so
I need to do a couple tasks to make it
happen I need to compile my recipes I
need to compile my ingredient lists I'm
going to have to create my micro and
macronutrient profiles I'm going to have
to create the meal plans so a bunch of
different tasks which cluster under the
title of nutrition cookbook and let's
take another example onboarding overhaul
so like I said I have that private
Community Country Club and it has an
onboarding sequence so as soon as
somebody joins there's a set of sequence
which they need to progress through to
really get the best out of the
experience and right now it's there like
there is an onboarding in place but it's
not perfect I want to improve it I want
to perfect it and that requires a
certain level of dedication a certain
number of tasks to be completed and I've
organized those into this Cloud so the
reason I do it in clouds is just for the
Aesthetics of it so it's almost like a
sky some days I'm going to have a lot of
different tasks a lot of clouds and each
cloud is heavy with tasks and it's like
an overcast sky but I know with
determination and hard work I'm going to
be able to clear clouds one by one so as
soon as I get done with the onboarding
overhaul I'll just erase it off the
board and then there'll be one less
cloud on my sky so what I'm trying to
work for is of course a clear sky
there's no clouds I have no tasks going
on I'm just chilling I know it might be
corny I don't really care because this
is what works for me man I like to have
a kind of visual or artistic take to the
things which I do it's just the way I
work it's just why my psychology works
so do what works for you and then here
is a timeline so I have a hard deadline
for the 22nd I need to get all this
stuff done by the 22nd so I'm marking
down the days and I'm also logging the
stuff which gets done per day so I have
a clear timeline on what needs to get
done when so then we have the order of
business I have priorities non
priorities and stasis so priorities are
of course the task which you need to get
done right now then non priorities are
things which kind of can wait and then
stasis is stuff which I'm not going to
even think about for example I want to
grow on Instagram I want to go on
Twitter but I don't have the bandwidth
to do that stuff right now so I'm just
going to put on stasis I'll get to it
when I get to it then we have the
autistic level day-to-day plan so Monday
Tuesday Wednesday all the way Thursday I
literally have a bullet point for every
task that I need to do and as I get
these things done I'll just take them
off as I go along so it allows me to
have a lot of control it tells me
exactly what needs to get done per day
and here I just have a bunch of notes
it's just my ideas list so I have more
than 84 I have 84 video ideas right now
on hand which is probably all the videos
I need for the next year so there you
have it boys I'm going to take an idea
from this convert it into a a sticky
note put it on this board and then I'll
go and push it through the entire
sequence of video creation and that's
essentially how I run my YouTube channel
and I want you to use your own
imagination and adapt these techniques
for whatever work it is that you do