I wasted the last four years of my life
I became an academic machine I could
have improved my behavior my body and
relationships I could have tried to
build a business or start a YouTube
channel instead I based my self-worth on
my grades and this drew me nearly
suicidal as I found myself worthless
compared to better students these words
aren't mine but they might as well have
been Andreas a channel subscriber sent
me this message on Instagram when I
asked you what is causing you the most
pain right now you told me that it was a
lack of Direction and andreas' message
it just puts a face on the pain of
millions of young folk when I ask you if
you're feeling like you're waiting for
life to start 70% said yes I felt that
same pain and regret in my 20s after I
burned out getting through
bioengineering in college but get this
Andreas is not in college he's still in
high school he's a teenager now I'm not
about to trivialize his worries because
he's young in fact his assessment of the
situation is precocious and I'm proud to
have an audience that is composed of men
of his potential it is only man of
potential that can feel regret for
wasted time if Andreas had no potential
he wouldn't feel this pain of time
wasted so if you're confused and if
you're in pain cuz you feel your youth
slipping by then I tell you that this is
a good sign the more pain you feel the
more potential you have I'm going to
give you five steps that ensure that you
don't waste your youth like the average
person will there's a lot of conflicting
messages on what you should do when
you're in your teens or your 20s should
you focus on school should you start a
business should you maybe start a
YouTube channel should you maybe do
coaching calls should you travel should
you read books every single Choice has
drawbacks but here's the thing you might
as well get used to it because in real
life there are no Solutions there's only
tradeoffs I've been an engineering
student I've worked in food preservation
I've worked in solar energy I've been a
genetics PhD student working on parasite
biology and human genetics I've been in
the Army as a 50 cal machine gunner and
now I'm a businessman I'm proud of my
growth in some of these phases and in
some other phases I am regretful of my
stagnation I want to spare you the pain
of that regret your time and your youth
is precious I wish somebody told me the
things which I'm about to tell you the
easiest way to waste years of your life
is to live towards somebody else's
vision for you one of the worst days of
my life was when I completed and
graduated from my engineering program it
was one of the finest programs of its
kind on the planet I was guaranteed an
$80,000 starting salary that could very
easily go to 100,000 and Beyond in a few
years Mega corporations like Fredo Le
Monsanto and PepsiCo had stalls eagerly
waiting to give me a secure high-paying
prestigious job I worked brutally hard
to get where I was I had pulled all
nighters and sacrificed my health in
order to do these engineering products
and study for exams I'd gotten through
fluid dynamics thermodynamics Calculus 1
2 and 3 linear algebra differential
equations and so much more to get where
I was and even before then I had
sacrificed so much as a high schooler to
get into this top university so waking
up at 6:00 a.m. and studying as a
full-time job going to extra classes
after the actual school hours to
hopefully gain an advantage like Andreas
said I was an academic machine but still
that's what it took I had the degree in
hand I was living the dream but it was
of course somebody else's dream I felt
alone in the crowd and all my classmates
who graduated with me they had a day of
Celebration but for me it was a day of
depression that day I hated my parents I
hated them for being proud of me because
deep down I knew that I was a fraud they
had invested years worths of savings to
get me through college I went along with
it on autopilot because I was so scoped
into thinking that everything I wanted
was on the other side of that degree it
would have been better for me to have
just failed out of the program to face
reality and have those tough
conversations with my parents that I
never did the reality was I didn't
really want to be an engineer I wanted
to be a writer though at that time I
didn't even know that and get this my
parents aren't irrational or dogmatic
people they would have supported me if I
just had the gut to say the truth I felt
guilty though because I didn't want to
lose out on the competition I didn't
want to be a failure I didn't want to be
the man Left Behind the day you finish
your degree is supposed to be a day of
Triumph because you holding proof in
your hands that you're officially ahead
of everyone in the game of life but
whenever you spend time chasing a dream
that isn't yours you take a step
backwards not forwards I felt I had
wasted four years of my life just like
Andreas did the first rule I want to
teach you is reject your programming the
truth is nobody has it figured out least
of all your Boomer parents our parents
grew up in a different economy with
different job security different saving
rates and different home prices
different opportunities they mean well
but they aren't profits the best they
can do is provide a framework in the
past it was great because technology and
the economy were fairly the same
generation to generation but now
everything is changing if you're the
kind of person who watches my channel
you have an above average intelligence
and above average potential a new era of
opportunity is open to you the only way
you can fail is by playing somebody
else's game accept the fact that you
don't know much about life but neither
does anybody else else everybody is
playing this game for the first time you
must be willing to accept the Grand
Adventure that life offers and be open
to your unique instincts and intuitions
this is the only way you can find your
own unique talents and Gifts our
programming are just limiting beliefs
the first step in destroying a limiting
belief is just identification this is an
action step identify one source of your
pain in life it could be loneliness it
could be hating your looks it could be
being broke whatever isolate one
limiting belief that's keeping you stuck
and comment it below and I'll see if I
can provide any advice this is the only
way you can have the experiences and
live the stories that make you a unique
player in the great game of life rather
than being an interchangeable Pawn the
education system is a fossil from a
bygone era it was invented with the
explicit goal of creating Factory
workers the ideal factory worker does
the same thing every day at the same
time he follows a schedule that is set
for him by somebody else he eats exactly
what they expect tell him to he always
asks for permission to do something I
had to learn the hard way that there's
only one Authority whose judgment truly
matters everything else is [ __ ] stop
asking for permission be decisive roll
the dice and see what happens this
brings us to rule two rule two is to
make memories if you feel that time is
slipping by or that life is slipping by
then I want you to pay attention you
might have had this feeling that time is
speeding up that the days and weeks are
flying by faster than can even keep up
some people say that this is an illusion
because as you grow older each year is a
smaller proportion of your total life
this is not the reason our time
perception comes from how many memories
we're creating per day you can test this
out for yourself if you go for even a
short trip to a new city even years
later you can recollect the memories of
the new places you saw the things you
did the foods you ate a week of travel
actually feels like seven separate days
rather than merging into one long day so
it's clear that time perception is
uneven some special weeks feel full of
memories but some months get completely
forgotten two years ago I went to New
Orleans for 7 days and I still roughly
remember what I did on those days I
remember the hostel that I stayed in I
made friends with this cool Australian
dude and we went and tried the legendary
beignet at Cafe Dumont I went to the
World War II museum the next day I even
remember some of the cool art on display
the music scene the architecture I also
remember on the last day I met this
chick from Portland who showed me a good
time anyway in comparison a week of the
school or college routine feels like one
terribly long day even working on your
own business day after day can feel
drawn out no details stick out and it
all feels gray this is because if you do
the same thing day after day your brain
has no reason to record it this becomes
a mindset of you know different day
different [ __ ] and it's not just travel
that I'm speaking of I just use it as an
example that everybody can kind of
relate to and it's easy to understand
here's my observation every successful
man I know in real life got got there
from very different places many of them
though has had a unique formative
experience in their youth I know a
geneticist who traveled to India during
his college Years to study plant
genetics to you and me it may not sound
like an adventure but for him it was a
foundational experience that opens up
doors for him to this day and more
importantly it gave him context for why
his research mattered and this more than
his intelligence or schooling made him a
great scientist it is not about
traveling to meet women or anything like
that though I'm certainly not against
that it's the expansion of one's
Horizons to understand what is possible
if you allow yourself to be exposed to
the strange and dangerous situations
that's how you can test yourself you
don't have to go alone of course and go
with friends if you have the money go
explore the bazaars of turkey go to the
fortifications of Europe the temples of
the Far East or if you don't have money
just explore your own country go to the
Rocky Mountains Yellowstone National
Park the Grand Canyon expose yourself to
the great art great architecture and the
great achievements of mankind go to the
museums this is how you rise about the
swamp of mediocre Minds in fact there
are other options I was talking to
Pierre Durano an expert in regenerative
farming and permaculture he was actually
a guest in my private Community the
country club he talked about how there's
this organization called woof that
connects young guys and girls to
regenerative Farms that they can go for
a month or so and learn about organic
farming literally hands-on experience
you'd be provided with room board you'll
be provided with food you'll meet guys
and girls just like yourself who are
interested in being healthy and avoiding
toxins a month of that kind of
experience will set you apart from the
Rats of the Rat Race if you think about
it the girls you meet in such a
situation might be the kind that you
want to pursue here's another example
you could just choose to hike the
Appalachian Trail or the Pacific Crest
Trail the at and the PCT it takes 5
months to complete these trills you'll
have to plan Food Water Shelter medic
supplies everything you can go with
friends you can go alone if you go with
friends it'll be more of a social
challenge if you go alone it'll be a
challenge against your own mind it's
things like this that instantly Elevate
you to a one in a million status without
much money you can Elevate yourself to
the status I'd wager that stuff like
this is more valuable than years of
college college is a tool only after you
know what you want to do in life should
you commit to college in his message
Andrea said he's afraid to be a
one-dimensional man and he should be
afraid a man should be capable of
creation and destruction he should be
able to wield a weapon and create art
make a fire or bake a cake he should be
able to perform first aid able to hunt
to survive he should be able to write an
essay or plant cabbages life for a man
should be anything but one-dimensional
however a man should have a sense of
purpose and an eye towards that one
thing that he will be remembered for
even men of singular Focus like Caesar
or Napoleon were nevertheless competent
at many things
but now let's bring it back to the
present I've never met a single person
who said man I wish I spent more time
studying if you're in the ages of 15 to
25 and you haven't had any Adventure
worth speaking of you need to fix that
right now if you're older than 25 and
you don't have any interesting stories
you really need to fix that right now
I've been thinking about this a lot over
the past year the heavens have given me
this beautiful gift in the form of this
YouTube channel it allows me to connect
with hundreds if not thousands of men
who would only be watching if they like
the overall Vibe of the entire Channel
Channel why not use this power what's
stopping me from organizing in-person
events that could result in formative
experiences and memories it wouldn't be
easy but I could organize a 3-day hike
across the Alps of Europe or we could
explore the ruins of Greece we could go
to the Rocky Mountains the world is our
playground and we should use it as such
certainly you could go solo but it's
just more fun with friends speaking of
rule number three is to build bonds
nothing of note was built by single man
in isolation the greatest projects are
only possible through collaboration what
was Caesar without lavenus but here's
the thing it's not about the expected
benefits you want bonds with others
because it is critical for your own
mental health even the most robust Minds
decay in isolation but how do you find
men like yourself the isolation of our
generation is structural it's not just
psychological have you ever heard of
this concept of growth houses the idea
is simple the idea is a group of
like-minded guys team up to supercharge
their growth I know some entrepreneur
friends right now who have booked this
Villa in Turkey for a month and they're
just grinding with 100% discipline on
their projects they have accountability
check-ins every day they have a strategy
update meeting every week imagine how
productive you'd be in an environment
like that but it's not just work these
guys explore turkey they're going on
Hikes they're trying new foods meeting
women isn't this the ideal life for a
man before marriage and kids I would
have joined them but I couldn't because
I have this long stint of military
training coming up which mil training is
similar in a kind of way an entire
platoon focused on one Mission the idea
of growth houses is so appealing to me
that I want to organize these some in
the US and some in Europe This is where
my audience is mostly located if you're
interested in the idea of going on
adventures or living in a growth house
there's a form in the description that
you should fill in additionally you'd
consider joining the country club that's
where these ideas are currently being
fleshed out the growth house which I'm
imagining is a physical embodiment of
the country club imagine spending a
month getting into the best shape of
your life while making massive business
and social progress that's what I want
to bring to life and if you joined you
also get my courses which used to go for
$300 each and a new course is coming up
the mindscape course and this might be
my best work yet if you have the
combination of mental Clarity community
and physical health there's really no
competition for you anymore you're
actually winning at life now this brings
us to rule four focus on health nobody
in the history of mankind would have
regretted investing in Health the worst
thing about the youth of today is just
how anxious everybody is everybody's
cortisol is through the roof it is is
normal we have the hormonal profile of a
prey animal investing in health is the
one investment that makes sense at any
point in life and always pays dividends
if you're young you want to put
resources into hormonal Health when I
was in my teens and early 20s I really
didn't know anything about these topics
and even today most people haven't a
clue of what a good nutritional plan
looks like or what the benefits of a
detox protocol can have most people
still think that butter is going to give
them a heart attack or that sugar is
going to give them diabetes we know
better here are some non-negotiables get
Sunshine get good sleep eat real foods
get some exercise if you can do these
four you're already winning and I'm
going to be releasing updated esoteric
Health guides that focus on the 20% most
effective steps so watch out for those
and finally we get to the last and most
important rule rule number five is to
have faith faith is the illogical and
unfounded belief in something faith is
an asymmetric Advantage Embrace Divine
carelessness stop being a neurotic mess
have faith in your own destiny there's a
reason the Ancients praised youthfulness
recklessness and carefree abundance if
you have faith in your eventual Victory
you can actually live in the present
instead of being an anxious rat in a lab
experiment competition and constant
comparison to others is peasant
mentality it comes with constant
self-doubt and comes with not having
faith in one's own Destiny it leads to
short-term thinking it leads to
dishonesty and even physical ugliness in
the '90s and the early 2000s we spoke of
the midlife crisis but over the past
decade this midlife crisis has been
moving younger and younger the reason is
because young men are absorbing the
anxieties and mindsets of old men now
you think I'm going to blame social
media for yet again brainwashing the
youth the problem actually started much
earlier and it's actually a deeper
problem even before social media there
was a blurring of the lines between
Youth and and full adulthood that's why
today we have youth that are filled with
the anxieties of adults and at the same
time we have adults stuck in a pseudo
childhood part two talks about why you
feel like a child even though you're in
an adult's body I'll show you how you
can embrace the youthful life force
while having the maturity and shity that
expected of a man part one talked about
how to not waste your youth part two is
going to show you how to leverage your
youth to become a man at this time I'll
have the title for part two up so you
can click on that go to the second video
and complete your knowledge