have you ever experienced brain fog your
brain is slow your thoughts are moving
through oil you are not having the
energy you're always feeling lazy it's
almost a pain to wake up in the morning
get a shower go outside get some
sunlight and actually do the work which
you are destined to do it feels like you
go into a room and you've already
forgotten why you went there you open up
a computer program you forgot why you
did it this is not normal it happens to
me I like clockwork every single winter
and I used to think it's some kind of
seasonal affect disorder it's not for a
lot of people depression seasonal affect
disorder all the stuff is just over
diagnosis so what's actually going on is
a metabolic syndrome rather than a
mental illness it's nothing more and
nothing less than a lack of energy in
the cells that make up your brain it's
not some kind of mental illness and you
shouldn't feel overly guilty for being
lazy is that you literally have less
energy because your mitochondria are
poisoned and how does your mitochondria
get poisoned it's because of these
filthy feed oils that these big
corporations with the support of the
government have pushed upon your parents
generation and your own generation
poisoning your blood stream right now so
what's going on exactly let's break it
down right it's mitochondrial health and
your mitochondria are broken and of
course you know what mitochondria is
everybody who's taken any kind of
biology will tell you mitochondria is
the PowerHouse of
and of course it is the energy center of
the cells which produces the energy
which literally fuels your entire body
including the Mind including the brain
so I'm going to give you the red white
and blue
protocol which is going to be a
metabolic reset going to give you
infinite energy to bring your Ambitions
to life the red white and blue protocol
is red light therapy white in the form
of creatine and blue as in methylene
blue so you might be thinking what the
hell does these three things have in
common you might have heard of red light
therapy it's something that you see on
Tik Tok and stuff it's something you put
on your face to make your skin better
and you know what's creatine obviously
creatine monohydrate is the stuff which
you take to go to the gym helps you get
some last few reps in a little bit more
energy and of course creatine is like a
bodybuilding supplement right and then
methylene blue this is a more Uncommon
one you may not have heard of it but if
you're a follower of my channel you
already know what this stuff is it is a
cognition and mental energy type
supplement so you must be thinking like
what's bringing all these things
together and I'll give you some hints
the first is all of them are actually
good for skin including creatine so
topically applied creatine actually
causes skin to reverse age and same is
true of methin blue that also causes
reverse skin aging and red light therapy
is kind of that's what the purpose is so
of course it's good for skin and then
creatine is not just for energy it's not
just for the gym creatine is actually a
mental supplement as well it is a
anti-neurodegenerative supplement so
people take this to prevent neurod
degeneration literally creatine is first
and foremost a mental supplement even
before musculature and lastly we come to
methylene blue which is a well-known
antiparasitic antiviral but of course it
is first and foremost a mitochondrial
supplement so actually all three of
these are working on the mitochondria
they are not drugs they do not work on
any kind of receptors they work directly
on the mitochondrial function they have
very different Pathways and their
mechanism of action is very very
different from each other which means
that they have the synergistic effect
they don't interfere
with each other's Pathways they in fact
reinforce and reinvigorate the
mitochondria in completely different
ways that's why I've created this red
white and blue principle which brings
together different mechanisms of helping
the mitochondria so that you finally
have the energy Vitality Focus both
physical like you have raw Vitality but
also mental focus and Clarity to make
whatever Vision you have your destiny to
become manifest let's talk about these
one by one I will break down the actual
mechanisms of action I'm not going to
say that the so and so is good because I
think it's good I'm going to give you
the exact signs behind it and you can
make whatever determination you want
because this is of course not medical
advice this is my personal experience
and my own research first let's talk
about red light therapy this one is
something which a lot of people are very
skeptical about and that's fair enough
skepticism is a good thing but if you
look at the mechanism of action of red
light therapy it actually makes a lot of
sense so what's going on is mitochondria
has these five complexes if you've seen
my methylene blue video you know what
the five complexes are and you perhaps
from a previous bio class know that
complex 5 is really remarkable piece of
protein it's remarkable piece of
technology to be honest it's a turbine a
literal turbine so you know how a dam
works right a dam works by having a
large body of water kind of applying
pressure on this fan and it spins the
fan and that's connected to a generator
and you produce electricity that's what
happens in your cell in complex number
number five I'm speaking about
mitochondrial cells complex number five
literally has a turbine which spins
against the pressure of protons against
it and as it spins it has a little claw
which kind of cranks out these ATP
molecules which are energy molecules
literal packages of energy created by
this damn turbine brilliant I I couldn't
imagine like the beauty of this
little this invention this miracle like
it's it's a it's microscopic it's not
even microscopic it's literally a
molecule it's truly mindblowing truly
brilliant and it shows you the beauty of
nature the beauty of nature goes from
the smallest molecule to this massive
tree behind me but let's not get too
philosophical let's go back into the
science right so the this machine this
turbine functions better with red light
irradiation because it causes the water
around it to be less wiscus and that
means the turbine can spin faster and
that claw can attach more more ATP
molecules giving you more energy but
even that's not the only mechanism of
action for red light therapy in the
mitochondria complex number four which
is cytochrome C that's a completely
different kind of molecule it has a
different function altogether and
cytochrome C what it does it has this
claw and this claw can bind to nitrogen
well nitric oxide specifically or it can
bind to oxygen so what the red light
does is it knocks out the nitrogen from
the claw and it instead has to bind to
oxygen when it binds to oxygen you have
more energy from this thing called the
KB cycle which is what is producing ATP
in the first place so there you have it
that's two mechanisms where red light
directly influences the mitochondria to
produce more ATP and of course more ATP
means more energy overall you got to
remember there's more mitochondria in
the nerve cells than the muscle cells
you think of mitochondria we think of
energy we think of muscles but actually
20% of the calories which you eat it's
being used for the brain it's used for
mental capacity is used for thinking
it's for thoughts it's for the
subconscious to function not for the
muscles 20% for one single organ which
is roughly the shape of or the size of a
a football while the rest 80% is for the
rest of your body so a lot of energy
goes to your brain and the efficiency of
the energy utilization depends on the
health of the mitochondria which is why
we bring up the red white and blue
principle so we talk about about red
which is red light therapy and I will
say that red light therapy you cannot
just get any kind of lamp any kind of
product because a lot of the products
are I will link in the description
to the one which I have used I think
it's a really good brand and the reason
I think this is because they've taken a
lot of care in the engineering of this
product and of course as a past engineer
I really appreciate this they know that
non-native emfs so non-native
electromagnetic frequencies are damaging
for the human body and knowing this they
custom designed their fans to have less
magnetic radiation they also custom
designed a faraday cage around their
housing of the actual lights so that the
EMF exposure is very limited it's
basically zero and when a company takes
so much care of the fans and the housing
I'm going to assume that their lights
are of high quality as well and you
might be asking well red light therapy
is quite expensive and it is it's from
$400 all the way to like thousands of
dollars and I don't want to prescribe
something which is outside the buying
power of most of my viewers doesn't make
sense for me to do that so I'll tell you
right now that you don't need red light
therapy devices in order to get red
light therapy you know what's a really
good source of red light it's the Sun so
you can get this in the morning you can
get this in the night so red light so we
usually associate blue light to be in
the morning right blue light wakes you
up gives you the circadium Rhythm reset
that's fine but the truth is there's
also red light coming from the Sun in
the morning as well as in the evening
times so the moral of the story is get
sunlight as much as you can every single
day I would go so far as to say that 1
hour minimum and here's the thing
there's something which just happened in
the morning modern world which prevents
us from getting the sunlight we supposed
to have in the winter month especially
we're spending practically 24 hours
within our indoors enclosure inside our
homes either in the office or college
and this is not how our ancestors lived
our ancestors even during winter months
would have to go out either to collect
firewood to fish to hunt to milk their
cattle whatever it was you would get
some sunlight even during the harshest
winter months except when there's an
actual blizzard going on
yes you would get some sunlight and
that's simply not something that we do
our modern habits we go to our office or
college and by the time we return back
home the sun's already gone down and
there's no more opportunity to get
sunlight so I would suggest if you
cannot afford a red light therapy device
just wake up in the morning get sunlight
as soon as you can or even during the
day it doesn't matter when just get some
sunlight but of course if you can afford
it then a red light therapy is a great
long-term investment Now we move on to
creatine and of course I know that you
you know what creatine is creatine is
the stuff you take to get your muscles
more jacked give you more reps in the
gym it's an energy supplement it's for
bodybuilders correct yes and no it is of
course great for muscle building and it
is a safe and healthy supplement to have
but there's actually even more research
suggesting it's amazing for the brain
health in fact creatine is used as an
anti- neuro
degeneration prescription it is not a
drug it doesn't bind to receptors it is
a mitochondrial supplement yet again but
the way the creatine works is completely
different from red light therapy so red
light therapy works on the complexes in
the mitochondrial Inner Cell Wall
creatine doesn't do that creatine
converts to phosphor creatine and the
phosphor creatine so okay I should
rewind a little bit so we talked about
how ATP is the energy unit of the cell
fine but when ATP is used up it becomes
something called ADP so ATP is adenosine
triphosphate so TR as in three ADP is is
adinos D phosphate which is d as in two
so when it loses a phosphate group it
becomes a less energetic state so
phosphor creatine can add an extra
phosphorus well actually a phosphate and
then you have an high energy ATP again
so it's a conversion mechanism from ADP
to ATP of course the actual biochemistry
is a little bit more complex than this
but it suffices to say that creatine is
a mitochondrial support supplement and
that's why it has these amazing
properties of regeneration for the brain
as useful for nerve cells as it is for
muscle cells and I'll go so far as to
say it's actually more helpful for nerve
cells than muscle cells because nerve
cells actually have a higher
concentration of mitochondria than the
actual muscles do so this combination of
red light therapy plus creatine is
already very powerful it's already
protective of the neurons in your brain
it's already firing up mitochondria in a
way that it wasn't doing before and then
you add in the third component of the
Red White and Blue protocol which is
methylene blue I did a whole video about
this but let's go into the just the
basics methyl blue is an auto reducing
agent which means that it can donate an
electron or accept an electron why it's
important is as the mitochondria is
cranking out more energy it's also
producing R reactive oxygen species
which are a waste byproduct which are
kind of toxic to the cells so this
methylene blue can actually neutralize
them by accepting an electron from them
and basically making them neutral and
non-harmful it can also donate an
electron to the components within the
electron transport chain in order to
have that functioning of glucose to
actual energy so this combination think
about what's going on here you have a
synergistic effect you have three
different mechanisms of action all of
which are not only protecting the
mitochondria from damage they're also
boosting up the mitochondrial function
they're also clearing out the waste
products of the mitochondria this unique
protocol I haven't really seen this
discussed elsewhere is a short-term
solution to be fair in the long term you
want to actually fix up your
mitochondrial Health through a better
diet better nutrition better lifestyle
in general but often times in order to
make long-term changes you need a
short-term win to make that happen
because what is long-term success
long-term success is a series of
short-term successes which build one
upon the other I believe that the red
white and blue protocol can be one small
success in that chain of Greater
successes until you reach your final
Destiny so let's talk about dosages and
specific actionable steps so when it
comes to red light therapy I have done
20 minutes a day in 10 minute sessions
so morning wake up get 10 minutes of red
light therapy in at night 10 minutes of
the red light therapy and there's a
theory that it could boast testosterone
function and the idea is red light
therapy improves mitochondrial functions
of course the ladig cells which produce
testosterone in the balls they contain
mitochondria obviously and by boosting
mitochondrial function in theic cells
you actually can produce more
testosterone there's very limited data
on this so I cannot say that this is
something which is true but if you try
it and you feel better then there's a
likelihood that it's having some kind of
effect whether it's testosterone or not
you are going to feel better through red
light therapy regarding creatine 5 G of
creatine monohydrate per day that's a
standard dosage I have no
recommendations above that and then when
it comes to methylene blue it depends on
how much you react some people will have
a massive reaction to just one or two
drops of methylene blue and some people
like myself I need a whole dropper of
methylene blue in order to see the
effects and there's also the worry about
the side effects of methylene blue some
people have a higher level of anxiety
due to methylene blue I think it's
because methylene blue is so effective
at removing brain fog that when you
remove the brain fog you're face Toof
face with your anxious thoughts so if
that's the case for you I would suggest
of course fixing mental health issues
before getting on methylene blue now
mental health is a little bit different
so what I talked about today is actually
metabolic health I'm talking about
mitochondria and I'll of course make a
separate mental health guide when the
time is right and I have of course
suggested what brand of red light
therapy that I've used you may choose to
use that brand or if you have some
better suggestion put it in the comments
when it comes to creatine go for any
brand doesn't really matter I personally
just go for the Optimum Nutrition brand
just make sure that the ingredients list
has nothing but creatin monohydrate if
it has any kind of fillers any kind of
stabilizers that's not the correct brand
to go for and then lastly the Metaline
blue there's only one brand that I've
used and the only brand that I trust
because you really want to get the
pharmaceutical grade Metaline blue if
you get the industrial grade like from
some random brand on Amazon that's going
to do you far more harm than good so the
brand which I use I'll link it in the
description and there you have it boys
that is the red white and blue protocol
if you want the show notes for this
video there is an email intake form in
the description which will send you the
show notes the actual actionable steps
and everything and bullet form to your
email and finally if you like me I'm
talking about outside my content if you
like me personally then you should
follow me on Instagram for like actual
personal day-to-day wisdom or knowledge
or stuff like that which I learn on a
day-to-day basis I'll put it on
Instagram before it comes to YouTube
thank you for watching and remember
always that fortune favors the Bold