I'm going to share with you the magic
wand that changes your face this is the
REM straw I'm not sponsored by them I
don't make any money by promoting them I
just thought this might be valuable to
you so I'm sharing it it's essentially a
silicone nozzle on a standard metallic
straw and that's just what it is the
interesting part is how they've designed
this nozzle like the shape of this thing
it's shaped in such a way that you
cannot just suck water through this
there's a specific way in which you need
to position your tongue and your pallet
that forces you to apply pressure on the
roof of your mouth it's a lot like
mewing but it's just stronger you apply
way more pressure and in a different way
than usual that it causes your face to
change it applies pressure to your
maxilla which basically the more
prominent or I should say the better
developed your maxilla the overall wider
your face is going to be the more
handsome you're going to look now you
already probably know this because every
single video on Mee on the planet
explains this so there's no reason for
me to do so again there used to be a
time in which Mee was this underground
phenomenon but now everybody knows it
it's a meme so I won't bore you with
boring Mee stuff I'll show you the new
stuff this straw was designed to prevent
people from snoring now the actual
technique on using this is kind of
confusing so I'll do the best I can with
a demonstration I have a glass of water
with me I have the REM straw it's
basically done like this all right so so
pay attention all
right uh I don't know where to start
with this first start by making the N
sound so n when you do that your tip of
the tongue is going to touch a specific
part of your mouth basically the um the
bump right behind the teeth right so try
to do it for yourself right now say and
and feel where the tongue lies on the
roof of your mouth all right keep that
in your mind so when you use this thing
what you're doing is you put this in
your
mouth and then you press the tip of your
tongue to that same spot that you
connected with when you made the N sound
so your tongue is basically going to
going to press against this part of the
nozzle so if you look at this carefully
and I'll I'll put in b-roll which kind
of zooms into this you are placing your
lips right here right not on the actual
bump on the nozzle so it's going to look
like
this all right and you're going to place
the tongue right here to essentially
shift this like this to the roof of your
mouth all right so this thing is facing
like like in there pressing the tip of
the tongue against this part and you're
using the middle of the tongue to
actually cause the suction required to
drink the water so imagine this right
this is this is the roof of the mouth
this is your tongue this is going to be
your teeth so you start like this with
the tip of the tongue touching the top
of the roof of the mouth or the front of
the roof of the mouth I should say from
here
you bring down the mid of the tongue
which causes a vacuum which sucks in the
water and then you press up against it
to force the water to go into your
throat so essentially you're doing this
right with your tongue in order to get
the water down your throat you can
obviously understand how that's going to
apply a pulsating pressure to the roof
of your mouth your and that's going to
apply pressure to the maxilla and that's
going to change the structure of your
face so the main benefit isn't even even
the structure of your face there are
other benefits but I will explain after
the actual demonstration so I have I'm
going to do it I'm not going to speak
obviously I'm just going to do it and
you're going to see how it
looks all right even after doing it for
only a few seconds I'm going to this let
this uh airplane fly
overhead even after I do it for just a
few seconds right I can feel these
muscles engaging I'm not even sure why
that is why the neck muscles would be so
involved in the tongue movement but it's
the case I mean in the end of the day
like all the muscles of the how would
you say the airway system of our body
are interconnected so I'm not entirely
surprised that the next muscles are
involved in the movement of your jaw and
your tongue and of course the tongue is
actually a very important structural
muscle most people just think of the
tongue as a thing which tastes food it's
not true the tongue is one of the
pillars keeping your head in a stable
position of course your neck is the main
pillar but your tongue is in some sense
muscularly attached to your neck the the
structure of your head is supported by
the neck muscles and then the tongue in
the middle regardless we getting getting
way off topic I think when you when I
did the demonstration you could see that
my cheeks were not engaged they were not
I was not using the cheek muscles to
swallow I was using the tongue and the
throat muscles to swallow this is very
important and I'm going to explain this
this teaches the correct movement
pattern to swallow food so essentially
you're using this to learn how to
swallow food correctly and that is of
course a lifelong habit this has obvious
benefits for your jawline but also for
digestion in fact you will stop craving
fast food candy and packaged Foods if
you actually chew properly let me
explain myself the reason is because
these corrupt food scientists they've
engineered the food in such a way that
they're overstimulating for the first
few seconds of chewing so that you get
addicted to it if you actually chewed
your junk food your if you actually
chewed your junk food your candy your
packaged Goods more the real flavor
starts to emerge and it doesn't taste
good you can try this experiment for
yourself if you chew and unhealthy food
any unhealthy food for a longer period
of time it will taste like on the
other hand if you have a whole food meal
steak and potatoes or even something
more basic like chicken and rice it will
actually taste good as you chew more in
fact more flavors will be unlocked as
you chew now of course you need to be a
good Chef essentially you need to know
how to prepare good food if you want the
return of the old style cooking videos
let me know in the comments but why is
this this is because these corrup food
scientists have hijacked your brain and
they can only hijack your brain for a
few seconds basically if you're eating
like Cheetos or something it has uh what
do you call it MSG it tricks your brain
into thinking this is highly highly
nutritious food but only for a few
seconds if you give your body time to
analyze the truth you know analyze the
food using your chemical receptors which
is your tongue so what is taste taste is
chemical signals it's information about
the world right it is
not just for your enjoyment taste is not
something for your enjoyment taste is
created as a system to assess the
nutritional value and the risks of food
because food can obviously be spoiled or
it can contain parasites whatever right
so taste is a function that prevents you
from eating unhealthy food and eating
healthy food the modern day we have
foods which act as though they're hyper
healthy by tricking the brain but
they're actually not just give your
taste receptors time to act and the
truth truth will come out think about
the downstream effects you crave snacks
because you perceive a dopamine reward
if you can teach your brain that the
reward isn't real not through logic not
through watching educational YouTube
video but through experience how
valuable is it to pass on this skill of
correct chewing to your children and
your grandchildren if you incorporate
mindful eating you will eat better food
it is that simple but coming back to the
REM straw the REM straw was designed of
course to improve breathing and prevent
snoring and when we speak about looks
looks is Downstream of two things it's
health and genetic quality and of course
health is more within our control than
our genetic quality is that being said
look out for the esoteric epigenetics
guide when it comes to health the
quality of our breathing is such an
underrated Factor this is of personal
importance to me because I had breathing
problems for years I have recorded an
updated esoteric breathing guide and if
I had this guide 6 years ago I would not
have needed to go through surgery to fix
my breathing if you have learned
something new in this video you should
watch that video next I will place it in
the end screen tile I will show you the
exact techniques that you haven't seen
before and devices that you have not
seen before with that I'll close out
remember if you do not sacrifice for
your dreams your dreams become the
sacrifice