For more than six months of my life, I
ate lead, handled mysterious government
substances, and drank moldy water.
Unsurprisingly, after this, I felt like
absolute dog [ __ ] I had the worst brain
fog imaginable. If it wasn't for
zeolytes, I would be still stuck in a
rut, and you wouldn't have this YouTube
channel. In Army basic training and the
infantry school, you're going to shoot a
lot of guns, and that means you're going
to come in contact with a lot of heavy
metals from the combustion dust from
using these rounds. You're also going to
use CLP to clean your rifle. CLP is
cleaner, lubricant, and protectant. It's
a liquid that you use to clean your
weapons and also just as a lubricant to
make sure your mechanism of the rifle
works correctly. The actual formula for
this is not published by the government,
so we don't really know what's in there.
But a common hypothesis is that it's
liquidized Teflon. So, I was in contact
with liquidized Teflon and lead
practically every day. Worst part is
often times you'll go to the range,
you'll shoot all day, and then you'll
have your MREs. MREs are these packaged
meals, and there's no real place to wash
your hands or be hygienic. So often
times you'll go from shooting to
cleaning your rifle to eating. So I'm
sure I ate a bunch of lead and heavy
metals. On top of this, there was a
third enemy that I had to face. In basic
training and the AIT, you have this
thing called a camel back. It's like a
backpack that you wear which contains a
pouch which has water inside. It has a
hose through which you can drink the
water. So it gives your hands freedom to
you handle stuff but you can still get
water quite easily. That's why you're
always required to wear it. We had this
brilliant idea that we would take our
electrolyte packets from our MREs, dump
it into the pouch on our backs and then
get electrolyte water through our hose.
What happened we didn't realize was the
electrolytes had sugar in it. It's not a
problem in this case except for the fact
that it allowed mold to grow in that
hose that we drank from just on a whim.
I decided I was going to clean my camel
back. Most people never did this. So, I
took a pipe cleaner and shoved it into
the hose just to see how dirty it was.
When I took it out, it was just black,
completely black with mold. And I had
been drinking water out of this hose for
months at that point. So to speak about
mold toxicity, I think I would I'm quite
of an expert in being toxified by mold.
Once I got done with all this, I had the
terrible brain fog that I mentioned. I
just could not focus. Also, my allergies
were absolutely flared up and I had all
these plans in basic training. I had
journal almost every single day and I
had this plan for the life that I wanted
to create for myself, but I could not
execute on it because my health was
holding me back. That's where zeelites
come in. When I learned about zeolytes,
I learned that they were a detox tool.
So, what did I do? I just went to
Amazon, bought the cheapest zeolytes,
and then started taking 2 g per day, 4 g
per day, 6 g per day. I was lading it
up, which is what you're supposed to do
with most supplements. But zeolytes are
not supplements. A dietary supplement
supplements your diet, but a zeolyte has
no nutritional value. It's not a
supplement. So the dosing structure
which I used which was the slow lading
up was completely misguided and caused
more problems than it solved. So I felt
even worse because of the zeolytes. In
this video I'm going to teach you why
that paradoxical dosing structure works
for zeolytes. What zeolytes are how they
work whether they're right for you and
what what should you look for in a
zeolyte product. And zeolytes are top of
mind for me because very recently,
couple weeks ago, I was traveling a lot
back and forth, 12-hour journeys, and in
the process, I probably ate something
bad. Cold meat from a Delhi in the in an
airport. Things like this happened, and
I just got terrible gut distress. Gut
distress is just a fancy word. What
really happened was I woke up in the
middle of the night feeling like
garbage. Went to the bathroom, not
thinking too much, and just absolutely
heaved into the into the toilet bowl,
just gripping on for dear life. Ah, it
was like it was actual projectile.
Luckily, I made it to the bathroom, but
god, it was awful. I lost like 5 lbs in
a day and not in a good way. So, it was
not fun. Here's the thing. Usually, you
take days to recover from this. Days to
rehydrate, days to actually, you know,
for your body to fight the infection.
But what I did was I had zeolytes at my
home and I took a mega dose, 20 g one
time. And then the next day I felt
normal, like completely normal, like
nothing had happened the previous day.
And that just goes to show you how much
of a powerful detox tool zeolytes can
be. Now, if you haven't had the same
life experience as me, you're not
exposed to toxins in the same way as me,
but you are still exposed to toxins. If
you live in an older home, guaranteed
you're going to be exposed to lead
piping and lead paint. If you've eaten
at any restaurant ever, you're going to
be exposed to aluminium cookware, which
is what all restaurants use to cook
their food. Arsenic is in the
groundwater. So even if you have a well
in the middle of nowhere, quite a good
chance that there's arsenic in your
water unless you've tested it and made
sure that that's not the case.
Glyphosate is a common essentially a
herbicide used in agriculture seeps into
the ground water. It seeps into our
drinking water. If you eat fast food or
frozen foods, you're going to be exposed
to a lot of heavy metals toxicity.
Canned food and fish are a source of
mercury. And then if you're using
nonaluminium free deodorants, you're for
sure being exposed to aluminium. And
finally, all these heavy metal
toxicities, they do have a way of
interacting with your genetic material,
which means that you can pass on the
damage from these toxins to your future
generations. So, this is something we
certainly want to avoid. If you're
feeling fatigued, brain fogged, and just
tired all the time, and you can see that
he has these bags under his eyes. If
that's you, it's not what we want. So,
the first thing we talked about is the
heavy metal toxicity. But another
problem commonly faced is ammonia
buildup. So as you live and just having
natural chemical reactions in your body,
ammonia is produced and that's normal.
But if you have an ammonia buildup that
causes brain fog because ammonia can
actually travel through the bra blood
brain barrier and enter the brain and
disrupt well of course the brain
functioning. It specifically disrupts
GABA which is one of the key
neurotransmitters for sleep. So I'm
going to go ahead and draw some worry
lines. But ammonia also messes with
mitochondrial function. The mitochondria
produces ATP. Everybody knows
mitochondria is the powerhouse of the
cell. Produces ATP through something
called the Kreb cycle. Ammonia can
disrupt this cycle. So, I'm going to
give our Jack kind of an unhappy
expression and even some drool because
he's just brain fog. He's confused. He
cannot put his plans into action. On top
of this, if you get sick often or if you
have allergies, you also have a
histamine buildup. Histamine is a
byproduct of an allergic reaction. It's
just your immune system overreacting or
even normally reacting, you will produce
histamine. So, if you have allergies or
sickness, you have histamine buildup on
top of the heavy metal buildup. And I
should also put in the ammonia. And
how's your digestion? That's his
stomach. And as you can see, is just
bubbling up with all kinds of
indigestion. You have gut toxicity
issues. You have constipation. You can
also have diarrhea. On the other side,
this is not where we want to be. Also
want to draw some some flies cuz yeah,
bad gut health just results in bad
overall health outcomes across the
board. You are not going to be able to
succeed at your business, at your career
at being productive and focused and
actually making a step in life. If you
have gut toxicity or any of these other
buildups, now what's the dream outcome?
Where do we want to be? We want to have
a nose that's 100% functional. We want
to have eyes that are clear and free of
any kind of allergic reaction. We want
to have a deep and resonant voice with
which to communicate our ideas. We want
to have long luscious locks making us
look handsome. Want to have a big old
neck for our strength. Let me finish out
his other
eye. There we go. That's what we want to
be. We need a clear set of actionable
steps. And that is what I'm going to be
providing. I'm going to show you how
zeolytes work, how the dosage works, how
to find good products, and how to get
same day benefits. And all of this
completely unsponsored. I'm not making
any money by selling you any products.
How does toxin buildup even work? So
it's like this. Imagine this is your
body. B O D Y. You have toxin coming in.
You also have toxin leaving. Since your
body is pretty good at removing toxin.
Now the problem is if your level of
toxin intake exceeds the level at which
your body can remove toxin then you are
going to have a buildup of toxin with
time. So we can do one of two things. We
can either start to eliminate toxins
entering which is a certainly a good
idea. But in this video, we're speaking
of how to increase the outflow of toxin
using zeolytes. So if you do this, you
will reduce the level of toxin buildup.
This is what's called a stock and flow
diagram. This is a stock and these are
flows. This is just a basic introduction
to how system theory works. And I will
get much more into depth in other
videos. So why should you listen to me?
Well, I'll put the credibility stack in
the description where really my
experience comes from running Crusade
Labs, a functional health practice
designed to help men become the most
productive and focused versions of
themselves. And I accomplished this
using hormone optimized training. But to
be clear, I'm not a medical doctor and
this is not medical advice. So, let's
get started. So, what are zeolytes?
Zeolytes are volcanic ash. This is a
volcano spewing out ash. But the ash has
fallen into a lake. And this lake
contains
alkaline water. And if this is allowed
to react for 50,000
years, what you end up with is a
zeolyte. But why are zeolytes special?
Zeolyte, zeo means steam and lithos
means rock. So a rock which has steam
inside. What does this mean? So the guy
who discovered it, what he did was he
heated the stone and in so doing he saw
that steam was released which is a very
strange phenomenon. Why this happens is
because the zeolyte itself has porous
structures. It has all these little
cavities in the structure which can trap
water. So upon heating this water is
released as steam. This is very
important because it's these cavities
that give zeelites their unique
properties. So different zeolytes have
different properties based on the shape,
size and charge of the pores in its
structure. Zeolytes are made of
aluminium, silica and magnesium. But it
traps mercury, arsenic, lead and
cadmium. And like I said before, it also
traps histamine. On top of this, it also
traps ammonia. So theoretically, if your
body has a reduced load of heavy metals,
histamines and ammonia, you're going to
solve your brain fog problem. And the
reason why it's able to attract these
heavy metals is because zeolyte has a
slight negative charge and these ions
are all positive charge and it's able to
trap them because of the cavities and
the pores. Now the thing is not all
positively charged ions are toxic. For
example, if you take a supplement like
if you take a electrolyte supplement
you're going to have sodium, you're
going to have magnesium, you're going to
have calcium, you're going to have
potassium. All these are positive ions
but they're they're good for you. their
electrolytes. In other words, zeolytes
selectively traps the bad stuff and
leaves the good stuff alone. It does
this because again, it's a selective
binder. And this is actually in contrast
to other binders like activated
charcoal. Activated charcoal will just
capture anything. Zeolytes are
interesting because of the selective
binding property that they have. In
fact, this is not a big secret. Farmers
know about this. Farmers feed zeolytes
to their cattle in order to protect them
from ammonia toxicity. A lot of farms
use ammonia to fertilize their grasses.
So if a cow or cattle eats grasses which
are ammonia based fertilizers in them,
then they're going to have ammonia
buildup in their bodies. Not good for
them. So they feed them with zeolytes in
order to eliminate the ammonia toxicity.
On the other side, chickens fed with
grains are exposed to aphotoxins. So
farmers feed them with zeolytes to
remove aphotoxins from their bodies. And
what's true for chickens and cattle is
also true for the human body. In fact,
most zeolytes are not used as a human
consumptive supplement. It's actually
more used in agriculture and in the
industry. It's a hugely beneficial
substance for chemical processing. In
fact, they literally use zeolytes to
clean up nuclear waste in a place like
Chernobyl. They literally use zeolytes
to clean up the nuclear spill. If you're
watching this, it's clear that you're
invested in improving your health. It's
clear that you want to fix your brain
fogs, gut issues, whatever else you
might be facing in order to live a
better life. If this is you, your first
step in fixing your health has to be
getting your blood work done. Getting
blood work done provides you the road
map on what you need to do next. But
getting blood work is a pain because
first, there's a million biomarkers to
choose from. It's not clear which ones
you need. And the second is once you get
your results back, it's hard to know
what the numbers actually mean. We will
actually help you to solve this for
free. Me and my team are certified in
functional blood chemistry analysis. If
you fill out the form below, we will be
able to help you. And now we're going to
move into the tactical side of how you
should actually use the zeolytes. So
here's a graph of dosage versus time.
Most supplements, especially supplements
which you're not sure of, supplements
that are new to you, you'd want to start
out small, see how your body tolerates
it, and then go to a healthy stasis
amount and then maintain that. With the
zeolytes, it's quite the opposite. So
this I'm going to rate as normal subs.
So this could be something like
creatine. This could be something even
more exotic like metaline blue. But
that's how you should treat most
supplements. But with zeolytes, it's
actually like
this. And the reason for this is because
zeolytes work using a swap and drop
mechanism. And I'll explain that using
an analogy. Imagine you're living in a
home and you notice there's a bunch of
mercury vials in your basement. You're
like, I don't want these toxins in my
house. I'm going to take them outside.
So, you go down to your basement, grab
this mercury, and you're on the way out
to the exit to dispose of this. But on
the way, you just see a pile of lead on
the floor. Like, okay, that's higher
priority. And you you look at that and
then you just drop the mercury, grab the
lead, and take it out the exit. Now,
taking the lead out the exit is the
correct move. But in the process, you've
dropped this mercury and spilled it
across your floor. That's kind of how
zeolytes work. They just have shiny
object syndrome. If they see something
of higher priority, they will drop the
thing which they're carrying and pick up
the higher priority molecule. This is
not good because you don't want to drop
the mercury on the floor. It would have
been better if the mercury was just
safely sequestered in the basement. And
so it is with your body. So what does
the good look like? Good looks like it's
just not you. You and you have a team of
five buddies who are right behind you.
So that if you drew drop the mercury,
they pick that up and you can pick up
the lead and take it outside. Basically,
what I'm saying is a small dose of
zeolyte will actually do more harm than
good because you're accidentally taking
out the toxins from from storage and
just releasing them into the body. Not
good. What you need is a big army of
zeolytes ready to capture all the toxins
and take it all out on the same day.
Which is why you want to start with high
dosage and go with low dosage. Now
again, I want to make the disclaimer
that I'm not doctor and this is not
medical advice. Use your own research.
And how do I know this? I know this
because I made the same mistake. As soon
as I got out of the army, I tried the
zeolytes, but I did this supplementation
regime instead of how you're supposed to
do it for zeolytes. So, in terms of
exact numbers, what I would do right now
is 10 g of zeolyte every day for 7 days.
And how you use it is you take your
zeelite powder, put it into clean water
with a wooden spoon. This is important.
Stir it up and then drink it. So, 10 g
per day for 7 days is what I would do.
Now there are special cases for zeolite
use. For example, what I said is if you
fall sick. If you fall sick with an
infection, then you want to absolutely
nuke it. And I would go all the way up
to 20 g for a day. So how do I actually
use zeolyte? I don't consume zeolyte
year round. I use it on a need basis.
When I feel more brain fog, when I feel
an infection coming on, or when I've
recovered from an infection, I will
absolutely use zeolyte. But it's not
something I use day by day. Now I'm
going to move to product
recommendations. Before I do that, I
want to just say that you can have
zeolytes any time of day. Before or
after food, it doesn't matter. It works
the same. When you're looking for a
product, you're looking specifically for
cleanup tillite zeolyte. That's the only
kind of zeolyte which is acceptable for
human consumption. You want to look for
third party testing to make sure that
they are free of impurities. Then you
want to look for the ratio of silica to
aluminium in the structure of the
zeolyte. You want at least 70%,
preferably more. And finally, there are
liquid zeolytes in the market. I reject
these. These just don't have enough of
the actual zeolyte to be effective. The
powder form is far better. And then
there's micronized versus mil. You're
always looking for micronized zeolyte
over mil because when you have mil
zeolyte, this is mostly for industrial
purposes. This will shatter the
cage-like structures in the zeolyte.
Micronized will keep those intact. And
there you have it, a full rundown on how
to use zeolytes. But even so, the first
step in health is still getting blood
work done. And like I said before, we
can help you with that. Just use the
link in the description. And
specifically, if you have histamines, if
you have allergy problems going on right
now, the previous video I made is
specifically about that. It's going to
help you. It's going to change your life
if you have allergies. I want to leave
you with a reminder. Being healthy in a
sick society gives you an unfair
advantage.