those look like ball okay now it looks
like tips so don't believe the jackasses
who say fruit are bad because they
contain sugar of course they contain
sugar that's the whole point carrots
will actually improve your skin tone
pork and poultry are both monogastric
humans don't synthesize vitamin C most
animals actually do this all right boys
you know it's serious when I'm off my
ass and I'm actually delivering a
lecture on a whiteboard so this one is
about the esoteric food pyramid we
already know that the government issued
food pyramid is trash so it's time that
we make our own one based on the
principles outlined in this course so
let's start off with the first thing the
Keystone of this diet is red meat
especially red meat from ruminants so
ruminants are animals which have a
multi-stem digestive tract like cows
sheep and lamb goats all these guys have
a multi-stage digestion process which
means that their fat quality is going to
be better so monogastric animals like
chicken turkey pork their protein
quality is on par right they're the same
in terms of of protein quality but
they're not the same in terms of fat
quality that's why we start off with red
meat red meat especially from ruminant
so let me go ahead and draw a nice ribey
I don't know if this is going to come
out well but we'll give it a go that's
supposed to be a riy boys so a nice
ribey is the ultimate piece of our
puzzle here and I will say that this is
going to be costly red meats from
ruminants are usually expensive lamb
meat for example at least in the US is
really expensive it's it's much cheaper
elsewhere because there's more demand
for it but in the US lamb meat is kind
of expensive of course a riy is really
going to set you back but you don't have
to get a riy so that's the thing red
meat doesn't have to be expensive it
depends on the cut so get good at making
meals from the so-called less desirable
cuts which are equally nutritious it's
just that there's not as much demand for
them so what you do is look for steel
meat so Ste meat most people don't know
how to use it most people don't buy it
so there's not that much demand the
prices are low but it's massively neut
nutritious or choose ground Meats ground
beef ground venison can be really an
amazing source of nutrition especially
because they often do contain organ
Meats so become an expert on cooking and
creating meals from the so-called less
desirable or off Cuts can save a lot of
money but get optimal nutrition at the
same time and not just optimal nutrition
this is Elite tier nutrition so that's
the first entry into our list is red
meats could be ground beef could be
ground venison could be lamb could be
goat could be sheep could be any of
these the next next item on this list is
of course eggs high quality eggs the
quality is of course important so red
meat you're going to get grass-fed grass
finished eggs we're going to get them
from pasture raised let me go ahead and
draw a nice basket how do you draw a
basket I don't feel like I haven't seen
a basket in a while but let me give it
my best approximation one dozen eggs so
how many eggs should you have you should
have at least two eggs per day l two day
two eggs a day minimum that's the
requirement you can go go all the way up
to 10 eggs if you so choose you really
want the eggs for the sulfur benefit the
sulfur is going to bind to and remove
excess iron highest quality protein on
here and indeed does have high quality
fats as well especially if you are not
going to eat red meats you should
supplement with eggs instead then we
move on to the next item which is
carrots carrots are really really good
for detox cuz they have these baa cartin
and also not just Berry cartin also
other catenoids which bind to and remove
estrogens they so remove Metals so
carrots are an amazing part of your diet
but this segment also includes things
like pumpkins and squashes which also
contain carotenoids so let me go ahead
and draw some carrots highly highly
highly beneficial and the thing is you
can have a lot of these carrots are
pretty low in um calories so whether
you're bulking or cutting doesn't matter
carrots are very low in calories you can
smash a whole bunch of them and the
coolest thing is carrots will actually
improve your skin tone so literally you
look better your skin will be more
lustrous more luxuriant In Color by
eating carrots because those beta
keratins they actually do become a part
of your skin not so important for me cuz
I have pretty dark skin already but if
you're super pale then carrots are a
important part of your diet then we have
poultry I'm going to also lump pork into
this because pork and poultry are both
monogastric so let's go ahead and write
P Tre and pork I'm not a huge fan of
pork myself I don't like the taste and I
tend to avoid myself except for bacon I
do enjoy bacon so poultry and pork these
are also good quality protein really
high quality protein I should say but
simply not on par with red meat that is
to say red meat from ruminants when it
comes to the fat quality let me go ahead
draw a chicken drumstick that is
terribly drawn but we're going to go
with it and finally we'll finish this
out with fruit fruit contains a lot of
vitamins and especially vitamin C humans
don't synthesize vitamin C most animals
actually do this but humans do not which
is why fruit is important for us so
don't believe the jackasses who say
fruit are bad because they contain sugar
of course they contain sugar that's the
whole point someon one of simple sugars
is really beneficial for us so yeah go
for fruit man fruits are not a problem
when it comes to fruits kiwi are solid
those look like balls that's a terrible
drawing then we have pomogranate another
solid option pomogranate looks like a
circle with a crown oranges oranges are
a nice option I don't know how to draw
an orange really I think okay now it
looks like tits so let's add another one
then we can also include coconut water
in here if you can get coconut water
that would be really cool coconut water
is the elite level electrolyte I'm not
sure if coconut water is a fruit as such
but I want to include it anyway of
course berries when it comes to berries
blueberries are a solid option let's
draw some blueberries oh grapes grapes
are a solid option as well bananas
especially if you're going to go work
out solid option so really any kind of
fruit are good and speaking of fruit and
also carrots you should absolutely wash
them well before you consume them
carrots not so much because carrots are
anyway under the ground so they're kind
of protected but fruits for sure for
sure you need to wash fruits before you
consume them when I say wash I'm saying
10% salt solution or 10% apple cider
vinegar solution soak them in there for
a little bit and give them a nice scrub
before you consume them and that's your
basic tier boys so this in itself is
going to set you apart like this diet
just this alone is already better better
than 90% of people around you but now we
take it one step further we introduce
some living Foods so I'm going to go
ahead and draw what I think a glass milk
bottle would look like not the best but
hey actually that's all bad I'm pretty
happy with it milk and I'm talking about
raw milk all right boys so you know the
drill raw milk high in probiotics has
live cultures in it the enzymes are not
destroyed by homogenization which means
that the enzymes in this milk is
actually going to help you digest it in
the first place so highly recommend some
raw milk if you can get raw milk that's
fine at least try to get nonhomogenized
ultra low temperature pasteurized
instead that's also a solid option do
not really go for the ultra pasteurized
stuff there's really no point in getting
those if you can get raw milk or low
temperature pasteurized good if you
cannot then just skip it and we'll go to
the next one which is honey I'm talking
again of raw honey and if you can get it
get unheated honey so the difference
between raw honey and just your regular
store Brad honey is that the enzymes are
destroyed upon heating so you don't want
the heating and let me go ahead and draw
some Honeycombs cuz the honeycomb is
also pure magic so you want to actually
get the honeycomb if you can honeycomb
contains its own Suite of minerals and
vitamins and enzymes highly recommend
let me go ahead and draw a b cuz these
guys are Real G's for making this stuff
be that looks like honey I think I can
deal with that so raw honey then finally
we finish out this layer with vegetables
that's right vegetables are not bad I
know that a lot of people are freaking
out because of plant toxins the hype is
overblown unless your diet is literally
a vegetarian based diet where you're
eating only vegetables that case yes
plant toxins will add up when it's a
part of your diet rather than your whole
diet plant toxins are not a problem
garlic is a great option for its detox
benefits is that how you draw a garlic
there we go garlic Ginger is a solid
option because it has thermogenic
properties potatoes are a great option
for smashing on the calories if you're
trying to bulk that's my approximation
of what potatoes look like then we have
other root vegetables so we can add
these into stews especially meat stews
makes it taste good we can have beetroot
and I know a lot of people will freak
out about beets because of the oxalates
and stuff don't cry about the oxalate
boys you're not having beats every
single day you're just having a small
amount of Beats as a part of a stew so
long as vegetables on the core of your
diet you're fine we can also have
radishes radishes are solid for a bunch
of reasons one of them is they contain
aromatase Inhibitors which is a really
cool benefit people have been having
vegetables for a very long time so it's
not going to hurt you all a sudden so
veg and this includes potatoes oh what
about grains so grains are fine in very
specific circumstances if you're having
whole grain based sourdough bread it's
fine so sour dough bread can also be
added into this let's see if I can draw
a loaf of bread without autism there we
go that's that's bread souro bread and
there we have it that's this triangle
done and finally we'll cap Stone this
entire pyramid with of course liver I'm
going to draw a nice big liver and put a
crown on it because yes indeed liver is
King there you go boys liver is the
ultimate multivitamin in nature highly
bio available really top of the line you
can toss out all your supplements if you
have liver you consume liver you don't
really need to cook it yourself you can
use liver crisps instead equally good
but much more easy to eat and finally
we'll close out with supplements you
don't need supplements they don't really
have a place on the pyramid they have a
place as an optional on top of the
pyramids so when it comes to supplements
what can you have whe makes sense if
you're trying to bulk but you're trying
to get way Protein Isolate and you're
trying to get the unflavored stuff then
there is a potential for cod liver oil
especially in the winter months I don't
use cod liver oil throughout the year
just the winter months you can also use
creatine and of course be cognizant that
if you see any hair loss then
immediately stop using creatine and then
the last one which is a possible good
supplement is collagen you can also use
glycine instead this is going to help
you fall asleep this is going to help
with your skin hair and nails there one
thing which is missing here you might
notice I haven't really talked about
butter I haven't talked about fats in
general that's because it's not a part
of the pyramid it's just something you
use for cooking for example if you're
going to make an omelette with eggs
you're going to use butter to do it if
you're going to make yourself a carrot
salad you're going to sprinkle black
seed oil or you're going to sprinkle
olive oil so there's not a separate
place for fats because that's
Incorporated in all the dishes that you
prepare so perhaps what I should do is I
should make a little special Circle in
here and use this for fats and I mean
butter I mean saturated fats by the way
butter I'm including here olive oil I'm
including black seed oil I'm including
ghee so let me go ahead and draw a nice
stick of butter looks like a cigarette
that's a terrible drawing of butter but
I don't think I can improve upon it
there you have it boys that is the acetc
food pyramid this is Elite level
nutrition
if you can actually Master this this is
better nutrition than the Kings and
rulers of olden times this is the
pyramid that's literally going to cause
your government officials and your
registered dietitians to have a stroke
if they see this thing this really goes
against all the average Normy BS this is
my personal guide for Designing my own
meal plans I hope this has helped you at
this time go ahead and Mark your module
as complete