This box contains the legendary Navage
device. One of the most effective tools
against allergies. So, what is this
thing? How did I come buy it? And how do
you actually use it? That's what I'm
going to discuss. So, I found this
randomly in a CVS store and I purchased
it and I tried it and it was actually
life-changing. How it works is it has
two containers. What you do is you fill
the top container with water, clean
water, so filtered or boiled. And what
it does, it has a pump inside and it
passes water through one nostril and out
the other and it collects the water in
this bottom container. This is
essentially a way to clean your airways
and remove allergens. So I know this is
effective. In fact, I this is so
effective that whenever I travel, I
still carry it with me despite being
kind of heavy and bulky. This is
something which I suggest to almost
everybody in Crusade Labs. One of the
members, Teemo, he tried it recently and
he reported that when he tried the first
time, this thing, the bottom container,
just collected a bunch of fleg, mucus,
and even blood. And this is actually a
common thing. Many people will find that
the first time they use it is almost
unpleasant, but also a relief because
think about it, there's so much junk in
the airways of your skull. If you have
allergies, it's better out than in. This
is a common thing which happens. The
first time you use it, hell, the first
week you use it, you'll collect so much
mucus like infection like tissue and
even blood, clotted blood in this thing,
but once it's out of the body, you feel
amazing. So, I've been using it for more
than 6 months at this point and nowadays
it's almost clear water which comes out.
But in the start, yeah, it wasn't that
way. This is essentially like a ni pot.
It performs a similar function. However,
because it has a pump and it pulls water
through. It just works way better. So,
when you're actually using this, here
are some tactical things that I found
which make the experience better. It's
very important that you use clean water.
You do not want to be passing just
straight tap water through your airways.
That's just a recipe for disaster. So,
you want to be using RO filter or
boiled. I still add methylene blue to
this because methylene blue is a
disinfectant. It destroys bacteria. It
destroys bofilms. It destroys viruses.
It destroys fungus. So that makes sure
that the water that I pass through is
free of those things. But also the same
benefits inside the airways of course
destroys fungus, destroys bacteria of
course and the water removes the
allergens. So really nice if you have
any of these symptoms. And for
maintenance this is also important.
Every month at least one time you have
to put in couple drops of alcohol with
your water and just run it through like
obviously not run it through your nose.
Just run it through such that the
alcohol passes through the pipes within
this thing. That just makes sure that
any kind of bacteria or infection which
is growing inside will be destroyed.
This honestly might be one of the best
$100 purchases I've ever made. If I had
this device when I was younger, 3 4
years ago, 5 years ago, I would have not
had these symptoms. I would not have had
to get surgery and I would be years
ahead of where I am right now. Just as a
good intervention can get you years
ahead, a bad intervention can actually
put you years behind. And that is what
happened to me. So when I first had
allergies back in undergraduate in
college, I I did the natural thing which
is I went to the doctor and I told him,
"Hey, my nose is inflamed. I can't
breathe. Um, what do I do?" And this is
what the doctor did. He prescribed me
something called Cinex. It's a nasal
spray. And this was the wrong thing to
prescribe. What Cinex is is it's a
decongestion. So you spray it into your
nose and immediately your congestion
vanishes like literally within 30
seconds. And it was a godsend because I
could become confident again. I could go
to the gym. I could make gains. I could
live my life as normal using the Cinex.
So, in the first few months, I loved it.
It was great. But Cinex is actually
quite a dangerous prescription. It's
it's quite a dangerous drug to use. And
the reason is the more you use Cinex,
the less effective it becomes. And
eventually it's going to cause your
turbinets and I'll explain what that is
to enlarge to the point at which you
need surgical intervention to remove
them. So everybody has turbinets.
Turbinets are projections which come
from the outside of your nose to the
inside. They literally look like like
finger projections on the inside of your
nose. And what they're designed to do is
slow down the air intake as it goes to
the lungs and also increase the humidity
of the air as it goes in so that when it
goes to the lungs it's not very dry.
That's what turbines are supposed to do.
That's why they can enlarge and reduce
in size depending on the situation,
depending on the humidity. But also if
inflamed, if there's a histamine
reaction going on, they will become
overenlarged. So coming back to cinex,
what sinex does is it acts on these
turbinets to reduce their size, which is
why it acts as a decongestion. You can
actually find out if you have enlarged
turbinets. Right. Now, the way you do
this, I'll show you, is take your
fingers and press it on the bone of your
nose. Like at the top, of course, the
nose has a bone. So, just feel the bone
go down. And as soon as the bone ends,
squeeze in. If you squeeze in and you
feel that one side is significantly
bumpier, like if you have some kind of a
bony um feeling like there's a bead
stuck in your nose, that's an enlarged
turbinet. Can happen because of many
reasons, but if you have this, you'd
want to talk to your ENT to see what can
be done about this. This is why I needed
surgery is because I overused the sinex.
Sinex is addictive. The doctors didn't
tell me about it. And because of the
overuse, the only option left to me was
surgery. In fact, I have pictures of the
surgery that I did. The before and
afters looks pretty messed up, but I
wanted to show you. So, if you look at
this, you can see after the surgery,
after they cut the turbanet off, there's
so much air space compared to in the
beginning. So, don't use Cinex. Sinex is
just a terrible product overall. Don't
use Afrin. Terrible product. Instead,
use if you have to use a product to
clear up your congestion, use fluonise
or just zerek tablets. Much better for
you than sinex orphan. If you have these
symptoms and you go to a doctor and he
doesn't help you, he's not able to help
you. I know that feeling cuz I've been
there. Instead of the doctor helping me
get better, he actually helped me get
worse. And that's the reason I'm making
this video and giving you all this
knowledge is because I want to give you
the story without the scar. Speaking of
doctors, another weakness that they have
is they're not so good at interpreting
blood work. So if you give a doctor your
blood work, he's just going to see if
your markers fall within the reference
range. If it falls within the reference
range, he's going to say that you're
good. This is not the way I see it. The
way I see it is blood work is a map, a
map towards optimal health, not just
reference ranges, not just the averages.
But there's problems with getting blood
work done on your own. The first is you
don't know what biomarkers to get.
there's literally thousands of them that
you can choose from. And the second is
once you get your results back, you
don't know what to do with it because
there's like dozens of numbers and you
don't know what the actionable steps
are. You don't know what the numbers
actually mean. And that's why I started
Crusade Labs. If you fill out the form
in the description, either myself or a
certified functional blood chemistry
analyst is going to speak with you, give
you guidance on what biomarkers make
sense for you to get and provide you
interpretation as well. And all this at
this time is completely for free. We
could talk forever about blood work, but
this video is not about blood work. It's
about allergies. Speaking of, turns out
I'm allergic to cockroaches. So, what I
have in front of me is the allergy skin
prick test. What this test is is a
comprehensive test of all the allergies
that you have. The way it works is you
go into the lab and they will prick your
skin in a dozen spots with different
allergens. They have the concentrated
versions of each of these allergens. And
the way your skin reacts is going to
inform how allergic you are to each of
these allergen species. So if you look
at my report, you'll see a lot of threes
and fours. Threes and fours indicate
quite a high level of allergy. Something
like a one or two, not so much. So you
can see there's grasses, trees, weeds,
environmental, and molds. And in this
video, I'm going to talk about each of
these classes of allergens and how to
fight them. So at the end, you'll have
methods to destroy any of these. When
the allergy specialist looked at my
report, the first suggestion he made to
me was to change my bedding because I
was highly allergic to mites. And
there's a very good chance that you too
are allergic to mites. Because one of
the reasons why this reaction even
happens in the first place is to fight
off parasites. Mice would be one example
of that. Mites are these tiny insects
which like to live on fabric. Solution
number two is changing your bedding.
Let's draw some
pillows and a
nice bed. In terms of order of priority,
the first thing you need to change is
the pillow covers. Pillow covers. Think
about it. onethird of your life in bed
sleeping. Your face and your nose by
extension is very near near the pillows.
So if you change your pillow cover to be
a mightfree pillow cover, then you're
going to save yourself from direct
exposure to mites and their body parts
which both cause inflammation. So what
are these might fabrics? It's just
cotton. It's just cotton, but they weave
it extremely tightly. And what this does
it it leaves no space for these mites to
build their homes and live making the
fabric essentially might resistant. So
you can actually find might resistant
pillowcases. You can find might
resistant pillows, might resistant
blankets, bed sheets, mattresses, and
comforters. All these things exist, and
I'll link to them in the description.
Even if you change none of the bedding
and none of the fabrics, you could just
use a mightkilling detergent and wash
your bedding in that which will just
kill all the mites in the fabric. To get
into solution number three, we got to go
all the way back to the college
dormitories. This is when my allergies
first started in the first place. This
was prior to me seeing the doctor for
the first time for this purpose. What
was happening and I didn't know this at
the time was my dorm had mold growing in
it and I had an allergy towards mold.
That's what was causing the
inflammation, the runny nose and all the
symptoms that we discussed in the start.
So mold releases spores and these spores
cause allergy cause inflammation and
also have ZA which is a xenoestrogen
which reduces your testosterone. So here
we're essentially speaking of airborne
allergens from mold and this is
generally indoors. So just as pollen is
an airborne outdoor allergen, mold
spores are an indoor airborne allergen.
So how do you fight this? You need to
improve your indoor air quality. And the
biggest reason why most people have bad
indoor air quality is because they have
carpets. If you have a carpet in your
floor on your floor, very likely that
the indoor air quality in your living
space is garbage because carpets, they
are the perfect breeding ground for
mites, cockroaches, all kinds of pests,
but also release microplastics into the
air. So, if at all possible, you'd want
to get rid of carpets and move towards
having a tile or wooden floor. But
sometimes that's just not possible
because you live in an apartment, you
live in the dorms, and carpets are what
you have. So, what can you do? You can
use filters and off filters. There are
three kinds. The first is using a a HEPA
filter that you can just buy on Amazon.
And the way these things work is they
take in air through the sides and
release air from the top and they have a
filtration system on the sides.
Basically, it purifies your air. And
well, that's one thing you can do.
That's one clear solution. So these
things they capture dust, airborne
mites, captures pollen, captures mold
spores. We have another filter which is
a vent filter. So if you have an air
conditioning system in your home, you
have these vents in your rooms, in your
living spaces. So this is a vent and
there are filters which kind of go on
top and prevent the mold spores which
are growing in the vent system from
entering your breathing space. So that's
filter number two. And the third kind of
filter that you can use is the actual
HVAC filter itself. So if you live in a
home which has central heating, central
cooling, there is an HVAC system likely
in your basement. That system has a
filter that needs to be changed at least
once every month and a half. Usually
they suggest 3 months, but if you have
allergies, you would want to change it
at a faster cadence. Those filters look
kind of like a big cardboard sheet but
with uh perforations. So you want to
change your HVAC filters. That's how you
fix your indoor air quality. And in
addition to this, you would want to be
vacuuming. That's a vacuum cleaner. You
want to be vacuuming your home every
week absolutely minimum. And another
option is just to use a
Swiffer. This works great as well.
Captures all the allergens. So you
essentially hygiene, right? Solution set
number four directly attacking the mold
situation. So what you can do here is
you need to actually find this stuff. So
sometimes it can be quite tricky cuz you
don't know where it grows. So the easy
hint is wherever there's moisture,
there's a chance of mold growth. So
bathrooms, kitchens, basements, attics,
high spots for mold growth. So where are
you looking? You're looking under the
sink. If there's wood paneling, you're
looking at the wood and you're looking
for green or black spots or patches. If
you see that, that's mold and you need
to get rid of it yesterday. I'm going to
attach some pictures of mold and
locations and I'm also going to give you
a kind of a guideline or places to check
in the description. But now, how do you
get rid of the mold? Here are some
important steps. First, if you're going
to attack the mold, you need to be
wearing protective equipment. You need
to be wearing at least an N95 mask and
also gloves to prevent the skin contact
with the mold. Highly important. Do not
skip this step. Do not clean the mold if
you don't have the protective gear
needed to do so. The second thing is you
need bleach. You can either get bleach
and you mix it in the ratio of one cup
per gallon and just use that to scrub
this mold or you can actually buy
specific chemicals which are designed to
kill mold. That's what I will actually
suggest. There's two two chemicals, two
sprays really, which I will put in the
description. The first one is going to
be designed to destroy the mold and the
second one is a sealant. So, it's going
to make it so that the mold does not
regrow. If you have a mystery allergy,
it's quite likely that it's actually
mold. So, if you have an allergy which
just appears out of nowhere, like you
feel like garbage, you feel like this
guy just randomly at different parts of
the year. It might not be pollen, not
might not be animals. It could be mold
because whenever there's a mold flare up
in your home, you're suddenly going to
feel like And you're going to feel
like it's random, but it's not random.
It's just that you didn't know what the
causing factor was. And the fifth
solution set is how do you prevent mold
from growing in the first place? Mold
grows great where there's high humidity.
Well, and that means that you need to
maintain or measure the humidity in your
home. So, there's two things which can
happen. One is there's too much
humidity. Any humidity above 60% is
perfect for mold growth. So, you would
want in this case to have a
dehumidifier. Very important. If you
happen to be living in a basement or a a
dank or damp location, you absolutely
need a dehumidifier. So, here's the
thing. In the winter when it gets super
dry, you'd want to get a humidifier. And
specifically, you want to get a cool
mist humidifier. and Wix makes good
ones. Essentially, there's two types of
humidifiers. The first kind is has a
wick and the wick basically suctions up
the water using osmosis, has a fan which
then produces the humidity. Don't get
this kind. This kind is bad because the
wick is usually saturated with water and
it can be a substrate for mold to grow
on. Not good. The other kind uses a
vibration to make the water essentially
into its gaseous form. He's looking for
cool mist vaporizer. So look for that.
If you do all these, you can go from
being this guy to being him. Before we
close out, I want to remind you that
being healthy in a sick society gives
you an unfair advantage.