when people realized that I was in the
army they asked me if that's why my
posture was so good but that was never
the case the Army doesn't really care
about posture that much even in
formation the Army doesn't really care
about posture that much this is in North
Korea you know but you know who does
care about posture ballroom dance so I
took lessons in walz Fox Trot Tango
couple other dances and they are
extremely strict with posture and I was
never the best dancer by any means but I
got quite a few ribbons and that's
because of POS posture and because I
cheated to improve my posture about
everybody else and if postural
Improvement was the only thing I got
from ballroom dance it would absolutely
still be worth it even if you negate all
these social benefits of which there are
many this video is going to be extremely
actionable I'm going to give you the top
20% things which improve my posture and
this is because most people don't know
this but posture is a skill and a very
high Roi skill at that it will pay
dividends for years to come I'm not
talking about okay it makes you
attractive to women or makes you more
confident seeming let's that's fine I'm
talking about straight up biological and
health benefits I also want to remark
that just because you lift or you go to
the gym doesn't mean that you're not
living a sary lifesty what I mean by
that is if you spend most of your day
sitting behind a desk looking at the
computer and you spend 1 hour of your
day lifting that's not going to
counteract the effects so even if you
have a desk job man try to make the
effort to get up and move around every
20 minutes at least so I know what the
hell I'm talking about regarding this
subject because I actually had a
postural problem like a serious postural
problem called lumbar lordosis it's also
called like swe back it's also called
having a duck butt literally so this
happened during my first year of college
so first year of college was a disaster
man like I had a great high school I had
a great college experience after my
first year but I did not have a first
good year of college because it was bad
time for me man so I didn't know what
the hell I was doing I don't know why I
was in college in the first place I
didn't have any friends I didn't have a
Social Circle so I fell into a deep
addiction for video games so I was spent
like 10 hours plus per day playing Rome
Total War which is like a strategy game
and by the end of the year Year my spine
like my actual back was curved my butt
was sticking out and my my abs were
distended because that was just a result
of playing video games in a bad posture
for basically a year but at some point
in the end of the year my computer broke
down which was a godsend cuz I couldn't
play the video games anymore I was
forced to confront what I had created
for myself so within 6 months I had
actually completely fixed my lumbar Lord
Doses and you're going to learn exactly
how I did it so in dance posture is very
important you are literally given points
or deducted points based on posture so
if you wear a back brace while you're
dancing and if you calibrate the like
the straps length correctly you can hold
a very nice solid frame effortlessly and
this this actually very challenging in
dance to hold this frame for a long
duration but if you're riding a back bra
it's pretty easy so just because of that
one reason and of course because my
partners were really talented in their
own right I got all these ribbons like I
got one for Waltz this one's for foxtrot
I think these two are for Tang and a
couple other dances as well but
regardless let's get back on topic right
so this is a back phrase wear it for no
more than 3 hours per day and what
you're going to do is you're going to go
for nice leisurely walks in the outdoors
in nature every single day for at least
10 minutes and that's your point number
two go for walks man and I'm not talking
about for burning calories or for
Fitness or anything like that though of
course those are benefits I'm talking
about going on Long leisurely walks for
the purposes of relaxation so that you
are actually receptive to ideas and
that's the key point so where do you
think good ideas come from you think the
best scientists of our history are sad
behind Des trying to get good ideas no
if you read biographies of great
scientists and discoveries by great
inventors almost always they say that
the idea came to them whole almost like
a divine inspiration and this is only
possible if you're receptive to those
kinds of thoughts and for me the easiest
way to become receptive is going on a
walk you're not taking your phone with
you you're not taking your notification
ations you have a notebook and a pencil
with you and you are just going for a
walk could be 10 minutes could be 1 hour
and what you're doing is you're being
mindful of your breathing and you're
being mindful of your posture and if
you're writing a back brace as you're
walking you're going to basically train
your body to have an upright walking
posture it's going to become a habit so
this brace is basically it's um
stretching my chest muscles and it's
stretching my front delts which are
tight and it's causing the activation of
my lower trapezius muscles all things
which are good for overall posture but
then again I'm saying like you don't
need to be dependent on this no more
than 3 hours per day and yeah it's very
cheap very easy to get and three is to
do those walks while wearing barefoot
shoes so I have with myself my barefoot
shoes so the thing about these is
there's no rise so so rise is the angle
of the sole of the shoe and when you
have zero rise you're basically allowing
your Achilles tendon and your calves to
function as they're supposed to as shock
absorbers most modern Footwear have a
rise which means that they have a big
heel and a small toe box which kind of
forces your feet to be in an incline and
this puts more stress on your knees and
hip joints you don't want that obviously
so I'll make a separate video on
barefoot shoes and in fact how to fix
flat feet and you can watch that
separate video but as for right now I'll
link in the description to the Barefoot
shoe brand that I recommend you can
check it out if you so please changing
your Footwear is going to be a massive
Boon for your postural health and
overall health in general man highly
recommend it's just a matter of buying
an equipment you you don't even have to
have discipline or anything just by
buying better Footwear you're going to
improve your lower body posture and the
third point is barefoot running or
jogging so go out into the open on
grassy Fields start running without
shoes on your body has all the knowledge
it needs for good posture I don't have
to be sat here teaching you anything
because your instincts are already there
as soon as you start running jogging or
walking barefoot on grass Millennia old
instincts will kick in to teach you how
to maintain good posture I'm talking
about from ground to the top man I'm
talking about neck posture shoulder
everything and finally are there any
specific exercises to do to fix your
posture absolutely there is I am a
certified yoga instructor so I know what
I'm talking about I'm going to guide you
through the exercises right now once you
improve your posture it literally
changes the way people perceive you and
I'm not talking about the obvious
benefit of being more attractive to
women that's obvious I don't need to say
too much about it I'm talking about in
general once you fix your posture it's
almost like you been visible for the
first time in society with B posture you
can go in cognito and that has its
functions to be honest in some places
you don't want to be noticed and you
don't want to stick out in which case
compromise on posture ball up but if
you're trying to be the main character
in your own life then embrace the space
Embrace good posture and literally you
feel like you're in a video game and
you're the lead character people will
try to interact with you you have more
positive interactions with others life
literally becomes more beautiful when
you embrace the space that you have been
given if you implement mindful posture
literally today you will see a
difference in your life all right boys
I'm going to show you your morning
stretching routine first thing it was