run to the girls dorm almost naked and
they would start singing songs serenades
some of the girls would play along take
off their pennies swing it around their
fingers and then toss it across the
courtyard
life has gotten objectively more boring
since we all started carrying around a
high resolution camera in the form of
our iPhone in our pocket every day about
a week ago a friend invited me over for
lunch and he had his family there his
father was there his father is about 60
years old that he attended the same
University that I did he was telling me
about his experiences in my University
some of the things that you said just
blew my mind like things that he
mentioned could never happen in today's
climate I fact checked all of these so I
went back and looked at Old School
newspaper records he wasn't making it up
so there used to be this culture in my
University a group of guys maybe like 15
guys they were all stripped down to
their underpants they'll run to the
girls dorms with a courtyard in the
middle so these guys would go into the
courtyard almost naked and they would
start singing songs doing serenades just
making a whole Ruckus and being being
annoying being funny doing stupid things
to impress these girls and they would
ask them for their panties now obviously
like some of the girls would just hate
this whole thing and stay indoors but
some of the girls were would play along
they would walk onto the balcony do a
dance do like the whole show and
everything make it interesting and take
off their pennies swing it around their
fingers and then toss it across the
courtyard and these things would just
like you know fly and then float down
like parachutes and the guys would go
wild like they would jump and try to
catch these that would be their trophy
and people would fight over these and
you know they'll get bloody nose and
everything so can you imagine something
like that even remotely like that
happening in today's University
environment impossible it would be
Crackdown like they people would call
the cops on these guys guaranteed but
even leaving aside the administration
side of things you know even the
University Administration coming in
people would still not do crazy things
like this nowadays simply because if it
was done somebody would have their phone
on them everything which happens would
be online the next day or the same day
like on Tick Tock or something and this
causes us to not have these crazy
experiences and looking at these crazy
things happen because no one is gonna do
him and instead if crazy things are done
they're done solely for the purpose of
tick tock slash social media so if
something fun and crazy like this was to
happen it would be done with an
intention in mind not just the fun but
the clout on social media and that just
changes things somehow and and other
experiences with this father of my
friend was talking about they used to do
this thing called The Naked Mile and I
know you've probably seen that stupid
absolutely stupid movie well it was kind
of fun though American Pie Naked Mile I
think it's like a decade ago this movie
came out yeah but that's a real thing
like people used to actually do that so
in the coldest winter night in my
University these guys they would strip
down to barely nothing they would run
across campus on this well-known path
butt naked and then they would go back
to their dorm so at this time there was
this all-male dorm in my University also
had this Courtyard in the center so they
would do something called the authentic
Olympics and it is as bizarre as it
sounds get this right these guys would
strip down to nothing I don't know why
nudity was a part of all these stories
but anyway they've still done basically
nothing and they were do the entire
Olympic Games in the privacy of their
all-male Dawn they'd have like discus
throw long jump running and printing all
those Olympic events they would just
have fun you know they have a whole
sports day and I see nothing like that
in the modern University system and let
me be very specific I'm not talking
about the nudity and the craziness of
this I'm talking more about the sense of
community that existed among these guys
which doesn't exist now well first thing
if anybody tried to do this obviously
there'll be you know videoed and put
online but besides that I have never in
my many years in University seen a whole
dorm come together to do anything unless
it's University mandated most of the
time guys don't even know other guys on
their same floor they'll only know their
roommate because they have to and
there's no sense of fraternity and
co-mingling friendships forming across a
group of 100 guys I've never seen that
the maximum friend circle of guys I've
seen is like three four fraternities are
different of course the fraternities are
essentially 100 dies hopefully you know
living together and well that's a
different most people most guys don't
join fraternities and another
interesting story was the fights
apparently back in the day the Freshman
Class sophomore class would literally
fight like the whole class of course the
University was a smaller place back then
but it must have been at least a couple
hundred guys maybe like 200 guys
everybody would meet at this water tower
that we have they would just go at it
like complete brawling like whole mosh
biting it out and the reason was so
usually the sophomores would kind of
pick on the freshmen but if they could
win the respect of their Elders then the
bullying would stop and that's why they
would do these fights it's also another
reason to weed out the week if you
didn't show up for the fight for your
class you know represent your class and
fight for your class then you would
immediately be singled out as the guy
who didn't show up for the fight and
then you would be bullied by your own
class now this all seems very crass it
almost seems as though it's a good thing
we left these things behind I strongly
disagree fighting especially as a part
of a tribal unit like your class a
university class even there's something
important that we've lost when all these
Traditions fell away we know with the
Advent of more administrative pressure
and also the Advent of the smartphone
it's hard to put my finger on it but I
think you feel the Nostalgia that I do
it would be fun wouldn't it to just go
with all your boys and fight this other
huge group of guys and then maybe you
come back to your dorms kind of bruised
but proud that you did what you did I
missed that even though I haven't
experienced that in college strange
strange feeling but now the question
becomes Well you aren't going to get rid
of smartphones anytime soon like
smartphones are not going anywhere so
what do you do you are never going to
see a panty raid you're likely never
going to see a whole on war between
classes you're never going to see you
know any of these things which our
father's generation got to see however
we can still reclaim some of that
spontaneity spontaneity how do you say
the word and love for life that these
gentlemen had By ignoring the fact that
yes you could get recorded doing
something something stupid but you do
something stupid anyway just for the
hell of it why not not for tick tock not
for the cloud but just for the hell of
it Ah that's something I'm gonna have to
work on myself I'll post you an update
once I get there