making decisions in life is hard most
people are indecisive and they're filled
with self-doubt if we are able to make
decisions with confidence and follow
through with conviction then this gives
us an asymmetric advantage over the rest
of society people suck at
decision-making because they're taught
that logic and reason always lead to the
correct choice but here's the reality
that most people never realize
rationality just leads to
rationalizations half the time we've
already made up the decision in our
minds and we're just using logic to
justify it this is stupid this is stupid
because you're not getting the benefits
of cold hard logic nor are you embracing
the power of human intuition you're
losing on on both sides in this video
I'm going to show you how to make better
choices because we all have choices to
make should you start a business should
you stay in school should you ask her on
a date or wait till you do more looks
maxing or should you quit your job now
should you wait till you have more
savings there's so many decisions each
decision has pros and cons in real life
there are no Solutions there's only
trade-offs and even if you make the
perfect decision after making this full
pros and cons list the outcome is often
outside your control on top of this if
you avoid making decisions you lose
because others will make that decision
for you and if you constantly doubt your
decision you still lose because
circumstances will make the decision for
you so you have to make decisions and
you have to have the confidence that
it'll work out in the end so what do we
do no human has perfect knowledge no no
human can predict the future and all
humans have limited time on this Earth
how do we stop having regrets at what
could have been how do we stop wasting
years of our life on stuff that doesn't
really matter I'm going to give you a
tool that's helped me make decisions
quickly that leave me with zero regret
this tool has given me the peace of mind
to see a decision through to its
conclusion and not have regret even if
the outcome isn't exactly what I
expected it to be this tool is called
the eudemonic compass here I must
confess that it took me a decade to find
my identity my ethos and what I wanted
to do for a living I don't want you to
go through the same unnecessary
sacrifices and avoidable pains I jumped
around a lot in life I went to one of
the top American engineering colleges
and at the end I felt crushing
depression because I never really cared
about thermodynamics or turbulent flow I
did it because my parents vision for me
until going to engineering school then I
joined the PHD program in biosciences
because it would give me a very fine
road towards success it give me Prestige
among my peers to have a PhD then I quit
and I joined the army hoping to get as
far from Academia and the traditional
career path as possible luckily this was
the start of my self-mastery journey
because I was able to dedicate eight
months of my life to physical effort in
the form of getting smoked every day and
the mental effort of writing and
thinking oh I should show you so there's
three journals right here I don't know
if you can see it I don't know if it's
within frame but these three journals
are completely full every single line is
filled by my thoughts and inpections
that I wrote down during basic training
and to this day these journals provide
insights that I use to make videos I
used to carry these journals everywhere
I used to go during training I used to
carry them to the M4 range during Rock
marches wherever I went one of these
journals came with me whenever there was
downtime I'd be riding so many guys
would be asking me you know what are you
writing in there well one of the things
I was writing was my problems in life
basically I was doing a self-analysis
one of my problems in life I
triangulated was that I wasn't able to
make or stick to decisions when I was a
kid I was decisive I was curious I was
driven I was Fearless but with time the
education system just ground me into the
dirt and shaped me into the Cog they
wanted me to be there are all these
pressures man what would my parents
think how would I make money how would
it look on the resume May what would
girls think all this [ __ ] without
asking the main question of what would
future me think would I be proud of my
past decisions or would I feel guilty it
was then that I created this tool this
emonic compass that has never failed me
there are two types of situations in
life situations that are within your
control and situations which are outside
your control I'm going to give you a
prayer that I like give me the courage
to control that which I can give me the
stoicism to accept that which I cannot
give me the wisdom to tell the
difference in some cases we don't have
control the death of a loved one famine
disease all these things right but in
most things we do have control over our
destiny and when we make choices it
matters luckily we have deep intuitions
within us to help us make decisions I
used to think that good decisions are
made with cold logic and brutal
reasoning now I have more trust in my
intuition now I'm going to teach you
exactly how to develop that this does
not mean I just do whatever I feel like
doing there's a structure to this most
modern people make decisions based on
perceived pleasure humans are actually
terrible at predicting how much pleasure
and action will give them we've all felt
the pull of Temptation we've all yielded
to the pull of Temptation there's no
need for me to give examples because
every one of us has yielded to the
weakness of the flesh at some point but
in the aftermath the pleasure is nowhere
to be found replaced by emptiness the
pleasure never lasts and our prediction
about how much pleasure we're going to
get is always a miscalculation so what
have we stopped using pleasure as the
North Star what have we got off the
honic treadmill the honic treadmill is
when you continue to walk and walk and
never really get anywhere because the
pleasures start fading away and you keep
walking forward seeking for more
Pleasures which in turn Fade Away there
is a better way we can use this emonic
Compass UD demonic is the opposite of
hedonic emonic is pursuing happiness
through actions that give you a sense of
Pride and accomplishment rather than
pleasure Pride Stacks pleasure decays
and that's the chief difference between
the two a good gym session brings you
pride pride and accomplishment but in
the same gym session if you slacked off
and you knew you could have gone harder
you bring a sense of guilt if you
prepare a highly testosterone's meal of
lamb and carrots you feel Pride but if
you Chow Down some seed oil slop then
you will feel guilt if you resist
watching porn you will feel Pride if you
fall to weakness you'll feel guilt
humans are good at predicting Pride but
they're amazing at predicting guilt
whenever you're making a complex
decision or you're in a new situation
you can predict which decision will
leave you with a sense of guilt seeking
pleasure is always an unreliable North
Star but avoiding guilt will not lead
you astray I spoke about Pride but isn't
Pride bad I don't think so is it wrong
to work for years to have a phys that
you're proud of is it wrong for your
parents to be proud of you when you
finally retire them when you have kids
and they grow into strong independent
men and women with their own missions
would it be wrong to feel pride in their
achievements would it be wrong to have
pride in a job well done a day's honest
labor Victory won by the strength of
your hand of course not from all this
and more we know that Pride as such is
not bad yet the ancient texts warn us of
Pride but if you read deeper these texts
aren't talking about the type of Pride
that I described they're talking about
hubris or egotism that's when you think
you're Flawless and perfect that's when
you have pride without gratitude for
example there's nothing wrong with
having pride in an aesthetic physique
however when the ego gets too attach to
the physique then you're setting up
yourself for failure Chris Williamson
talks about this with Tim Ferris how
Chris even though he's an amazing shape
he started to see the signs of aging at
some point he's not going to get better
physically he's going to start slowing
down Chris talks about how if all his
ego is invested into his physique he'd
be going into depression you can see
egotism when influencers Turn On Their
audience when they start losing traction
you can see hubris when corrupt
politicians thinks that they deserve
power or when Bankers leverage
everything for more returns egotism is
when a businessman has no gratitude
towards his employees his customers or
his advisers I think you can see the
difference from having a healthy level
of pride in oneself versus being
hubristic or egotistical I think the
word pride is confusing because it's
changed meaning over the years and this
happens all the time happens in all
languages Jordan Peterson actually gives
an example of the word meek there's a
famous phrase the meek shall inherit the
earth in today's English Meek means
submissive but in older times actually
the word meant being peaceful until
provoked so don't get stuck on the
language language is just a tool of
communication and it's not perfect focus
on the terrain not the map focus on the
concepts rather than the exact words
that I'm using when I'm talking about
pride in this video I'm obviously
talking about Good Pride not hubris not
arrogance not egotism now let's discuss
how to use this y demonic Compass when
you're confronted with a fork in the
road you often know which road will lead
to guilt and which one leads to Pride
even in a complicated situation where
you don't know what the outcome will be
you can ask yourself the question which
option leads to Pride and which one is
going to give me guilt literally cannot
make a bad decision if you do this
instead of asking how much money will I
make or how much Prestige will I get or
what will my parents think what will the
girls think what would the resume look
like ask yourself would I feel good
about this in the future the interesting
thing is even if you have a less than
optimal outcome you won't feel guilty
because that was the best decision you
could have made given your current
knowledge if you focus on stacking pride
and reducing the level of guilt then you
win in the long term in fact you win in
the short term as well as the longterm
I'll explain the exact mechanism why
that's the case if you follow this
principle of Pride stacking even over a
week it will change your self-perception
in some sense you're winning your own
respect and you should start small every
day we have small choices to make should
you wake up and step out into the Sun or
should stay scrolling on your phone on
your bed should you go for a walk
outside or play video games should you
call your parents should you study for
your exams should you be honest should
you lie if you make the the choice based
on which road leads to Pride and
accomplishment then you're winning your
own respect when I was making the
decision to show my face on camera and
stand by my beliefs I earned my respect
by doing what I believed was right when
I quit the biosciences PHD program
despite working so hard to get in I won
my respect by willing to bet on myself
when I defeated my addictions I won my
respect by proving to myself that I am a
man who keeps his promises when I got
through the Infantry Warfare school I
won my respect by proving that I had
what it took this Pride stacking concept
has changed the way I see decision-
making it's no longer a matter of pros
and cons and Min maxing it's no longer a
matter of just optimization it's a
matter of building my psyche that's what
every single decision point in life is
it's not the actual outcomes which stack
it's how you build your psyche because
every time your psyche is built and
becomes more antifragile becomes
stronger your strength of character has
improved you'll just have a higher and
higher chance of making the right call
in the next decision that you make
that's how you really stack success
that's what I've recently learned it's
not like I'm some wise old guy who's
lived you know 30 years doing this this
is something I learned in the last few
years it served me well and so I'm
communicating this with you you're
teaching your subconscious that you are
a person worthy of your own trust and
respect they say that you can't force or
buy respect and that's true and
certainly it is true when you're talking
about self-respect you can only earn
respect and especially self-respect
because there can be no deception or
trickery you know all your dirty secrets
you know when you fail you know when you
lie to yourself you cannot trick the
subconscious it's always looking at you
and there is no shortcut to be had when
you choose the guilty option versus
Pride you're chipping away at your
psyche eventually you'll have a
fragmented psyche this is the kind of
psyche that most modern people have
people have a disconnect between what
they think they should do and what they
actually do this gap between what you
think should be done and what you
actually do is the source of pain I
found that as I shrink this Gap nice and
slowly every year I've been just more
content with the person that I am the
things that I'm doing I'm making better
decisions and that's translating in all
kinds of success relationships money
everything most people don't know this
but the most valuable asset you have is
your character nobody's talking about
how to train the character and what I'm
describing so far is really Progressive
overload for your psyche people go to
the gym to get big they go to college to
appear smart but size and intelligence
don't correlate with making better
decisions the strength of character is
the only thing that correlates with
better decision-making and sadly this is
the metric on which the modern society
fails this is the metric which I want to
strengthen because at the end of the day
character is Destiny not genetics not
height not education not IQ character is
Destiny above all else if you don't
train your psyche when you are young and
you have less responsibility then when
you grow older and you have really big
decisions later in life having kids
getting married buying a house selling
your business starting a business
whatever right then you're going to be
unprepared another reason to use the ud
demonic Compass over the honic treadmill
is that it forces morality and morality
is a strategic advantage in the long run
should you cheat on your exam or just
take the L should you lie on your resume
to get the job should you mislead your
business partner should you exaggerate
your products to get more sales the
dishonest answer will give you better
results in the short term but You' be
teaching your subconscious that you are
fundamentally dishonest if your
subconscious cannot trust you then it
will sabotage you no man can feel pride
and dishonesty only guilt by making
decisions to minimize long-term guilt
you're actually maximizing long-term
profit and you're doing this by building
a reputation of honesty and quality that
others can see but also your own
subconscious can see this y demonic
compass works great when you're making
strategic decisions my third ever
YouTube video got 400,000 views in just
3 weeks absolute Black Swan event
unpredictable right completely
unpredictable that's what Black Swan
events are they can be life-changing but
not repeatable so I had to make a choice
I had a good job at the time I was doing
well I landed an engineering job with a
startup that made food preservation
systems it is fairly meaningful worked I
enjoyed it to some extent I had decent
freedom I had a good paycheck and I was
on track to even gain equity in the
company my parents were happy I was
making similar money to other
engineering friends I was on track man I
was finally on track after so many
different trials and testing and doing
different things on one hand I had the
safety of the job which I understood on
the other hand YouTube is fickle yes I
had one video take off but that's not a
guarantee of income I had to make a
decision and the decision boiled down to
B basically the tides of Fortune had
handed me this prize in the form of this
video just randomly taking off if I
didn't grab this opportunity I would
feel guilty forever because my dream was
always to be a creative businessman not
an engineer if I commit to
entrepreneurship and take a chance of
myself then I would feel Pride
regardless of the outcome on the other
hand if I chose the path of safety
despite the opportunity falling into my
lap then I would feel guilt forever
framing it like that it became a less
hard dis I choose the thing that made me
feel self accomplishment and pride and
don't choose a thing that I knew would
make me feel guilty Forever by the way
if you're in a position in life where
you're trying to strategize and look
towards the future trying to make
decisions or if you're trying to do
Health optimization especially hormonal
and testosterone optimization I've
recently opened up one-on-one coaching
very temporary you should look in the
description for the scheduling link and
also I should say this is actually part
two of a two-part series part one
discusses Chad flation how competition
is speeding up and what you can do about
it you should watch that video to
complete your knowledge and closing out
I want to tell you one thing if you
remember nothing else from this video I
want you to remember this one sentence
we all make choices but in the end our
choices make us