this bottle of raw milk says on it right
here not for human consumption it
literally says on here for intermittent
feed used only for dogs and cats but
I've been drinking this for more than a
year I will tell you the story of raw
milk it's god tier benefits for hormonal
function as well as gut health I'll
expose the demonization of raw milk by
governmental organizations and a certain
Mega Corporation by the name of Monsanto
I'll give you my personal experience
teach you where to find the stuff I'll
also clear up the whole controversy
between A1 and A2 milk I'll give you the
full milk tier list and tell you exactly
which milks you should consider and
which ones you should
reject that being said everything in
this video is my own personal views and
my experience this is not medical advice
see most people don't know this but
drinking raw milk isn't even that risky
if you actually run the numbers and look
at how many people have actually died or
gotten sick due to raw milk versus other
Foods in general raw milk doesn't really
stand out as a massive public health
hazard at all I mean think about lettuce
every every now and then you always hear
this headline people died or got sick
because of an outbreak of eoli in
lettuce in like Chipotle or something
but there's no movement for Banning
lettuce and yet in many states it's a
felony to sell raw milk the Industrial
Revolution and its consequences have
been a disaster for the human race and
definitely for cows as industrial plants
grew and more people moved towards
cities and got clustered in these
claustrophobic cities they brought their
C with them and these cows they were
living under horrible torturous
conditions and to be fair the humans
themselves were living in very bad
conditions so I understand it but these
cows were ridden with parasites which is
a separate topic they were living with
their own feces they were living in
extremely stressed environments and so
they were imuno compromised and when
they produced milk yeah this milk was
not good for people got them sick and of
course the Industrial Revolution is
always there for the rescue the
technique of pasteurization which is
nothing more than just heating the milk
basically kills the milk it kills the
milk milk is supposed to be a living
food milk has living organisms in it
which actually aid in digestion and gut
health it has enzymes in it which
actually help you to digest the milk so
when you pasteurize it you lose the
enzymes you lose the living microbes you
just have this dead liquid which is
chemically the same as raw milk but
biologically
different So speaking of pasteurization
I said that pasteurization entally kills
the milk and this is exactly why a lot
of people who are lactose intolerant
those who cannot buy and drink the
store-bought milk they actually fine
drinking raw milk this is because raw
milk actually is easier to digest
because the bacteria in there and the
enzymes in there actually make the body
more able to actually digest the milk I
suppose it goes without saying that raw
milk is a probiotic it helps the gut
microbiome and here's what happened in
the grand scheme so big farms which
could afford the pasturization equipment
they would pump out huge volumes of milk
and because they had increased the shelf
life through pasteurization they could
drive down the cost and they could
therefore outcompete all the small farms
which are making an honest day living by
giving you raw milk and so today we end
up in a situation where to buy raw milk
can be challenging luckily I have a
solution for you I'll teach you exactly
where to get raw milk without any milk
but of course the bigger problem is the
artificial hormone issue the RBST issue
so a lot of countries have banned RBST
but not the us though so what happened
here is there's a genetics company
called Genentech and they created this
artificial hormone called RBST and
eventually Monsanto came to own the like
the IP the intellectual property for
creating that stuff and just understand
the understand this properly so they
take the cows they inject them with this
artificial hormone which causes them to
lactate more and therefore produce more
milk what this does to the cows is truly
inhumane it causes the cows mamory
glands their breast tissue to come over
tax and diseased these cows have a
higher chance of going lame these cows
also have a weakened immune system which
now means that you have to pump these
cows full of antibiotics to keep them
alive and this apparently is the more
healthy option as compared to raw milk
and despite all this the FDA says that
milk with and without RBST are the same
thing and of course I haven't even
touched on the topic of xenoestrogens it
should be pretty obvious that the
artificial hormone which literally
causes cow to lactate more is a
xenoestrogen xenoestrogen are basically
estrogen like compounds which will cause
a man to get more feminine trait and
it's certainly not good for females
either because it essentially out
competes with natural female estrogen
and causes serious harm to the female
reproductive system as well so it's no
joke and certainly not the only Hazard
here so grain-fed cows get understand
this so grain is already a problem
because grain gets moldy and mold
contains something called Zea which is a
xenoestrogen that's certainly a problem
on itself but there's even more to it
when cows eat grain instead of grass
they're rumin so the rumin is a part of
the cow's digestive tract it becomes
more acidic than it's supposed to and
what that means is the eoli which might
be present in that digestive tract
evolve to become acid resistant why is
that a problem for you it's because your
digestive system the digestive system of
humans is a pretty remarkable piece of
equipment our digestive acids can
destroy ecoli most of the time but if
you feed cows with grain and the ecoli
in their gut becomes acid resistant now
that ecoli when enters your gut is still
acid resistant and this is the stuff
that can actually make you sick so
that's why I get my milk from grass-fed
cows producing raw milk there was a farm
in Maine which wanted to put on their
milk bottles a label which said we don't
use artificial hormones and Monsanto
came for them with their entire Army of
Gremlin verminous lawyers because they
said that if that farm in in Maine said
that their milk was free from RBST they
were implying buying that milk that does
have rbsd is inferior that is to say
monsanto's so-called milk was inferior
which it is and they actually took that
farm to court and that farm was forced
to have a disclaimer on their label
saying that the FDA does not see a
difference between milk with RBST and
milk without RBST how twisted is that a
farm doesn't even have the Liberty to
say that they don't use artificial
hormones that's how twisted the system
behind this is because of how much money
is involved when that FDA tells me that
the very same kind of milk which my
ancestors have been drinking for
hundreds of thousands of years is
actually the enemy and their Factory
farmed ultr processed dairy product
which barely is milk is the safer option
I find myself rejecting them in a world
where the government legalizes alcohol
and weed and prohibits the sale of raw
milk to Consumers and when the CDC
recognizes raw milk to be a public
health hazard I have have very little
patience so now the question becomes is
it worth it and the answer is definitely
yes definitely been worth it for me for
two reasons specifically one is the
joint health reason so raw milk contains
something called bolsen factor which
basically helps heal and improve joint
health this was personally important to
me because almost a year ago I took an
injury to the right elbow and left knee
which really put me out of the gym and I
only now slowly getting back into it and
then finally we have of course the gut
microbiome benefits which are the
easiest to understand this stuff
literally contains live bacteria which
is why I will not leave this on the
table for very long I'll keep it in the
fridge as soon as this video is done and
finally we come to the actionable steps
I'm going to break down exactly how
where and when to consume this milk
right so the easiest way to get milk
like how how I get it is from local
grocery market so just literally search
on Google organic grocery near me and
you'll often find one I lived in the
small little town in Indiana for what 6
years now and only 2 years ago did I
realize there was a small cute little
organic grocery store literally 10
minutes away from where I live so if you
don't search for it you're not going to
find it I'll link in the description
below to a website which you'll find
local farms near you it's called
realmilk.com and it will link you to the
nearest farm which produces raw
milk A1 versus A2 milk what's that
entire controversy about all right I'll
make it super simple for you I'm not
trying to waste your time A2 milk is
good A1 milk is bad so it all comes down
to the breed of cow which produces it
and the protein structure in the milk
itself so when A1 milk is digested it
can break down in some people into
something called bcm7 which is an
inflammatory substance and not only that
it even seems to have an effect on
opioid receptors yes weird stuff now not
everybody reacts the same way for you it
may not matter for me I just want to
keep it safe A2 is more digestible so
I'm just going to go for A2 if I have a
choice if you're getting raw milk from a
farm you can actually ask them what
breed of cow they use and you can just
Google it and find out what kind of milk
they produce in the US it's mainly two
breeds Holstein and Jersey cows Jersey
cows produce A2 Holstein cows produce A1
so you want to look for Jersey cows if
you can find them and finally we must
discuss chocolate milk chocolate milk as
you know comes from brown cows and is
known to increase testosterone by 69.6
n% but for real though so um Brown milk
actually contains a lot of CLA which is
conjugated lolic acid which does
actually improve
testosterone and I have some good news
so the tide is turning and I see this in
real life so one year ago when I started
purchasing raw milk from their little
grocery store I mentioned they would
often just run out of raw milk because
so many people were coming and grabbing
them which tells me there's a demand
growing for this stuff and there's an
awareness growing about raw milk and
what happened was nowadays they don't
run out of milk because the farm which
produces it had enough money enough
resources to purchase more cows so it's
happening right now boys so this
movement of moving towards Natural Foods
is happening right now and I want you to
capitalize on this I want you to create
businesses which literally produce
better stuff you don't have to invent
anything new Just Produce better stuff
more natural less toxic stuff and just
watch your business grow over the next 5
to 10 years companies which make real
authentic products are growing and
they're making money if you told people
that applying animal fat on your skin is
actually better than any product out
there in the drug stores and that you
don't need like a whole bunch of
products and you use one product they
probably look at you funny except that
companies like vintage tradition and
plenty others have been growing years
after year this is possible because of
this awareness which is growing
currently now is the time to create
products which are genuinely better than
the Legacy stuff because the market is
there the opportunity is there it's time
for you to get all into it I have a full
esoteric nutrition course which
literally breaks down everything you
need to know about hormonal Health
metabolic Health gut health and
everything you could possibly want to
know about nutrition so if you're
interested in that it's included for
free within my private Community the
links in the description
now I'm going to tell you which milks
are worth consuming on the top the king
we have of course raw milk not
pasteurized not homogenized and this can
be either cow milk or goat milk or shape
milk or camel milk if you can find that
that's the highly esoteric option if you
have freaking camel milk then good for
you man below that you have something
called low temperature pasteurized
non-homogenized this is something you'll
find in some grocery stores not all of
them but this is also a good option I
would 100% recommend that and I should
note that the both options I've
mentioned so far I assume that they
grass-fed grass finished then we start
moving on to the options which I don't
consume pasteurized ultra pasteurized
the stuff in the cartons so let me
explain this so milk that you find in
cartons in your grocery store that's not
just pasteurized that's ultra
pasteurized at that point I would
consider just to be another processed
food and I would dismiss it and then
even lower than that we have skim milks
you have the 2% 1% and skim milk at that
point like why why would you drink such
a thing that's barely even milk so yeah
that's an easy rejection section and
under that we have of course the nut
milks and soy milks why would anybody
drink something literally called nut
milk just based on the name alone I
would not consume such a thing of course
bottom of the barrel we have your soy
milk so really you don't even have that
many options and of course I should just
have a disclaimer saying none of this is
a dietary recommendation and if you
don't have access to this I would
suggest going and getting kefir instead
Keir is a um a fermented product and I
should say fermented products across the
board are really good one for the
microbiome benefits but also because
fermentation itself destroys estrogens
so you could find buttermilk yogurt
kefir all these are good options what
for
me so first I'm going to have to shake
this thing this is non-homogenized milk
which means that the cream will
basically float to the top so open this
up pour myself some raw milk purchased
literally just today so question how
does raw milk
taste raw milk tastes Rich it tastes
velvety it tastes a little bit sweet too
because the this is the first day right
this is literally the first day I got it
so it contains a lot of the sugar still
in there so it tastes wonderful and it
even has a little chunks of cream in it
which makes it even more delectable but
every day that passes the bacteria is
going to consume some of that sugar so
it will lose some of its sweetness which
is fine it's still nutritious but I'm
just pointing that out because it's not
that your milk is going bad it's just
that some of the sugars been consumed
and raw milk will stay good for 7 days
so when should you drink this this this
is the ultimate post-workout snack
there's literally nothing which gets
better than this when it comes to
post-workout but of course like I'm not
your boss man you can drink this anytime
there's there's no like right time or
wrong time go go go go