you have to understand these companies
don't give a single thing about your
health so let me give you the straight
of actionable steps right now just buzz
it off note that you must have a shower
filter installed any YouTuber who wants
to talk about Hair Care without talking
about diet doesn't know what the hell
he's talking about Vitamin D supplements
are mostly trash when I was in my early
20s my hair was oily and gross and my
scalp was dry and Flaky which makes no
sense until you look at what shampoo is
actually made of and how it works from a
chemical perspective and then you see
what Procter and Gamble actually
engineered you see shampoo is one fat
psyop it's a multi-million dollar
industry which gives you the problem in
the first place and then sells you the
Cure you believe that shampooing your
hair every day or every other day is
normal and healthy because that's what
your parents did and that's what all the
advertising says this is complete BS I
want you to understand what hair really
is I actually look at it from an
evolutionary perspective so look at the
human body we barely have any hair on
our body compared to most animals
but on our head our hair grows
indefinitely that's because our head
hair and in men facial hair is an
indicator of health so if you're having
hair problems whether it's hair loss or
dry scalp Etc you don't solve this by
buying the next latest and greatest
product you have to look a little bit
deeper because hair quality and quantity
is an indicator of Health it's a signal
for attractiveness and mate Choice which
is the fancy biological way of saying
good hair makes you attractive to women
and of course other way also we find
women extremely attractive and they have
good healthy hair the science and my
instincts are in perfect alignment if
you ever run your fingers through a
woman's hair and it's full and it's
healthy and it smells nice that's
insanely attractive not because the hair
itself is healthy but because hair is an
indication of overall health and
fertility and of course in men a nice
full beard is an indicator of sexual
health an extreme virility I wish I
could grow with my beard but of course
the Army regulations prevent it if you
have a dog or a cat and you've noticed
that its fur is kind of patchy or if
it's shedding way more than normal you
don't try 10 different booze on it you
realize that the pet is stressed or sick
or there's something else wrong with it
and these changes in its fur are just an
indication we don't assume it's hair
fall is because of genetics and you
don't start using finasteride that is
the angle which I'm going to take I'm
going to teach you everything I know
most people don't know this but
shampooing every day is a modern
invention Procter and Gamble had a
massive massive advertising campaign in
the 1970s specifically targeting white
American women probably one of the most
impressionable demographics on the
planet and they fed upon their
insecurities and made them feel as
though their hair was gross and they
would lose their standing in the dating
Market if they didn't use Proctor and
Gamble's greatest products good looking
girl until you looked close dandruff you
have to understand these companies don't
give a single [ __ ] about your health so
looking at the statistics Americans wash
their hair five times a week the Spanish
and Italians washed their hair half of
that and I was just there I was in Spain
and Italy just a few days ago and they
have perfectly beautiful hair have you
ever seen a shampoo advertisement do you
know how they have that graphic going on
they show like a zoom Up 3D render of a
hair follicle and they have the shampoo
they're coming in and removing all the
impurities that's complete BS what's
really happening is the shampoo binds to
and removes fats from your scalp and
that causes your scalp to over produce
those oils which causes your hair to be
greasy and then you need more shampoo to
fix the problem and then they sell you a
conditioner to coat your hair in
silicone to make it look as though your
hair is actually nourished when it's
actually not so how did I realize the
shampoo and conditioner was BS well
actually I did a hard reset on my life a
hard reset so I was feeling very stalled
in life it's about a couple years ago
and of course there was a woman involved
who is no longer in my life I needed to
gain massive momentum so I developed a
hard reset protocol and I followed it
for a month and it worked amazingly but
for this video the important part was
one part of that protocol was to buzz my
hair out completely and I did and
because I didn't have a shampoo or
conditioner you know I didn't need
shampoo conditioner when you have buzzed
hair I didn't use it and by the way if
you want to know more about the hard
reset protocol let me know in the
comments I know my technique works
because usually when I go to the barber
and get a haircut my hair would fall
along with a whole bunch of flakes it
was super gross and I hated it but once
I got off shampoo and conditioner after
I buzzed my hair and used the natural
means to take care of my hair and then I
got my first haircut after the buzz
there was no flakes at all so I asked my
barber how my scalp looked it's
interesting because he says something
along the lines of okay it looks like
your shampoo is working I was like yeah
no it doesn't so note this like if you
have rings in your hair like rings of
flakes in your hair or your scalp rather
then that's not dandruff and that's not
dry skin that's some kind of an
infection and you need to see a actual
dermatologist and the quick thing about
hair loss so a lot of people think that
hair loss especially in men is caused by
testosterone this is not true just
having high testosterone doesn't mean
you're going to lose your hair that's
not a thing it's more complex than that
and an interesting thing is it's
actually stress which causes it and not
in the way that you think so stress
causes skin to be pulled taut over your
scalp so if you've ever seen a bald
person like a person who has lost their
hair you know how there's like scalp is
super shiny right that's because the
skin is pulled tight over their scalp
usually because of tightnesses in their
jaw caused by stress so if you're losing
your hair it could be because of stress
what you need to do is you need to give
yourself deep massages on your scalp and
you're not going to use your nails
you're going to use like the the pads of
your fingers you're going to put coconut
oil or olive oil and like really
properly massage your scalp and you're
going in an upward motion to kind of um
to give more slack basically improve
your skin quality along your scalp so
that you don't start losing follicles so
let me give you the straight of
actionable steps right now so if your
hair and skin up or in a bad condition
right now like really trash if your hair
is super oily or super dry if your scalp
is super oily or super dry and if you're
a young man just buzz it off
just take a trimmer or go to your Barber
and bust the whole thing off you have
nothing to lose and then you can start
fixing your body fixing your health
fixing your scalp Etc and when your hair
grows Anew it's going to be the best
hair you've had and if you don't want to
do that that's fine still follow the
rest of the protocol so you're going to
quit shampoo and conditioner cold turkey
right just stop using it hey boys so I'm
in the field a couple days oh but I had
to make this quick video so my editor
Jackie brought up an interesting point
which is once you stop using shampoo
what happens is your hair doesn't
magically get better it actually gets
worse it gets worse for the first two or
three weeks maybe even four weeks before
actually improving
so be aware of that so the way it works
is you know everybody needs sometimes to
reset from the
cycle that the shampoo has created oh
yeah so quick tip if you're out in the
field like you're gonna be using a lot
of energy and you're gonna be outdoors
honey highly energy dense highly
nutrition dense I literally had honey
for breakfast
it works you can absolutely and you
should use just water to wash your hair
so you can actually do this even every
day if you wanted to to move the water
around your scalp and give yourself a
scalp massage as you're getting water on
your scalp without using shampoo or
conditioner and that's going to remove
the dust and pollen and pollutants while
not removing the oils which are actually
required for nourishing your hair but
note that you must have a shower filter
installed this is a non-negotiable
unless you know for a fact that your
water quality is super high I guarantee
you if you live in any major city your
water quality is trash it's full of
hormones it's full of chlorine which is
going to be very damaging for your scalp
and you definitely need to install a
shower filter in order to filter it out
I'll link in the description to the one
which I use so you're free to use water
to rinse off any number of times a week
and probably once a week or maybe twice
a week if you're living a very congested
and polluted city you'll want to use a
non-toxic shampoo or what I use is
actually a olive soap so this thing is a
olive soap so it's made of olive oil
basically and it does the job of
removing the pollen and pollutants and
everything but it doesn't strip away the
oils but even then I just use it once a
week and I'll link to the description I
even have a discount code for this
actually I got the discount code way
back during my skincare video and the
same company which makes the skin care
products which is like Tallow bomb which
I use makes the soap so very trustable
company I know the guy who owns it if
you live in the US this is a good option
if you don't live in the US find any
small business in your country which
makes similar products that's the good
thing about living in 2023 is that we're
starting to see the glimmer of hope you
know you're starting to see companies we
just started just by normal people like
you and me who are simply sick and tired
of the mega corporations creating toxic
products which actually cause the
problem which they purport to solve and
instead start small businesses which
produce genuine good products I'm
telling you if you're an entrepreneur or
you want to start a small business this
is the time this is the perfect time you
see this is the gold rush you know
people are starting to realize that the
mainstream products are trash and
they're starting to adopt
non-traditional products if you start
your company right now and if you're
selling anything like literally soap
shampoo sunscreen so many products that
we use day to day are toxic so if you
are the guy to make non-toxic version
which is still effective and completely
safe your business is gonna grow
massively exponentially in the next 10
years so basically let me quickly
summarize the way you wash your hair is
you use just water every day or every
other day it doesn't matter and then
every once a week you're using non-toxic
shampoo that does exist they are
non-toxic shampoos out there or you use
in Olive soap like how I do and I'll
link in the description to the products
which I use or I approve of and after
washing your hair you're still going to
lose some of the oils so here's what you
can do this depends on your specific
needs I personally use a single drop of
olive oil I'll spread it along my palms
and then I'll just run it through my
hair you can also use coconut oil but
the problem with coconut oil is if you
live in a cold climate the coconut oil
is going to solidify and it's going to
be gross so olive oil is the way to go
for me and for some of you you may not
need any oil because your scalp already
produces enough so you have to kind of
experiment and find out what works for
you after you run oil through your hair
you use a wooden comb you have to use
wood you cannot use your plastic Combs
because otherwise you leech micro
Plastics into your scalp so you're going
to use a wooden comb it has these wooden
bristles and you'll run it through your
hair and this is going to kind of
stimulate the follicles it's going to
increase blood flow on your scalp very
good if you're having hair loss this is
a must and lastly don't use hot water
use lukewarm or body temperature water
and of course we're going to talk about
dandruff so most people don't have
dandruff most people have freaking dry
scalp which looks like dandruff but it's
not the same thing if you have genuinely
you have dandruff then yeah you might
need to see a medical professional but
most people have dry scalp which is
caused by shampoo like I said before so
do what I said and you'll most people
will solve their problems because most
people don't have dandruff but if you
still have problems you know after a
month of following this protocol then
yeah perhaps you do have actual skin
condition called dandruff and you can
actually go to a dermatologist any
YouTuber who wants to talk about Hair
Care without talking about diet doesn't
know what the hell he's talking about
like in the start of the video I said
that hair is an indicator of health so
if your gen newly unhealthy even if you
follow this protocol even if you buy the
most expensive products you are not
going to have good hair good hair starts
from genuine good health and I mean
hormonal health I mean physical health I
also mean mental health like I said
before stress has an effect on hair loss
so for diet I'm going to make it super
simple for you this is not a diet video
as such but I have to point it out
otherwise this video makes no sense so
first thing eat animal protein eggs red
meat white meat fish so long as it's
well sourced I'm talking about grass-fed
grass finish I'm talking about local
farms buying high quality meat high
quality eggs and your hair is going to
improve even if you continue to use [ __ ]
shampoo next thing is Omega fatty acids
right so Omega-3s omega-6s the problem
with this is because most of our water
is polluted most fish have microplastics
in them which means most cod liver oil
has microplastics and on top of that
Omega-3s and omega-6s are
polyunsaturated fatty acids which means
they're unstable and because they're
unstable if you don't know if the
company doesn't know how to store them
properly or doesn't care enough to store
them properly you're actually going to
be doing more harm by consuming these
supplements than not so most drugstore
or you know CVS brand Omega-3
supplements cod liver oil supplements
they are trash the only one which I
actually trust is a very interesting
product it's a blend of cod liver oil
and butter oil it's made by this company
called Green pasture and I trust them
because they work with vintage tradition
and I know that vintage tradition is
good so I'll link to that company in the
description next thing Vitamin D
supplements are mostly trash sunlight is
the absolute King and actually you may
not know this but vitamin D is not
exactly a vitamins more like a hormone
than a vitamin so looking at it from
that perspective your skin is the
largest endocrine organ in your body so
make sure you get your sunlight get sun
exposure on as much skin as possible
even on cloudy days this is what I'm
talking about this is going to improve
your Genuine Health like literally
genuinely you're going to be more
healthy person and that's going to
result in better hair and then hydration
hydration is key because it brings the
nutrients to the scalp in the first
place and hydration is not simply
drinking a lot of water there's a whole
science behind the electric lights and
the balances Etc in order to be hydrated
so what's my hydration guide to get
properly hydrated and then of course
sleep sleep is an absolute must sleep
also genuinely improves your health
which causes your hair to be better and
to optimize your sleep I have a whole
sleep optimization video so that's the
one you need to watch and also a few
other things which I should note if you
want to style your hair you can
absolutely use a good pomod the one
which I use is this really cheap one
actually it's pretty cheap and the
ingredients are top quality it's a
Seattle Pro Mod company Pomade pomod I'm
not really sure this one's on Amazon so
it's pretty easy to get I'll link it in
the description so you see how
government and corporations can use
their knowledge of biology and
psychology to poison you to poison you
mentally physically and spiritually I
seek to give you the very knowledge
which they use to make sure that the
battlefield is even I would like you to
hit the share button and if you want to
share this video with somebody great but
even if you don't want to do that just
hit the share button that's going to
give this video the moment intimate
needs to promote our way of thinking if
you really want to get involved my
private Society the country club will be
opening its gates in August