well if you buy your milk in the grocery
store and you get one of these
things these boys these bad boys then
yes absolutely your milk is estrogenic
so get this there's actually three
different kinds of estrogens in this one
carton of
milk so first the cows which make this
milk are fed with soy and grain cuz it
doesn't say grass-fed so that means it's
being fed with soy which of course you
know has
phytoestrogens which have estrogenic
effects then it's also fed with grain
and usually the lowest quality moldy ass
grain and this contains fungus and
fungus produces a toxin called zaa which
is an estrogenic so phytoestrogens plus
zaa already two then it's in this kind
of compressible plastic which means that
it contains BPA and if it's B B free
which doesn't even say BPA free so it
probably just has straight up BPA and if
it said BPA free I would think that it
has BPS or BPF so three different kinds
of estrogens just in this carton of milk
so what's the truth then what should
what should you do well the truth is
both more
terrible and more hopeful because if you
just go down the aisle and you pick up
one of
these this is
some high quality milk in a glass bottle
so this is the one which I would choose
and I do choose
cuz it's in a glass bottle so it doesn't
have the uh BPA and I know it's
grass-fed grass finished high quality
milk so I'm happy to drink it every day
and the thing is I um actually have an
eggnog recipe which calls for milk I
have the esoteric eggnog Elixir and you
should absolutely check it out because
it's combination of egg and milk and
cream high in fat perfect for boosting
testosterone and counteracting some of
the effect of this estrogenic stuff in
our diet another thing I should say is
um if you drink skim milk what are you
doing bro like you shouldn't be drinking
skim milk skim milk is a scam 2% milk is
a scam 1% milk is a scam they literally
take out the best most nutritious part
of the milk and substitute it with
fillers and they sell it for the same
price it's like why do you drink that if
you're going to buy milk buy whole milk
buy it in a glass bottle if possible
grass-fed grass finished and you should
be good
[Music]
he