when I asked you are you waiting for
life to start 70% said yes so you are
not alone I went to one of the best
engineering colleges in the United
States it has an awesome history during
the Industrial boom of America and even
during the second world war the United
States was an industrial giant it is a
machine of such size and power that not
even the proud German engineering could
withstand her output
my University produced some of the
finest engineering men of the century
literally like Neil Armstrong but when I
graduated I didn't feel like I was on
their level I didn't feel empowered to
make decisions I felt like I had to ask
for permission to do things I felt
untested I felt that there was something
I was missing I knew in my bones that I
had skipped some important and vital
step when you complete your degree you
get a paper but that does not transform
you into a man over the next few years I
had to join the Army build and fail at
business travel across the world
experience love and loss to eventually
have a sense of grounded maturity I have
a sense of self- knowledge now it took
me a decade of trial and error to figure
these things out I'm going to show you
how I'm going to show you how not to be
a child stuck in an adult's body the
grotesque thing about the modern age is
that there's no Frameworks to understand
when you achieve manhood what are the
exact steps you need to take the
transition from a child to an adult from
a boy to a man nobody knows least of all
your Boomer parents a lot of
self-improvement guys think that culture
has started to Decay because of Tik Tok
or porn but that's not true the decline
really started with the first world war
this terrible dis genic War cost mankind
some of its best men then of course the
second world war happened which made the
first one look like a rehearsal every
country fed its best men into the meat
grinder the best men died in
dishonorable battle mow down like grass
slaughtered like cattle in fact the best
men were the first to die as they queued
up to get enlisted it was in the fires
of that war that the world lost its
traditions and its religions it is from
this Unholy fire that the Modern Age of
the neoliberal order was born we've
destroyed our cultures so we default to
the image that social media feeds us
it's fairly obvious to you and me that
the social media image is fake it's a
bunch of Lies but it's not just because
the influencers themselves lie it's also
because the algorithms push the image of
a freakish super minority now this is
not another video about how social media
is bad I'm bored of such milk toast
opinions and my message is quite
different none of this is to say that
teenagers are silly or wrong to feel
behind on life in ancient cultures there
was a set point at which Boyhood ends
and manhood starts the Spartans famously
had the ritual of sending out their
agogi graduates into the wild with a
blanket and a spear only when they
returned if they returned would they be
initiated into the homoo as a
full-blooded spartiate the Messiah of
Kenya to this day need to kill a lion
with a spear to prove their Ascension to
full manhood only then do they get their
full adult name or lion name here's a
key idea that I need to explain with
more clarity many YouTubers will
emphasize this masculinity and danger
aspects of these rituals but they missed
the point these rituals aren't just
about bravery they're also a reflection
of the competence needed to excel in
their particular culture depending on
their specific threats the Spartans
needed to know how to survive in the
brutal conditions of their Homeland the
Messi needed to know how to gain Mastery
over the beasts of Africa it wasn't just
a matter of showing that you had balls
it was a matter of showing that you had
balls and also the brains not just to
survive but actually win here's a
different but highly similar example
Roman teenagers of patrician class would
be sent abroad on missions of State his
father we usually send him with a
trusted adviser or a slave this is
different from hunting lions or
surviving the hinterland of Sparta but
it made perfect sense for a young Roman
man it isn't just a matter of showing
bravery like I said it's a matter of
practical training it's a matter of
initiation not as a matter of tradition
but a matter of Education these
initiation rituals are a culmination
exercise a Capstone project at the end
of an educational series of steps if you
are a Roman Patrician you needed to know
how to would handle diplomacy and
politics you'd be tutored over years to
what that looked like and then be put to
the final test Spartan youth would have
done plenty of wilderness training under
supervision before they were sent out
alone the Messiah youth would have
hunted small prey Antelope and gazelle
before actually facing off against a
lion today this progression and this
initiation ritual is impossible because
we have no consensus and what competence
looks like or how to excel in society
since we have no initiation rituals
teenagers must find their own way to
demarcate the end of childhood and the
beginning of full adulthood without any
guidance they have to look towards what
activities adults can do but children
cannot do there's three categories of
this the first is the legally prohibited
activities like underage drinking or
drug use the second is biological
activity sex or if you don't have sex
then you have to settle for porn the
second is Adventure when you don't have
Adventure you settle for video games in
a video game you have initiation rituals
built in you have a tutorial that shows
you the ropes you have the boss fights
that test your expertise you have an
epic vision and a meaningful story you
need to travel long distances to explore
and do side quests to get rewards
sometimes it feels like video games are
more lifelike than real life and so the
modern initiation ritual is just a
selection of alcohol drugs casual sex
porn and video games this drive for a
teenager to prove their Worth to their
tribe is a force of primordial power the
ambition of Youth is the fire that
forges the steel girders of civilization
the wall that defends the tribe and the
spear that strikes out into the enemy it
is the Vitality of Youth that builds
Empires and indeed burns them down our
Modern Age under the rule of Leviathan
conspired to smother that fire under
paranoia Neurosis addictions and anxiety
and on top of this you have the
pharmaceutical intervention in the form
of anti-depressants and the
psychological neutering in these school
systems nothing makes my blood boil the
way the modern society squanders its
youth the drive towards sex and intimacy
is turned towards dating apps and
pornography youth is for adventure
exploration and to experience love of
women for the first time is for
friendships is for daring decisions and
the honing of one's innate talents even
in olden times when travel was perilous
the aristocratic youth would be sent
overseas for mentorship Julius Caesar
was on such a trip when he got captured
by Pirates now this story boys is one
for the ages Caesar was about 20 or so
when he was on a small ship to the
island of rhs and while Caesar was on
this journey some corsac Pirates had the
great Misfortune of boarding and
capturing the small ship Caesar was
captured and held for ransom by these
Pirates and when he learned that the
Pirates were going to demand 20 talents
for his release he laughed and told them
that he was worth at least 50 imagine
the attitude of this man at such a young
age he was so sure of his worth that he
negotiated his Ransom up not down even
as a captive he would not act like a
prisoner he would play music he would
sing songs write poetry and basically he
treated the whole thing like a little
vacation he'd even practice speeches to
his pirates in fact that's why he was
going to roads in the first place he
wanted to be mentored by the finest
orators of the globe he knew the power
of speech he knew that that was more
powerful than any Shield or spear he was
utterly Carefree in captivity I want to
drive this point home because it is
important we moderns stress out and have
anxiety because our grades are low on an
exam or some chick said that she wasn't
interested this level of anxiety and
doubt is gay a captive man Caesar had
more life force than we do in the
comfort of our homes I think of how much
delusional Faith Caesar had in his
future and see if I can emulate even 1%
of his Aura but get this when Caesar was
eventually freed his story did not in
there he came back Caesar rallied troops
at that young age at the Port of militus
and went after the Pirates he found them
on the same island on which he was held
captive and he captured them in turn and
this is where the story turns red the
governor of Asia Minor actually wanted
to punish the Pirates but didn't want to
necessarily kill them but Caesar had
other plans he didn't just kill them he
crucified them Caesar was obviously no
ordinary man that's for sure I think the
older and wiser Caesar wouldn't have
done this I think he was young and
bloodthirsty in a different Universe if
Caesar hadn't gained political power in
Rome he would have joined the Pirates
and become the king of pirates Caesar as
the king of the Mediterranean now that
would be a fanfiction I'd be interested
in writing myself but here's the key
Point even Caesar needed mentors he
looked up to Gus Marius his uncle and he
was mentored by crus and pompy ancient
societies had mentors that would help
craft the psyche of the Next Generation
to pass the T of Illumination when the
time is right what mentors have we in
this most banal of Ages which fat unread
Boomer would be a mentor to us the Youth
of our age is withering away the youth
are the future of society and the future
looks anxious depressed neurotic
medicated and spiritually burnt out the
youth is wasted in video games porn
casual sex alcohol and also needless and
unnecessary schoolwork which I think is
the worst of all these some young men
will waste their time playing video
games and others will waste it studying
calculus because their idiots School
bored or their ignorant parents made
them it's all the same in the end at
least video games are fun but here's the
real kicker even in modern times we did
have rights of Passage we had mentorship
and we had initiation rituals just as
little as 20 years ago we had it all the
Boy Scouts were this institution young
boys would learned the basics of
survival skills appreciation of nature
through the identification of plant and
the identific ific ation of animal
tracks they'd have mentors who are
long-term outdoorsmen who teach these
skills and impart wisdom to the Young
Generation the Boy Scouts had a mission
they would serve nature and they would
serve Society they had uniforms they had
a clear competent progression through
the earning of badges this is the modern
equivalent of an initiation ritual but
they killed the scouts man this
particular act by the Leviathan boils my
blood more than most the infiltration
and the overturning of the scouts was a
devastating low to our society many
great men came from the Boy Scouts Neil
Armstrong actually came from the Scouts
in fact I was in the same fraternity as
Neil Armstrong was when he was in
college the story of The Fall of the Boy
Scouts is a sad story first they made
the Boy Scouts no longer Fun For Boys by
banning all the activities that young
boys actually enjoyed they banned water
gunfights they banned dodgeball banned
mechanical bulls all the fun stuff that
guys actually want to do when they're
young and then of course they became gay
there's no other way to say it they
allowed gay and transgender leaders and
volunteers naturally they lost the
support from parents and religious
organizations then of course the sexual
abuse scandals picked up attendance
dropped even more and then they let
girls in it's all political they knew
exactly what they're doing none of these
people wanted the Boy Scouts to succeed
they did it purposely to kill this
movement but what can we do first there
is hope smaller movements have already
been started by men who were Scouts in
their youth to provide their sons with
what their fathers had provided to them
so what if this huge organization lies
dying in fact it's because of their size
that they were targeted so much smaller
decentralized scouting movements could
actually be the future because it's more
anti- fragile to attack when we become
fathers it will be up to us to enroll
our sons in the future version of the
Boy Scouts and if one doesn't exist
we'll have to make it ourselves but of
course what about the steps that we can
take right now for our own personal
growth we never had any initiation
ritual so we have to make it ourselves
the key component in an initiation
ritual is not just proving to the tribe
that you are an adult but more
importantly it is to prove to yourself
that you're an adult most young guys
join the Army to prove that they have
what it takes but obviously this is not
a recommendation it may not be the best
choice for you you can start going to a
martial arts gym I don't care which kind
of martial arts it is the initiation
ritual for you might be to get into your
first ever real fight but I'll say that
there's certainly a real risk of injury
which I know too well there's a reason
why I had to step back from martial art
but martial arts and fighting is
certainly not the only option it depends
on your inner nature if you don't like
physical combat but love gardening why
not sign up for this organization called
wolf to connect you with an organic farm
where you get hands-on experience and
competence at farming hell if that seems
too challenging at least go camping most
guys haven't spent a single night under
the stars and they wonder why they're
depressed if you're interested in
Business and Entrepreneurship maybe you
should join a growth house a growth
house is basically when a group of guys
get together and create a high Tempo
environment to supercharge their growth
can you imagine the level of
accountability you'd have if you had a
progress check every single day can you
imagine the physical growth if you went
to the gym went swimming went running
with a pack of wolves rather than a loan
I want to host this myself I want to
create this for myself I could do some
in the US I could do some in Europe
that's where my audience is I planning
to organize these growth houses in the
near future so if you're interested in
that I've included a form below which
you should fill in obviously the success
of such a growth house depends on
handpicking the members to be invited so
if you're invested in this growth house
idea and want to shape future projects
then you should join my private
Community the country club in addition
to the community you also get access to
my courses which used to sell for $300
each otherwise travel could be a
formative experience I've done plenty of
hiking Urban exploration solo travel
across the oceans here are some cool
things that you could do cross the Alps
hike the at te swim in the oceans go
camping go rock climbing if you like
running run a marathon find community in
whatever interests you it is a plebian
mentality to cry about modernity it is
the Patrician mindset to ask what we can
do about it comment below some ideas
that you have of activity that would
serve as an initiation ritual comment
below some places and experience that
were transformative to you don't ever
believe the doomers it's not over unless
you believe that it's over in fact life
life has just begun by the way this is
part two of a two-part Series in part
one I give you five rules that will
prevent you from wasting your youth if
you feel that life is passing you by and
you want a structured approach to make
the most of your youth you need to watch
that video I'll have the tile pop up at
this time so you can complete your
knowledge