all right so at this point you know the
testosterone is important but how do you
actually get it tested here's exactly
the steps you need to take go to your
browser type LabCorp testosterone
you'll find it total testosterone blood
test that's what you're looking for
69 bucks
you'll just go down or yeah that's it
add to cart
and just go to card and check out like
how you always check out right that's
how you buy the test then you'll get an
email the email will have instructions
on how to book an appointment with a Lab
Corp location in this Lab Corp locations
all across the U.S so you'll just find
one which is closest to you book the
time go in there and you'll get it get
your blood drawn you're probably
wondering what my results are I haven't
got my results yet but I'm basically
trying to do some experiments and find
out what the best testosterone vaccine
protocol is once I have that down
to a science that's when I'll release
all the information tell you exactly the
steps you need until then I'm simply not
ready to give you that information I
don't have enough knowledge but one step
you can take right away is to watch my
video on atrazine which is an estrogenic
toxin present in your water supply I
guarantee you atrazine is tanking your
testosterone right now