would you agree with me if I said that
the biggest names of the masculinity and
self-improvement space just feel hollow
you have first man Tate Jordan Peterson
and Hamza all of these you know
unshakable pillars of wisdom all of them
just feel hollow and the entire space
just feels Barren I did this poll and
90% agreed with me that they felt a Vibe
shift they felt that something had
changed and the comments just reinforced
my belief that we are in fact a period
of transition ition even Hamza is losing
support not just in numbers but also in
public perception are we at the end of
the Hamza era you likely know this but
actually worked very closely with Hamza
for months during his meteoric rise from
500k to 1 million subscribers so I
personally know him I worked as a
thinker and strategizer he's far more
intelligent than his empathetic
personality conveys I'm going to
continue to do that exact same job in
this video by analyzing the entire
masculinity and self-improvement space
and tell you exact L what's going to
happen in the next 8 months to
understand hamza's rise and fall we need
to look at the broader context and we
need to look at the timeline of his
Ascent I'm going to take you back all
the way to 2014 when the story of the
masculinity movement on YouTube first
started so most people don't actually
know this but the current masculinity
era comes from the dark days of the Pua
the pickup artist era the older guys
might know what I'm talking about right
so I started watching YouTube around
2014 and this was during the dying gasps
of the Pua movement the Pua movement was
basically a collection of guys who
figured out the exact tricks and you
know techniques to get laid so we had
the ogs like Neil Strauss and mystery
and some of the terms from this movement
are still in circulation today things
like approach anxiety body count neing
pickup lines Day game cold approach all
these terms came from that cultural
movement the Pua movement it even it
even went mainstream in 2005 2010 an
Neil Strauss wrote the game in I think
2005 it's was a book very successful
book which brought in a whole new crowd
of young horny guys who wanted to get
laid at all costs mystery even had a
show on MTV back when MTV was still a
thing Barney Stinson from How I Met Your
Mother was a Pua so I started following
and learning this stuff back in the day
and the in the tail end of the movement
and the threads that already began to
unravel mystery lost his mind Neil
Strauss lost his soul and went through a
messy divorce every one of the OG pickup
artists is an absolute joke they're a
big deal back in the day but now they're
just done the Pua movement basically
defined man as he who sleeps with women
and the more women you slept with the
more of a man you were it was always a
shallow movement and the leaders of that
movement literally lost everything they
lost their reputation they lost their
wealth they lost their loved ones they
lost their sanity we even had other
clowns from this era we had R we and i i
r we actually became a Christian
repented everything he he stopped
selling all his courses and products and
everything like that and I don't know
what he's doing now right I don't follow
this stuff anymore but he he failed like
he's in a terrible mental state right
now then we had Rolo tomasi who he's old
now but he's still speaking about the
same topics that he spoke about back 10
years ago Rolo tomasi is also a spent
Force even so there are some gems from
this era this is one of my all-time
favorite books the book of pke written
by an anonymous author we don't know who
wrote this book and it's just great it
talks about frame in the correct way and
it doesn't treat women like a bunch of
mindless cattle to be slain but like I
said this movement was dying when I
joined it then it completely died it got
nuked when the gamergate event happened
so this gamergate event happened in 2015
and it was a ridiculously important
cultural event that may have been kind
of Forgotten today but it literally
shaped the Paradigm of the masculinity
movement that you are currently living
through this was the first clash between
feminism and the anti-feminism literally
caught fire right this is actually where
the term sjw comes from this is the
event that kicked off the whole
conversation about what it means to be a
man versus a woman in the modern
environment so you may have been too
young to appreciate the gamergate event
when it happened but basically a bunch
of radical feminists you know the blue
hair type they hijacked all the major
gaming related media outlets and they
made the case that Gamers men and the
entire industry was just sexist and
misogynist and oppressive and that all
games should include women and
minorities these harpies literally put
fake accusations on men and ruined lives
to make their case in fact the whole me
too movement is nothing but an echo of
gamergate I'm sure there were cases of
actual assault and harassment but to use
that as a political tool that's just
wrong right so the response to all this
was led by Sargon of aad and other
creators who used to get hundreds of
thousands of views by taking down the
feminists this new anti-feminist
movement defined man as he who does not
take from women as opposed to the
old Pua definition of he who beds the
most women the anti-feminist like Saron
of fad had become kind of the rulers of
the men's space in 2016 on YouTube then
a new man arose and a new vision arose
From the Ashes of that Battlefield
Jordan Peterson had entered the chat the
bill c16 controversy got going around
the end of 2016 starting of 2017 and one
man arose to challenge this this man's a
straight G right from day one he was
impressive he had been developing his
mental fortitude and his skill at
speaking for decades as a professor he
was sharp he was refined he was
extremely well read to say the least he
knew the literature inside and out it's
very hard to debate a man like that his
views were aligned with the
anti-feminists but he diverged because
he was not an atheist he believed in God
believed in the Bible and said so talked
about it a lot so he defined man as he
who beared responsibility for himself
and others around him which is a huge
step up from the past definitions of man
for sure he basically dominated the
discourse and was the face of the
masculinity YouTube space for straight
two-year period 2018 is when he was in
his prime he was crushing it in his
debates his Industrial level demolition
of Kathy Newman was a piece of art worth
watching the entire interview you cited
freedom of speech in that why should
your right to freedom of speech Trump a
trans person's right not to be
offended because in order to be able to
think you have to risk being offensive I
mean look at the conversation we're
having right now you know like you're
certainly willing to risk offending me
in the pursuit of Truth why should you
have the right to do that it's been
rather
uncomfortable well I'm I'm very glad I
put you on the
spot I have my point you get my point
it's like you're you're doing what you
should do which is digging a bit to see
what the hell's going on and that is
what you should do but you're exercising
your freedom of speech to certainly risk
offending me and that's fine I think
more power to you as far as I'm
concerned so you haven't sat there
and I'm just trying I'm just trying to
work that out I mean
[Music]
H gotcha you have got me you have got me
I'm trying to work that through my head
yeah yeah it took a while it took a
while did it did yeah up at the same
time he also had this Cambridge Hall
interview he won this debate basically
where they discussed the gender pay Gap
the feminists were intellectually
dominated by Peterson and he basically
showed that the anti-feminists actually
had something they they were talking
about actual legitimate um circumstances
which men were facing
men were really struggling to find
opportunity and meaning in life Peterson
moved the Overton window in the right
direction and laid the foundation for
the Hamza era he showed a problem he
showed that men are failing out they're
struggling to fix themselves they're
addicted to porn men aren't this
privileged oppressor class that and
misogynist that they made out to be in
fact depression rates and suicide was
actually higher in men men were less
than 40% of college graduates that they
don't make more money if you do the
statistical analysis correctly which of
course the feminists didn't bother to do
in fact men were in the worst place they
had been since the beginning of mankind
and unfortunately this is where Peterson
starts to lose his mind they had to
literally fly him to Russia for
immediate psychiatric help so he's out
of the game just as the pandemic starts
he's out of the game when people needed
him most he was out of the game this is
when men's mental health just falls off
a cliff right lockdown start isolation
happens
and there were some self-improvement
type channels out there but at this time
self-improvement was not linked to
masculinity the self-improvement
channels at this time were you know Ali
abdal there was um better ideas and
these guys would tell you to do the
right thing they would give you the
right information but they couldn't give
you inspiration and the world needed
inspiration and there arose Hamza Hamza
starts doing his gymnast ring workouts
in the park and showed that you didn't
need gyms you didn't need this
infrastructure to get jacked if you
wanted to put in the work you could find
a way to do so and when all these other
self-improvement guys were kind of
androgynous Hamza walks in looking like
a Chad takes YouTube by storm soon as
Hamza enters the fry everybody kind of
becomes irrelevant everybody becomes a
footnote to the rise of Hamza and it was
glorious Hamza took the wisdom of Jordan
Peterson and taught it in simple terms
that anybody can understand he had the
body for credibility he had the honesty
to show the inner workings of
self-improvement and mental health
Hamza defined man as he who does the
hard work especially when he doesn't
feel like it absolute Chad message
that's why we love Hamza ham started
getting serious momentum somewhere in
the um you know when he was 300,000
500,000 subscribers area he put out a
community post asking for applications
to be his thinker and you bet I jumped
on it like literally on the same day I
can still remember getting hamza's email
from his private email and I remember
thinking this is a golden opport
opportunity and it was for months I
worked with him and helped him get
closer to the 1 million uh subscribers
Milestone I would get up at 2:00 a.m. to
do calls with him because of the time
zone difference right he lived in UK I
lived in the US and and I I didn't see
it as a sacrifice I enjoyed it because I
believed in the mission I even did calls
with him during army training I would
sit on the top of my Hume and do calls
on Discord on my phone and this is when
Andrew Tate blows up the internet right
Andrew Tate Loki reprogrammed all our
minds including Hamas including mine and
sneo is just an extreme case of the
absolute power of persuasion that Andrew
Tate exemplifies the man's a genius to
your business and paired with the
speaking skills of a Roman orator plus
he was built like a draft horse of
course he was going to conquer the
internet and he did I still remember
discussing Tate with Hamza they we were
discussing whether you know Hamza should
publicly support Tate or we should just
ignore it at the time and we both were
fans the the sex allegations hadn't
dropped yet this was the end of hamza's
Golden Era where he made the best
content that he has ever made and even
then we were running out of topics he
had already covered the basics you know
covered working out meditation all this
we didn't know what to talk about next
at this time he was going hard against
the social media companies he got
canceled on Instagram he got cancelled
on skillshare and that's when we stopped
working with each other so let's do a
quick review Tate's a brilliant man who
sold his soul to the devil next we have
first man who cannot deliver on promises
to save his life we have sneo who's a
joke we have fresh and fit who's an even
worse joke we have CEO of testosterone
who is another Deen passport bro we have
Jordan Peterson who was truly brilliant
but now lies broken then finally we come
to Hamza Hamza is by far at this current
time the best influencer in this space I
know him personally he really does care
and he is actually the same on and off
camera this video will be me talking
directly to Hamza because I know he's
likely watching this and I will break
down the criticism into parts and
explain it clearly I'm not going to go
easy on you Hamza because of our past
friendship I'm going to be brutally
honest and you're just going to have to
deal with it first your handling of your
ex-girlfriend was hypocritical and
here's why you showed her on camera
literally a million guys knows what she
looked like you talked openly about how
you demolished her in bed and put her on
her knees and all this like graphic
detail it means a million guys have
visualized her getting real like
absolutely demolished that's that's the
level of a porn store you know what I
mean and you left her for even more
attractive
girls the problem isn't that you broke
up with the female like that happens
even with the best of intentions right
the problem is that you created another
Alpha Widow you created more degeneracy
on the on the society and you
potentially caus irreparable damage
because you wanted to party and be
social and do business you couldn't hold
commitment the problem is you talked
about having kids with her publicly even
and then you pulled the rug couldn't
couldn't go through with it right the
problem is that you were giving advice
on finding a wife and having a long-term
relationship when you didn't really know
anything about that topic you talk about
the degeneration of Western women but
you just created potentially one more
broken female you took a potential
traditional life as it were and made her
undatable and unmarriageable because any
man who wants to marry this chick right
is going to come across videos of you
talking her in the most sexual way now I
can understand completely that
relationships can fail and things happen
people drift away but to do this in
public does her more harm than does you
you talk about how she lost attraction
for you when you stopped acting like
James Bond and started being more
authentic to yourself you basically
saying that you need to play a character
to keep attraction but that's not
practical doesn't make sense because no
one can play a character forever to
summarize you clearly were giving out
advice in a very authoritative manner
like a teacher like a leader about a
topic that you were simply not an expert
on you were a student in that topic but
you speaking as though you were an
expert it's just the wrong thing to do
but it was done you shouldn't share
bedroom secrets about a girl online
that's just obvious at this point
shouldn't show her face and you've
basically allowed a million guys to
visualize her getting smashed right so
here's a recommendation obviously don't
do that and of course change out the
thumbnails where your old GF shows up
delete the videos which she actually
appears because it's not about you it's
about her dignity as a woman and here's
a personal prediction I don't know if
this will happen but I I think there's a
small chance that they do get back
together in the future but regardless
the second criticism that Hamza gets is
that he keeps on flip-flopping on his
views so you Hamza yes you change your
mind quite often that in itself is not
wrong but whenever people criticize you
saying you are always changing your mind
you've changed you always come back with
this NPC reply this kind of a
pre-programmed script saying oh bro you
haven't like that's some kind of Genius
comeback it's not a genius comeback it's
just a linguistic trick to avoid the
issue the accusation is that your ego is
too big and your NPC reply is yeah it's
because I'm so successful guys I make so
much money the recommendation I give you
is is stop calling yourself cult leader
that's where the problem truly arises
because otherwise people will understand
that you're just a a leader you know a
solid Man worth following but you're not
a cult leader right to call yourself a
cult leader it means you have to be
perfect you have to do everything
exactly correct because you're leading a
cult I think it's outlived its
usefulness right it's it's kind of
cringe at this point think about it when
you're 50 years of age are you still
going to be calling yourself a cult
leader probably not it'll be so stupid
if you're calling yourself 50 at 50 as a
cult leader so The Branding needs to
change and the cult leader thing has to
be phased out and the time for phasing
it out is right now while it's true that
different viewers want different things
and you cannot possibly please everybody
it wouldn't hurt to show viewers some
gratitude especially because you
pioneered the whole gratitude type
messaging on YouTube told us how it's
important to have gratitude for good
mental health if you show gratitude to
anything it has to be your viewers show
especially as you move on to a
businessman and you want to make
businessman SL entrepreneurship type
content the cult leader branding doesn't
even really help you or apply just take
it own back shoot it be done with it
finally go to Adonna school is is Hamza
a scammer is Adonis School a scam no
absolutely not Adonis school is a legit
product with tons of great content
inside the courses are legit the calls
are legit I've been in Adonis school
probably since day one Hamza added me to
it and I've learned enough from Adonis
school to build my own community and
courses so what's the future of the
masculinity movement I think in its
current form it's dead and think about
it it's not actually that masculine to
talk about masculinity 24/7 it's like
that old Marcus orus quote waste no more
time arguing what it means to be a good
man be one the modern version of this is
waste no more time arguing what a
masculine man should be B1 so that's
where we are at at the masculinity
movement it's kind of everything which
is supposed to be said has already been
said I think everybody kind of sick and
tired of the same old talking points and
we want to focus on a higher tier of
knowledge I've championed the esoteric
Health movement for a while but that's
only one aspect of it ham is essentially
going to be doing the business version
of this he's going to be providing
business knowledge that nobody else is
talking about I think it's very valuable
I think it's the right space to be in
for him the next wave of creators is
going to lead a new type of movement the
New Breed will be authentic but not
authentic for shock value the New Breed
will be polarizing but not to be
polarizing for its own sake I believe
that the next wave of creators will
speak more openly about religion and
prayer and I welcome this change and I
believe that the next generation of
creators will be more masculine without
yapping about masculinity 24/7 I want
real men who have actually lived life to
step up and start talking I want to hear
from Firemen police officers soldiers
doctors Engineers fathers grandfather s
plumbers electricians Lumberjacks and so
many life experiences which I've just
never had earlier in the video I talked
about how there's different definitions
of man and each of these movements had a
different definition well here's my
definition man is he who is capable of
reason and moral judgment man is he who
commands his Destiny to duty man is he
who Bridges the bestial and the Divine
and first and foremost man is he who
Masters himself I'm just sick and tired
of this whole masculinity movement it
feels like a lar you know what laring is
laring is basically when a bunch of guys
they pick up foam Shields and swords and
they do a mock battle and from afar it
might look like a real battle but when
you get close to it it's kind of a joke
that's what the masculinity movement is
slowly becoming and I'm just done with
it I reject it I'm just too old for it
and I ask the question what comes next
the movement of self-improvement and
masculinity is set to crumble under the
weight of his own contradictions the
self Improvement think about it
self-improvement is self-centered and
any man of true worth will be
dissatisfied with this and of course
speaking about masculinity all the time
isn't even that masculine so is the
Hamza era of self-improvement and
masculinity really over I think so I
think these small dick influencers who
cannot reinvent themselves will die out
but what about Hamza himself well Hamza
I think he's just getting started