law number 11 complete garbage law two
utter garbage lost seven garbage this
book is so dumb that people actually
read this and take this seriously 48
Laws of Power 48 Laws of Power claims to
give you all the secrets all the
forbidden knowledge about how Society
actually works because you can use those
tools and get yourself to the top of
that social hierarchy in this video
we're going to explore is that true does
the 48 Laws actually help you get better
at the social game or does it have
fundamental flaws that might actually
hurt you more than it helps you and of
course whether you should read the book
at all the hype that this book is
receiving is just crazy there's people
who literally memorize the 48 Laws and
make note cards and try to learn them
there's a whole rap song about this book
how many books are popular enough or
have a cultural status enough to have a
whole rap song based on them the song is
actually pretty good but is this book
actually helpful is this book true in
the most fundamental sense does it
reflect Society like Robert Greene
claims so that's an interview and with
Jordan Peterson is interviewing Robert
Greene and he asks him what's your
motivation for creating this book and
don't Peterson explicitly says what's
your motivation for creating a
manipulative book and Green's reply this
is essentially it's it's not
manipulative you know it's just
reflecting society as it is and people
need to know how Society actually works
well so the question is does this book
really reflect society as it works and
does it help you do better in your
social game and try to improve your
status I think not some of the advice in
this book is actively harming you I'll
give you an example law 12 is
essentially to use selective honesty
that just means lying if you read the
chapter he'll talk about how you should
omit certain things slash fabricate
other things in order to improve your
status in your social hierarchy and he
says to do this so that you're more
liked by people people trust you more
people think you're more kind he uses
this as a power tactic once you're seen
as a likable kind character because of
your manipulation slash lying you have
higher status in that group and people
trust you more and you have more
opportunities but this is garbage advice
and here's why people aren't dumb the
human species a human being is a social
creature and has evolved for a company
over thousands of years to interact in
this social Dynamic and just because
you've read this 1200 page book about
social game you know social dynamics it
doesn't mean the people around you are
dumb it doesn't mean that you're better
at understanding Society than they are
even if they aren't able to articulate
how social dynamics Works they're still
human beings they're still programmed by
Evolution to have an intuition for how
to interact with people so if you're
playing this game of you know lying
slash hiding truth in order to be kind
and more liked by people around you
people are going to pick up on this and
you cannot stay consistent for very long
they're going to be seeing you as a
snake a kind of person whose advice
slash compliments don't mean anything
that will actually harm you this 48 Laws
of Power mindset the idea that you know
you're in some kind of like Game of
Thrones setting in which you're trying
to manipulate and handle people you have
to understand that everybody's playing
the game and this book might actively
make your game worse by giving you bad
tactics there is such a thing as a bad
book let me explain so the idea that
watching Tick Tock for too long is bad
for you makes you less successful that's
pretty much accepted you know we have
this understanding that certain video
content might be actively harming you
but we think books and reading is just
always good that is not true just as
there is bad video content there's also
bad ideas in books I think that 48 Laws
has a lot of bad ideas I'm not saying
the entire book is bad I'm not saying
it's a worthless book or anything like
that but it has a lot of bad ideas which
you need to identify for example law 2
says never put too much trust in your
friends think about what kind of a bad
mindset that is you should be able to
trust some people in your life if you
live a life in which you cannot really
trust anybody including your closest
friends then you're losing out on power
so this entire book's premise is to give
you these tactics in order to make you
the most socially powerful person that
you can possibly be but trust has power
to it if you have one or two friends
Brothers you're close with them and you
can trust them implicitly that gives you
a level of power over the guy who has no
friends and he's the Lone Wolf kind of
guy so Robert Green is just wrong in
this maybe he never had any friends and
that's why he writes this maybe he got
betrayed by his friend but the fact of
the matter is is throughout history
friendships strong friendships strong
brotherhoods have always existed and in
fact these were the precursor to
achieving great things so if you neglect
friends who you can actually trust
you're Australia missing out on the
maximum amount of power that you're
capable of regardless of whether this is
manipulation or not having friends is
objectively useful even if you are just
using to use your friends to get you to
the next level so law two other garbage
law seven let others do the work and
take the credit you shouldn't do this I
don't know why I have to say this but
this book is so dumb that people
actually read this and take this
seriously firstly you do want to do the
work because doing the work for whatever
it is that you're trying to improve on
actually makes you better so you
shouldn't just let other people do the
work that's part one second part is if
you take all the credit and don't give
credit to your team people who have
helped you along the way you will not be
able to have them help you the second
time and the third time fourth time two
they will resent you and you will have
made enemies and these enemies know you
they know your weaknesses so you've made
enemies who have intimate knowledge of
your weaknesses why would you do such a
thing that objectively lowers your power
level thirdly I don't think this
actually helps if you have have gained a
lot more success and you don't share
your success with the credit to your
team and the people who are brought you
there you don't actually gain anything
in fact you actually gain by showing the
world your team and how they've helped
you because that builds authenticity and
people actually like you more for having
done so so this law is complete garbage
law number 11 learn to keep people
dependent on you this is the most
blatant power play right you want to
have people depending on you so that can
have them do what you want them to do
but firstly this is very very specific
in context the only times this applies
is say you are working a nine-to-five
job and you really want to keep that job
and you want your company to never fire
you perhaps you should work hard slash
make yourself indispensable such that
the company is dependent on you to some
extent and you know if you have job
security something like something like
this that's a good example of how this
law can apply but more often than not
you don't want people to be depending on
you for everything for example if you're
running a business you actually want to
train your employees to kind of take
care of things themselves make their own
decisions and help run your company
otherwise you're just going to be always
having to manage everybody so even in a
business business setting this law
doesn't really work imagine in a family
setting would you want your kids to be
always dependent on you that sounds like
a terrible way to raise kids you want
kids to be independent and make their
own decisions learn and grow and Thrive
without you so that once you're gone
they can do better than you so this
advice in business or family settings is
garbage even when it comes to friends so
you cannot really have a friendship when
the person is dependent on you for
something for example if your friend is
also your employee and they depend on
you or their salary it's not a real
friendship because you have power over
them a good friendship only happens when
neither parties need one another but
choose but choose to spend time with
each other slash interact with each
other that's what a friendship really is
so law 11 another garbage law law 24
another despicable law this says
essentially play the perfect courtier so
a courtier is the lowest possible life
form a courtier is a person who is a
hanger on like he's a like a companion
of a royal person like a companion of
the Queen the king so back in the day
the king and queen would just reside in
Dallas's and they would have a whole
bunch of courtesy years in the court in
the palace whose job was essentially to
exist to be a perfect courtier is the
stupidest thing you're going to Aspire
to courtiers didn't do anything they
didn't have a mission of purpose other
than the status game the only thing
which they lived for was the status game
how to improve their status in the
palace to get closer to the royalty and
didn't have any real power because the
king and queen would have real power so
is this something you really want to
Aspire to do you want to be a courtier
in life you know you want to Aspire to
be somebody without meaning and purpose
and actually creating something of your
own all you do is play the status game
try to be better than your friends
better than your family like what kind
of pointless fools errand is this this
book is preaching to you something which
is inherently in an undesirable outcome
but it's still a popular book so
hopefully this video gets views and then
people realize this book is full of
trash Lot 29 Lot 29 essentially says
plan all the way to the end dumb dumb
don't plan all the way to the end
planning is a little bit overestimated
well at least for me for me I find that
quite often I need to act and acute in
order to actually get things done I
easily fall into the Trap of just
planning and planning and planning and
not actually getting the work done to
actually meet the goal so this is
probably a law which is actually true
for some people I'd say there's people
who just jump into action and just start
doing things and perhaps they should
take a step back and plan things out
that's fair enough so this law does
apply I agree but for a lot of people I
believe that they get stuck in this
procrastination slash planning phase
without actually doing things so I would
rather say go and do things and then
learn along the way then just sit and
plan all the way to the end because
first off that's kind of pointless if
you plan all the way to the end and one
thing happens which kind of derails your
plan then you can't even bring that to
be rather you should have a strategy
tactics which get you closer to the end
goal piece by piece rather than planning
all the way to the end so that if
something happens which throws you off
track you have ways around it and then
you can get to your desired outcome so I
don't think you can plan to the end even
if you could you shouldn't but another
stupid law you know law 29 another
stupid law law 30. so law 30 says make
your wins seem effortless so the idea
behind this is yes you put in a lot of
effort in order to succeed but you hide
all the effort slash hard work and you
make it seem as though you just
succeeded you're just that good you're
just blessed by the gods and you're just
succeeding and then this creates this
Aura this Aura of success that people
see it and they're like in awe of your
success because they don't see the hard
work I don't think this is a good
strategy at least today because we
respect the hard work we know that any
degree of success requires effort so we
respect and like people more when
they're authentic and they reveal to us
their struggles and strategies on how
they got to their success so this law
goes both ways I mean I'm sure that some
people would benefit by hiding the
struggles but equally fifty percent
probably gain by revealing their
struggle so this law doesn't really
apply law 30 and other stupid law all
right final law I'm going to describe
law 33 discover each man's thumb screw
so thumb screw is essentially a torture
device what they're saying is find each
man's weakness so that you can control
slash manipulate him this is not good
advice because firstly you assume that
you're better than people around you
this is me may be true but probably not
true you're probably either average or
between average and the best so if you
have this idea that you want to find
people's pain Point press on them to
manipulate them to do things for you it
might succeed for people who have a
lower power level than you but it's
going to backfire terribly when you mess
with the wrong person because you're not
necessarily the smartest person on the
planet there are people who are smarter
than you very likely and people who are
better at making money slash having
better connection you mess with the
wrong person by pressing their buttons
and manipulate them they will carry that
Grudge and they will do the same thing
to you effectively lowering your power
level so another law which is very
hazardous people who follow this book
they're setting themselves up for
massive social failure so the question
now is should you read the book you know
I spent the last minutes dissing the
book hating on this book going law after
law hating on it so should you read the
book yes you should read the book and
here's why firstly you shouldn't read
the full book because it's too long if
you read The Abridged version but anyway
you should read the book because it
tells you about how Robert Greene thinks
why is it important why do we want to
know how rubber green things it's
because there are mini Robert greens all
around us just many manipulation people
Petty tyrants snakes there are snakes
all around us so Robert Greene's book is
immensely helpful because he allows us
to identify snakes around us and avoid
them that's why you should read this
book as a defense mechanism against
people like Robert Greene but even
that's not completely true the book
essentially makes you cognizant of the
social game so that is an advantage of
reading this book so you have the bottom
tier Normie who doesn't understand how
Society works at all and just goes
through life assuming everybody's good
and nobody cares about power this guy's
a dumbass he's never going to get
anywhere right and then if you read the
book you understand that there's games
being played in the background there are
things going on behind people people's
intentions aren't pure you know they are
doing things to improve their own status
in the world and that awareness itself
is useful so you reach to level two
you're better off than the bottom guy
and this book will get you there because
it reels to you a lot of truths about
human nature the dark truths and
everything but level two is not where
you want to be you want to read the book
understand its contents have the wisdom
to realize which rules are garbage avoid
those rules and understand that there
are people who do actually follow these
rules and then you go to level three to
actually play the social game right this
is a level of authenticity you see that
people are manipulative around you
there's a lot of snakes there's a lot of
people They're all playing status games
you see all this and you choose to be
different from them what I mean by this
is you choose to play a different game
than the status game you can choose
another game to play you can choose to
be authentic to yourself you can choose
to play the money game you can choose to
play the value game the value game is
essentially providing value to society
in exchange for that they give you money
and respect and status and everything
essentially what this book is trying to
give you this so there's two ways to
attain High status one is by playing the
social game well which is what this book
is about but the other way is actually
providing value to society in general
like actually doing something good for
society either it be through providing
you know some kind of good content
educated content or creating new
technology whatever it is you know find
your actual purpose and fulfill that
that gives you status and there's other
things too you know building a good
physique being healthy being well that
gives you status there's many many games
that you can play many many strategies
that you can do to get status you don't
have to play the social game to get
status and especially not the kind of
game which 48 Laws of Power is preaching
so I'd say read the book understand the
message and actively don't follow the
message that's my advice to you thank
you for watching and thank you to my
editor for editing this video goodbye