this is the esoteric King maker Elixir a
cousin to the world famous esoteric
eggnog Elixir it's easier to make has
fewer ingredients and it's just as
nutritious this drink will help you
recover from your workouts unlike
anything else if you're looking to gain
muscle or build strength there's really
nothing like this it tastes like summer
it tastes like sunshine and rainbows it
tastes like mango and honey this is
truly the drink of the Gods and Kings so
for the esoteric King maker Elixir what
ingredients do we need we need milk we
need yogurt we need mango chunks honey
eggs so it's what 1 2 3 4 5 just five
ingredients in order to have a top 1%
nutrition plan all you need to do is
create or learn seven recipes total and
just rotate them you don't even need to
learn seven at the same time you just
need to collect them like you collect
Pokémon cards or something and I believe
that this recipe can be one of your
standard seven every man needs to have a
standard seven recipes that he is a god
at every man will find himself at some
point having the opportunity to show off
his cooking skills if you spent months
and years perfecting your standard seven
you can appear like a pro without
necessarily being one first you need
milk preferably you can get milk low
temperature pasturized or even raw milk
in my opinion is the king of all drinks
it is the perfect blend of protein and
fats it is one of the primary reasons of
the success of certain tribes if I can
get it in a glass bottle I would but in
Hawaii it's just not possible and so I
get the plastic one however this is not
just BPA free but it's also BPA F and S
free pretty good second I'm making sure
that the milk is from cows that were not
given RBST RBST is recombinant Bine
somatotropin it's essentially growth
hormone for cows they use this because
it upregulates the cow's milk production
but there's a trade-off there's always a
trade-off RBST also downregulates
immunity so you need more antibiotics if
you look at milk cartons or even uh milk
products you'll find a strange paragraph
it'll say something like the FDA doesn't
find a difference between RBST milk and
non rbsd milk this is actually a result
of one of the most interesting legal
cases involving of course the infamous
Monsanto corporation so Monsanto
actually went to war with small farmers
who are labeling their milk as RBST free
they basically um their case was that if
Farms brand their milk as RBST free then
they were implying that monsanto's RBST
milk was somehow inferior so they were
able to go through the legal system and
make the case that if a farm was to
claim RBST free they also had to say
that the FDA does not find a difference
between RBST milk and non RBST milk me
personally I'm just going to go with the
non RBST milk regardless of what
monsanto's position on this matter is
but coming back to milk why is it
important to get grass fed this is
because cow's digestive systems are not
built for grain feeding if you feed them
with grain the Rin becomes more acidic
and thanks to Natural Selection the
ecoli in that Rin becomes acid resistant
usually our stomach acids are strong
enough to destroy most ecoli strains but
it cannot handle the acid resistant
version of eoli so again the risk of
infection increases which means that the
companies need to add more antibiotics
to the animals finally I'm looking for
A2 versus A1 milk A2 milk is preferable
because it contains a higher
concentration of CLA which is conjugated
linolic acid and also at milk is just
overall more digestible for most people
second ingredient we want some high
quality yogurt just plain yogurt just as
high quality milk stands Head and
Shoulder above regular milk high quality
yogurt stands about regular yogurt a
brand like f contains twice the amount
of protein per serving as does a brand
like Denon but besides this some Brands
add fillers and additives if you see in
the labeling if you see milk protein
concentrate so
MPC um yeah milk pudding concentrate if
you find that ingredient in your yogurt
then your yogurt is likely trash and I
always aim for the higher fat percentage
because fat is a feature not a bug and
if I'm going to pay for this product I
might as well get all the nutrition
benefits of this third we're looking for
the pasture raised eggs when it comes to
eggs the labeling is crazy there's so
many different labels and some of them
don't mean anything and some of them are
actually useful to look for what should
you look for look for certified Humane
the label for certified Humane it means
it's been third party verified and then
what that what does that mean it means
that these chickens spend more time
Outdoors which means that they
synthesize more vitamin D which they can
concentrate into their eggs so happy
hens lay better eggs fourth we're
looking for raw honey especially if you
can find raw unfiltered or even unheated
honey that would be the best pasteurized
honey loses its enzymes and its
antioxidant benefits but here's the main
thing if the ingredients of your honey
contains dextrose sugar syrup or
anything other than honey it's not honey
Fifth and final ingredient is the Frozen
mango chunks mango is the king of all
fruits the star ingredient of this
recipe when people talk about nutritious
fruits they often are talking about like
blueberries or kiwis oranges sometimes
dates but mango is really not mentioned
but the truth is mango is actually
pretty great it's better than Apples at
almost everything but besides mangoes
just taste amazing and so forms the
Cornerstone of the king maker elixer
once we have these ingredients now all
we're doing is combining them in equal
parts so the three main ingredients for
the recipe is the chunks the um the
yogurt and the milk so just one part of
each plus one egg plus 2 tbspoon of
honey so first what I'm going to do is
take handful of
mangoes drop them in there and I'm going
for an
approximately 200 mL then I add in 200
mL of the
milk then I will add
in 200 mL of the yogurt
boys I know you haven't tasted this yet
but this is genuinely one of the best
recipes I know highly highly recommend
trying it out the egg one of you
actually taught me this the easiest and
the correct way to break an egg is not
is not by hitting it against the edge of
something and it is not by taking a
spoon and whacking it that's the wrong
way to crack an egg how you actually do
it is find a flat surface like this
glass top and one
crack
and open it up and the reason for this
is this way you minimize any contact of
the egg whites with the shell of the
actual egg in so doing you reduce the
chance of any kind of infection or
illness because it's often times the
eggshell the outside of the eggshell
which contains uh the germs
so yes I know raw eggs might make you
sick whatever
I've been having RS for a long time I'm
okay with the risk not saying that you
should be okay with the risk but I am if
you want to full Deep dive into the
risks and rewards of raw eggs I actually
have a video on that exact topic which I
will be sure to add to the description
below so what do we have now we have the
yogurt we have milk we have egg we have
mangoes we need the honey this is the
highly esoteric approved Indo-European
honey from Turkey actually turkey is
actually uh a source of really high
quality honey but coming to the recipe
I'm just eyeballing about two
tablespoons of
this being pretty generous because I am
right now my priority with diet is just
increase muscle mass increased strength
because I had that um surgery back in
November of last year leading up to the
surgery I was extremely weak which is
why I had the surgery in the first place
and then after the surgery there's a
long postoperative period where I
couldn't really lift weights or anything
so honestly the entire year of 2024 was
rough from a physique standpoint just
lost a lot of strength lot a lot of lost
a lot of muscle but hey that's where the
king maker elixer comes in this will
basically rebuild me and I'll will show
you some pictures of my progress in the
past what is it Fe right right now it's
February right so four five months if
that not even right just made a massive
amount of progress in the gym boys just
through nutrition like this so I
strongly recommend giving it a shot ah I
almost forgot to talk about this one
thing hold up hold up hold up so this is
an interesting ingredient it's cestrum
now it's a very hyped ingredient so
let's discuss this here's the deal with
this we have some initial studies
showing chrom to be a superfood it
contains the antibodies IGG and IG it
destroys infections basically and it
even contains the um igf1 and igf2 which
are essentially growth factors some are
saying that by consuming chrom as a
supplement you can maximize your height
is there any truth to this or is it just
marketing well if you have the money to
spend yeah you can go and try it out
it's not that it's a bad supplement it's
just very low leverage for the price you
pay you can get much better value for
your money with just something like hard
cheese the main benefit of chrom is that
it improves The Taste and texture of
this King maker Elixir which is why I
have it but once this canister is done I
probably wouldn't repurchase it see the
thing is you don't need these esoteric
supplements as it were you don't need
cestrum you don't need uh you don't
need any of this stuff you just need to
be good at the fundamentals in fact one
of the first things I do in my cohorts
is I ask people what supplements they
take and just slash them cuz you don't
need that these are all distractions all
these weird supplements that people are
taking nowadays spending lots and lots
of money on are just distractions just
focus on a solid Whole Foods diet and
that's 99% of the work once you have 99%
of nutrition solved you're already
consistent you're already making
progress then if you have money to spend
and you're like okay what supplements
can I try then yeah go for the tonat Ali
go for the frodia agrestis go for all
the huberman subs the truth is you're
not hubman huberman has already dialed
in everything to an autistic level and
then he has some small benefits from
these supplements unless you're huberman
in terms of your health optimization you
just are wasting your money that money
and the the bandwidth like the mental
bandwidth are much better spent
Elsewhere for example like this tub of
chestone right think cost 60 bucks and
I'll tell you right now that this ninja
creamy uh blender right I'm just going
to show this to the camera is also
around 60 bucks maybe 70 and this is
just much higher leverage like getting a
high quality blender is way better use
of your money than a chrom supplement is
going to be so I'm not against spending
money on health far from it my internal
guideline is actually to go broke
investing in myself all I'm saying is I
want to make sure that my investments go
towards things that actually make a big
impact so if you have $60 to invest in
health get a good blender don't get
cestrone so now let's go blend this bad
boy up and see how it
tastes all right it's Blended it's time
for the legendary taste test so let's go
ahead get our yourself a
glass all right now here is a true
esoteric tier ingredient it is saffron
so how many do you need just need like
that many ah
perfect so how does it taste it tastes
like something Fit For A King it's so
rich and creamy and sweet but it also
has a subtle Tang from the yogurt so
it's not so sweet that it's cloying
instead it's actually quite refreshing
the hint of honey just takes this and
elevates this to a Divine status and the
Egg you can't even really taste the egg
so try it out and comment below your
experience with the esoteric K maker
elixir
n
[Music]