your whey protein has nothing on this
this is a jar of eggnog and you might
think eggnog is that Christmas you know
celebration treat which makes you fat
it's not think about it eggnogs
ingredients eggs milk whipping cream
honey in my case
cinnamon vanilla extract nothing more
perfectly healthy ingredients which make
this amazing testosterone boosting drink
think about like it has a cholesterol
and healthy fats that you need for your
hormonal development has proteins from
the egg whites which are of course for
you know muscle building and everything
and it has milk which is another
delicious compound of literally
everything you need for your body to
function
cinnamon which has thermogenic effects
and let's get started I'll tell you how
exactly to make this just look at it
it's beautiful if you serve this chilled
with cinnamon on top
it's game over so this thing is the
perfect drink for post-workout you know
if you're done working out it'll give
you literally all the ingredients your
minerals
your electrolytes everything back
restored you're ready to go it's also
great for before you sleep because your
body actually makes testosterone when
you sleep
hope hope this thing's recording your
body makes testosterone when you sleep
so if your body is provided with
you know the healthy fat it needs the
actual saturated in fact it needs to
create testosterone you're going to have
a boost when you wake up in the morning
and this will take the shape of a boner
if you are a man and if you're a female
of course you want to get a testosterone
boost but you will get the
female endocrine systems are extremely
complicated and I don't want to get into
that topic let's just say you'll be more
hormonally healthy regardless of male or
female
all right let's get back into the actual
cooking video
we have eggs
milk cinnamon honey heavy whipping cream
and vanilla extract which is an optional
but you can have it so eggs you want the
high quality best quality eggs you can
find
usually the difference between the price
of low quality eggs and high quality
eggs is a couple bucks
if you're going to spend five bucks on
anything getting high quality eggs is
one of those best places to spend it
because there is a genuine difference
between free range eggs and just your
carton you know those thermocol carton
eggs you find in Walmart those hens have
lived their entire lives in a coop
indoors have never seen the Sun so they
don't have any vitamin D in their own
system so their eggs don't have any
vitamin D so you don't get any vitamin D
from eating those eggs these hens from
which I got these eggs
you know they spend their life Outdoors
eating bugs and worms and whatever it is
and they have the micronutrients they
essentially assimilate into their own
body systems and lay in the form of eggs
which I eat which keeps me healthy so
get the good quality eggs my boys
eggs so that's one ingredient let's go
ahead and process this ingredient what
we're going to do is I need a bowl a
second bowl
okay
so we're going to separate the egg yolks
from the egg white this is an important
step don't mess it up so what we're
trying to do is
crack the egg
and catch the yolk
all right easy crack the egg catch the
yolk that should be all you do
so I've already washed my hands and
everything so make sure you're being
sanitary with this
so you catch the a yolk let the whites
kind of just filter through your fingers
and that's how you separate them so you
kind of do want as clean a separation as
you can get the reason is the egg whites
are made of proteins and the egg yolks
are made of fats so
in the later stage of this recipe we are
going to be whisking the egg whites
and when you're whisking the egg whites
if there's any fat in it it'll prevent
the egg whites from from becoming a foam
and it's not the end of the world or
anything like if you get a little bit of
egg yolk in your egg whites it doesn't
do anything but that's just some more
information to know to make this recipe
perfect
so I'm trying to separate this as best I
can
and by the way guys
huge thanks for visiting this channel I
literally started YouTube maybe a week
ago
and my main Channel already has 7
subscribers I didn't even know that was
possible
I assume that it's going to take six
months to a year to get to 1K
subscribers but to get to 7K within a
week that's basically 1000 subscribers
per day
is just insane and mind-blowing
and
I have my greatest gratitude for those
who have subscribed and commented and
everything
and so I make this amazing recipe
for all of you to enjoy make it for your
family make it for your friends actually
enjoy cooking and consuming food if you
think about it you eat food every single
day and your food is literally what
transforms into your body and therefore
your mind
why wouldn't you gain the skills to make
good quality highly nutritious amazing
tasting food
that's a skill you're going to use for
the rest of your life you know you they
all talk about high value skills like
coding or God knows what at this point
but what about cooking you know if you
have somebody to cook for you're good
for you but like most of us we need to
know our basic recipes to keep ourselves
healthy
so yeah let me get just wash my hands
I'll get back into it
so by the way soap right I'm gonna use
soap to wash my hands
the soap which you use might be killing
your testosterone let me explain
so always reading ingredient list of the
Soaps and shampoos that you're using
because a lot of them will have
something called parabens
parabens which come in two forms ethyl
and metal paraben these essentially are
endocrine disruptors so without going
into like how they function and
everything basically they messed your
system up and they reduce your
testosterone so
make sure you buy soap it doesn't have
those
yeah so coming back yolks eggs egg
whites that is separated I'm also going
to have to heat my milk up
which I need I need a sauce man
okay let me get that real quick
all right so
that was that yeah the milk
okay so I am using
organic grass-fed grass-finished whole
milk not that two percent or skim milk
why would anybody even drink skim milk
the best part of the milk is removed in
skim milk basically water I don't
understand why people drink things like
skim milk or two percent the best part
is in whole milk try to get raw milk if
you can but you know most people the
best you can do in grocery stores is
probably past uh low temperature
pasteurized
non-homogenized milk that's what I'm
using so it basically means that this
milk is as natural as you can get and
cream will actually rise to the top
that's how you know it's good quality
milk
so it's one cup of whole milk
no skim milk allowed guys that
that's just nasty
um heavy whipping cream
nothing too special about this just just
heavy whipping cream
I'll do one cup so
I'm doing a one-to-one ratio of the milk
and heavy whipping cream
uh I think that's what tastes best but
it's completely up to you what you want
try to experiment with it this will
determine the thickness and consistency
oh yeah it's good of the end product so
you know depending on your taste you can
change this ratio
so I put it on the heat
I'm not trying to make it boil
I'm trying to get it just below boiling
so just when it has steam coming off but
it's not actually boiling that's the
ideal place to stop that's what's going
to essentially kill the bacteria and
potential salmonella in the egg so when
that's on the heat we are going to work
with the eggs
honey
so
eggnog recipes traditionally like the
Christmas ones contain a
H I try to not curse on this channel
calm peace clean content
so honey instead of sugar because sugar
is cancer honey is the good stuff
especially if you get high quality honey
so what's high quality honey right if
you're trying to find out
it's if when you see
raw and unfiltered that's a good sign
but if you can get unheated if you can
get unheated honey
that's the ultimate best quality honey
that you can find but it's hard to find
though so don't stress out just get the
Iran unfiltered
so good
just natural ingredients
you know high quality natural
ingredients just
there's so much better for you and
tastes so much better than anything you
can get in like a fast food restaurant
like this eggnog which I'm going to
teach you
literally tastes better than anything
you can find in any fast food restaurant
I promise you
all right
so milk mixture is on the heat
I mean wash my hands a little bit like
moss
we're gonna whisk these eggs so okay so
you basically okay
you know you're done when you see these
Peaks forming in the egg whites that's
perfect that's exactly what I'm looking
for
really really nice
okay so that's what I was talking about
like if you had a little bit of yolk in
the egg whites it wouldn't rise up as
much it's not a huge deal you're still
going to get the same nutrition oh boy
no I'm good
um
but this is just gonna be nicer I don't
know so okay egg whites have been
whisked and that's good it's ready to go
we have the yolks
yeah that's basically it all we're doing
is waiting for the milk
mine is just heating up slightly oh I
mean give you a warning so this
ingredient this eggnog has four eggs
and basically if you're not used to
eating eggs your body is going to have a
little bit of a reaction towards it
put to put it bluntly
the first two days of having a lot of
eggs your farts are going to smell like
sulfur because eggs contain sulfur
however your body's going to learn from
it and adapt to it and
there won't be any problems like you'll
be fine you'll be whoever you were
before consuming the eggs so in just a
just a warning
kind of gross I don't want to talk about
it in a cooking channel but you know
this is not a cooking channel this is
like nutrition well-being Etc
and
at some point I want to talk about other
topics on this channel also things like
you know
philosophy of warfare or something like
that like deep topics
anyway milk yes okay so next step we're
going to combine the ingredients
essentially so the egg white foam goes
into this hot milk
all of it can go in at the same time no
issue remember this contains the honey
so the honey is going in as well
get in there all right
yeah buddy
okay
so this is going to be I'm going to
combine this and then we have the egg
yolks we're going to break them
mix them up a little bit
put them in mix it mix it mix it mix it
mix it mix it mix it
put some into this mix this I'm just
trying to get all of it in because you
know this entire thing the yolks
especially are full of micronutrients
zinc magnesium selenium everything that
your body needs to secrete hormones so
this is literally the stuff which gets
converted into testosterone so you don't
want to waste a single drop of this
stuff
especially because this is expensive
like I bought the best quality
ingredients to make this thing so might
as well get every last drop
like these eggs like this carton of eggs
cost I think like seven dollars which
you know I happen to be blessed
and fortunate to be able to afford it
without too much concern but
no
um
hopefully you find yourself in
a fortunate situation such as myself
so yeah combine the ingredients
keep going keep going
I think it's probably combined enough
oh yeah I forgot so vanilla extract this
is the most optional ingredient in this
entire recipe it's a little bit of a
splash for taste
and make sure you don't get the
like the Kroger Brand like the cheapest
vanilla extract because usually those
are synthesized you want to at least
make sure that it's coming from an
actual plant
a lot of ingredients in our stores
they're all fake they're all just
terrible for your body not necessarily
the vanilla extract but you know other
things
so
that's what this channel is going to
kind of
he's trying to teach you
protect you from the harms of
industrialized food processes
essentially and you know make better
choices in the grocery store which
results in directly in better hormonal
Health which results in better
like mental health which increases your
productivity your financial status your
social status your dating life
everything goes up so we have this
mixture I think we have all the
ingredients combined very good now let
me grab
when these glass jars try not to use
plastic jars plastic jars will leech
chemicals into your food like literally
they leech microplastics and chemicals
into your food so no plastic
and then we have the mixture ready to go
I'm going to hopefully not make an ass
of myself on camera
and pour this thing nice and clean
deep breathing guys keeps the stress
away right
yeah uh yeah let's go let's go let's go
almost almost
a little bit more in here but so
I guess I didn't calculate too well
right maybe maybe I should reduce the
milk a little bit I have more than what
one jar can contain
so that's fine I mean I have more jars
I have more jars
she has one
pour it in
and I also have
some leftover from a previous batch
so
yep yep yep there it is so
when do you serve this thing so after
you make it and I have like three jars
or two and a half jars of this stuff so
that's really good this is gonna like I
do one jar per day four eggs per day
that's it seems like the right amount
for me
and basically you want to chill this you
want to put in the freezer not the
freezer the fridge and it's going to
taste amazing overnight when you have it
the next morning but even if you chill
it for just an hour or two it's still
really good so what you'll do is
well
for the sake of b-roll and to make this
video you know comprehensive
I will
pour some and serve
let me grab
this they put these away
so let's go let's add let's have some
eggnog I mean it's not ideal because
it's still kind of warm ideally served
chilled but still gonna taste good
though
so let's go
eggnog here we go
oh yeah it's good it's good you can kind
of taste the honey
this is the ultimate
esoteric eggnog Elixir move these out to
get that front view
yeah buddy add some cinnamon
beautiful
and cinnamon has thermogenic effects so
essentially it's a fat burner
and
that is a drink fit for Kings
just look at that like look at that
compare your whey protein
milkshake to this thing
all right
let me oh yeah so I like to kind of stir
the cinnamon in
so that's up to you
let's see how this thing tastes
perfect
a little bit too much cinnamon I think
but
perfect so it's it's warm it's not you
know the right temperature it's not the
way it's supposed to be served so I'm
going to put it all in the fridge and
after a couple hours then I'm gonna have
it
so it's been a while since I uh finished
the video so I got my eggnog nice and
chilled got it by my fireplace you can
see it
and let's see how this thing tastes
yep it's perfect so it doesn't taste
anything like eggs it doesn't even taste
like milk really it tastes like custard
it tastes like
bit Yeah it tastes like Custard with the
hint of honey and vanilla so if that
sounds yummy to you it sounds good to
you you need to make this 100 need to
make this try it and comment if you
liked it or not and I'm not asking just
for you know the YouTube engagement like
actually I want to know like did you
succeed did you like it