if women had evolved to do anything it
is to be able to detect the quality of
their mate at the deepest genetic and
biological levels and they do this using
smell and in this video I'm going to
answer the question do human pheromones
exist what does that mean for dating
life and sex in general I'm going to
tell you which colognes are toxic to
your hormones and why you might smell
bad to others even if you shower every
day and can't really notice any bad
smells yourself see the thing is people
are usually too nice to comment on
anything people are too nice to let you
know so I'm also going to give you a
technique to find out if you smell bad
without asking anybody so the tears
right a tears of a crying woman can
literally reduce free testosterone in
men lower sexual aggression and make
them more pacified that's chemical
warfare but also works the other way the
scent of a man can actually pacify a
woman the scent of a man can lower her
stress give her feelings of well-being
so they did this experiment it's very
easy to show that women actually feel a
sense of calm when exposed to the sense
of a man healthy women have the ability
to sense Health in men and when I speak
of Health I'm talking about hormonal
health so the balance between cortisol
and testosterone if you're a highly
stressed unhealthy male you're not going
to be attractive even if you have good
facial Aesthetics because you're going
to be emitting smells and pheromones
that convey your low status I want you
to imagine a version of you who's
hormonally healthy who's mastered his
social skills and he's optimized his
looks if you do all three of these then
you're going to be golden so most people
don't know this but looks money and
status the Holy Trinity of the red pill
is just a surface approximation of the
real underlying biology these red pill
dorks they think they're so clever and
wise for figuring out that women care
about money looks and status of course
they care about these things what's so
special about that you could ask any
Village Bumpkin in any civilization any
random mud hut tribe across history in
any part of the globe and they will tell
you the same thing there's nothing
surprising about the fact that women go
for looks money and status if you really
want to dig deep into human nature
including male and female nature and
interex interactions I suggest you read
a book called the Red Queen by Matt
Ridley I spent more than $1,000 on
cologne complete waste of time you may
not know anything about fragrances right
but there's actually a huge community on
YouTube they call themselves The
fragrance community so first you buy
your first colog you think it's your
signature scent I had something called
the Chanel alure ediion Blan and this is
actually a very rare fragrance it smells
like key line pie and it's really nice
but then I needed a summer fragrance so
I got myself mugir Ultra zest which is
another highly cetted fragrance and this
one smells like orange creamsicle and
for dates I got myself some Creed
aventus which is a super expensive but
really good smelling fragrance smells
like musky pineapple almost and women do
really like this but this wasn't
suitable for the workplace so I got
myself some Prada LOM which is like kind
of like a sophisticated Iris smell which
is still very alluring but it's more
like professional I also had a molecule
over one which is a magic scent like it
smells different on each person like I
had spent hundreds of dollars per bottle
on this stuff so I know what the hell
I'm talking about and I tell you with
some amount of pain that all of these
are incredibly toxic these are chemicals
which should not come in contact with
the human skin if you look at the
ingredient list of any of these colognes
you will not be happy with what you see
for example Dior saage which is a very
famous fragrance it literally contains
red four I don't know what purpose and
all fragrances all Colones contain
benzophenones on or other photo blockers
and the reason this is important is
because the smells come from aromatic
chemicals and aromatic Rings they tend
to break down with heat or light and
because of this the manufacturers have
to add photo blockers in order to kind
of protect these sensitive chemicals
from denaturing because if they denature
then the smell is going to smell bad but
these benzo phenos other photo blockers
are endocrine disrupting which means
that they tank your hormones so now
you're in a awkward spot you're using
those cologn to smell good to women but
these cologn are decreasing your hormone
levels and that's is going to make you
less appealing to women so it's very
counterproductive so are all colognes
trash well all designer colognes are
trash yes but I'm going to give you some
recommendations and what you can
actually
use we care about the pheromones between
man and woman the first Topic in here is
imprinting so a woman who's parab bonded
to a man can detect which clothing
belongs to him using fermon alone so
they literally take T-shirts from like
group of men and they wash them again
and again until all smell is destroyed
and they give it to women and the women
can smell a t-shirt they don't smell any
smell so they they say it to the
investigators like I don't smell
anything but I feel like this t-shirt
belongs to my husband or boyfriend so
even if it's not at a cognizant level
there is chemical signaling at the
subconscious level how do you know if a
woman finds your scent attractive the
simple answer she will tell you it
happens all the time women love talking
and they will straight up tell you once
they have enough confidence once they
have enough warmth developed towards you
they will be very open with you but if
you have never gotten a compliment like
that then we have to evaluate first
maybe you don't smell good good because
I'm going to give you the protocol to
fix that problem and the second maybe
you're not that attractive that's fine
I'm going to make a full looks maxing
guide in the future look out for
that so here we go boys actionable step
the smell maxing protocol here we go so
first one is your environment so
literally your home and people
completely don't understand how
important the smell of your home is
because these smells basically adhere to
your skin and your clothes and you will
never detect it because you're used to
smell of your home but others absolutely
can so you have to maintain cleanliness
in your home you're going to wash your
bed sheets pillow covers and all the
bedding at least once a week because as
you sleep you're leaving your know dead
skin cells and these will rot and cause
smell and you'll never smell it but
those smells will stick to you as you go
about your day so your bed covers bed
clothes all that stuff needs to be
washed every week for sure the next item
is food what you eat absolutely has a
massive impact on what you smell like
spices will absolutely be metabolized
and then just sweat it out from your
skin this is not a myth this is fat and
you can prove it all my Indian Brothers
will know of Maggie like every single
Indian knows what Maggie is Maggie is a
spicy noodle dish and it has it's really
tasty but it has a strong smell of Rich
spices and if you eat Maggie you're
going to smell like metabolized Maggie
for 24 hours 100% guaranteed so be aware
of what you're putting into your body
because that can cause smell for sure
I'm going to show you how to evaluate
that but before that we're going to go
to another example so probably nobody
has had true organic bacon from a
healthy Pig so 100% of bacon store Bo
bacon is coming from castrated pigs so
they take these pigs and they brutally
they snippet balls man they snippet
balls and they do this for a very
specific reason pigs which have their
balls and therefore have testosterone
their meat literally smells different
and I know this I've literally
experienced this and it even has a name
it's called bore taint you can look this
up right now so basically if you have a
intact Pig like a healthy Pig which
actually has its balls its meat will be
infused with kind of an animalistic odor
like a very animalistic and almost kind
of like sweat it's not a very pleasant
smell and if you eat organic bacon which
has that smell then you will emit those
very smells and here's the thing this
has nothing to do with hygiene as such
you could be showering every day you
could still smell bad purely because of
the diet and how do you evaluate this
here's one way so take a shower be as
clean as possible and then go into the
sauna and spend 15 minutes in there and
after 15 minutes if you can smell
yourself
uhoh stinky this means that this is not
just a skin level or Surface level smell
this is coming from your metabolism now
this could be very easily fixable maybe
it's just diet maybe you're just having
a lot of spices but potentially it could
also be something else it could be a
sign of bad metabolic Health it could be
a sign of bad gut health it could be a
sign of parasitic load but then again
parasites are a topic for a different
discussion so what's the shower protocol
obviously I've been saying this for a
long time Tallow soap is the best soap
that you can have it's very gentle
however if you have acne you want to be
using sulfur soap sulfur soap will
destroy acne but you don't want to use
it permanently I I would switch out of
sulfur soap and go to Tallow soap as
soon as the acne clears up and then for
hair so hair is actually a place where
you can store a lot of bad smell so i'
strongly recommend using shikakai
powders so it's a herbal powder so
basically you take it put it into a bowl
add some water and make a paste out of
it and that paste will act as shampoo
and it it will lit foam up and act
exactly like shampoo without destroying
your scalp so as you know shampoo is
mostly a scam it purposely makes your
scalp dry so that you produce
overproduce oils and then you need more
shampoo to fix that problem so shampoo
is trash try to use shikakai powder
instead and finally of course get a
shower filter it's good for your skin
removes the chlorine from the water the
chlorine kills skin cells and dead skin
cells can Decay and cause smell so I
wouldn't be surprised if switching to a
shower filter would actually reduce body
odor and then deodorant what deodorant
should you use I use a magnesium based
deodorant and I'll link to the one which
I use in description below and then what
about oral hygiene obviously you want to
maintain good oral hygiene you don't
have bad breath and don't of course buy
into your lisine propaganda lisine is a
scam product from day one it purposely
dries out your mouth so that your body
doesn't have enough saliva saliva can
actually kill germs and so blisterin
actually causes bad breath it literally
causes the problem designed for it to
solve hello then we discovered that a
daily garle Listerine antiseptic
mouthwash deals with the germs that can
cause bad breath hello man the guys at
propor and gamble are actually Geniuses
they're just Evil Geniuses so when it
comes to oral health flossing is a must
every single day at night Second Use the
right toothbrush change out your
toothbrush every month use an Ultra Soft
bristle toothbrush in fact get a kitty
brush you know like the brushes which
they make for babies extra soft that's
what I use literally and third what kind
of toothpaste should you use I always
always go for a non- floridated
toothpaste currently I'm using a hydroxy
appetite powder I will link to that as
well in the description hey boys so I
actually forgot to mention this the
first time I recorded this video so I
had to like make the segment separately
because it's that important so this is a
tongue scraper if your tongue is always
white then you definitely need to be
using this and lastly gut health so you
could have the perfect mouth hygiene but
you could still have bad breath if you
have bad gut health and of course gut
health is a vast topic onto itself it
doesn't really fit neatly into this
video I do include a whole section on
gut health in my esoteric nutrition
course if you are so inclined you can
check that out in the description
below and you will know that there's a
lot of fragrances which purport to be
human pheromone fragrances I think it's
all Bs and I wouldn't personally use
them I wouldn't use them because why
would I put an artificial pheromone on
myself to make myself attractive to
women I would much rather focus on my
own health and my own genuine
testosterone levels in order to become
genuinely more attractive rather than
have these Band-Aid these quick fixes is
instead just focus on good hygiene which
I've already described and also focus on
getting good colognes which smell really
nice and have an attracting factor to
them without purporting to be human
pheromones so as I've said before a lot
of cologne is toxic don't use toxic
colognes here's the Alternatives instead
and essential oil blends are exactly
what they sound like they are basically
a combination of extracted Aroma
chemicals from plants so some companies
have made really creative Blends by
mixing different Aromas so essentially
this is perfume is just not perfume how
we understand it as modern people we
understand cologne and perfume as to be
those big bottles with the alcohol
sprayer but in ancient times this is
what they used as perfume or cologne
essentially nothing more and nothing
less than a distillation of plant
Essence so truly speaking in ancient
times this is what the Nobles and rich
people and kings and ambassadors would
have actually used so I consider using
these to be almost like a status symbol
man these are really cool so two in
specific are interesting to me one is
called egyp Egyptian gold and what in is
called chivalry and both of these are by
a company called Young Living first we
have chivalry which is a kind of a
daytime or summary scent really
beautiful and the name really does do it
justice so it even has a little like um
a night riding on a horse symbol on it
so the scent is kind of like flowers but
without being gay or feminine plus bark
and wood plus kind of citrus smell so a
little bit of flowers a little bit of
Woody smells plus a little bit of citrus
and that's what this basically is it's
really nice very crowd-pleasing very
nice for daytime very nice for summer
and spring this is the opposite this is
Egyptian gold this is a dark
frankincense and myrr smell so I
completely see what they're going with
the naming scheme here an Egyptian gold
does do it justice it's very like a
mystical and mysterious and dark smell I
think this would be really nice for
winter or nighttime I would definitely
wear this on a date it's that kind of
smell you know kind of mysterious Vibes
while this is kind of more like a first
impressions
vibe so if you're already doing 80 to
90% of this protocol and you're still
facing body odor then there could be an
underlying issue you see the skin is a
detox organ it's always garbage in
garbage out and the modern world is full
of modern toxins we're talking about
xenoestrogens we're talking about heavy
metal toxicity we're talking about
microplastics and perhaps the most
relevant for this topic is just chronic
stress it is not normal for you as a
human being to be facing cortisol
inducing spikes throughout the day and
you can test this out for yourself think
about the stressed people in your life
don't they smell worse and even yourself
in times of stress Don't you smell worse
of course you do so you need to combat
chronic stress in your life and one way
to combat chronic stress is through
breathing exercises which are linked to
below and speaking of these modern
toxins as well as the ancient enemies of
mold toxicity and parasitic load all of
this applies directly to me because for
the past 1 month I've been in India and
I've been there to learn meditation but
the problem problem is in India I didn't
have access to RO water I didn't have
access to a shower filter and
practically all the food I consumed was
cooked in seed oils and I did eat street
food which obviously has the risk of
parasitic contamination so I personally
will be looking at my own detox course
and following it and speaking about
parasites check this out this is
Ivermectin belonging to the atin class
of antihelmintics there is also of
course the benzimidazol class of
antihelmintics like albendazol if you're
in my private Community you already have
access to one of the best herbal
parasite Purge protocols on the planet
and in about a month or so you're going
to have a new module added to the detox
course for the pharmaceutical option the
pharmaceutical parasite Purge also I'm
going to be adding a new module into the
nutrition course I'm going to be adding
a mini gut reset protocol because I
understand that a month-long gut reset
protocol is unrealistic for most people
if you're interested in these modules
they're just a small part of these
courses which I have in my private
community if you are so inclined you can
check it out in the link below