the esoteric moment has been taken over
by husters twinks and retards what's
happened after the covid crisis is a
complete mistrust of Science and I get
it I feel betrayed too but this mistrust
has been co-opted by charlatans Crooks
and quacks to make a quick buck in this
module I will cut through the noise and
give you the truth I will expose the
scam supplements and show you the
synergistic supplement systems that
actually work so here's the deal sex
cells and testosterone is the molecule
of sex so quite understandably there's a
massive business opportunity out here
any supplement that can Market itself as
a testosterone booster makes Bank
especially if they can find some new
novel ingredient that's esoteric
sounding such that the target market
hasn't heard of it guys are taking pine
pollen because they think it's going to
give them phyto testosterone they're
taking deer antler wet because they
think they're going to get the igf1 from
there for their height they take tonot
Alit make their balls bigger now there's
Tribulus there's testerone there's
stinging nettle schilit there's appenine
and ashwag gandha all these make the
promise of testosterone mood and energy
but here's what I see guys will take all
of these and still behave like losers
and then for productivity there's the
huprine there's nicotine there's Lions M
this Alpha GPC they take all of these
and still absolutely not get any work
done guys will take five HTP Gaba myo
inositol and chamomile te for sleep they
still won't get any sleep it's all
just as I have a bone to pick
with the healthcare industrial complex
so too do I have a bone to pick with the
supplement industrial complex let's do a
real life example using the firstman
supplement yesterday I made a community
post asking what's wrong with the
supplement and you my audience delivered
I am proud of you and I expect nothing
less first The Good the supplement
contains Boron also contains iodine to
balance out the Boron that's a good move
second the bad the L citrine dose is too
small to make any difference oh well
whatever the ugly why is there MAA tonad
Al ashwagandha and Tribulus in the same
supplement but that's even not my
problem the biggest problem for me is a
dosage of black pepper extract the
reason for black pepper extract is to
increase the absorption of everything
else in the supplement but how does it
accomplish this it does so by negating
the detoxification benefits of the liver
to be clear I think first man tried to
make the best supplement that he could
he just didn't have the knowledge of the
hormone engine this supplement does not
show a systemic understanding of the
underlying biology instead it's just a
collection of the trendiest ingredients
on Google Trends in one capsule listen
you don't need any of these these
supplements do not address root causes
they promise quick fixes where instead
you should be thinking in system so how
do you think in systems well this is
part one of a five module course you'll
have at the end of it you'll have a
grand picture of the hormone engine in a
way that even first man did not many of
the herbal supplements like ashwag
gandha and tonat Ali that you saw in the
first man supplement are not even
supplements these are actually medicines
which were administered centuries ago
under the direct supervision by a shaman
these are powerful adaptogens that can
actually screw things up in the long
term of course they don't tell you this
then there's the other supplements that
getting popularity stuff like pine
pollen and antler velvet what they don't
tell you here is that a good night's
sleep that you to give you more benefits
than a $100 supplement many influencers
site scientific studies to back up their
claims about these weird supplements but
it's mostly none of these
people actually know how to read the
scientific literature and actually
compare the facts and it shows like for
pine pollen the major study that they
keep citing is done on fish and when it
comes to the deer antler velvet did you
know that antler velvet is actually used
to monitor the lead levels in the forest
literally forestry teams will go into
the woods and find this antler velvet
and use it to track the amount of lead
exposure in the environment so unless
the sourcing is perfect it actually do
more harm than good now we make fun of
the traditional Chinese for eating Rhino
horn or tiger dick to get a boner now
it's the same psychology how is this any
different the same with with a bit
of scientific wrapping around it another
example stinging nettle yes it increases
testosterone but it drops DHT not good
for pine pollen let's say there's enough
phyto testosterone in there for it to be
viable and let's say that we can absorb
it through our gut which again big if
should we actually take it here's the
Paradox either it is strong enough to
make a big difference in which case you
should not take it because it's likely
to downregulate your natural
testosterone production or it's too weak
to notice in which case why spend the
money I see guys freaking out when they
touch a receipt I see guys losing sleep
because they're so anxious about
optimizing their sleep I thought that
Health would be something that makes men
more robust but instead what's happened
is this hyperfixation on health has
actually made men more fragile I don't
like this phenomenon you must understand
health is not the goal health is the
foundation upon which to build an
amazing life you are not maxing
testosterone by being a hypochondriac
health nut with a drawer full of
supplements stop taking this weird
unless you actually know what you're
doing for example I had a a client and
he wanted me to help him increase his
testosterone okay I looked at his blood
work and his estrogen was too high I
asked him what supplements he was taking
he was taking the standard stuff you
know creatine whatever he was also
taking DHEA and pronone these are the
precursor molecules to testosterone so
he had heard online that taking these
precursors would help him support his
natural testosterone production but no
his body was just aromatizing all this
precursor to make more estrogen
eventually yes we fixed him we're able
to get him to a healthy 500 plus
nanogram per Des testosterone get him
lean and mean but my point here is got
to focus on the basics Excellence is
just the fundamentals done 100% of the
time to drive the point home I want to
scroll through some of these physique
updates in my communities everybody's
jacked to the gills and they're all just
fundamentalists they don't it's not that
they don't use supplements is that they
don't take their eyes off the
fundamentals now are all supplements
of course not there are some
supplement systems that are genuinely
powerful I'll show these to you but I
want to make the disclaimer that none of
this is medical advice it's going to be
dependent on your specific biology the
first good supplement system is boron
paired with iodine so Boron frees up
testosterone from its deactivated State
and generates more testosterone overall
at any given time only 2% of your
testosterone is actually activated most
of it is bound to this spherical carrier
protein called
shbg ideally we can get the free
testosterone above
2.5% the reason I suggest Boron where I
didn't mention zinc selenium or copper
simply because you can't get Boron from
food Boron is only naturally found in
some places on Earth like Greece and the
Middle East and these are the results of
long ago meteor strikes that predate
mankind begs the interesting question
Greece and Turkey and the Middle East in
general the Fertile Crescent are the
birthplaces of civilization the Persian
Empire of the zarrian the Assyrians and
the Babylonians the Trojans and the
Mesopotamians the um Hittites the
Phoenicians the Sumerians the acadians
in Greece we have of course the
legendary molossians the Athenians the
Spartans the atrans and the Corinthians
if you go even more north of Greece
you'll find the Brave thians and you'll
find of course a legendary of
macedonians who produced Alexander the
Great could it be that these meteor
strikes and the resulting Boron deposit
had a role to play in the history of
these tribes were the testosterone
levels of these men in these areas
boosted by the Boron causing them to
have a shift in their behavior and their
values as an entire Society accelerating
these tribes into the pages of History
worth studying also worth studying is
the opposite what happens if our tribes
in in the modern time lose testosterone
does this change values at a ital level
which well has negative consequences in
the game of History again word studying
by regarding Boron as a supplement Boron
is a powerful goitrogen which means that
you need to be pairing it with iodine to
balance it in terms of dosage 6 Mig of
boron is what I do plus two drops of
Lugal solution which is an iodine Source
two drops of 2% Lugal solution I should
say pairing Boron with iodine optimizes
testosterone as well as a thyroid
hormones this is an example of a
synergistic supplement system Boron on
its own would not be advisable but when
you pair it with iodine now it's a
Powerhouse balancing zinc with copper is
another example because zinc can
actually deplete copper in fact the um
firstman supplement you have a bunch of
zinc but you didn't have copper to
balance it out with in fact every
supplement I mentioned will be paired
with its counterpart to create a Synergy
now we go to vitamin D vitamin D is not
a vitamin it's just a hormone and it's
very valuable to supplement because
because we spend most of our days
indoors especially in the colder
climates now to be clear if you're
getting 30 minutes plus of direct
sunlight on your bare skin you don't
need supplementation I've been able to
leverage my biology to be able to build
a business that affords me the ability
to live in Hawaii so I don't need
Vitamin D supplementation but of course
I lived for almost a decade in uh West
Lafia at Indiana studying biosciences
and college so I know what it feels like
when the sky turned gray and you haven't
seen the Sun for like 3 months 6 months
even the winters tend to depress
testosterone and dopamine and you can
mitigate some of its effects with
vitamin D if you're taking vitamin D you
should pair it with vitamin K because
these two again have a synergistic
effect and the reason for this is D and
K balance each other with respect to
calcium intake together they can make
your bones insanely strong powerful for
martial arts and Military regarding the
dosage I actually have Revisited my
thoughts on vitamin D A lot over the
past years and now again it's not
medical advice but what I would do if I
was in a position where I did need
supplementation was to go 10,000 IU per
day yes the number sounds like a lot but
in terms of the actual biological
effects it's not that uh outrageous till
10,000 IU is what I would personally do
now we come to King creatine it's safe
it's cheap it's more efficacious than
99% of supplements out there that are 10
times the price when we think of creatin
we think of gains in the gym but it's
way more than that it's truly a
mitochondrial support supplement and
wherever does mitochondria creatine can
work its magic yes muscle cells do
contain mitochondria so creatine can
help you lift more volume but the brain
neurons actually have more mitochondria
concentration this means that the actual
benefit of creatine is actually in the
cognitive benefits in fact if you look
at the scientific literature there's
more work done on Creatine as an
anti-aging agent or reversing cognitive
decline than even the gym stuff highly
valuable supplement you can parir
creatine by the way with methylene blue
to create another supplement system both
supplements work on mitochondria but
they're completely different overlapping
Pathways just to be clear you can
absolutely use each of them separately
it's just up to you whether you want to
pair them up creatin directly helps
amino acid synthesis it lowers oxidative
stress and it converts testosterone to
DHT ah but DHT DHT causes hair loss so
should you take creatine if you're
afraid of hair loss so here's the deal
creatine only causes hair loss if you
have a DHT receptor in your hair
follicles that is to say a sensitive DHT
receptor in your hair follicles so how
would you know this either you can take
a DNA test and it'll straight up say you
have the gene for hair loss or you can
just try the creatine and as you are
showering your hair if you find that
more hair is coming off just stop taking
the creatine and you'll just regrow your
hair follicles you'll get your hair back
so it's up to you the trade-off that you
want to make do you want to have the DHT
or do you want to have the hair and
that's not something that I can
recommend you that's up to you now we
come back to the herbal supplements
these get a lot of hype on the internet
tonat Ali foda aesus however you say it
ashwagandha and the rest these are to be
seen as medicine for example if you have
a date lined up then if you take ton cut
early in the morning might lead to some
pleasant surprises later on if you know
what I mean so it's very situational
these are medicines these are not
supplements in the sense that you don't
take them on a day-by-day basis
ashwagandha is also very situational it
has the ability to numb stress so if you
have a big project coming up and you
have you know that you're going to be
stressed out you know that you're going
to have sleepless nights then ashwag
Ganda can dull the stress response it'll
also dull any happiness response so it's
one of those things where if you know
you're going to have to grind it out and
there's no source of Happiness anyway it
makes sense to D everything and go
hardcore work mode I personally don't do
this I instead rely on other me methods
for dealing with stress which I will
build up in the fifth module of this
course now what about the basic
micronutrients for testosterone like
zinc selenium copper I don't think you
need to supplement with any of these I
think you can get these from diet so red
meat and eggs contain all of these and
More in more bioavailable forms if you
can't get red meat then just double down
on the eggs you can have like eight eggs
per day that's all the micronutrients
you'll need you don't have to spend
money on zinc and whatnot at the end of
the day the key point I'm trying to
drive here is that health is a system of
interlocking systems so if you think
that buying the next latest and greatest
supplement is going to change your life
you are mistaken before I close out this
video we must zoom out what is it that
we are trying to achieve with these
supplements in the first place what's
the dream outcome for you what does your
dream lifestyle look like what would you
be working on if you knew you couldn't
fail don't sacrifice for your dreams
your dreams become the sacrifice