inferior turbulent mucosal reduction
they literally wanted to put a drill up
my nose and carve out the center bone a
little bit so that I could finally
breathe with my nose that's how bad the
situation was until I finally embraced
the esoteric Health methods which I'm
going to show you I don't use any of
these sprays these steroid sprays and I
finally can breathe better than I've
ever breathed before and even just from
my voice you can tell that breathing is
not a problem for me anymore first thing
you got to do is stop using these things
so this is the thing which gave me a lot
of problems this substance will
literally cause the inner membrane of
your nose to grow new wanes and arteries
and actually swell and grow in size to
the point they actually need surgery to
get it out this was given to me by a
doctor be careful what you learn or do
even if it's from a medical professional
so all I'm going to say about that so I
have stopped using these sprays entirely
and I'm going to show you the esoteric
methods which I have found which have
been used for thousands of years and
continue to be effective starting with
your new friend alkalol so I found this
substance is so good this is completely
organic it's only made of herbal oils so
this is an excellent product they give
you the alcohol alcohol with this little
nasal dispenser thing I'll show you how
to use these but also I want to
introduce you to the Neti Pot but this
is also an ancient invention like
historical records we can find it in the
museum these exact things dating
thousands of years ago this has been
used by humans for God knows how long so
this plus the alcohol alkalol plus these
salt packets solve 90 of your issues all
right I'm going to show you how to use
it so what you do take the salt packet
one thing of salt take the alcohol just
a bit of alcohol then you add water and
I'll put b-roll on here which shows you
how to use it so basically what you do
is you add the water and then you go to
your bathroom you go to your sink and
then you put the spout on one nostril
and then tilt it so that the water flows
up one nostril and then out the other
nostrils it'll just clean the entire
nasal exactly and that way he'll remove
any allergens the alcohol is very
interesting well it does it it kind of
irritates the nose a little bit and
allows it to eject all the excess mucus
immediately and the salt buffer is there
so that there's no dryness in the nose
so the salt plus the alcohol plus the
Neti Pot amazing combination I don't see
anybody else suggesting it so I'm I'm
glad to bring this method to your
Consciousness that's about the Neti Pot
and then we have the other things on
this list so we have the Breathe Right
Strips right that's what I'm putting on
my nose right now I use this when I'm
sleeping it just expands the nasal
passages a little bit so that you have
better nose breathing and you're less
prone to mouth breathing but even then
when I'm sleeping I have tape I'll just
take a small strip of tape and something
like that put it over my mouth that'll
prevent my mouth from opening when I'm
sleeping and that ensures that I'm only
nose breathing when I'm sleeping that
plus the nasal strip works wonders I get
maximum quality sleep speaking of sleep
if you want the esoteric sleep guide let
me know in the comments right and so
that's Max maximizes My Sleep Quality
among many other sleep practices which
you surely will learn in the future so
how often should you use the Neti Pot
and how often should you use the alcohol
twice a day or once a day so it depends
on how much you need it right I use it
twice a day I do it once in the morning
immediately after I wake up and once
just before sleeping now even if you
didn't have a runny nose or a stuffy
nose or any symptoms you should still do
this thing you should still use a Neti
Pot maybe once a day okay even if you
don't use a Neti Pot that's fine you
should still be taping your mouth and
using a breath trip for your sleep it's
going to increase your power output
because it gives you more oxygen the
more oxygen your body can use the more
energy it can produce so more
productivity more relaxed and better
feeling throughout the day breathing is
everything if you aren't breathing right
you aren't living right and I will
finish this video off with a breath
practice which I've learned my
grandmother taught it to me and it's
amazing it's a combination of breathing
and meditation it works really well it's
great for mental health and of course
the breathing which is physical health
Oh and before I forget when you're
putting water into the Neti Pot it has
to be purified water filtered water or
distilled water or boiled water at least
otherwise you're going to get an
infection you're going to get a brain
infection you like might actually die
because of it so be careful what water
you're using and before we get into the
breathing practice mewing so mewing is
an interesting one because I've never
actually done it let me or rather I've
always done it so I didn't know that the
term was mewing until a couple years ago
I've always just always kept my tongue
in the roof over the mouth like mewing
says to do and you know I'm pretty happy
with my face structure right and before
I teach you the breathing practice
cardio does cardio help absolutely
cardio will boost your productivity
throughout the day by giving you more
oxygen more energy and I don't like
running I find running really boring so
I do the others other more fun cardios
do Hills prints Hill Sprints are just
much more fun than just regular Sprints
and then there's of course Barrel carry
so buy yourself a big barrel of water
and just hoist it on your shoulder and
start walking up some stairs that's
killer cardio most important type of
cardio that there is which is simply
just walking I'm not talking about
jogging I'm not talking about fast
walking I'm just talking about just
walking nice and slow in the morning
preferably in nature but not necessary
so this is one of the key components of
my esoteric morning routine this is
important because as you're walking
around you're gonna breathe nice and
deep you're using your diaphragm to
breathe your diaphragm is the muscle at
the base of your lungs you're using your
diaphragm tonight be nice and deep into
the belly inside just your upper chest
and what that does is it oxygenates you
so you're increasing your oxygen intake
in the morning exactly when you want it
so you can have that energy through the
rest of the day if you're doing it
outdoors in nature that's even better
for the of course the mental health
benefits and what's especially important
for the dopamine system is the sunlight
what you might not know is the eyes the
retina behind the eyes is actually an
important part of the dopamine system
and what happens there is as you expose
yourself to early morning sunlight and
honestly doesn't even have to be early
morning like right now it's just
um nine nine a.m closing yourself to
sunlight allowing sunlight to hit your
retina is an important important part of
your dopamine system and that way you
essentially recharge the amount of
dopamine in your body every morning and
then we are finally here at the
breathing exercise which I promised you
this is what you do take your right hand
fold your index and middle fingers let
me Center myself a little bit and you
can do this sitting down on the floor
you can sit on the chair like how I'm
doing it doesn't really matter I like to
Do It Outdoors in the morning but here
we are I'm doing this for the video
right
so what you do and and hear this
carefully so what you do is you cover
one nostril with your thumb and take an
inhale with the open nostril and then
you close that and open the other
nostril and you let the air out and then
you'll take in air
and then let it out so in
out
in
and out
what this does now it is kind of fast I
did it fast because I'm on camera and
this is a video and all that right but
ideally I do it at my own pace really
slow really be mindful about my
breathing
and this is like meditation on steroids
meditation is difficult because you get
bored right your mind wanders and the
whole point of meditation is to bring it
back to the breathing or at least be
conscious of the wandering I understand
I understand but meditation is hard this
is much easier and in many ways equally
effective what you're going to do is
you're going to be focusing on the
breathing and you're going to be
focusing on that pacing and that that
makes your mind focused the breath is an
interesting thing most of the day you're
breathing and you're breathing
unconsciously of course if you don't
want to be paying attention to your
breath throughout the day but you can
you can voluntarily breathe you can
choose the pacing of your breathing you
can breathe voluntarily and also it's an
involuntary function correct so when you
breathe voluntarily with intention and
having attention on the breath it tells
your body that you're not in flight or
fight mode it tells your body that it's
in relax and rest and digest mode and by
giving your body that sense of calm
because this is how you communicate with
your body your mind doesn't want to be
stressed but your mind doesn't get to
choose that your body may be stressed so
you tell the body you know there's no
physical threat you're fine relax and
you can do that by using the breath as
the language the breath is the language
between your mind and your body you can
use the breath to communicate with the
body and say calm down there's no
physical threat you can relax you can
reset you can breathe so in summary
every morning do this breathing exercise
as I showed you it will change things
for you I guarantee you it might change
things more fast than meditation could
it might be more effective than
journaling even so 100 high Roi habit
100 I guarantee and there we have it
that is the esoteric breathing guide if
this guide was helpful perhaps you want
to know about the skin care how do you
look better how do you look smacks how
do you get the best quality skin and
hair to do that go and look at my
esoteric skin care guide might be
helpful
[Music]
thank you