I am going to show you how to do lucid
dreaming correctly there's a lot of
these methods online like wild and Mild
these are all trash I will show you the
right way how to do lucid dreaming and
in fact chemically indued lucid dreaming
using the lucid dreaming Elixir all
right so let me get my
marker all right boys so here's the
thing about lucid dreaming right first a
lot of people don't even believe that
it's true it is absolutely true and the
science actually backs this they did
three experiments which I can recall
which actually prove that it is true the
first experiment they ask these people
who claim to be lucid dreamers to
visualize a triangle and they take the
electrical impulses in an F fmri scan
and they ask them to dream when they're
sleeping and it's the same exact results
which they get proving that they have
control over their dreams and they can
visualize what they said they would
visualize another experiment which they
did is they told the scientists they
told the these lucid dreamers what
pattern to move their eyes while they're
dreaming and they tracked their eye
movements while they were dreaming and
they were able to consciously mimic that
same exact pattern showing that they
could actually have control over their
surroundings and their eye movement even
during their dreaming phase they did
other experiments too like clenching the
fist the same they told the lucid
dreamers to clench their fist as they
Lucid dreamed and the exact same
chemical sorry electrical signals which
happened when you clinch a fist happened
when they were dreaming so lucid
dreaming is a fact there's no question
about this in fact I believed in it
let's say because of Tim Ferris Tim
Ferris is the author of The 4-Hour Work
week and I mean you probably know Tim
Ferris right so Tim Ferris actually has
a story where he talks about wrestling
so he got good at wrestling by
practicing wrestling as he slept during
lucid dreaming and that skill actually
carried over into his practice the next
day so that immediately got me curious
It's like that's a super power if I can
practice stuff and get good while I'm
sleeping that gives me a genuine Edge
over the competition so that's why I
started doing it in the first place and
there's a certain reason I stopped doing
it and now I'm picking it up again
because I want to get good at these live
lectures and every bit of practice helps
so what are the benefits that you can
expect from lucid dreaming the first one
is of course the rehearsals like I
mentioned but it doesn't have to be just
rehearsals you can rehearse anything you
can rehearse specifically social
interactions
suppose you are a shy guy you know you
don't have confidence in public
understand suppose you kind of have some
kind of insecurities about your physique
your face whatever it is right you can
actually practice social interactions in
your lucid dreams suppose you have
trouble speaking to girls as every guy
does at some point in their life you can
practice and put in the Reps in the
comfort of your dreams you can play the
scenario out in any number of ways as
you sleep and yes absolutely this skill
does carry over and indeed this was one
of the first skills I was trying to
improve on while I mastered lucid
dreaming the most important component of
course is not any of these things it's
actually the Improvement of the
self-image I've told you this before in
a previous lecture the one on
brainwashing which was yesterday that
your success always lags behind your
self-image if by some chance your
success gets ahead of your self-image
for example if you win a lottery win a
dollar but your self image is still
behind you will actually be confronted
with immediate and successive failures
until that success comes back behind
your self-image so the real way to have
genuine lasting Improvement in life is
to improve the self-image and you can do
this using lucid dreaming I'll of course
pad it out and give you the full
autistic level steps soon I'm sure you
must be you know eager to learn this
lucid dreaming Elixir so let's get into
it I will warn you that this El will
actually work on the first night all
right this is a chemically induced lucid
dream but I don't recommend you do it on
the first night because you aren't
really looking for the lucid dream as
such you want the benefit of lucid
dreaming so I want you to follow the
protocol which I've laid out for you
there's nothing like this on the
internet if you want the benefits of
lucid dreaming please just do what I'm
saying just have trust and just adhere
to this all right lucid dreaming does
have some dangers which I will walk
through but if you do these then you
will get the best of it without any of
the risks so let's start talking about
the protocol hopefully you can see this
and the camera is not like too close to
me or anything hopefully by the grace of
God the camera is pointing in the right
direction today cuz yesterday it was
pointing the other direction I made you
guys watch grass grow literally for 30
minutes so let's talk about week one so
this is a two week program week one is
recall so in week one you are not
actually trying to induce lucid dream
dreaming all you're trying to do is
improve your dream recall all right so
dream recall is basically how well can
you remember your dreams if you're the
kind of guy who just has felt like you
never had a dream that you could
remember then this is most important for
you and I'm going to teach you the Casio
method I don't think there's anybody
online who's who understands this
concept well enough to have a method
like this so the Cassio method comes
from this my watch this Casio which of
course you don't have to have exact
watch and you don't even have to have a
Casio for that matter you can have any
kind of digital watch which has an
hourly chime function the hourly chime
function is basically I set it up such
that every single hour like 12:00 1:00
2:00 it will beep and I'll notice that
beep I'll look at my watch and let me
explain this very carefully all right so
the hourly chime function after it's
enabled makes you do something called
full day mindfulness so full day
mindfulness is kind
of a relaxed state of mind throughout
the day because every single hour you're
being reminded to be mindful when that
hourly chime Chimes you'll look at your
watch look at what time it is take a
deep breath let it out be very aware of
the environment like literally every
detail like I'm looking at a beautiful
scenery of grass in front of me and I'm
looking at every single blade of grass
every leaf that's fallen down the
concrete under my
shoes the feeling of this you know
whiteboard against my hand the
environment the warmth against my skin
take another deep breath let it out and
become aware of the body itself so the
feeling of my the pressure I'm applying
on the surface the feeling of breath
going into my lungs bodily awareness so
there two components right environmental
awareness and body awareness and you're
doing this at the time of every hour and
I'll explain exactly why this is
happening the other continent is the
reality check so if you have ever looked
at lucid dreaming videos online before
you'll be aware of the idea of reality
checks and the most common reality check
is doing this like I have in my mind the
intention of pushing my finger through
my palm and obviously it doesn't happen
because I'm not
dreaming but in the dream I could
actually do this because in the dream
you kind of control the physics you can
do what you want so the reality check
which I'm going to give you is take your
watch right you're already concentrating
on the watch cuz you looked at it for
the hourly Chim you're going to try to
slide it off have it in your mind I can
slide off my watch obviously it doesn't
happen because I'm in reality right now
I'm not dreaming so the watch doesn't
come off that's a reality check if the
watch does come off you know that you
are in a dream and then we have the
totem so the totem is your watch so
understand what I'm doing here I'm
creating a system where this watch has
become your tie to reality have you seen
the movie Inception they each like
character in Inception they have this
specialized item which they carry which
is their totem and they use this totem
to distinguish between what's a dream
and what's reality that's exactly the
concept I'm going for here by tying
together the mindfulness aspect of your
body and the environment to this
physical object this Casio watch and by
kind of practicing this reality check
for the first one week you have encoded
these thought patterns and this Behavior
pattern and it's tied to this physical
object this watch so when you are in a
dream which you aren't going to be
inducing a dream right now right you're
going to be inducing a dream only in
week two when you're starting to induce
lucid
dreams and you have these mental habits
and these physical habits this will be
your tie to reality and you'll know when
you're in a dream when you're not and
when you're loose to Dreaming you can
use that essentially as your tether to
what's real and what's not all right so
that's the totem your CIO watch and then
you're going to keep this watch either
on you you're going to actually wear it
when you're sleeping or you can actually
take it off and put it next to your
pillow if you want because that hourly
chime is still important so the hourly
chime has become your your queue for
mindfulness and this practice of trying
to take your watch off that queue stays
with you even in your REM sleep so when
you are sleeping you're deep in sleep
but your ears are still working when
your ears hear that chime it's going to
send to your brain hey remember we're
supposed to we're supposed to be mindful
right now we're supposed to take this
watch off right now and in your dream
you'll actually have that sensation
you'll have a sensation to be more
Vigilant of your dream and then you
start realizing that you are in a dream
because the dream doesn't really look
like reality it's it's just odd and
you'll have you kind of a feeling right
you start observing things and they
don't have the same kind of resolution
as they do in real life it might be hazy
might be blurry things aren't making
logical sense I mean it's a dream right
it's literally a dream and then you have
the sensation maybe I'm in in a dream
try to take off your watch and it comes
off there you go boom lucid dream that's
the concept of the Casio method and then
I also want you to Habit stack this
thing called journaling I mean you
obviously know what's journaling but
this is specifically dream journaling so
what you're going to be doing is you're
going to have a journal next to your bed
and whenever you have a dream for the
first one week you're not trying to
induce any Dreaming by the way it's just
like Preparatory phase every time you
have a dream during the first week
you're going to journal about it
specifically you're going to be focusing
on the environment write a couple
sentences two or three sentences about
the place where you find yourself in
your dream for me I have a lot of Dreams
in nature which is you know I like that
so I'll describe the nature around me
the Greenery and I think it's probably
because I spent a lot of time of my
childhood in nature like literally
climbing trees eating raspberries right
off the branches spending all my time
kind of alone but with nature I think
that's kind of seeped into my
subconscious and that's why I love this
setting so much so environment the
second thing you Journal about is
symbolism so often times in dreams the
objects that you see have a deeper
meaning to them and you may not be able
to interpret them but that's fine just
write down what symbols you see for me a
recurring theme has always been Bridges
the setting of the dream could be
different I could be in a city I could
be in nature I could be in a desert but
there's always some kind of bridge even
though the bridge looks different that
tells me that that's a that's a
symbolism there's something going on in
my subconscious about a bridge and
Bridge can be a symbol for tying two
different things together could be a
symbol for going from one place to
another you know transition Point don't
know why but that's a symbol which
manifests in my mind so I'll write my
best interpretation of that symbol of
course your symbols can be completely
different a lot of religious folk will
see religious icons which is really cool
but it's completely different some
people will see birds very often they'll
see lizards lizards is a common one some
people have bad symbols too some people
will dream of teeth falling out and that
could be a symbol tooth could be a
symbol so write your best interpretation
for what that might be and then you talk
about your emotions in your your Journal
you're talking about the mood of your
dream happy sad lustful highly possible
that it's
lustful jealous envious depends on what
your subconscious is giving you and I
don't want you to shy away from
everything that's why I wrote no secrets
your dreams could be dark places man
your dreams can be dark places at times
but if you are hiding it that's not
helping even if your dreams are of a
some kind of a criminal nature it's
better to write it out than to suppress
it CU that's also a part of your
yourself it's the shadow learning side
of it and you know you and in more
modern times Jordan Peterson talks about
this the Shadow Self so you can have a
better relationship with that self only
if you don't have any secrets this is
your personal Journal like no one's
going to read this so be honest with at
least yourself next we go to week two
which is the actual induction phase now
we are consciously wanting to induce
lucid dreaming so in week one you are
not actually consuming this uh Elixir
week two you are but not just yet the
first thing you want to do is Express
intent for lucid dreaming so you are
going to before you sleep your last
three sentences that you tell to your
mind will be something like today I will
control my dreams today I will control
my dreams today I will control my dreams
and then you try to fall asleep right
that tells your mind what to do it's an
auto suggestion you're telling your mind
hey this is what's expected go according
to the
plan next is the mental rehearsal of a
dream so try to have a memory of a dream
that you had in the past I have this
very specific dream of me I was a child
in this dream because because like all
the bushes and everything were pretty
high so I knew that I was like you know
four or something like that and in this
dream there's a bridge like many dreams
and it's not even a real Bridge it's
like a Chasm between two grassy Hills or
or Cliffs there's a tree which is fallen
over forming a bridge and it's a
slippery tree it's like moss growing on
it and and there's a girl on the other
side and this is not any kind of sexual
dream right this girl is just a child
like myself so this child girl is on the
other side and I need to talk to her I
need to meet her I don't know why it's
important but it is and I start walking
on this bridge but every time I reach
the other side I wake up so I don't know
what the conclusion of that dream is but
I remember that dream pretty vividly so
I'll induce Dreaming by imagining that
dream and then eventually you fall
asleep and for whatever reason that
doing that increases the chance of lucid
dreaming induction
then let's talk about the aler all right
this is the chemical induction for lucid
dreaming and I have to have a medical
disclaimer I don't recommend lucid
dreaming I don't recommend any of
these substances which I'm going to talk
about this is not medical advice you
proceed at your own risk so this is not
something you may be familiar with this
is a bottle of methylene blue it's a
very special and interesting substance
this is actually a mitochondrial support
solution
and what this does is it has many
properties some of them are anti-aging
properties but that's not what we need
for this purpose and in fact Metaline
blue is not considered to be a sleep
supplement at all in fact it's a energy
inducing supplement makes you more
energetic it makes you more cogniz and
makes your brain power crank up it's an
overclocking type supplement but it also
has the function of increasing memory
memory recall by boosting up the
mitochondria in your brain so that's why
methylene blue is a core component of
this but meth blue is kind of like a
time bomb so mealine blue has 30 minutes
to 1 hour before it kicks in so you
don't want to have this 1 hour prior to
bed you want to have it immediately when
you're lying down to sleep cuz then you
fall asleep and then it activates which
is ideal you want it to activate once
you're already asleep not before cuz if
it's before then you're going to lose
sleep you're not going to be able to
sleep if Metaline blue is activated so
mein
blue then glycine glycine is a neuro
transmitter which it boosts the widness
of your dream it makes your dream come
to life it's more colorful it's just
more easy to remember it's
it's kind of cranks up the dream to 11
all right so glycine is for the
neurotransmitter benefit and then you
have something called zma zma is a
supplement it's zinc magnesium aspartate
so it's a zinc and magnesium supplement
basically it also contains vitamin B6 so
you can either buy zma or you can just
buy zinc supplement separately magnesium
supp supplement separately and B6
separately that's completely up to you
how you want to do it it's the core
components are the same if you are
struggling to sleep then perhaps leave
the zinc out because zinc is a little
bit of an axiory so just stick with the
Magnesium the B6 also if you have a
powerful um animal based diet you don't
really need B6 cuz you're getting plenty
of B6 through your animal based diet so
the main component is really magnesium
and if you if you want to cross out zma
by the the way let me tick these things
off I I wanted to tick these things off
as the video progress I thought that' be
cool progression but I forgot so here we
are talked about methylene blue talk
about glycine so zinc magnesium and if
you want to just do magnesium you can do
magnesium glycinate and just leave out
the zinc and leave out the B6 if that's
what you want to do all right so this B6
is an optional because if you're already
getting zma then you don't need an
additional source of B6 so that's why I
put a question mark you have two other
items Co and Valerian root these are
optional if you want you can try them I
have not needed them but I do think that
they help so Valyrian route is going to
relax you and Coline is going to again
boost recall of your dreams so it's
experimental I'm going to put a question
mark on these depends on your personal
biochemistry there's other things too
but these are the basics try these if
they don't work then put in the comments
and maybe I'll add other components to
The Elixir all right very powerful like
think about what's going on here the in
blue is boosting cognition and memory
recall and glycine is making your dreams
more lucid and more Vivid the zma on
itself is a powerful inducer of sleep
because of the Magnesium specifically B6
improves recall choline improves recall
Valerian gives you a more relaxed state
so together this is you know a one shot
success to get to lucid dreaming so we
talked about intent we talked about
mental rehearsals we talked about the
now we talk about programmable lights so
this is another tactic which I've never
seen anybody cover on YouTube because
most YouTubers don't know what the hell
they're talking about right there
actually a whole Channel called explore
lucid dreaming and he has the most basic
freaking advice you don't get basic
advice here boys you get the actual good
stuff so programmable lights there's an
I give you an example Philips Hue is a
kind of a programmable light which is
what I own you can kind of set up when
the light turns on you have a program
like you have a app on your phone which
you can use to set up when the lights
turn on so take your time of waking for
me it's usually 8:00 a.m. subtract 2 so
6 a.m. so minus 2 you get that time and
you use the holy it's getting windy
out here hopefully you can still here
because I have this um lav mic so the
programmable lights turned on 2 hours
prior to waking and what you're doing is
you're setting it on for 15 minutes and
then off for 15 minutes on 15 minutes
and then off for 15 minutes and you're
not getting it too bright you're just
getting it bright enough that it induces
some kind of wakefulness in you what I
mean by that is doesn't straight up wake
you up because it's so bright but it
just tells your brain hey be alert and
doing that induces lucid dreaming so
follow this protocol and use this Elixir
and it's like 80 to 90% guarantee that
you're going to get lucid dreaming
finally the question is once you
reliably induce lucid dreaming what do
you do with that new found power what
you do is first you find yourself a
mentor so you can actually find high
quality me not even find make your own
Mentor cuz you're are lucid dreaming
right so what you do is choose whichever
influencer or even historical figure
that you want to emulate or get advice
from and you can actually bring them
into your lucid dream so I did this and
it's kind of cringe now but I did this
with Jordan Peters
and this was before he joined daily wire
this is before his mental breakdown
which I don't know something bad
happened to him during that one year and
when he came out he was just not the
same I didn't like him anymore I didn't
have the same respect but during the
first you know 6 months of his rise I
really liked him I really liked his
message I really liked his Charisma I
lik the fact that he knew so much about
the world which I didn't so I watched a
lot of his content with the intention of
I'm going to create this Jordan Peterson
in my mind and I can use him for advice
and M mentorship in my dream you can do
this for anybody right if if hamza's
message really resonates with you and
list Hamza as your personal Mentor just
watch a lot of his content absorb his
way of speaking the kind of advice that
he gives and then have the intention of
bringing him to life in your dream next
item is future sight this is something
that you should definitely do even if
you don't do mentorship because
mentorship like creating a a file of a
person in your dream is a challenge but
future site is something you should
absolutely do I talked about this
yesterday's lecture
future sight is the art and craft of
bringing to life your future self before
he has even Arisen so I bring to life my
30-year-old version of myself and I
imagine that's this man he's stronger
than me he has calluses on his arm his
neck is thicker his voice is deeper his
Charisma his presence is more powerful
he's a better Storyteller he's a nine
out of 10 Storyteller he has an
abundance mindset with money I'm not
there yet right I'm not 30 yet but I can
Envision that 30-year-old version of
myself in the lucid dream and get
mentorship From My Future Self and
thereby become him before I have to
become him thereby basically I'm using a
shortcut imagine if you're you know 16
17 you visualize the 25y old version of
yourself now you have the maturity and
understanding and attitude of an older
version of you and you're still
competing with fellow 16-year-olds how
powerful is that that's the power of
Luci dream man you bend reality to your
will and use that to bend the actual
reality to your will next okay I don't
know if I want to talk about this one
you can PR you can practice sex all
right you can practice sex in your lucid
dreams don't get too carried away but
you can and it does carry over to real
life it makes you more mindful makes you
more present makes you enjoy the
experience
more I don't know how much I want to
share about
this
all right I'll tell you some guidelines
all right don't get carried away don't
do it every single day I don't know what
effect it has on the dopamine circuits
like you know watching porn does it's
not the same though um I've experimented
with it I don't understand the
neurochemistry I'll be completely honest
I don't think anybody has studied this
no scientist even the foremost experts
doesn't know what's going on over here
but it's real it's different from
visualizing porn on the Internet cuz
you're making a reality it has a
different effect on the dopamine
circuitry it's not a ative effect but
like anything I want to caution you that
you know too much of a good thing is a
bad thing right so I want to give you
that
disclaimer next we have triumphs so you
have core memories everybody has won at
something in the past everybody has some
kind of victory in their life I want you
to relive those core Victory memories to
shape the person that you are right now
so future sight was looking forward
Imagining the Victorious triumphant
future you and bringing him here core
memories is when you look at the past
and relive memories which you have
already have been seeing success in so
one of mine is I remember this very very
vividly and I'm I'm young like super
young I think like fifth grade or maybe
fourth grade even I run out of my school
bus and I have this silver metal with a
green ribbon around it I'm running to to
my mom because I was so proud I had won
this Science Olympia at something like
super nerdy stuff but I'll never forget
it because was a m of Triumph for me and
I use that to remind myself that I have
the mental ability to solve any kind of
problem I am I believe myself to be
gifted enough to crack any kind of
problem using my intellect is it true or
not doesn't matter I manifest a reality
that's helpful for me in my life and
then finally we have the rehearsals so
this is what Tim Ferris was talking
about you know rehearsing uh wrestling
before he had to do any kind of
competition you can use this for
anything you can use this for any kind
of musical instrument you can use this
for talking to girls you can use this
for public speaking like what I do so
the reason I started doing lucid
dreaming again is specifically for these
calls these are live streams so I don't
really have any kind of crutch I don't
have notes that I can read and deliver I
can't edit this too much in post I don't
have ai generated images to drive
engagement it's just kind of me chilling
with you in real time having a
conversation trying to impart some kind
of knowledge that I have but even so
this is a YouTube video and this is of
course a business I need these videos to
perform yeah that's just the truth of it
right any YouTuber who says otherwise is
lying so the question is like how do I
make a compelling video but do it
without notes do it without editing I
practice this in my sleep before I come
on stage this is essentially a kind of
stage well a personal stage cuz I'm
trying to talk to one of you and that's
that's a part of the lucid dreaming self
hypnosis I'm trying to talk as
personably but in a prepared way to one
person now it's a question whether that
comes off like that on camera or not but
that's the thing you can practice any
kind of scenario that you want you can
modify this oh and I should also say
Metaline blue is not FDA regulated all
right so the quality control is all all
over the
place so you can only get it from some
places which have the highest C C
ification rating it's called a
certificate of analysis uh yeah
certificate COA right it's a it's called
a pharmaceutical certificate of analysis
and there's also something called the
USP rating so you need to look for these
two components in order to make your
purchase cuz a lot of brands are selling
bad quality methine blue which have
heavy metals which are probably doing
more harm than good so you want the good
quality stuff the one which I use is
called maroi medicinal all right I don't
know how well you can see it but Mari
medicinal you can see I've gone through
quite a bit of it this is the brand that
I recommend I actually reached out to
them so that I can read their COA which
is the certificate of analysis and
actually make sure that they are you
know being truthful to their claims so I
talk to them I even got a discount code
for 15% off I think so if you use a
discount code you're going to get 15%
off it's up to you if you want to use it
or not so that's my disclaimer about
methine blue do not get the Amazon
Brands there's a lot of brands on Amazon
which are just selling methine blue they
claim to be USP verified I don't know if
that's true I know that this brand is
actually verified so just choose this I
hope it's available across the world I
don't know but if you're in the US for
sure you can get it and I have a
challenge for you so as you know these
lectures are not free I have a fee for
these one of them is the homework so the
homework for today is write down in the
comment section below or in if you're in
calls Country Club my private Community
for health and education you should do
this in the col Country Club instead go
to the challenges category and write
this down you're going to write why you
want to do lucid dreaming because when
you connect a why to what you're going
to do that's when you see success and I
want you to you got a bunch of knowledge
right I taught you a bunch of things
immediately connected to your why and
then write it down in the comments or in
colge Country Club I will assess and I
will give feedback as
required finally I'll say that
tomorrow's lecture is actually going to
be a whole lecture on methylene blue
because I believe it's that important
this chemical has many applications I
think you should be educated on its on
its uh importance yesterday's lecture
was about brainwashing yourself for
success I think that goes really well
with this lecture so you haven't watched
that you absolutely should I teach three
other techniques other than lucid
dreaming to brainwash yourself and then
the supplements I mentioned I've
mentioned uh glycine zma B6 Etc I have
the Amazon page for those exact
supplements including the lights and the
watch actually so you can check out the
supplements and everything in the Amazon
link and of course I should mention the
risk of lucid dreaming there's the
reason I stopped doing lucid dreaming
which is lucid dreaming actually takes
away from the restfulness of sleep
because you're using your sleep also as
a training device so when you do that
you aren't getting the full restorative
benefits of sleep on top of that there's
another thing you're not that wise you
know you don't have that much wisdom and
nor do I so when you're taking control
of your subconscious like this you're
basically say to your subconscious hey
this is what we're going to focus on
let's focus on this but the thing is in
life you often don't know what the right
thing to focus on is so your
subconscious has its own wisdom and
sometimes it's better to let go of the
wheel and let the subconscious rehearse
whatever it wants to rehearse so I was
doing lucid dreaming for quite a while
almost a year more than a year probably
and I let it go because I wasn't getting
the restful sleep that I wanted and also
I wanted to leave the rains and let the
subconscious take over for for some time
now that I have a definite intent of
getting good at these video calls I want
to bring back lucid dreaming and take
command of my subconscious so it depends
on you where you are in life I recommend
getting a Mastery of the skill and then
when you don't need it just don't do it
so you can actually induce this right I
told you how to induce this chemically
so just don't take the Metaline blue at
night and you won't lose a dream also I
should speak about the timing of these
um of The Elixir so the glycine zma B6
choline valerian root you can have it an
hour before bed because if you drink a
lot of liquids just before you sleep
it's likely that you want to piss and
then you're going to disrupt your sleep
cycle right so you can have all these an
hour before bed so that you have an
opportunity to urinate and then you
aren't interrupted when you are actually
dreaming but the methylene blue is
different the methylene blue you have it
just before sleeping like you have it
then go to your bed so how much of it do
you have uh you have 5 Mig which is one
let me actually show you this stuff it's
it's actually just one dropper of
mealine blue just before you sleep so
that's the recommendations on
dosage finally I'll say that if you like
me and I'm not talking about my content
if you like me personally then you
should follow me on Instagram cuz I
always share these little nuggets of
knowledge as I go about my day and I
think it will greatly benefit you and
also if you just want to know me
personally right Instagram is the way to
go there we have it boys that's the
lecture for today I appreciate
appreciate your time watching this if
you have any questions leave them in the
comments I'll try to answer them and
also tell me would you like private
coaching from me something I've been
pondering and I haven't made that offer
yet but if that's something you're
interested in then put in the comments
maybe I'll create a private coaching
product so there we have it boys good
day I'm going to enjoy my gorgeous day
here in
Hawaii peace