Jeffrey wakes up. He's already late to
school. But he grabs his phone.
Jeffrey's depressed. Is this all there
is to life? Just go to school, go to
work, and then die? Isn't there someone
who can show Jeffree a better way?
Adonis.
Adonis takes Jeffrey under his wing and
shows him the ultimate life for young
men. He teleports him to Barley,
surrounded by other masculine men.
They're lifting weights. They're talking
to girls. They're eating good food. He
lives in a beautiful villa. He drives a
motorbike. He makes money online. You
can achieve this, Jeffrey. There's a
whole world out here just waiting for
you to take life by the horns. Poof.
Wait, wait, wait, wait. What? We're back
in Jeffrey's room. Was it all a dream?
Did that actually happen? Oh, Jeffrey's
going to slump back into his old ways,
isn't he? Wait, what is he doing? He's
writing something down on a piece of
paper. He's sticking that paper onto his
wall. What does it say? For the first
time in Jeffrey's life, he wrote down
his goals. He smiles and gets to work.
One day, when I was 10 years old, me and
my brother wake up early and we sneak
downstairs to play our favorite game,
Runescape. We're not allowed to play
video games in the home cuz my dad tells
us not to. But my mom lets us. But since
it's a Sunday and he's not working
today, me and my brother have this habit
where every Sunday we wake up early, we
grab our walkietalkies and one of us
stands near the stairs just hearing out
for the noises that my dad might make if
he wakes up whilst the other one plays
the this video game like on the computer
for like 5 minutes at a time and then we
switch and switch and switch. I was
addicted to this game. It's kind of like
an MMO RPG. You have like a character in
this virtual world and you can literally
play this game for thousands of hours
without completing it. So that's what I
did. Age 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15.
Every day, hours and hours and hours
just put into the virtual world. I'm sat
there with pizza, Doritos,
Lucasade, like Mountain Dew, energy
drinks, brownies, and chocolates, just
eating and playing. Whilst all the kids
are learning to socialize and be
confident with girls and going to sports
clubs, every day I'm just playing video
games, eating junk food, and watching
porn and jacking off two, three times
every single day through my teenage
years. I get to 18, 19, 20 years old,
eating junk food, like the unhealthiest
food, you know, the from the takeaway
where it's fried chicken with this
greasy sauce or it's from the
supermarket, these bags of cookies,
staying up late drinking. Eventually, I
start smoking weed every single day,
which of course, weed is the perfect
companion to the life I was already
living, playing video games every day.
By this point, I'm playing like Fortnite
with my roommates. We're smoking every
day. We're drinking two, three, four
times a week. were eating junk food. My
entire teenage years and early adult
years were just spent consuming. It went
from being so fun and so wholesome, like
sneaking downstairs with my brother to
play this video game, like 5 minutes
each, to eventually me just being like a
21-year-old
loser. I didn't take life seriously.
What was once fun
turns into mundanity,
boredom,
depression. Whilst other kids were
taking life seriously and studying and
working hard, I was just grinding in the
virtual world. And so when I get to
about 21, 22 years old, I find myself
just working my first ever full-time
job. And I hate my life. This one day, I
wake up sleepd deprived as always. get
ready for work, put on my tie, walk out,
and it's cold and dark and miserable. I
get onto the tram, like the public
transport, and there's almost no one on
there. There's like one other guy on the
other side wearing like a high viz vest.
He's going to work early in the morning
as well. It goes through the city. I'm
cold, listening to my music, almost like
shivering, wearing my jacket. I've got
another 20 minute walk in like these
work shoes. get to the office, sign in
on the computer, say hello to my
co-workers who I've got nothing in
common with, and just do this mindless
work for the next eight hours, 9 hours
actually, because I have a 1 hour unpaid
lunch break. Finish work at 6:00 p.m.
The entire day is basically gone, and
I've made like £64.
Never mind the price of lunch and the
commute and everything. I've profited
like £55 today for an entire day of my
life. 20 minute walk to the tram and I'm
gonna walk fast because if I get there
just fast enough I might get the earlier
tram home but I I see it leave and I've
got to wait 12 minutes for the next one
and it's only 12 minutes but it's
[ __ ] like it feels so long. Wait the
12 minutes. The next tram comes it's
packed of everyone who's going home
after work. Everyone's just kind of
depressed. Every now and then there's
like a random [ __ ] angry crackhead
just being loud or whatever. You feel so
uncomfortable. I get off at my stop.
It's already dark outside. I've
basically not even seen the sun today.
Walk down the stairs. choose the
shortcut to get to my apartment
building. The shortcut's like kind of
undeveloped. There's no street lamps.
So, you have to use the flashlight on
your phone to be able to see the floor
cuz it's completely dark. I'm using the
flashlight
to walk over to my apartment. I can see
it in the distance and I am so
miserable.
I can't believe this is what life is
like. When you're young and you're in
school, you you know, you you feel like
it's going to last forever. the school
mindset, who you have a crush on, who
you're going to hang out with today,
what you're going to watch when you get
home. But when you become an adult, when
you grow up and you realize this is what
life is, it's miserable.
And so I go on my phone and I turn the
flashlight off. So I'm just in complete
darkness outside, like on this random
street. It's completely dark, like you
can barely see anything.
And I just start crying.
This is what life is. I'm depressed
and
it's my fault.
All those years when I was younger that
I was just playing video games and not
taking life seriously and just watching
porn and eating junk food, what I was
doing with all those bad habits was I
was stealing happiness from tomorrow.
That's the new view of depression that I
want you to have. The view, the idea of
depression that we've gotten from the
pharmaceutical companies and the
medicine and all this [ __ ]
modern-day world, the idea is that
depression is kind of this disease that
can strike you at once and you're just
stuck with it and you have to take these
pills. I'm here to tell you that that is
a complete and utter lie. It's from
companies that want to profit from your
misery. It doesn't even work. Everyone
believes these days that depression is
this random disease and I'm depressed
and I need to take this medication and
this and this and this and it doesn't
[ __ ] work. People who are depressed
stay depressed forever. So, I'm going to
tell you a better mindset, a better view
with depression. If you are depressed,
it's because you deserve it. It's
because you have done so much of the
instant gratification habits, the bad
habits like porn and video games and
junk food and staying up late. You've
done so many of those bad habits. Each
one of those bad habits steals happiness
from tomorrow. And when you keep doing
them, you stole so much happiness from
tomorrow that then you wake up and you
feel depressed. Instant gratification is
the word that you need to understand to
cure your depression. Instant
gratification basically just refers to
the things that we do that feel good
right now, but they steal happiness
tomorrow. Like junk food. Junk food
tastes nice right now, but then tomorrow
you feel kind of depressed because you
ate the [ __ ] food. You feel worse. your
stomach kind of hurts and you've gained
some fat. Porn. Porn feels good when we
watch it right now. It's like
stimulating. But the moment you get the
postnut clarity, it feels bad and it's
like we were up here. Porn makes us go a
bit higher. It feels good and
stimulating. But after we're done, we're
lower than the baseline that we started
at last time. On a short-term basis, if
we just take some junk food or play some
video games or watch some porn, our life
goes up a little bit, but then it goes
down lower than the baseline. But then
if you do this every day, the baseline
just keeps going lower and lower and
lower and lower. And that's the feeling
of depression. When you feel depressed,
it's because you have done so many of
these bad habits that you've just
lowered the baseline of your happiness
so much to now that you look into the
mirror and you're like, "Damn, I look
like [ __ ] I feel like [ __ ] I've had a
stomach ache for like 3 days straight. I
get headaches like twice a week. I've
been getting bad grades in school. I
have no future prospects with my career
or with a business. My physique looks
like [ __ ] There's no girls who are into
me. I'm kind of ugly. I don't like the
way that I look. I've got no confidence.
I've got no good friends. Of course, you
feel like [ __ ] because every day for the
past years and years and years, you've
been doing these activities that makes
tomorrow worse. When you eat junk food,
it feels good right now, but then
tomorrow is worse. When you watch porn,
tomorrow is worse. When you take drugs,
when you play video games, it all feels
good right now, but then tomorrow is
worse. When you overdose on instant
gratification activities for long
enough, then you feel depressed. So then
what's the big strategy to cure
depression in just 2 weeks? We need to
do the opposite of instant gratification
activities. Remember, instant
gratification is the bad habits that we
do that feel good right now, like porn,
video games, junk food, but then they
make us worse tomorrow. The opposite of
that is the delayed gratification
activities. They feel hard right now,
but then they make us better tomorrow.
Can you think of a few of those right
now? What feels hard right now, but then
makes you better tomorrow? Exercise,
meditation, reading books, learning,
walking in nature, socializing with good
people, learning skills, spending
quality time with people that you love,
with your family. These things can feel
kind of uncomfortable right now. Like
imagine if I told you go spend some
quality time with your mother or your
father. If you're really visualizing it,
a lot of the guys watching this might
feel a bit cringe thinking like, "Oh,
like how do you do that? Oh, I don't
know. Like we're not really the type of
family who does that." Or if I tell you,
"Go and exercise right now." Some guys
will be like, "Okay, exercise is fun for
me." But for a lot of people, they'd be
like, "Oh, I don't know. Last time I
exercised, it just kind of hurt and you
don't even see any progress, whatever.
It doesn't feel good." Delayed
gratification activities feel hard right
now, but then tomorrow your life is
better. Now, straight away, if we just
go and do a few sit-ups right now or a
few push-ups, tomorrow technically we're
better because, you know, we worked out
today, but you don't really notice
anything. But then, if you stick to it
for 3 months, there's a big difference.
If you stick to it for 3 years, you look
completely different. That's the way to
stop being depressed. We get depressed
because we've done so many of the
instant gratification, the bad habits
like porn and video games and junk food
and going to sleep late and waking up
and scrolling on our phones to the point
that we just stolen happiness from
tomorrow. And then we look around and
we're just miserable and we have no good
friends. We have no women in our lives.
We don't like the way that we look.
We're not confident. We're not healthy.
We've got physical pain, emotional pain.
We just live a [ __ ] life. Of course, you
feel depressed when your life is [ __ ]
But delayed gratification is the way out
of depression where we do the hard thing
today. Like we eat clean. When we eat
clean, it doesn't really feel so nice
right now. Especially if you're new to
eating clean. If you've been eating
clean for a while, then it starts to
feel good. But let's say you're like
you're used to eating like a normal
person, junk food, whatever. And then we
give you like a healthy meal. It's got
single ingredients. It's not processed.
You eat it. You're like, "Ah, it doesn't
feel stimulating. Doesn't feel good."
Whatever. Doesn't feel good. It feels
hard. But then tomorrow you're a little
bit healthier and a little bit fitter.
Now, if you do that again and again and
again, your baseline goes up. That is
the way out of being depressed. That's
the big strategy you need to think into
your own mind. I got depressed because I
did those bad habits that feel good in
the moment, but then they make you feel
worse long term. The way that I stop
being depressed is I do the good habits
that feel hard right now, but then in
the long term they make you feel better.
So now let's go over the four major
causes of depression. Each one of these
is like a form of like instant
gratification. It happened because we
are basically just like living the fun,
enjoyable, stimulating life right now
which is stealing from tomorrow. The
first major cause of depression in young
men is bad physical habits. Poor sleep,
lack of exercise, bad diets. These
things that just make you physically
feel like [ __ ] Like maybe you wake up
and you don't even have morning wood
anymore. Maybe you eat a diet that makes
your stomach rumble. Maybe you're not
even like drinking water or something so
you've got like a headache. Maybe you're
just scrolling for so long that your
head hurts and you just feel kind of
numb and your attention span's all
[ __ ] up. This is one of the major
causes of depression in young people.
They just spend hours scrolling on their
phone destroying their attention span.
Like their brains are literally
shrinking. They've got all these bad
basic level habits. Like they're not
going to sleep on time. They're going to
sleep at really inconsistent times. One
day it's 9:00 p.m. The other day it's
11:00. Right? You're probably thinking,
"Oh, that's not so bad. 9 9:00 p.m. then
11:00 p.m. the next day." that's really
terrible for your health. Or you're
eating different foods. You're eating
foods that like randomly you'll get the
[ __ ] afterwards or your stomach hurts.
You've got a headache. You're just doing
all these poor physical habits. This is
like the foundation of a good life that
you actually feel good in your body.
Now, the second major cause of
depression in young men is social
isolation. You've lived the kind of life
because of instant gratification
activities like video games where you
don't even have good people around you
because the craving of your social life
has been fulfilled with fake
brotherhood. We as young men desire
brotherhood status and recognition.
We're supposed to mix with other men, be
competitive, and grow. The problem is
these days it's just easier to do that
on video games. Imagine if technology
didn't exist. You would have such a pull
to hang out with the boys and then to do
competitive [ __ ] like martial arts or
lifting heavy weights to develop
yourself as a man because you wanted to
be respected by the other men around
you. Now that video games exist, instead
of craving that brotherhood in real
life, you crave it in Call of Duty.
Instead of getting your purple belt in
jiu-jitsu, you want to get the sixth
prestige in Call of Duty. Instead of
making money in real life so that you
have like this status and this feeling
of importance, you want to make money in
GTA or these MMO RPGs. We need to have
brotherhood in our lives in our physical
world, not just online, so that we have
this huge pull to succeed. Because look,
a lot of people online will tell you
that you don't need to like, you know,
like you shouldn't care what anyone
thinks about you. And I swear to God,
everyone who says that is a [ __ ]
Jeffrey little [ __ ] If you don't care
what anyone thinks about you, you're
probably a [ __ ] freak. Every guy that
I know that I respect very much cares
what his tribe thinks about him. He
cares what his family thinks about him.
He cares what the other strong men
thinks about him. You shouldn't care
about what like the peasants think about
you, the Jeffre, right? Let's say if you
start going to the gym, some of your
Jeffrey friends will look at you and be
like, "Ah, he's gay. He's going to the
gym." You don't want to care about what
they think, but you should think of some
like highlevel guys you know. Maybe you
think of like your big brother or this
one guy that you know who's successful.
Or maybe you just think about role
models in your life and you think,
"Okay, I know this sounds a bit cringe,
but I'd like to impress them. If I ever
meet Hamza, I want him to look at me and
be like, "Damn, bro." Like, you're in
good shape. It's that desire of the
feeling of importance and acceptance in
a male in like a masculine brotherhood
that causes you to really want to grow.
And there's nothing wrong with that.
That is a completely natural desire for
men. We want other men to see us as high
status, important, and competitive. In
the modern day, we're told that that's
like an insecure thing. It's not at all.
The guys who say like, "Oh, I've got no
ego. I don't care what anyone thinks of
me." They're the biggest [ __ ] [ __ ]
of all. They try and act like all
confident when they say this, but
they're like [ __ ] little skinny neck
little dweebs, out of shape, weird
people. You don't want to be like one of
those people, even though it sounds like
a flex. Like, I don't care what anyone
thinks of me. I'm telling you, no
[ __ ] masculine guy actually believes
that. Every masculine guy cares what
other people in his tribe think. Yeah,
you don't want the peasants to judge
you. Who cares about their perspective?
But I care what people think about me. I
care what my my followers think about
me. I care what my family think about
me. I care what my male friends think
about me. Because if they think badly
about me, that's a reflection of me
messing up. When I do good in life, when
I've been hardworking, I get more
respect from my friends. So therefore, I
can use the respect that I get from my
friends as a judgment of whether or not
I've been actually living to my
potential. other men in your life should
be able to pick out your weaknesses and
tell you that you're [ __ ] up, tell
you that you've been complacent. When
you don't have brotherhood in your life,
it's so easy to just get into these bad
habits and to just go sink away on the
internet and just go play video games
and just go sit at home. If you lived
with like masculine guys, imagine that
scenario. Imagine you lived with
masculine guys. Like imagine me, you,
and 10 other guys like us lived in the
same massive villa together. You would
not be jacking off in your bedroom. You
would not be in there playing video
games. There's a 0% chance. You know
why? Because I wouldn't let that happen.
The other guys in the house wouldn't let
that happen. If anyone was like in their
room all day would knock on, be like,
"What the [ __ ] are you doing, bro?
You're not jacking off, are you? You're
not playing video games. Okay, you're
just doing work. Okay, sweet." It'd be
so easy to get to competitive. One guy
drops down and starts doing push-ups.
The other guys would just [ __ ] start
as well. One guy says, "Our boys, let's
go spar today. Let's go box each other.
Everyone's down." You're just like 10
times more productive. When you don't
have brotherhood, it's so easy to get
into those bad habits, the porn, video
games, junk food, and then you feel
depressed. Now, the third cause of
depression in young men is having
nothing to look forward to. Having no
hope for the future. What does that
sound like? Think about it. Having
nothing to look forward to.
Delayed gratification. Remember what I
told you before? Instant and delayed
gratification. Delayed gratification is
when we do the good habits that feel
hard right now, but they make our life
better and better and better. Like
exercise. When you do the delayed
gratification activities, the good
habits like meditation, exercise,
journaling, reading, all those things
that develop you, right? They do feel
hard right now. I won't lie to you. They
feel hard and uncomfortable, but you
just know they make your life better
tomorrow and more and more and more. So,
when you do loads of delayed
gratification, good habits, you have
something to look forward to. When
you're consistently going to the gym,
you start feeling happy for the future
because you know you're going to get a
six-pack soon. That's what makes you
feel so hopeful and pleasant and it
gives you a positive outlook on life
when you don't have something to look
forward to which is basically instant
gratification. You almost don't want
time to pass, right? Imagine you're only
doing the bad habits. You know tomorrow
you're going to wake up with a worse
brain. You know that tomorrow you're
going to wake up with more fat on your
body. You don't have anything to look
forward to. You're literally the future
seems bleak. This is how guys get so
depressed and they even start getting
the desire to delete themselves because
they look to the future and they don't
see anything positive happening because
they keep doing the bad habits that
makes tomorrow worse and worse and
worse. Can you imagine just how bad of
an existence that is? And you probably
live this way where you're mostly just
doing the bad habits that makes tomorrow
worse. When you do so much of them, you
get to this point where you start
getting so depressed and you're so
nihilistic for the future because you
think when I wake up tomorrow, I'll be a
little bit fatter and more of a loser.
when I wake up the next day, I'll be a
little bit fatter and more of a loser
and over and over and over again. So,
you don't want it to be the future. You
don't see anything positive happening in
the future. So, of course, you get
depressed. You get this like nihilistic
sad kind of energy. And now linked with
this, the fourth cause of depression
that I see in young men is no purpose,
no mission, no contribution to others.
As a young man, the single most
important thing in your life, do you
know what it is? It's not girls. It's
not even your family. The single most
important thing in your life is your
goals, your mission, the purpose of your
existence. Basically, your mission is
like the big work that you're going to
spend the next 5, 10, 20 years of your
life on. And it's always best if you
feel like it contributes to others. What
is the mission of your existence? Who
are you contributing to? Most young men,
if you ask them, "What's your purpose?
What's your mission?" They'll be like,
"Oh, what? Unk so corny, bro? Dead rose
emoji." Like they're just kids who like,
"Oh, you're so corny, bro." They're
depressed, getting ready to [ __ ]
delete themselves, but they'll think
you're [ __ ] cringe. Corny because
you're talking about purpose or mission.
No, being [ __ ] suicidal is the corny
thing. Being suicidal is [ __ ] cringe.
Not the guy who's like got a purpose for
his [ __ ] existence, right? Most young
men, if you ever ask them like, "What's
the mission of your life?" They'll be
like, "What?" They'll have no idea what
the [ __ ] you mean. They'll try and clown
you and say that it's cringe or
whatever. And that's why they're all
depressed and their screen time's
[ __ ] obn like like crazy like [ __ ]
6 hours a day. And there'll be some guys
watching this thinking, "Oh [ __ ] like 6
hours is crazy. Mine's like 12." What is
the mission for your existence? What is
the big thing you're working on that's
going to help humanity? This isn't just
your work or your career. This is like
the thing that you wake up for and you
think, "Holy [ __ ] I am needed in the
world." Can you imagine how I feel?
Think about the kind of videos and the
work that I do. I wake up and I feel
like I'm needed in the world. There's
guys who come up to me with tears in
their eyes and they say they would have
deleted themselves if it wasn't for my
work. My mission is to help the young
men of the world. Can you imagine how
much like energy vitality that gives me?
I could never even be close to deleting
myself because I'm needed on this world.
When you feel like you're not needed,
then honestly, that's where those
thoughts come in where you're like,
well, look, I'm not needed. I'm just a
drain. My family would be better off
without me. That's how you get so
depressed and nihilistic and suicidal.
That's where you start to rationally,
not even with emotion, you start to
rationally just think like my family
would be better off if I died. Right?
This is because you are not contributing
to others. When you don't have a
mission, like this kind of work that you
feel like is helping others, then you
start to just get so depressed. You need
to have some kind of mission. You need
to have some kind of work that you feel
contributes to others. Whether it's like
I'm doing like on this global scale or
if it's just you with just one person
you're trying to help or maybe you're
just trying to help your family and
you're focused on them because you want
to make money so that you can retire
them. Maybe you're trying to help the
stray dogs in your country and you feel
like a man like these animals, they need
me. Maybe you're trying to fix the
climate. Maybe you're trying to help the
world stop using plastics because that's
causing infertility. Whatever the
mission is, you need to have some kind
of mission. Cuz if you don't, your
rational brain will just tell you,
"Yeah, there's literally no one will
miss you. There's no reason for your
existence. You're just a consumer." And
and when you're done feeling good about
consuming and you just feel bad, and
there's also nothing hopeful for the
future. Well, then what's the point on
existing? As men, please remember what
I'm about to say here. I promise this is
one of the most important sentences I'm
going to say in this video. As men, we
need to feel helpful. We need to feel
helpful to either our family or to a
certain demographic of people like I do
with young men. I feel helpful towards
young men. We need to feel like we're
contributing in some ways. For women,
you know what's interesting? Not so
much. For women, they don't have as much
of this desire. A woman, no offense, but
like especially for feminine women, a
lot of their focus is just on
themselves. For a masculine guy like us,
a lot of our focus is outward on other
people. We have like the hero complex.
Like we want to be a hero. We want to
save people. If you don't have that,
your brain will just tell you, "Yeah,
there's no point in you even being alive
right now." So, think right now, one of
the reasons why I'm depressed is because
I just don't have a mission that feels
like I'm actually contributing to other
people. So, I've just went over the four
causes of depression in young men. I've
gave you a bunch of highlevel ideas to
think about, but now, let's make them
super tactical. Let's make them so
tactical that if you follow the next
section, I give you my word, within two
weeks, you would have cured the
depression feeling that you have. And I
know what you're thinking. Wait, what?
Shut up. Two weeks, you're going to cure
my depression that I've had for years.
Yes. Two weeks of you following my
advice is more effective than all of the
therapists in the world put together. My
advice is better than therapy. I give
you my [ __ ] word. I know there will
be some dorks watching this who are
[ __ ] taking anti-depressants every
day saying, "Oh, that Hamza, that can't
be true." Look at their results. For
anyone who doubts me, look at their
results. They stay depressed forever.
For every guy who watches me and
actually just tries what I say, they'll
come back within two weeks. You'll see
some of them in the comments after this
video has been posted for two weeks
saying, "Holy [ __ ] it worked." I am
telling you, this has helped literally
millions of guys. Two weeks of my
advice, which I'm about to give you
right now, I promise will be better for
you than 2 years of therapy or
anti-depressants. You know why? Because
I'm about to get rid of the reason why
you have depression in the first place.
When you take these stupid [ __ ]
medication like anti-depressants, it
only gets rid of the symptom, but your
life is still shitty. So, the cause of
depression is still there. So, now you
take this anti-depressant and now your
dick doesn't work and now you're more
depressed, but you don't really feel the
depression. you just kind of feel
nothing, which kind of makes you more
depressed anyway. So, you stop all that
[ __ ] and you put your trust into the
next section of this video. For just two
weeks, you just try the things that I'm
about to say, and you'll be one of the
guys in the comments saying, "I watched
this video 2 weeks ago. I've been doing
what Hamza said. I messed up a little
bit, but I've been trying it as best as
I can, and this is the happiest I've
felt for as long as I can remember."
Because this has literally worked, I'm
not exaggerating, this has worked for
over a million guys so far. Two weeks is
better than years of anti-depressants or
therapy or anything else you can
possibly find. This is exactly what to
do. Here are the seven steps to cure
depression. Step number one, set goals.
I want you to set some goals for the
future that you can achieve. The reason
why this is important, you're probably
thinking, setting goals, okay, I've
heard this before, but look, the reason
why setting goals is so important is
that it gives you something to hope for
in the future. And I'm going to tell you
right now, one of the best goals you can
set is just like what happened to
Jeffrey at the start of this video.
Adonis pops into his life and he shows
him the ultimate life for young men. And
that's where you're traveling the world
with other guys just like you. You make
money online so you can become kind of
like a digital nomad. You can move to
the hot spots of the world where you're
away from family, away from everyone in
your hometown who used to know you as
the nerdy little guy. And now you can be
anyone you want to be. You travel to
places like I live in Bali. You travel
to here with other guys who are just
like you. Everyone here is on like
self-improvement, reading books,
meditating, eating clean. You hit the
gym and lift weights with other guys
that you meet here. And it's hype
between sessions. Between sets, you're
making each other laugh. And you go do
some martial arts with them, some
boxing, some jiu-jitsu. Whilst you're
doing these sessions, you notice that
there's so many pretty girls around. And
all these girls read books. They watch
like self-improvement content just like
you. They've wanted to improve their
lives as well. You learn how to flirt.
You start feeling like this, you know,
like this [ __ ] young man full of
vitality. You're traveling the world
with your boys. You're flirting with
girls. You're eating good meals. You're
exercising. You've got a great physique.
You're confident. You're driving around
on a [ __ ] bike shirtless thinking
this is the [ __ ] life. That's the
goal that I would set for most of the
guys who are watching this. The goal of
being like a digital nomad in a place
like Barley. Make that your goal. And
it's something that realistically anyone
watching this can achieve within the
next few years. You just need to make
like a few thousand a month online,
which is definitely tricky of course,
but if you put your mind to it for the
next 1 to two years, you can achieve it
just like many people have. By the way,
bro, there's tons of retards who have
achieved this every day. I'll speak to
people who are like not intelligent at
all, and they all make like 5 to 10k a
month online. It's not like terribly
difficult. You're probably more
intelligent than most of these people.
It's just that these people have just
kind of like tried. That's it. So, you
set that as one of your goals. Along
with that, maybe you set building like a
really nice physique one of your goals
because going to the gym and lifting
weights is so fun. Such like a masculine
sport. It's so stimulating. You lift
weights for the like the rest of your
life. You get strong. You look jacked.
Every time you're shirtless or even when
you're wearing clothes, you look at
yourself, you're like, "Man, that feels
[ __ ] good." Boom. That's like your
second goal. Maybe the third goal is
that you want to have like an awesome
girlfriend. Maybe you even want two
girlfriends. You write that down. You
write a couple of goals for you to
achieve over the next few years. You
visualize these goals in your mind and
whatever one gets you hype and you're
like, "Man, that'd be [ __ ] cool."
Like, I that's actually possible. Like,
I could I could actually have that. Holy
[ __ ] That's the right goal for you. The
first step to curing depression is
setting those goals because now we have
something to work towards. And
instantly, this makes you feel better
right away cuz you're thinking, "Oh
[ __ ] like I've got a mission. I've got
something to march towards. There's this
lifestyle that I can enjoy, which is
completely different from the way that
I'm living right now." The second step
to curing depression once we have the
goals written down is to do the positive
mental health habits that will make us
feel mentally better. Meditation,
gratitude journaling, exercise, and also
mindset training. I'll go over each of
these briefly. Meditation. The reason
why we meditate is so that we can become
more present. Basically, when you're
present, that refers to a time where
you're not like deep in thought about
the past or the future. When we think
about the past or the future, that's
when we get like depressed or anxious.
The best moment in life is when you're
here right now, actually there. Let's
say we're having a conversation with
someone. We want to be present with
them, actually here with them. We don't
want our mind to be randomly kind of
thinking other memories whilst we're
speaking to this person. There was a
study that found that no matter what
you're thinking about, whatever memory
you have in your mind, even if it's a
bit of a pleasant memory, it's actually
worse for your happiness than if you're
just present here right now. Most people
are not very present people because a
lot of the [ __ ] that we do like you know
the phone stimulation it kind of
destroys a bit of your presence and you
start having all this mind wandering you
get random memories random insights
whatever you just want to be here where
you are right now so the way to get more
present is to meditate and you and every
time I tell someone to meditate by the
way they always tell me the same thing
they're like oh no well I tried it but
it doesn't work and I totally get that
but it's [ __ ] that's like saying oh
well I tried lifting weights but it it
didn't work you know I did like 10 reps
and then I couldn't do anymore. more.
So, you hit failure.
Yes,
that was the point. Like that was
literally the point. Like like if you're
not going to the gym, you might not
understand this, but people will say
like, "Oh, well, I tried to meditate,
but then I got a thought." You do
realize that was the point. Like that
you literally were meditating. If you
just kept on doing that, you would have
gotten the result. When you meditate,
look, this is how you meditate, right?
So, you just focus on your breath. Just
feel the sensation wherever. Just keep
it in one point. So, for example, I
always just choose this bit here. Right
there. I just feel whatever sensation I
can there.
Within a few seconds, your brain starts
to think about other stuff cuz it's
boring, right? Your brain starts to
think about this thing or this memory or
this to-do list, whatever. The moment
you catch your brain thinking about
anything else, all you have to do is
just focus back there again. It's like
your brain focuses here, then your brain
starts wandering away. You realize it's
wandering away and you just bring it
back here. Within a few seconds, your
brain starts wandering away again, and
you bring it back here over and over and
over again. Every time you bring it back
to this spot, you've leveled up the
skill of meditation. You'll get so good
at this that your speed of bringing it
back will be so quick that it'll feel as
if it never really left in the first
place and you're just there all the
time. That's how you train. So, if you
ever tried to meditate and you're like,
"Oh, you know, I started getting
thoughts. I couldn't stop thinking."
That's actually okay. That's actually
kind of even better because you noticed
you were thinking. So the next time you
try like and I would suggest you
meditate every morning by the way. As
soon as you wake up, set your pillows
upright so you can sit on the edge of
your bed. Set a timer on your phone. You
don't even have to download any app if
you don't want to. But I just set a
timer on your phone. 1 minute, 3
minutes. Just focus on your breath here.
The moment you notice, oh, I've been
thinking about high school or I've been
thinking about this guy or whatever,
just focus back there again. Every
single time you bring it back there,
it's like you've just done one bicep
curl for the brain. Every single time
you bring it back. So, it's a good thing
when you notice that your mind has
wandered. It's a good thing. That's part
of it. You just bring it back. When you
bring it back over and over again every
single day for a few minutes and, you
know, up to even 10 minutes, 20 minutes
eventually, but just start with 1
minute. When you keep doing that, you'll
notice that your brain will just
naturally do that when you're in
conversations. You'll notice sometimes
you'll be in the gym, you maybe you'll
be doing some push-ups and your brain
will start to think about some other
thing which is irrelevant like you know
what you're going to eat later and your
brain will just come back to the present
moment and feel the push-up, feel your
chest and you'll get like a way better
pump. What you want throughout your
entire life is you want to just be
focused on what you're doing right now.
Kind of like a pro alete would a pro
athlete is about to perform. Imagine
they're doing like a deadlift or they're
about to box or something. They're not
thinking about what to eat later.
they're thinking about, okay, make sure
you step like this. You know, they're
just in a flow state, right? That's what
you want to be in when you're speaking
to a girl. You don't want to be thinking
about what to do with my hands or
whatever. You just want to be here in
this moment. You don't basically, you
don't want any thoughts in your mind.
And the more you meditate, the less
thoughts in your mind you'll have, which
I know sounds a bit weird, but I promise
you, it's actually so much better for
your performance. Like, you'll perform
so much better in everything. The more
you meditate, the more present you are.
So, make that one of your daily habits.
Start meditating every morning. moment
your eyes open, you know, you turn your
alarm off, set your pillows upright, sit
up straight, and just set an alarm for
like 1 minute or something and just do
it as best as you can. It's literally
just one minute. It's so short that you
could do this every single day for the
rest of your life, right? Think about
it. Every single day for the rest of
your life, you could do one minute in
the morning. I would recommend doing it
first thing in the morning. I'm talking
your eyes open. You've not even brushed
your teeth. You've not checked your
phone or anything. Grab your phone,
maybe even use your watch or something
if you can't resist like scrolling on
your phone, checking your notifications,
whatever. And just for one minute, just
focus on your breath. Boom. After a
week, maybe increase it to two minutes.
Get up to like 20 minutes and that's
[ __ ] awesome. Do that, you'll be more
present, and that will stop you from
getting all these random thoughts that
just make the day-to-day life less fun.
Then the other mental health habit you
can do is gratitude journaling. So
that's where you'll take some time right
after you meditate, you know, you wake
up, do the one minute of meditation,
right after you've done that, grab a pen
and a piece of paper or the notes app on
your phone, but I really think writing
it seems to work better. And just write,
"Today I'm grateful for." and just sit
for a second and think, okay, what can I
be grateful for? What's something that
if it was removed from my life, would I
really miss?
And the first thing that comes to your
mind is your mother.
You think about one of your friends
who's lost their mothers recently, and
you think to yourself, what would you do
if one day you woke up and she was just
dead?
How would that feel? Imagine the the
gut-wrenching pain.
And now smile because she's still here
and realize the last few weeks you've
completely taken her for granted.
Suddenly you just appreciate her more.
How about like visualizing like just
pretend for a second
it's 60 years from now. Pretend we're
all like 70, 80, 90 years old. We're
getting close to dying. You know, we're
like in a hospital. We can't even stand.
We're getting dripfed [ __ ] nutrients.
We're about to die. Just visualize that
for a second and imagine somehow it's
like a miracle. You're like 90 years old
and you just press some magical button
and you've been transported to where you
are right now. Imagine we were just 90
years old about to die. You look down,
you're like, "Oh my god, holy [ __ ] I'm
like I'm like 20 again." You know, it's
like sometimes like there's like a movie
plot that's like that, isn't there? like
whether he's an old guy and then he
comes back to his re like young life and
he's about to change his life and
everything. There's no reason why you
can't behave like that right now and
just be like, "Holy shit." Like I I'm
young. I'm young. My legs [ __ ] work.
I can jump. I can I can run. My My
parents are still alive. Why don't you
just act like that right now? Think
about it. Like what's stopping you from
acting like you were just 90 years old
and you've just been transported back to
like your 20-year-old version? What's
stopping you from just pretending like
your mother died and then snapping back
and thinking, "Oh my god, she's still
here." What's stopping you really from
going into your mom's room right now,
going into the kitchen, wherever she is,
and just giving her a hug as if you had
lived a reality in which she had died
and now she's here again. What's
stopping you from doing that? And I know
it feels a bit cringe, doesn't it? Let's
be honest. It feels a bit cringe to like
go and give your mom like an extra hug
today or, you know, to do this. But I
promise you, you will feel happier.
Gratitude journaling. It's the act of
you just sitting there and thinking,
"Okay, if I lost something in my life
and I just got it back, I would
appreciate it so much more." So, look
around your room. Think about the people
and the things in your life and just
think to yourself, what can you be
grateful for?
Imagine you were in a car accident and
you lost like your arm. Imagine it got
crushed and they had to like sever it
and you had to get one of those weird
[ __ ] metal hands or whatever. And
yeah, the technology is pretty good
these days, but it's still not your
[ __ ] hand, right? And imagine how
much more new things you'd have to
learn. You'd have to learn to walk again
or to grab things, whatever. And now
look at your hand and just be like,
"Man, I've got my [ __ ] hand." Do you
know anyone who's ever like sat there
been like, "I'm so grateful for my
hands.
I'm so grateful for like this clothing
that I wear. I'm so grateful for the
house we live in." We could have lived
in a way [ __ ] house. I'm so grateful
that both my parents are alive. I'm so
grateful for these devices that I have
where I can connect to others. I'm so
grateful for my joints, the fact that I
don't have extreme pain. I'm so grateful
for the pen that I write with. I'm so
grateful for the school that I go to for
my teachers. I'm so grateful for my
friend. You visualize each of these
things just suddenly disappearing from
your life. How much pain you'd be in if
you went to school and you heard that
your best friend had passed away. And
then it's almost like you click your
fingers and realize they're still alive.
and all the things that you would have
said at their funeral, you can say to
them now. Do you see how powerful this
practice can be? Because it makes you
appreciate the things in your life. For
all of our day-to-day life, we think
about the things we don't have, the girl
that we want, the money that we want to
build, the physique that we want, the
few minutes that you spend in this
practice of gratitude, journaling.
It's finally some time where you're
thinking about the things you do have
and asking yourself, what would life be
like if you suddenly lost that thing? So
this is like your new daily routine. You
wake up and the moment you wake up, you
do the one minute of meditation. Just
focus on that one spot. When you notice
your your mind's wandered, you bring it
back. Boom. Do the one minute of that, 2
minutes, 3 minutes, whatever. Straight
after that, do some gratitude
journaling. Sit there for a minute.
Think about something in your life.
Think about someone in your life and
just write down how it would feel if you
lost them. And then write down how nice
it is that you still have them in your
life. And I know it will feel cringe,
but what if you just go and tell them
how much you appreciate them?
What if things were worse?
What if you were someone who has like
this random disease or this physical
ailment and you don't?
There's someone your age right now who's
disabled. There's someone your age right
now who's 10 times more poor than you
and your family.
So, it makes you appreciate the things
you have. So imagine you've just spent
the first five minutes of your day
practicing your presence with meditation
and now just being sat there thinking
about the good things in your life that
you appreciate so much.
What a powerful way to start your day.
The third mental health habit is
exercise. And so the type of exercise I
will always recommend to young men is
going to the gym and lifting weights. So
you've heard of exercise and most people
when they think about exercise they
think about just like running, whatever.
And you can do that if you want. That's
still nice for you. But I swear to God,
I promise you the single best form of
exercise that you can do when you're
young and even when you're older is
resistance training. Basically, lifting
weights. You go to the gym, you go to
the weight section, you know, where
there's those dumbbells and the rack and
there's like the barbell, the machines,
and you train with those. When you train
with those, it will hurt. You know,
you'll like do like this chest press and
it will hurt your chest. But after a
while of doing that, you'll literally
build some muscle and your physique will
look better. And this is the sport of
bodybuilding, weightlifting. And it I
promise you, bro, it's so good for you.
I started 11 years ago. I had like, you
know, this normal kind of skinny
physique with a bit of a fat stomach.
I've built like such a good physique now
where I get compliments from people all
the time. I walk into buildings and I
swear to God the staff who work there
every single time like these days they
call me handsome, you know, like they're
so happy to see me. They ask me to flex
whatever cuz I've got like a muscular
physique. I'm 6'1. I weigh about 210 lbs
now. So I'm [ __ ] big. I'm like a bit,
you know, like a bulky like kind of high
body fat right now. But like, you know,
I'm like big. It feels not just like for
the vanity of how you look, but it's
just such a good sport because when
you're lifting weights, it's all about
the number you can lift. like okay so I
can do this bench press for like 20 kg
for example but if you keep doing it you
eat right you sleep and you train hard
next week you can do it for 22.5 kg 25
kg 30 kg you stick to the same exercise
let's say it's like the barbell bench
press right just like this when you
first start off like when I did 20 kg
was too heavy I could probably do about
10 kg these days I can do about 124 reps
so you have imagine it's it's kind of
like like I'll try and explain this to
you because I've been doing doing this
for so long, but just imagine how nice
this is. Imagine, let's say you're 18
right now and you watch this and you
start weightlifting and there's an
exercise you can do right now like the
barbell bench press and you can use 40
kg on it. You'll still be doing the
exact same exercise 10, 20 years from
now and you'll remember the days where
you could only do 40 kg but now you can
do 140, 160 and it's like the exercise
has like grown alongside you. I was 17
years old when I first started
weightlifting and like the the the
barbell was too heavy for me to press
like this. You know, I'm lying on my
back. It was too heavy for me to press
like this. I've bench pressed three
plates 140 kg before. So, it's so it's
like it's not just, you know, you you'll
look sexy, which by the way is really
[ __ ] nice. When you look sexy, bro,
it's so easy to attract girls when
you've got like a sexy physique and
also, you know, the confidence that it
gives you, but also it's just a sport
that also makes you look forward for the
future cuz you start and you're like,
"Oh man, like maybe in like 6 months
from now, I could bench press like 60 kg
or 100 kg, you know, and it you start
like hyping up for the future, thinking,
oh man, like this sport is it's giving
me a reason to work hard. You know, if I
don't quit, I'm going to build like the
10 out of 10 physique that I've always
wanted." And it just, bro, it's it's so
nice when you can walk around shirtless.
Of course, you know, depending on where
you live, maybe you live in like a cold
country, but let's say in the future you
move to somewhere tropical like Bali,
you can just walk around shirtless. So,
I'll I'll drive to the gym on my bike,
like, and I'll literally just be
shirtless when I drive. And I swear to
God, the amount of girls and guys who
will look over at me, cuz I'm like
[ __ ] thick and jacked, right? The
amount of people who look over at me,
the amount of people who like flex
whilst they drive past me, it makes me
feel so [ __ ] nice, man. It's like
such a great sport. So you start
exercising, you start lifting weights,
you start building this physique which
makes you confident. You get physically
strong which is so good for your health
as well. Naturally when you get into
this you start thinking, okay, I really
want to make muscle. I want to look
sexy. So I'll start to sleep better as
well. I'll start to eat cleaner. I'll
start to like, you know, like really
take the gym seriously, conditioning or
start to like like double down on
hydration and mindset and everything.
And so your entire life changes when you
get into the sport of bodybuilding, like
of building a physique that you're proud
of. And remember I told you that having
the right mindset was really important
with your mental health habits. There's
a book that you can read which I always
recommend to people when they want to
improve their mental health. And the
book is called The Magic of Thinking Big
by David Schwarz. Go and get that book.
You can go find it online for free.
Maybe go buy it on Amazon or whatever. I
promise this is the book that every
young man should read because it's like
an old school success book. A lot of
books these days are written by authors
that are like left-wing skinny little
[ __ ] that I'd [ __ ] slap. You know
what I mean? Like these [ __ ] little
cowards. And basically they'll write
books that will tell you like, "Hey,
don't be so ambitious. You know, live
more of a balanced life. It's okay to be
a loser." I [ __ ] hate books like
that. This book that I'm recommending to
you is like an old school book, which is
the opposite. It's like this old school
guy saying that, yeah, you can achieve
the goal. Work hard. Work even harder.
You can work harder. You can be
ambitious. You can achieve any goal that
you want. That's the kind of mindset
that you want. Go get that book, The
Magic of Thinking Big. Start reading it
and it will really help you with your
mental health journey. The third step to
curing depression, and this is linked
with our first step of setting goals, is
to choose your purposeful work. So
remember, we set goals. And one of the
goals you probably set was, okay, at
some point I want to make money so I can
leave my family's home. I can move out.
I can move to wherever I want. I can
move to the place in the world where
people like me are like Bali, Thailand,
Dubai, these kinds of places where like
young ambitious people are going. Now is
the time for you to think about what the
purposeful work that you could get into.
What's the mission, the contribution? We
want to make money. We don't just want
the money. We want to make the money
whilst feeling that we are contributing
to the people that we care about or to
the cause that we care about. So now is
the time for you to think, okay, I'm
going to make money. I'm going to get
rich. But how do I want to get rich?
It's not just that I want to make money.
That's the basic level. The level above
that is that I want to make money whilst
I feel like I'm doing good work, that
I'm helping the kind of people or the
cause or the mission that I really feel
is important. So ask yourself right now,
if you were already a billionaire,
who would you help? What kind of person
could you help and do you want to help?
What problem in the world pisses you off
a lot? It could be porn addiction in
men. It could be loneliness. It could be
mental health like I'm doing here. It
could be social skills or men's dating
skills. It could be the environment. It
could be microlastics like you know like
recycling. It could be the climate. It
could be animals. What is it that really
like makes you so sad and you're like
man I wish that problem went away in the
world. Let's say for me it was helping
young men. When I started this work 5
years ago, I saw that young men were at
such a disadvantage in society. Women
have been hyped up for the last few
decades told that you can do anything
you want. You go girl, you can go get
the degree. You can work. You can do
anything that a man can. Men have been
told, "Stop being violent. Stop
mansplaining. Stop doing this. Stop
doing that. Stop making women do this."
And blah blah blah blah blah. We've been
told all bad things about us. Men have
been told to sit down, shut the [ __ ] up,
and just sacrifice yourself when you're
needed. But right now, you're not
needed, so we don't like you. I saw this
and it pissed me off. Even when I was
like a teenager, men's issues would
really get to me because every time it
was spoke about, some [ __ ] girl in my
class would hype up and say, "Yeah, but
girls have got this other thing." And
I'd be like, "Bitch, just let us [ __ ]
like talk about the fact that men are
killing themselves at four times the
rate than women. Let us talk about the
fact that most of the homeless in the
world are men. Let us talk about the
fact that most of the people who die in
the workplace are men. Let us talk about
the fact that most of the people who've
got a terrible mental health, who are
suicidal, are men." But we can't because
the moment we speak about these things,
we suddenly have to translate it into
women and say, "Oh, yeah, but women have
got shut the [ __ ] up." This like zero
someum empathy. When we're speaking
about men's issues, we have to say,
"Yeah, but you know, women have it bad,
too." No. How about we just [ __ ]
focus on the men for once? Throughout
our [ __ ] generation, men have been
left behind. Did you know that men
perform worse in every year of the
education system? Women go to university
and get degrees more. Did you know
remember the the phrase the gender wage
gap? Did you know that that was a
[ __ ] lie that men earn more than
women? Did you know that that was
literally a lie and women literally earn
more than men? And when the real
statistics came out, when the real data
came out, the feminists went quiet. They
always told us that feminism was for
equality. The moment it came out with
real data that women make more money
than men, feminists have just shut the
[ __ ] up about the gender wage gap. If
they care about men, they should be
talking about the gender wage gap and
saying, "Oh, women earn more than men.
We've got to bring the men up. But they
don't give a [ __ ] about men. Nobody
does. They don't give a [ __ ] about us.
So, I saw this as you can see right now
and I get pissed. I see the [ __ ]
inequality of the world. I see how how
left behind men have been. And if you
talk about men's issues, suddenly people
just think you're like a misogynist. You
hate women or some [ __ ] I saw this. It
pissed me off and I was like, you know
what? Look, you can get rich doing
anything. but you may as well get rich
whilst also focusing on the problem that
you genuinely want to work on because
you'll just work 10 times harder on it.
So, I thought to myself, you know what?
I'm going to take on the problems of
young men. I'm going to try and help
young men. I'm going to educate them.
I'm going to be like a leader for young
men. And I've worked so hard and I've
been so dedicated to this that of course
I got successful whilst doing this. So,
you need to do something similar. You
need to think to yourself, okay, what is
the problem, the cause, the mission that
spikes something inside of you? Focus on
that. that is like your career, your
business. That's the way that you can
make money in the world. Just for now,
you don't have to have the complete idea
because it's something that you'll kind
of discover over a few months of like
getting into it. But just as a start,
just think about what type of person you
might want to help and just think about
what type of problem you might want to
help them with. And then just think,
okay, well, what are the ways I can do
that? I can educate the people who are
going through that problem with social
media content. Let's say your the
problem that you want to get rid of in
the world is like porn addiction in men.
and you think, "Okay, well, I could
become like a nofap YouTuber and after a
few years, I might have like hundreds of
thousands of subscribers and I've gotten
like hundreds of thousands of guys to
quit porn." That's like, bro, that's
[ __ ] good contribution to the world
that you've just done. And you'll get
rich at the same time. Once you've got
that, the fourth step to curing
depression is such a simple one, but
it's so powerful.
Smile. This is such a powerful hack.
Smile. When you go through your normal
day, you wake up, you're about to
meditate, you're about to work on
something, you're going to go to school
or work, you're going to the grocery
store, going to the gym, whatever you're
doing, we'll often just be in our mind.
We'll just be thinking about what we
have to do. Okay, I've got a chore, I've
got to do this thing, okay, I'm going to
get to the gym, I'm going to do this,
whatever. I swear this is so powerful.
As many times as possible in the day,
just remind yourself to smile. And
literally, even though there's no reason
to smile, just force the muscles of your
face to smile. Just force them like
this. Within a few seconds, it will
often turn to a real smile. You can do
it right now. Just fake fake a big
[ __ ] toothy smile right now. Just
fake it for a second and allow it to
just like kind of like introduce that
feeling. There's real studies that have
shown that if you just fake a smile,
you're very likely to genuinely feel
happier because it is actually the
commands that we give to our body that
changes how we feel inside. The biggest
lie is thinking that you need to feel
happy to smile. That's what most people
think, right? They'll smile when there's
something to smile about, so we need
something to smile about first. No, no,
no. I promise this is such an
interesting mindset. That's not how it
works. You don't smile because there's
something to smile about. No, no, no.
You smile and then you get things to
smile about. You smile then someone like
a girl smiles at you and then you've got
something to actually smile about. You
smile and everyone seems happier to you
that day and now you're actually a
happier person. You don't wait for
something to happen to smile because
then you just won't smile that much. You
become the type of person who just
smiles as much as possible and then
people will smile back at you. Bro, when
you're smiling through the day in the
gym, whatever, you'll notice so many
more people will smile at you rather
than you being in like a normal kind of
face. You know, it's so rare for someone
to smile at you when you're in a normal
face. You're kind of thinking about
life, whatever. I promise if you become
the type of person who just f like you
remind yourself a hundred times every
day to smile, smile, smile, smile. You
have it on your phone and checklist like
you have a checklist for getting ready
for the gym, you have a checklist for
getting ready for work, you have a
checklist for getting ready for school,
and you know, you take off each one. I
promise if you have smile there like 10
times and it's like, okay, history
class, smile, gym, like you walk into
the gym, smile. You know, it's like a
little checklist you press on your phone
notes app every day. I promise you start
smiling more. More people will smile at
you and you'll just get so many more
opportunities. You'll have so many more
reasons to smile. It's like one of the
best hacks against feeling depressed is
just forcing yourself to smile,
reminding yourself to smile, even if
there feels like there's nothing to
smile about. There'll be some guy here
who's watching this thinking, "Oh, well
that's just stupid because you need a
reason to smile." No, you don't. Smiling
doesn't require a reason. It just
requires contractions of your muscle, of
your face. Do I need a reason to to flex
my bicep like this? No, I can just flex
it. How about can you move your eyebrows
up? Can you do that? Right, do this with
me. Right, you can do that. Right. So,
just like we can move our eyebrows up,
we can also just smile our lips. And it
feels a bit silly, but just do it and
just feel the goofiness of it, the
absurdity of faking a smile. And it'll
often just turn into a real [ __ ]
smile. And then it'll get you into the
moods where when I I by the way I do
this. I smile as soon as I wake up,
right? I try to like always remember
that when I'm driving to the gym, I
smile. What will happen is you'll start
to actually get into a good mood because
whatever we do to our body changes how
we feel, right? Imagine if I told you to
sit small like this. You'll start to
feel more anxious and whatever. When you
sit bigger and you take up more space,
you start to feel better. You start to
feel more confident. One, because your
body starts getting this message of, oh
yeah, he's a confident guy. But also
two, people start treating you with more
confidence. If if someone saw me sit
like this, they'd think, "Oh, yeah, this
guy's a bit more confident." Just in
their subconscious mind, and they'd
treat me like that. If I was like this,
they'd treat me worse. If I'm like this,
they'll treat me better. Likewise, if I
smile, more people will smile back at
me, which will give me a reason to smile
again. So, as many times as possible,
set like alarms on your phone,
checklists on your phone, reminders,
whatever. Get into the habit and just
smile, smile, smile, smile. Get like a
few people you see all the time, like
this girl in school or this teacher or
your mom, whatever. And always think to
yourself, smile before they just about
when they see you. Just be the guy who
smiles so much more. And if by the way,
you're going to the same environment,
like school for example, and you're not
really the smiley kind of guy, just
start anyway. I know it might seem a bit
weird. Oh, no, but you know, I've kind
of set the the vibe that I don't smile
when I open the door to like my
classroom. But you can, and girls will
be like, "Oh, you you look happy today."
They'll literally speak to you. It's
easy for you to speak to them and
they'll say, "Oh, you're smiling. You've
got a nice smile. You look happy today."
And say, "Oh, thank you. Like, how was
your weekend?" And just have a chitchat
with them. You don't have to think like,
"Oh, yeah, but you know, I've I've kept
up the aura that I'm not the smiley guy.
I'm actually the nonchalant." Stop being
[ __ ] gay, bro. I'm actually the
nonchalant type of guy. Stop being a
[ __ ] internet addict, bro. Oh, I'm
nonchal Shut up. You look like a [ __ ]
like the nonchalant guy who's trying to
act serious. You You look like
unwelcoming to people who want to speak
to you. When you smile, it's so easy for
other people to come up to you, to wave
at you, and smile back at you. And also
what helps by the way again the same
thing when you move to the type of place
where a lot of people are just smiling.
I swear to God where I live is like the
land of the smiles. You walk into a cafe
all the staff are smiling like genuine
not like commercial kind of American
style but they're like genuinely happy
people here. You go to the gym there'll
be girls who walk past smiling and
everything. Become so easy to talk to
people. Now that you've got your goals,
the mental health habits, you know the
direction you're going to. You've got a
bit of a mission to work on and you're
smiling. The fifth step to curing
depression is to get into more of a
playful mood. This is why smiling is so
important. Do you remember as children,
we used to just have like this playful
energy throughout the day. We'd see like
a puddle on the floor and we wouldn't
walk around it. We just randomly stomp
through it and our pants would get a bit
wet or we try and jump over the puddle.
Imagine you were in like the the forest
or the woods or whatever and there was a
bit of a ditch like this. You and your
friends would just like randomly just
sprint and decide to jump over it rather
than walk around it. You'd see a tree
and you just climb it. You'd pick up
something from the floor and you just
randomly throw it to somewhere. You'd
grab a leaf from the tree and look at it
and tear it into little pieces,
whatever. You do all these things. You'd
play. You'd integrate with nature, with
society. When we become older, we just
kind of stop doing all that. We just put
our AirPods in, we just walk to like
school or work and we just don't
interact with the world anymore. We see
a puddle, we walk around it. We see a
tree that would be great for climbing
and we just walk straight past it. Why?
You know, as adults, like we're supposed
to still live the exact same life. Like,
adults are still meant to play the exact
same way that we were as children. Why
don't we do those things anymore? Come
on. It's embarrassing to admit because
we're scared of being seen as corny, you
know, by those same [ __ ] internet
trolls who'd say that you're corny
because you feel like you've got a
mission in life. They'd be like, "Ah,
that's so so corny. Bro, bro's got a
purpose for his existence." Like,
they'll be talking in memes. Bro's got a
mission in life before GTA 6. They'll
just be saying this cringe [ __ ] this
internet [ __ ] the type of people who
will comment like first on these [ __ ]
videos, these [ __ ] like like come on
internet [ __ ] retards, right, bro?
We've got Hamza mental health guide
before GTA 6. Bro, that [ __ ] meme
comment has never been funny. And the
type of people who comment like this,
they've literally like they're so
depressed and so not funny people,
right? So the type of people who will
judge you saying like ah Unks corn he
was you know whatever [ __ ] that they'll
say if they ever see you like climbing a
tree they're depressed taking
anti-depressant pills and their uncle
probably rapes them so like who the [ __ ]
cares about what some [ __ ] kid is
going to say about you if he sees you
like randomly you're walking and you
jump over a puddle just jumped over the
puddle. It's like
you sound like a [ __ ] [ __ ] right?
So don't worry about any of these
[ __ ] dead rose emoji kids who judge
you. That's the reason why we won't do
these playful things anymore. That's the
reason why when you see a tree that
would be great for climbing, you
wouldn't do it cuz you're scared that
someone else from your school or some
[ __ ] kid would see you and put like
take a picture of you and say like, "Oh
yeah, he's climbing a tree." Like
enjoying nature.
Okay. Why are you scared of these
[ __ ] little trolls? Why are you
scared of them? Rely, when you think
about it, overall your life will be
better. This is particularly, you know,
to the generation Z or X or whatever,
the kids who are watching this who are
like under 18 years old. You guys are so
scared of like getting publicly outed
for doing anything that can be seen as
cringe or corny. Like I feel so bad for
the young generation cuz you're so
scared of behaving in a way where people
will like judge you. In my generation,
like we got, you know, Snapchat and
Instagram when we were like 16, 17 years
old, but these days, kids are so like
[ __ ] like they'll call, you know,
they'll just [ __ ] chat [ __ ] about
each other and say, "Oh, he's so corny.
He's this, whatever." So now, every kid
that I speak to who's like younger than
16, they're so scared of being
different. Like they all have the same
like Tik Tok haircut. They all have the
same taste in music. They're all like
little sheep, like little bots going
through the same [ __ ] NPC like hole
in the wall. Because if you're different
as a young person, everyone else will
say like, "Oh, he's so corny. He's
trying to be a content creator." But
it's like, bro, like, what do you lose
by some [ __ ] [ __ ] saying this about
you? That guy's not getting his dick
sucked. He's a [ __ ] little loser. So,
like, who gives a [ __ ] about these
[ __ ] kids who will say [ __ ] right?
And if you're older, then you shouldn't
even give a [ __ ] anyway. Like, and you
know, I said before, you should care
what people think about you. Obviously,
what I meant was like you should care
what like [ __ ] intelligent people
think about you, what some high
performers, some successful people, not
some [ __ ] you know, some [ __ ] from
your class who who's going to post about
you on Snapchat saying like, "Oh, I saw
him climbing a [ __ ] tree. That's so
cringe or something. Who gives a [ __ ]
about these kids, right? Who gives a
[ __ ] about these little retards?" So,
the fifth step of curing depression is
for you to start acting like a child
again in this playful energy. Go climb a
tree. Like, seriously, imagine that was
like a part of your daily habits, like
your checklist. Climb a tree. You go on
a walk or a bit of a run every day. You
find a tree like you're looking around
for a good tree to climb and you climb
it as high as you possibly can. I
promise you can't be depressed when
you're climbing a tree. You just can't.
I guarantee you'll start smiling. You'll
start like, you know, breathing heavies
like a little kid. Like you're trying to
like figure out which which one to go on
to next. I guarantee, bro, you go climb
a tree today. It's better than taking
anti-depressants. I guarantee you. All
the decades of training that all these
[ __ ] gay little therapists have
trained for in university, all the
billions of dollars that these like
pharmaceutical companies have spent on
anti-depressants and all this [ __ ] And
climbing a tree is literally better than
all of it put together. Just go climb a
tree next time it's raining. Go for a
[ __ ] run outside in the rain. Go
shirtless. Whenever there's a puddle on
the floor, jump over the puddle. I
guarantee you do these. I know it sounds
so silly. This is how you stop feeling
depressed. you start having this
childlike playful energy. You're like,
you know, you're making noises. You're
randomly playing games with yourself.
Best case scenario, you've got someone
else to do this with. If you've got some
friends in the same vibe, you can
randomly wrestle with them. Let's say
you all go to the park to like play
football together and you randomly just
grab one of your friends and you start
like wrestling each other and stuff. And
again, it's like some [ __ ] kid who's
depressed has to take anti-depressants
and he gets raped by his uncle is like
watching you guys taking like a little
picture of you saying like so corny.
These guys are wrestling before GTA 6
came out. It's like just you're [ __ ]
internet [ __ ] re GTA 6 oh corny dead
ros like just shut up man all this
shit's so gay now like the people who
say corny the people who write in these
memes are the corny [ __ ]
themselves right we're getting to a nice
part of society where basically there's
the two splits of people there's the
superhumans who are going to start to
live in the ways that I'm describing and
then there's the subhumans who whose
entire personality is built of like the
[ __ ] Tik Tok and Instagram comments
and they know what to to call someone
corny for or what meme is is popular
these days or something like we had
memes back in my time but it was like a
[ __ ] like dog meme or some [ __ ] or
like bad luck Brian or some [ __ ] you
know it was like [ __ ] just a JPEG or
something these days like there's just
kids who are like so hyperconnected to
the internet they'll try and mock you
for like like you know the way you're
living but these kids are [ __ ] like
little weirdos anyway so why who gives a
[ __ ] about what some [ __ ] kid
comments so these days if I see a kid
comment some [ __ ] like fell off I always
just reply with the same thing I'm like
grow up You're a [ __ ] sane on society.
You're like a [ __ ] weird internet
consumer. The gray matter in your brain
is deteriorating from your consumption
of of [ __ ] internet content. This
culture online where someone will [ __ ]
on you for being a productive human
being. So cringe. I think the people who
say cringe corny GTA 6 whatever the [ __ ]
these kids are talking about. I think
that's the corny thing. Like someone
will trim this up. Unks angry about GTA.
Like shut up. Stop this internet bro.
It's so cringe the way people talk
online. You know, if you go and live a
healthy life, if you start going to the
gym, there'll be someone in your school
who'll start saying this about you.
Like, ah, Unks going to the gym before
G. Just shut up. You [ __ ] You get my
point, right? I'm probably not using the
lingo correctly, but you get my point.
Like, you're so scared of what these
genuine genuine mental disability people
are going to say about you. Who gives a
[ __ ] bro? If you go to the gym, they'll
make fun of you. If you don't go to the
gym, they'll make fun of you. If you're
poor, they'll make fun of you. If you're
rich, they'll make fun of you. So,
clearly, their [ __ ] judgment of you
is just [ __ ] useless. Like who gives
a [ __ ] You should think about your own
judgment of yourself. And also, this is
what's controversial, but I think it's
good. You should think about what some
highlevel people would judge you on.
Let's say me, right? Maybe I'm like a
role model in your life. You should
think to yourself, how would Hamza judge
me if I go to the gym today? He'd nod
his head and think, okay, sweet. He went
to the gym. Respect. You should be,
okay, well, I'll go to the gym. Not not
just for Hamza, but because he's maybe
like I may be someone that you kind of
look up to. I'm 28 years old. I'm a
millionaire. I've got millions of
followers. I'm a happy guy. I've got a
great physique. I've got good social
life, good dating life, bro. I've
achieved like basically every young
man's dream in my [ __ ] 20ies. Most
guys don't even become a millionaire in
their life. I became a millionaire in
like four years of trying, right? That's
pretty like come on glaze. Just shut up,
bro. [ __ ] hell. Oh, don't just shut
up this [ __ ] internet. But you get my
point, right? So, I've achieved a lot.
So, you should be thinking to yourself
like, okay, what would Hamza think if he
saw me climbing a tree or if he saw me,
you know, being like this happy guy
who's speaking to like the elderly
person you walk past having a
conversation with them? Hamza would
respect me for it. Okay, well then I'm
going to do more of that. What would
Hamza think if he heard that I went for
a run in the rain? He'd respect me for
it. When you think too much about your
social circle and you know the internet,
you'll be thinking, okay, what would
they think if I went for a run in the
rain? And you just kind of visualize the
type of comments. Ah, bro thinks he's
the main character cuz he went for a run
in the rain or some [ __ ] And it's like,
yeah, you'll start to get scared, but
you've got to remember the people who
will judge you for living like a playful
life, they're all depressed. So don't
allow their judgment to change your
actions. Try not to think about their
judgment at all. Try to think of the
judgment of people who are at where you
want to be in life. What would those
retards say if you tried to make a
business? They'd insult you and they'd
call you names. What would the
businessman say if you tried to make a
business? He'd respect you and he'd want
to help you. So even though this is such
a simple step, step number five, be more
playful. You can see it's quite a big
thing because we are supposed to be
playful creatures. We're supposed to be
silly. We're supposed to goof around and
play, fight, and wrestle, you know, just
like lions do. Lion cubs, but also the
big lions, they'll just playfully
wrestle each other. Dogs do this. All
kinds of animals do this. We're supposed
to just play. But people will judge you
for this. And I'm telling you, the big
reason why a lot of us feel depressed is
we're so restrained in our behavior
because we're so scared of how people
will judge us. Step number six to curing
depression is to improve your social and
your dating life. When you are socially
isolated from other guys and when you're
not good at like flirting with girls,
you start to get quite reserved in
inside of yourself, you start to feel
really bad. You overthink. You get
anxiety when you've got a great social
circle around you. And when you're good
with women, you get this extra level of
confidence that really makes like life
so much more enjoyable. And I know what
you're probably thinking is like, "Oh,
well, you know, girls are a distraction.
I don't really care right now." You and
I both know that's [ __ ] You and I
both know that if there was a girl who
was genuinely into you, you'd be so
happy. So don't [ __ ] and say like,
"Oh, well, I don't care about girls.
They're just a distraction." Because if
you're actually honest, you'd love to
like go on a date with a funny girl
right now. You'd You'd actually love it,
right? It's so easy for us to say like,
"Yeah, I don't care about girls." What
we really mean is like, "Yeah, I'm not
really attracting girls right now, so
I'll just pretend that I don't care
about them." When actually I do. I'm
just not very good at like attracting a
girl right now. And there's nothing
wrong with saying that, right? If
anything, admitting to yourself that you
do want a girlfriend or you do want to
go and flirt with some girls and you
want to make some friends is actually
such a positive thing because then
you'll actually have the desire for it
more and more and more. So to make
progress here, you've got to become the
kind of guy who girls are actually
attracted to. And it's not as simple as
just like, you know, build a physique
and do some looks maxing and get some
nice hair or anything. A lot of it is
about understanding female nature and
becoming the the bad boy that girls
actually want. It's like girls want two
kinds of guys. They want the bad boy and
they want the nice guy. They want the
nice guy to text to become more like a
friend with. You know, the nice guy,
you've probably been him, is the one who
the girl will text and Snapchat and get
like Snapchat streaks with, but she
won't suck his dick. You probably have a
couple girls who actually see you as a
nice guy right now. They'll text you.
They appreciate the friendship that you
have, but they're actually getting
[ __ ] by someone else. You might be
thinking, "No, no, not the girl I'm
speaking to." Yes, bro. Yes, they want
the nice guy and the bad boy. And if
we're being honest, most guys when I
tell them this, they're like, "Okay,
Hamster, tell me how to be the bad boy.
I completely get what you mean. I've
been the nice guy before. I've been like
the friend." And it's like, I don't want
to be in that [ __ ] role. I'd rather
be the guy that these girls are coming
to to [ __ ] right? That you know that
they're really obsessed with. How do you
be the bad boy? You've got to understand
female nature. You've got to understand
how to flirt and how to carry that sort
of whole personality. This is why I made
a entire like sixh hour course on how to
be the bad boy. I'll put it as the top
link in the description. It's like my
program where you get like a ton of
courses. But one of the courses in there
is a full guide. It's called like the
red pill course. It's a full guide on
becoming the bad boy that the girls
actually want to [ __ ] So you take that
course, you learn and you start getting
way better in your dating life. And
again, this is kind of like the
weightlifting, you know, the exercise
that I told you where it makes you kind
of happy for the future because you see
yourself in the future getting better
and better with girls. And now the
seventh and the final step to curing
depression, putting this all together.
You know, we've covered a bunch of
steps, but it's time to put it all
together. The seventh step is to write
down a timetable, a daily routine,
putting everything that we spoke about
into one place, and then you can stick
to it as best as possible. Do you
remember in school we had like a timet
where you would see okay 9:00 a.m. we
start 10:00 a.m. we have maths 11:30 we
have lunch 12 we have science whatever
it was like a timet right you should
have a timet for your dayto-day life so
for example you might write down 5:00
a.m. wake up and morning routine 5:30
meditate 6 a.m. read 7 a.m. gym 9:00
a.m. school 400 p.m. come home and eat
5:00 p.m. gym, whatever. You get my
point. You But just plot out the
dayto-day life of what we're going to do
on the best day possible. So, you can do
this on your phone where you can just
have like a, you know, wrote it down
5:00 a.m., 6 a.m., whatever. You can do
this on like Google calendar. You can do
this on a piece of paper, but just
somewhere you should have your daily
routine written out. So, you know that,
for example, you're going to wake up and
do that morning routine, which I told
you about where you're going to meditate
and do the gratitude journaling first
thing when you wake up. Then you might
need to get ready for school or work and
you're there for a good few hours. Then
you'll come back. What time will you go
to the gym? What time will you eat? You
plot all this out, writing like the
hours of the day down. And you have this
timetable, this routine as if it's like
the best day possible. The big thing,
the big mindset here is knowing that
this is the best day possible. And
you're probably not going to stick to it
like 100%. And that's okay. If you stick
to this timetable, even 30 to 40%,
you'll actually be like living a way
better life than you usually are anyway.
Right? Most times when I when I'm
helping a young guy and I tell them to
write this timetable, they'll come to me
and be like, "Oh, Hamza, I kind of
messed up today. I was in school longer
than I thought, so it kind of took away
the time that I had for the thing
afterwards and you know, I I the gym
took me longer and I couldn't go
whatever. The time table got messed up."
And to that I always say, "Bro, the day
you had today was still better than your
normal day, wasn't it?" And he goes,
"Yeah." And I says, "See, the time
table's so powerful, you write down the
perfect timetable, the perfect daily
routine. And if you end up following it
even 30 to 40%, it's usually better than
your normal days anyway. But some days,
because you've got the timetable in
front of you, because you've already
wrote 7 a.m. exercise, the decisions
already been made, you end up having a
way better day than your normal days.
So, write down the timetable somewhere.
So, this could be on your notes. You
just write down 6:00 a.m. wake up and
morning routine, 7:00 a.m. school, 3:00
p.m. come home and eat, 400 p.m. gym,
whatever. Just write it out somewhere,
Google calendar, whatever. Just write
down the daily time table you try and
stick to as best as you can. slotting in
all the things that we spoke about
today. So, you might have some reminders
for smiling. You might have a block of
time for reading that book that I told
you about. You'll have a block of time
for going to the gym and lifting
weights. You'll have a block of time for
working on that purposeful mission that
we spoke about. You'll have reminders
for smiling. You'll have a block of time
for learning how to be the the bad boy
that girls want. You'll block all these
times into your daily schedule. And once
it's set, you just keep your schedule
open as much as possible. You look at
that on your phone instead of scrolling.
So, you know how sometimes when you're
on the bus or you're having a [ __ ] you
just end up like scrolling? Instead of
that, just keep the same page open on
your phone, just stare at the timet. And
what you'll do is you'll stick to it way
better than your normal days. It'll be
right there in your face. Okay, after
this, I'm going to go and do that. After
that, I'm going to go do that. And it's
just so good for you to just remind
yourself. You know, there's a reason why
schools and the military have their
people on timets because after a while,
you start to kind of know what you're
supposed to do after the current thing,
right? It's about 9:00 a.m. right now as
I record this, and my body is getting
ready to go to the gym because I go
always go to the gym about the same time
every single day. So, it's almost like a
habit, but for your entire day. Do you
see how powerful that is? Those are the
seven simple steps to curing depression.
And I just want you to do a
visualization right now, just like we
did for Jeffrey.
If you think about the life you're
living right now where you felt
depressed,
you're living with your parents, you
have no purposeful work, you have like a
shitty social life, non-existent real
dating life. You know, you're messaging
a few girls, but it doesn't really
count.
That's the reason why you're depressed.
Because your life is [ __ ] If I was you,
I'd be depressed, too.
Now, I just want you to visualize what I
genuinely believe is the ultimate life
for men. I promise you this is so true.
It's where you move to a place where
there's other people like you, where
there's other people who are switched
on, who are ambitious. Barley right now,
as of me recording this, is such an
amazing place to move to for young men.
You make a few thousand dollars a month
and then you can travel the world just
working on your laptop. You know, I
actually set this goal for myself back
in 2019. I went on a holiday to Thailand
with like an ex-girlfriend of mine. And
this was when the phrase digital nomad,
which basically means you make money
online and you travel the world whilst
working online. I traveled to Thailand
and I was so hyped. Things were so cheap
and you know, you got a motorbike and it
was so much freedom and you're not in
your hometown. No one knows you. So, you
can be whoever you want to be. And when
I came home from that holiday, I
literally wrote down the goal. I wanted
to make $2,000 a month online so that I
could be a digital nomad and travel the
world. And that's exactly what I
achieved. So that's like the I tell you
that is like the lifestyle. You make
money online. You move to a place like
Bali. You get your own place. You live
by yourself. The best case scenario is
that you connect with other guys who are
on the same level as you right now.
You're both trying to make money online.
You're both, you know, on
self-improvement, leveling up so that in
a year from now, you can move to Bali
together and you can literally share
like a villa together. You've got that
masculine vibe. And right now if you're
thinking like, "Yeah, but I don't know
anyone who'd even do that." That's
remember I just mentioned that that
course that you can join in, you know,
my paid community. Not only do you get
the courses as part of that program
that's linked in the description, you
get this community of guys who are
serious about self-improvement. So so
many of the guys there have connected
with each other saying, "Oh yeah, like
we're all working on this goal to be
able to make a few,000 a month online
and we can go live together and travel
the world together." That's like the
life for your men. You make money
online. You can travel the world with
your boys. You can hit the gym with
them. You end up flirting with girls in
all these different countries. You get a
motorbike here. You fly over to this
place. You get a villa here. You go to
the gym. It's sunny. It's beautiful.
There's good people here. You're you're
far away from your family, your hometown
so you can be who you want to be. You
step into like this best version of you.
You're training together. You're eating
good food. It's almost like you're in
this kind of like university kind of
college kind of experience. But now
outside of the education system with an
online business, you're on
self-improvement. You've developed
yourself. There's attractive women
everywhere. You're cold approaching.
You're meeting new guys. You're training
together. It's a [ __ ] beautiful life.
I've been telling so many of my
followers to set their sights on moving
to exactly where I live, which is
Barley. And a bunch of guys have a bunch
of my followers have literally moved
here and they all train in the same gym
as me. So imagine like like bro, every
day you go to the gym, there's other
guys who have watched videos like this,
who have quit the bad habits, who
understand, you know, the addictions
that we all went through, who are now
eating clean, lifting weights together,
being competitive, talking about the
same things that we talk about. We've
all got like inside jokes. We call each
other Jeffrey, whatever. And it's like
we've got like a [ __ ] little
community here and every guy who's here
has got massive smile on their face.
It's so easy to meet women and meet
other guys and you're making money on,
bro. It's [ __ ] awesome. There's a
whole world out here for you to explore.
You don't need to just stay in your
hometown and stay like, you know, this
small little traumatized boy as you've
been this entire time. There's a world
out here for you to enjoy, right? To
think about how beautiful it would be
for you to like speak to a few guys
right now who are on the same path as
you who have got the same goal as you
and for you guys to work together to to
maybe get here later this year or next
year at the same time. You rent a villa
together. How [ __ ] cool would that
be? That's why I made that community,
Library of Adonis. That's where like the
guys who are the most serious, the ones
who like are my followers, the ones who
are most serious about their growth, we
join there as a community. And there's
guys that you can meet who even who are
inside of your hometown. Like you can
see the map of our members and you can
start to like actually get onto this
path with other guys which checks off
that need of your brotherhood, of your
social life. There's a whole world out
here. One where it's sunny and you're
riding around on a [ __ ] motorbike
shirtless. The type of stories that you
will literally tell your future
children. Life's too short to be just
sat in your little childhood bedroom
depressed, consuming.
It all starts with you taking action on
what I've given you here of you mixing
with other men who are on this path who
are going upwards in life. Not downwards
like the Jeffre that you know, but
upwards. You integrate really, really as
best as you can in this like masculine
self-improvement space that you are
watching me for. And I promise you the
life that you want, I promise you it's
as good as I'm hyping it up to be. I
promise you it's achievable. I've done
it in a few years. I see a bunch of
young guys as well, 18, 19, 20 years
old, who have achieved it, and they they
look so happy. They're so productive, in
great shape, meeting girls and hyping up
with the boys and and training hard and
building businesses. There's such a good
life out here. And I really I wish that
for you cuz I've been in those days
where I was depressed and I hated my
life and I was just working some [ __ ]
job that was like expected of me. I went
to university, got the degree. I lived a
life that was expected of me and I was
so depressed and I changed up
everything. And I'm so happy now. So
happy. And I know that it is possible
for you to do the exact same thing. I
want this transformation for you. I want
more of our boys to start like, you
know, living like the real life. Maybe
moving out here. I know that's a big
move to, you know, move up across the
world to somewhere like Bali, but like
that's something that you can set as a
goal for the next like couple years when
you can achieve it.
I really hope that this helps you.
Do the hard work, especially when you
don't feel like it.
Woo!