what up primals what up primals don't
you know that liver is King we have
liver we have potatoes we have mushrooms
we have garlic and we have the whole
Beast pistachios liver King out all
right so here we have it guys I'm gonna
make you some liver in a crock pot it's
actually going to be nutritious and
healthy I'm not going to eat this raw
because that's recorded and here we have
turkey liver you can use chicken liver
you can use beef liver you can use bison
liver liver of all kinds is highly
highly nutritious it's one of the best
superfoods like you know how the
magazines and all these people will be
like kale kale is a superfood or quinoa
is a superfood no BS liver is actually
the king and all kinds of liver chicken
turkey beef whatever it is that you're
planning to use all of them are really
really good I happen to be using turkey
liver today but you can use anything and
the recipe will work out just fine so
what you need is the liver the mushrooms
potatoes and garlic not onion I think I
call this an onion before so first step
is is unless you're getting your produce
from a farmer's market you know for a
fact that all your produce is covered in
herbicides pesticides insecticides all
the sides which you don't want in your
body so everything which you eat whether
it be potatoes or mushrooms you need to
wash them not just with water but also
with baking soda and vinegar so we have
our potatoes we have mushrooms I'm going
to put the whole thing in so what do we
have one two three four five six seven
eight something like 15 mushrooms and
I'm using one two three four potatoes
and this is 2.2 pounds of the liver and
regarding washing vegetables it's not as
important for like potatoes but it's
very very very important for fruits and
berries more so than these ones because
fruits and berries especially berries
because they have such high moisture
content they tend to go bad easily and
so they have to add these fungicides to
protecting them from fungus and these
fungicides are very very toxic for
anybody who eats them so you add water
you mix it up and you let it soaked for
a little bit and as this soaks we can go
ahead and peel the garlic as trust in
the modern diet and Modern Health
practices declines there's going to be
more creators like me who want to show
you how to prepare healthy meals in the
traditional way but it's also going to
be a lot of scammers like liver King who
take steroids and abuse their body to
have a certain look and claim that
that's Primal right you have to use your
own judgment your own discernment to
find out who's actually natural and
who's not because whenever there's a
movement and I I really think that the
esoteric Health movement is going to
crash upon the mainstream in a big way
in the next five to ten years A lot of
people are going to be turning towards
traditional Health practices like eating
organ Meats like getting sunlight
refusing to eat seed oils and so on and
as this cultural shift happens there's
going to be money to be made that's just
the case right and people are going to
be making money in all the wrong ways
liver King is just a start there's going
to be more scammers I guarantee so keep
your eyes without know who's real who's
not and you know make your judgment
based on your instincts make your
judgment based on your knowledge and
make your judgment based on your eyes if
the guy doesn't look natural he's
probably not natural the prevalence of
performance enhancing drugs is just as
prevalent in the influencer industry as
it is in the sports industry and there
we have it we have our garlic nicely
peeled
and here we have a crock pot crock pot
is the ultimate cooking tool it makes
every food so easy to cook just drop
your garlic right into it you don't need
to slice them you don't need to do
anything just put them in there and then
we have to go ahead and cut the potatoes
into smaller chunks
and finally we have the liver you don't
need to cut it you don't have to do
anything in fact you don't even have to
drain the blood just add the entire
liver all of them now if you have
something bigger like if you have beef
liver or you have bison liver or
something then you have to cut it but
turkey livers are not that big so I can
put them directly and same for chicken
liver so you don't have to cut them and
then once you have everything in place
now it's time to add all the seasoning
and everything else that you need to
actually make this taste good first we
have olive oil and I'm using of course
extra virgin olive oil just
I'm not measuring exactly how much just
a nice generous Splash then we have salt
I'm using pink salt but it doesn't
really matter you can use any kind of
salt I'm doing one
big tablespoon
of salt in fact I'll actually go ahead
and increase it to one and a half
tablespoons of salt I could have even
put two because salt is not the enemy
they made you think that salt is very
bad for you it's going to give you like
heart attack and whatnot that's not true
salt is actually pretty useful pretty
good for your body then we have well
more importantly we have pepper so you
need you definitely need pepper in this
and this is just freshly ground
pepper and I'm just going to sprinkle
some of that how much is that probably
one tablespoon but again I'm not
measuring it perfectly because I don't
need to and then we have turmeric also
called haldi this you don't need that
much of probably like half a tablespoon
of haldi then we have red cayenne pepper
and this is just a Sprinkle not more
than that just for a little bit of spice
and then we have garlic powder you can
be more generous with the garlic powder
I like the taste if you don't like it
then don't put it obviously then we have
ginger powder also very important put a
bunch of ginger powder in this and
finally we have some oregano I'm gonna
sprinkle oregano on this thing
and before I forget you're going to use
chicken broth or any kind of bone broth
really because that's going to be the
base for cooking rather than water just
makes everything taste better it's more
nutritious as well
add a nice there's probably one cup
probably one cup of the chicken broth
and there we have it we have all the
ingredients in this already but we need
to mix it up and then turn it on so I'll
just use my hands mix all the
ingredients and that's it liver takes
much less time to cook than chicken meat
like the actual muscle meat so for
chicken you would usually put the crock
pot on low for eight hours or on high
for four hours for the liver we're going
to cut that time in half so I'm going to
turn it on high and remove it from the
heat in about two hours all right so
it's been two hours two and a half hours
actually since when I got this started
I'm gonna open it up
and
see if the potatoes are done why because
if the potatoes are done then everything
else is done that's the way this this
works so if you look at that the
potatoes are nice and fluffy they're
coming apart which means they're good of
course I can taste some
I mean it's super hot right now so I'll
just take a little bit
and
yeah
tastes fun tastes like it's done
which means everything else is done so
this is so okay so look at that the
liver is kind of coming apart I don't
want to break the livers I think I I
prefer eating them without breaking them
so if you have like chicken breast or
any kind of muscle meat it'll get
shredded and that's fine but for the
livers I like to keep them intact of
course get the get the mushrooms get the
potatoes get some of this extremely
nutritious extremely nutritious
um like broth going on with the stew
broth that has a whole bunch of
nutrients your body will thank you for
look at that see liver doesn't have to
taste nasty you know and you don't have
to eat the liver raw despite what
freaking liver King says this is well
cooked beautiful
tasting liver and and get some of this
garlic as well you see that garlic clove
right there so
just look at it let's look at it in the
light that's a really nice and tasty
meal the kind of the blandness of the
potato contrasts nicely with the rich
flavor of the liver
and we have an excellent easy to cook
meal I'm going to go ahead and turn this
thing off and then we'll taste test this
so the question is how does it taste so
have the liver and first I'm going to
try
the garlic
really good the Garlic's gonna absorb
the flavor of the meat the potatoes
not so much the potatoes are still a
little bit Bland which is which is fine
because it contrasts nicely in the
mushrooms because yeah the mushrooms are
also a very meaty kind of flavor so it
adds to the meat and kind of wholesome
and fulfilling nature of this dish
the mushrooms actually really excellent
the mushrooms might be the highlight of
this dish to be honest mushrooms are
high in a lot of micronutrients your
body needs for your testosterone
production and if you're a woman
obviously it's for your hormonal Health
as well and then the liver itself the
king liver is in fact King let's taste
it
perfect perfect you know liver is done
correctly when it's not too tough when
you cook liver for too long what happens
it becomes tough and kind of gross
tasting it kind of becomes almost like a
sandpaper like dry texture if you if you
cook it for too long this is perfectly
done so it actually tastes a little bit
moist it tastes really good has flavor
to it it's very different from muscle
meat that's for sure but it doesn't
taste bad a lot of people think the
liver tastes gross that's not the case
you make it right and it'll taste right
all right I gotta go and enjoy my meal
see you again