the Barbie movie is a Greek tragedy
where Ken our tragic hero his Destiny is
thwarted by his one fatal flaw his
unrequited love for Barbie and his
overall naivete the movie even shows the
greatest flaw of democracy a secret
cabal of Elites can use psychological
manipulation to sow the seeds of sexual
confusion and use Warfare as a
distraction to seize the levels of power
there is even a scene straight out of
Fight Club in this movie in the Barbie
movie but my favorite scene is when Ken
says something along the lines of first
I thought the world was run by horses
and men but actually horses are just the
extenders of men is this not true is
this not Ken's blood memory boiling up
from the depth our horse is not the
extenders of men this is the Mythos of
the Bronze Age when men first
domesticated horses their speed was 10x
their deadliness in the battlefield was
10x they could travel 10x further their
Dome main their conquest of land their
presence was 10xed is this not the
extension of man the world was indeed
created by men on Horseback from The
Chariot Lords of India to the
cataphractory of the byzantines to the
Polish Lancers to the step Warriors of
Genghis Khan to the Roman equities to
the saracens of salahuddin the world was
indeed shaped by men on Horseback was
not General Washington the finest
Horseman of his era could Alexander have
conquered the known world without
bucephalus I do not know if the
directors intended this movie to promote
the vision of Bronze Age Vitality but it
does just that and it does it perfectly
and I a scholar of Connecticut
philosophy will be your guide for those
who haven't watched this unintentional
Masterpiece I'll give you some context
so we start off our movie in Barbie land
where the Barbies the females own
everything they own all currency they
own all property they own basically
everything the Ken's basically don't
even have houses but the movie is not
stupid the movie doesn't portray this as
a feminist Utopia it clearly shows
through the use of irony that there's
some serious problems here they show how
vacuous the society is all the Barbies
do is party every single night there is
no need for water there's no need for
resources there is no birth and there is
no Decay There Is No Death and there is
nothing to fight for and there's nothing
to fight against here's a society where
nobody's life has any meaning this is a
realm of stagnation of infinite stasis a
land of never-ending triviality the
movie says every day is the perfect day
for Barbie but a day is only perfect for
Ken if Barbie looks at him and this is
how we meet Ken our protagonist Ken
begins his story arc as a simp
everything he lives for is Barbie's
attention so the Barbie universe is
basically reality and Barbie land and
whenever something bad happens in
reality that affects Barbie land so
basically the main Barbie Margot Robbie
has to go to reality in order to fix
whatever is going on there so that she
can come back perfect and on her way Ken
basically hides in her car and tries to
stow away with her to reality that's
basically like act one of this play for
act two Barbie and can have their first
experiences in reality and this is
actually done pretty cleverly I saw a
couple other reviews by the big name
right Wingers like freaking Shapiro and
they all start raging at this part of
the movie which doesn't make sense
because it's actually intelligently done
Margot Robbie has never had to hit
puberty because she just was a woman
from day one she's a doll but a real
woman's life is not like that there's a
genuine period of hardship and
misunderstanding and confusion with a
woman first hits puberty she has breasts
for the first time and this is not
something we men can kind of trivialize
it but we don't even understand the pain
slash discomfort of it but the fact of
the matter is when a young woman who's
basically a child she first develops you
know sexual features she starts to
become attractive to men for the first
time this can be a very difficult and
challenging experience for them and we
as men simply have no gauge to
understand that by so it makes perfect
sense that Margot Robbie Robbie when she
finds her way into reality I mean she's
looked on as a sexual object by men for
the first time she feels intensely
uncomfortable of course she does but
that being said there are some dumb like
feminist things added on which don't
make sense for example in broad daylight
in the middle of the park some guy comes
and slaps her in the ass like that's
another thing which really happens let's
be real and if that did happen other men
would beat him up for it but far more
interesting is of course the Ken plot
line so Ken goes on his own way in
reality and we the audience are treated
to an amazing Montage of Ken's
introduction to masculinity he goes
around the city and he sees men being
masculine you know he sees men sparring
fighting Being Fit he sees strong police
officers on Horseback maintaining Law
and Order he sees dollar bills with the
founding fathers of America stamped on
there for eternity he sees Cowboys and
horses he sees Golf and cars he sees
trucks and beer and Stallone and all the
cool things which make me love being a
man and this montage is actually really
really good like check it out and the
music is also perfect with it but it
does have one serious flaw you see Ken
hasn't spent much time in reality I just
only spent like half a day right so this
is the only angle of man that he sees
what he doesn't see of course is men
dying in needless Wars he doesn't see
firemen jumping through fires to save
innocent people and dying in the process
he doesn't see oil rig workers he
doesn't see plumbers electricians
linemen he doesn't see who cleans the
windows on skyscrapers he doesn't see
most of the sacrifices of man and this
naivete will come to bite him later and
the next scene is even better so he can
goes around in town trying to look for a
top job because he saw the Montage of
masculinity and he thinks that just by
being a man he's going to get a top job
he goes and tries to be a doctor he
doesn't have a license he goes to be a
banker he doesn't have an MBA he goes to
be a lifeguard and he he doesn't know
how to swim and men and women turn him
down at each of those places the lesson
to be learned here is men don't just get
things handed to them on a plate we
don't live in a dominance hierarchy we
live in a competence hierarchy it
doesn't matter if you're a man or woman
if you can't do the job then you don't
get the job and of course there's
nothing competent men despise more than
an incompetent man but sadly Ken doesn't
understand this he doesn't understand
that competence is a vital vital vital
important part of being a man and that's
what gets him actual respect you see a
little knowledge is a dangerous thing
and that is the tragedy of Ken and now
we go on to the Barbie side of the story
so Barbie has to go and find the human
who played with her basically what
happens in the story plot is when a
human is sad and playing with a Barbie
that manifests itself in Barbie life so
she has to find the human and then make
her happy in order to fix herself to go
back to Barbie land so she finds the
human she finds a mother-daughter Duo
and the mother is the actual human who
controls that Barbie or doesn't even
control but you know the feelings leech
onto the Barbie and then there's the
daughter who's just annoying as [ __ ] but
the mother is actually pretty decent but
meanwhile Ken has already gone back to
Barbie land think about this Ken thought
that the world was ruled by men in
reality but he still left it to go to
Barbie land to bring his new vision to
his comrades who just before he was
competing with with the Promethean fire
he harnessed from reality he goes to
Barbie land to bring his vision for the
future into fruition this is what is
meant by kennergy and at this time the
trio of Barbie and the mother and
daughter team are coming back to Barbie
land and now the movie really starts to
go The Barbers realized that the entire
Barbie land has been converted into
Kingdom and kendom is basically the
kingdom of the Kens there's horses
there's big ass trucks there's
attractive women everywhere everybody's
happy and having a great time and Ken is
explaining the things I told you before
you know he's explaining how horses are
men extenders and is is he not correct
from the Knights of the Round Table to
the pharonic Chariots of Egypt men on
Horseback built this world and indeed
the whole cowboy aesthetic are not
Cowboys emblematic of the urge of man to
expand past his borders into the unknown
to seize unknown riches and bring forth
a new future a new Destiny for his
people are not the Cowboys the poster
child of Bronze Age vitality and it's
not just men who like horses women love
horses have you ever talked to a woman
who's been raised around horses girls in
general love horses why because the
horse seen from the perspective of a
woman is a being of skull crushing power
this is the dream for most women is to
find a man who is immensely powerful and
whose power knows no bounds but to her
he is good kind and loyal that is the
imperative for a large fraction of women
no surprise then that all the Barbies of
Kingdom actually having a great time
they love the the change as it were lit
the president Barbie of barbieland says
she'd rather be serving beer than being
president it's in the movie I didn't
make it up but of course you know the
objection to that would be she's
brainwashed but we'll get to that soon
the psychological operations part of
this movie is actually the most
interesting I'll get to it don't worry
and here we are introduced to Alan
actually Alan shows up even earlier but
he's insignificant humans we're fine and
Ellen
you see Alan is the opposite of Ken
Allen is a weak jawed weak spine weak
Spirit worm of a man who is despised
equally by the Kent and Barbies alike
he's ignored by the Barbies as a
non-entity and he's disrespected by the
Kelsey Allen literally has to massage
Ken's feet and the philosophy behind
Alan is interesting too and we'll get to
that as well when the Barbies reach
Barbie's house they find Ken in there
and Ken has basically conquered that
space he's taken Barbie's house and
converted it into his Mojo Dojo Casa
house the mother and daughter team
object to this name they say you can't
say casa and Dojo if you're already
saying house but Ken just dismisses them
and says it sounds good and he asked
them to repeat it and they do and here's
an interesting scene actually the
mother-daughter team actually fall into
the trance they fall into Ken's command
prisons and they start calling it Mojo
Dojo Casa house they're only snapped out
of it by Barbie who wasn't in the trance
because she had known Ken before his
Ascension and there's some Banger lines
in this movie so Barbie finds out what
Ken has done and she starts crying and
throwing a fit and she says to Ken you
can't change society in a single day and
to that Ken says literally and
figuratively watch me that is a line
spoken by a man of action that is a line
spoken by a man of Destiny this is the
essence of canic energy he went from a
Barbie simp to the Lord of his land in a
day he became a Napoleon a Caesar
overnight if a doll could do it why not
you and if you feel like energy let me
know in the comments type out I feel
like energy everybody who does it gets a
heart from me and here's the thing about
kendom people aren't actually being
oppressed in Kingdom there is no threat
of physical violence and there's no sign
of psychological manipulation there's no
crime there's no harassment there's no
cat calling all the female Barbies are
essentially doing whatever it is that
they're doing on their own free will now
you can look at the movie and say this
is an undesirable state of events that's
fine but the factor of the matter is
this is not oppression this is free will
if you want to say that women can do
whatever they want and they choose
voluntarily to serve beer and appear
attractive that's on them that's up to
them and multiple Barbies say that they
like this state of affairs more than the
previous one the president Barbie says
it one of the physicist Barbies say it
the general consensus is that Ken made
the world better for them you see this
is what feminists don't really
understand men and women actually get
along just fine 99 of the time we like
women women like us there's a certain
kind of dance which goes around between
the Sexes you have to show that you have
attraction but you can't do too much of
it otherwise you look too available but
this is a dance which the feminists are
not invited to they don't understand it
they perceive that whenever a woman is
dressed attractively she's doing so
because of brainwashing or oppression
this is not true and they perceive men
being loud or Brash as a part of the
patriarchy or oppression this is also
not true women do absolutely go out of
their way to appear attractive to men
which they are interested in and men
obviously do the same exact thing this
is as nature intended and this is what
the feminists hate and how do we know
that Ken didn't Brainwashed the Barbies
we actually know the movie actually
tells it Ken actually says that all he
had to do was explain the immaculate
logic of patriarchy his lines not mine
and Society followed his vision that's
not brainwashing that's called giving a
speech to the masses and convincing them
of your ideals now you can disagree with
the ideals that's fine but that's not
called brainwashing that's called giving
a speech later on in the movie you'll
see what real brainwashing looks like
and it's the Barbies who do it and now
on to the interesting part the secretive
cabal so Barbie the mother and daughter
and a couple other discontinued Barbies
so the the kind of like the rejects of
society Barbies they form this cabal
this secretive organization and they
want Barbie land to be restored to the
old Barbie land before Kingdom but they
don't know how to do it and they're
frustrated what happens at this point is
the mother right the mother from that
mother daughter Duo she's had enough she
freaks 7 gives a monologue a speech and
the speech honestly wasn't that bad it
was actually pretty decent and I know
this speech did really well in feminist
circles which is fine because it was a
genuinely valuable speech it talks about
the pressure put on women which I agree
with if you think men are under pressure
women are also under pressure and it's
actually worse for them because at least
we kind of know what success looks like
for us but for women it's a double
standard it's kind of terrible actually
we judge women using masculine metrics
Society tells a young woman she has to
make money she has to own stocks and
bonds and certificates of deposit and
all the things which men used to do she
has to make big decisions but also she
has to be a mother and a caregiver this
is not reasonable we're asking too much
of women in society we're enforcing two
different metrics on one side we're
giving them the masculine metrics to
Aspire to and the other side the
biological imperatives of women still
stand they still want to be mothers they
still want to be Caregivers for their
children and every promotion you get
every other hour you spend working is
one hour less from your child the women
find themselves in a very unfortunate
position they find themselves trapped
and exhausted and they're always tired
because we're asking too much of them
this is an absolutely ridiculous State
of Affairs the movie does a good job of
pointing it out but of course it doesn't
put any of the responsibility on the
feminist movement I'm not saying
feminism is to blame for all the ills of
society that's unreasonable but to some
extent they do have to take some of the
responsibility that being said most
responsibility is not with the feminists
it's actually with certain decisions
made by certain people in certain parts
of government which I won't get into too
deeply in this video think about who
actually won out in the feminist moment
was it real women I'm not so sure a
woman now has to do both the job Alpha
mother and also the nine to five as the
average woman did not really win under
feminism I'm sure their lives improved
in some important metrics I agree with
that but the real winners were the
corporations weren't they because now
men and women both are competing for the
same position so the labor market
basically doubled overnight and when you
have intense competition for the same
exact resources the price for that
resource drops so corporations can get
away with paying low salaries which is
exactly why you need a man and a woman
both working in order to support a child
so the real winners of feminism wasn't
the females or the freaking corporations
but of course this movie was made by a
corporation so I don't expect that to be
brought up now comes a really
interesting part of the movie where they
dissect the biggest fragilities of
democracy the first one is the
manipulation of mass democracy by a
secret cabal what happens in this part
of the movie is basically the cabal of
Barbies the disfigured Barbies like the
mother the child and the freaking main
Barbie Margot Robbie they go into Barbie
land and they start kidnapping Barbies
against their will and indoctrinating
them against what they believed in and
they've basically force feed them
feminism until they become feminists
this is called brainwashing and this is
what the Kabbalah does the cabal
basically organizes a well-structured
deliberate plan of psychological
operations to use against the Barbies to
make them all into feminists of course
in real garments they don't necessarily
have to kidnap people and indoctrinate
them there's better more efficient ways
of doing things but still the analogy
strolls well you know any democracy
needs to be very careful that a cabal of
special interest groups doesn't
brainwash the population into doing
their bidding and then War needless War
Between Brothers this is also a
brilliant part of the movie so before we
get to there the newly feminist Barbies
each of them seduce one can each so
they're all sitting in like a big Gaggle
and every single Ken is being
manipulated by one Barbie and they
literally say this in the movie they
tell the Barbies to act as though
they're interested in their respective
Ken's and when the Kens are truly
feeling comfortable they genuinely feel
that they're getting the attention of
the woman who they love that's when they
go and swap partners to cause the cancer
to become jealous of each other to feed
their insecurities in order to seize the
levels of power this literally happens
in the movie and this is portrayed in
the movie as good and just but I see it
for exactly what it is we just deceit
and manipulation so this movie is
actually brilliant it shows young men
that even at the peak of their
performance they should always be wary
of manipulation not only by women but
also by anybody in general so the secret
cabal has sown the seeds of sexual
dysfunction and sown the seeds of War
and the next day the cans go to war
these cans were just best friends so
because of the psychological
manipulations now they're at War and the
war is to no purpose except that the
Kent are distracted when the kids are
distracted the Barbies want to go and
set up a new constitution so think about
that very carefully does this not happen
in real life are some Wars not just
distractions and psychological
operations do governments not cause
unnecessary Bloodshed and suffering just
so that they remain in power for a few
more years is this not a dire warning to
every single democracy that has ever
existed since the dawn of Athens to the
birth of the United States that the
citizenry must be very careful as to
what wars they enter into and every war
spills valuable and valorous blood while
the Gremlins and politicians sit back in
their Ivory palaces and count their
dollar bills and then we have a
brilliant scene which is literally copy
and paste from Troy the movie about the
Trojan War and at this point I think the
director knows what she's doing I think
she literally is trying to promote a
vision of Bronze Age Vitality because
why else would you use literally the
Trojan War and of course Troy Troy Ilyas
Ilion oh well however you want to say it
Ilion is a Trojan word for Troy it's
literally called the land of horses so
Ken he and his Navy they Beach on Ken's
Beach and the other Kens the opposite
side of Ken's they're holding the beach
and they have this violent battle
straight out of the Trojan War Ken is
Achilles and the other can the Asian can
he is Hector and Hector and achilles
face off and pitched battle in single
combat but unlike in the Trojan War they
realize thankfully that the war was set
up by the powers that be and they don't
really hate each other they're just
pawns manipulated by the machine and
they come together they hold hands and
they are brothers and when all the cans
realize the manipulation which has
happened that the Barbie set them up
just as a destruction so that they could
change the Constitution They Ride
against the capitol they go to the
Barbies to see what's changed and here
the movie gets even better so we have
all the kids recently bloodied from this
war ready to fight they realize that the
Barbies have taken their power through
the use of manipulation and at first
when Ken sees this treachery he's up in
arms he rages at this he calls out to
his brothers and they link arms in
Shield wall formation ready to besiege
the capital ready to take back their
power but now he doesn't know what to do
can he use the force of violence against
females and you see the female emails
may have used sexual manipulation and
psychological operations against the
Kent But Ken is a honorable man he
cannot use violence against women and in
fact they show this in the movie so one
of the Kents asks the main Ken who are
we attacking sir and Ken doesn't have an
answer and this is where the Epic Greek
tragedy part of this movie sits in at
this point Ken capitulates he breaks
down but anybody who's watching this
movie closely understands that he was
this close to snapping on the other side
the canarchic revolution almost happened
all he had to do was give the command
and the chems could have taken Kingdom
and deposed of democracy and they could
have had all the power the only reason
they didn't do this is because they were
Men of Honor and Men of Honor do not use
physical violence on women and so the
tragedy of Ken unfolds a man on the path
of ascent is brought Low by his one
fatal flaw his naivete of human nature
and his undying love for his women even
at this point Ken could have gathered
all the other kins and then gone to a
different place and set up a new kingdom
there he could have even ventured into
reality and set up a new kingdom in
reality but sadly he does not do this he
doesn't have the wisdom he had the
strength he had the Primark Aura he had
everything he needed to start a new
kingdom but he didn't have the wisdom to
know how to do it that's a beautiful
tragedy and a Learning lesson for every
young man who aspires for the greater
things in life and if you agree with
this message I want to see in the
comments Ken did nothing wrong you might
think that the juicy part of the movie
is over but not so there's actually more
stuff coming up so what happens now is
Barbie goes and visits the beaten and
broken Ken and delivers lines straight
out of Fight Club she says something
along the lines of you are not the
clothes you wear you are not your
girlfriend you are not the job you do
and this every man's job to find out who
he truly is Tyler Durden Fight Club says
the exact same thing you are not the job
you have you are not the amount of money
you have in your bank you are not the
car you drive and you are not the
contents of your wallet you are not your
[ __ ] khakis is the message of this
movie much different from that I'm
telling you right now Barbie movie is
The Fight Club of 2023. we are not prone
to manipulation and we understand how
these games are played and at this point
Ken's story arc is essentially complete
he realizes that Barbie doesn't give a
single [ __ ] about him and he goes on on
his own to find his own meaning which is
cool and then Barbie's story is still
unconcluded and then we have freaking
Alan See Alan did not participate in the
Battle of Ken's Beach Island being the
wimp that he was was despised by the
Kens and therefore he went on to the
Barbie's side and the Barbies of course
just ignored him you see this is an
important message which I have to give
to women and surprisingly I bought 10 of
the audience is actually female it's not
the Kens of the world that are the
actual threat to you understand this
very carefully a good looking man who is
already well off well-adjusted
pre-sociable is not the one who's going
to harass you he might try to flirt with
you you may not like that and hell he
might even be annoying to you but he's
not gonna harass ask you he's not going
to be a physical threat to you Allen's
on the other hand are a different
problem you see Allens won't flirt with
you Allens will not even show you that
they're interested Allens will use
psychological tactics they'll be your
friend but when no one's looking it's
the alliance who actually commit crimes
be very careful when a man says that
he's a feminist be very careful and go
in the opposite direction you see this
movie does a very good job of showing
male naivete it shows how men can be
very prone to manipulation by women but
of course the opposite also true men
also try to manipulate women that's also
a thing and it's the islands which try
to manipulate women and the ending of
the movie is actually pretty good for
the first time I see an ostensibly
feminist movie actually promoting
motherhood what happens is the movie
makes it very clear that pursuing
motherhood is not a bad thing which I'm
really happy to see that the movie
clearly says yes of course carriers are
options for women by the end of the day
they can choose to be a mother and
that's perfectly fine I would actually
go one step further and say actually
motherhood is the most sacred and most
honorable Duty and maybe feministic will
disagree with me on that but I don't
care what they say really at the final
scene of the movie Barbie goes to a
gynecologist which implies that perhaps
she will eventually if she wants to be a
mother it's very nice to see a movie
that actually promotes that kind of
thing because most young women think
that being a mother is a second tier
activity to actually getting a career
I'm happy to see that young women now
see that being a mother could be
actually considered the tier one
activity and being a career woman is
actually beneath that and for all these
reasons I give this movie five Bronze
Age chariots out of five if you're
interested in high level discussions
like these then you should consider
joining my country club a private
society which I will be launching later
this August well I will teach you all I
know about esoteric Health methods and
give you a full classical education
philosophy history economics you name it
these are the things which aren't taught
to you even at the University level
these are the things which make you
dangerous say bye to the camera B my B
friend right here take him out let me
see if I can bring him to the camera
come on there we go yeah take him out
cute little guy come on yeah there we go
can you see him look at him