I'm going to teach you how to overclock
your brain using methylene blue so
methylene blue is a mitochondrial
support supplement and mitochondria as
you probably heard in like every single
bio class that's ever happened that
mitochondria is the PowerHouse of the
cell so where do you find mitochondria
you'll find
mitochondria in almost I mean literally
every cell but they're highly
concentrated in the neurons which is
what our brain is made of so it comes as
no surprise then
that methylene blue is going to increase
your cognition so your power to think
your ability to solve mathematical
problems to work through Solutions and
to have even more
creativity also it's no surprise that it
improves memory both shortterm and
longterm you have more energy overall
because your neurons are able to fire
more efficiently and finally you have
more Focus which is to me the most
important aspect why
because time is not the most important
resource a lot of people think that time
is a finite resource and it's really
important it's important sure but you
only have 24 hours per day and no matter
what you do you're not going to get more
hours it's energy and focus that
actually gives value to time so anything
that improves my focus is going to be
highly beneficial to
me so how does it work you know how is
it possible that the same exact
supplement also improves skin like how
can a brain supplement improve skin and
it comes down to the mechanism of action
and when you saw that it increases
energy and focus you probably thought
well is it kind of like caffeine is it
like coffee and the answer is it's not
so coffee caffeine let's say it works by
a receptor being bound to by that
caffeine molecule it binds to the
adenosine receptor in the brain trying
to trick the brain into thinking it has
more energy than it actually has it
doesn't actually give you any energy
methylene blue does not bind to
receptors that's not its mechanism of
action it acts directly on the
mitochondria that's why it has all these
wide ranging effects because every
single cell has mitochondria in it how
does it work well let's go so you know
that mitochondria is is a Powerhouse of
the cell and it produces energy for the
cell all this stuff but how does it do
it so what's mitochondria actually doing
is when you have food and you have
glucose the first complex inside
mitochondria so mitochondria has five
complexes 1 2 3 4 and five actually
grabs an electron from your glucose and
and it shunts it from complex 1 to 2 2
to 3 3 to 4 4 to 5 and from five comes
out
ATP ATP is energy so think of this as a
race car engine all right and each of
these are like Pistons try to convert
that fuel into into momentum into energy
all right so what happens then if you if
you disrupt this it's a good question
isn't it that's happening to most people
a lot of people a majority of people I
would say have poor metabolic Health
which means that they have broken
mitochondria they have damaged
mitochondria and of course if you're
thinking of this as a race car engine
not only do you get energy you also get
waste products you get smoke in the cell
this is in the form of R oos reactive
oxygen species that's what the cell even
naturally produces even an undamaged
mitochondria is going to produce some
level of R so when you have a damage in
the mitochondria let's say the complex
one is no longer able to move electrons
to complex 2 you have a disruption let's
say you have a disruption between two
and three so if you have an engine and
you damage it somehow what's going to
happen first you're going to have less
energy obviously you're going to have
less energy but you're also going to
have more waste products and these waste
products are toxic so you really don't
want these in your body if you can help
it and let's talk about how methylene
blue plays a role in all this so
speaking of damage to mitochondria you
might be wondering like how does this
damage even happen and it happens to
many reasons obviously one of them is um
oxidative stress another is seed oils so
seed oils like safflower oil sunflower
oil soybean oil canola oil all these
seed oils what they're going to do
is they are going to
interfere with the mitochondria because
oxidized seed oils have these byproducts
called aldhy and that's not that's not
the only byproduct by the way these
alides are going to damage the membrane
and these complexes are situated on the
membrane so you can see how that's not
going to really help is it so was
methylene blue do methylene blue is an
electron
donor so if there's a break in the
circuit between complex 1 and two and 2
and three methylene blue can actually
donate an electron straight to complex 3
and you immediately have the restarting
of this electron chain and you can still
produce ATP and yeah you still produce
reactive oxygen species and now this is
where it gets interesting the same
methylene blue that can donate an
electron and thereby keep this engine
functioning can actually
neutralize the reactive oxygen species
which is because methylene blue is a
auto reducing agent there's not that
many out there Myan blue is kind of rare
because of this property it not only
boosts the energy function of the
mitochondria it also deletes the waste
products of the said mitochondria now
you can see how it's really powerful now
you can see why it would affect all
these different things from the brain to
skin so let's briefly talk about the
skin side of things so there's actually
research which shows that mitochondri
sorry not mitochondria methylene blue
will cause skin to reverse age causes a
reversal of Aging bizarre but it's true
it causes skin to be more elastic more
lustrous more thick and it's because
skin cells are cells like any other
cells if they incur damage it's a
struggle to fix it if you have bad
mitochondria fixing the mitochondria
allows skin cells to fixs and also
proliferate and generate more cells if
some of them die or get damaged so
that's why help with skin and I found
this interesting product which I want to
show you which is this company
they took Tallow bomb which is already
the best skincare product on the planet
and they infused it with methylene blue
this thing is called miraki
moo and now you might be asking the
question well is it actually better than
the product which I suggested before
which is the Vintage tradition Tallow
bom and I've been experimenting with
both of them and I actually still prefer
the Vintage tradition you can see like
this has been around I've almost used
all of it that's not sure why the
Vintage tradition is still
better but I've done the experiments
right I've done it experiment on myself
so what I found is with the makaki moo
product I have to reapply it during half
the day but the Vintage tradition
product I never have to reapply it you
only have to reapply it after you wash
your face or take a shower so I still
prefer the the OG vintage tradition
Tallow bom if you want to my opinion on
it so there we have it boys that's why
it improves all these things now those
who are astute have noticed that I said
it reduces viruses and that's because
indeed methylene blue is an
antiparasitic which parasites are a
whole different topic a whole can of
worms yes a can of worms indeed which I
will go into in a future video but it is
in fact an antiviral which is why it was
used against malaria for quite a long
time and which is why a certain new
invent in
infection actually methylene blue can be
effective against that I won't mention
it by name but I think you understand
what I'm talking
about though it is an antiviral and it's
an antibacterial so you might be
thinking well if it's an antibacterial
then could it possibly harm the gut
microbiome good question if you're
thinking in that way then I'm proud of
you that's the way you should be
thinking and I Al actually put off B
mealine blue for the longest time
because you know it could affect the gut
microbiome even if has these benefits
like I don't want to really compromise
my gut
health but I looked into it and there's
research and this is a really cool piece
of research by the way they took a bunch
of mice they let's call them mice a b
and c and they ran them with different
quantities of methylen blue group a
didn't get any methylene blue Group B
got a pretty decent dose of methylene
blue and group C got a mega dose a super
dose of methylin blue like they got I
think they were given like 50 g of
methylene blue per kilogram of body
weight which is ridiculous these mice
were probably blue for like
weeks well so they took these mice put
them through mazes as scientists are
want to do and what they found
was mice a underperformed which is
obvious because you know if you have
mice B and C with all these benefits IQ
well it's not actually IQ it's more like
cognitive power but increased cognitive
power increased memory then obviously
they're going to perform the maze better
cuz what do you need to solve a maze you
need memory you need energy you need
Focus so mice B and mice C easily won
over mice a and now they looked at the
gut microbiome they found that mice A
and B were the same so a moderate dose
of methylene blue doesn't seem to change
the microbiome now they looked at the
mega doed methylene blue mice in group C
and what they found was there was a
small change in the gut microbiome so it
seems as though even with a quite a
large dose of methylene blue it doesn't
completely screw up your gut health and
obviously no one's going to be taking 50
g of methylene blue per kilogram that
would be a ridiculous amount of
methylene blue and there's no reason to
be taking that much and of course I'm
going to talk about dosages soon but it
does seem to me that it's fine to take
it in terms of gut health and of course
none of what I'm giving you here is
medicinal advice it is all just for
educational purposes whatever risks that
you want to occur are up to you it's not
my
responsibility I'm just sharing with you
my personal experience with this
particular
supplement so let's talk about another
thing which is going on which is another
side effect which a lot of people notice
which is an increase in anxiety you see
have put actually lowering stress but a
lot of people will tell you that methine
blue increases anxiety so I looked into
it and it confusing because why would
something that increases ATP production
cause increased anxiety didn't make
sense especially when you consider that
ATP and energy are relaxing they make
you more
relaxed in fact if you take a dead piece
of muscle tissue it's going to be kind
of rigid right but if you put it in a
bat of ATP it will actually become more
lifelike it'll become more Supple become
more like how it was in in life cuz
energy is life ATP is energy so it's
really a puzzle why some would be more
anxious with the introduction of
methylene blue I was thinking about this
and I realized that what is anxiety
really anxiety is a recurring thoughts
of recurring negative thoughts really so
if you have increased computational
power increased recall and increased
focus on those negative thoughts of
course you're going to feel more anxious
so it's not that methylene blue per se
is increasing anxiety it's more so that
methylene glue is eliminating brain fog
allowing you to come head-to-head with
your anxiety I think that's what's
happening here so if you have anxiety
symptoms because of meal blue it's
likely that you just have bad mental
health and that should be the priority
you should be working on not some kind
of productivity supplement you should
work on the basics the fundamentals of
basic mental health so of course that's
going to be a topic onto itself so I
won't go into it but that's another
concern mealine blue is just a
supplement boys it's just a supplement
the fundamentals always matter more
nutrition and detox and mental health
are the foundations for a happy life
methylin blue is something which can
help but it is not the foundation and
never intended to be so I have two
courses the nutrition course and the
detox course but I don't have anything
on Mental Health I think I should
probably make something like that so
there you have it that is methylene blue
and that's how it works question is like
how do you get it where do you get it
from how much do you have and what are
the other side effects there's another
side effects which is kind of funny when
you start taking MB you will you'll piss
blue like straight up your urine will be
blue in color this is not something you
should be afraid of it happens to
everybody it's an expected side effect
so dosages where is the stuff this is I
didn't have that much left this is my
vial of methylene blue the dosages I
take one dropper so this has a dropper
right so I take one drop of this let me
actually show you properly I take one
drop or full before I hit any kind of
important task so what I mean by that is
I don't actually take it every day I
take it when I need it so I'll take it
before I am trying to come up with a
video I'll take it before a live lecture
like this I'll take it when I'm doing
something which requires my full
attention and full cognition power so I
take it only when I need it because
that's my attitude towards any kind of
supplement you only supplement when you
think you need it you don't take a
supplement every single day unless you
have some kind of condition you should
be getting most of what you need from
just Whole Foods so I use this as a tool
rather than a
fundamental you can take two droppers
actually and if you are really focusing
on something I would be okay with taking
two droppers of Metaline blue which each
dropper is 5 mg so there you go I take
two droppers if I really need it one
dropper usually
that's about
dosage now where do you get it from so
this is very important boys so there's
two grades of mealine blue there is the
industrial grade and there is the
pharmaceutical grade you're obviously
looking for pharmaceutical gr grade
because the industrial grade has heavy
metals it's going to poison
you so you need to look for two things
you need to look for USP verified which
means that it is pharmaceutical grade
verified and you need to look for a COA
which is a certificate of analysis and
it's done by like a lab which actually
goes through it and sees if it is a pure
product I get all my methine blue holy
this flies around here boys I get
all my methine blue from the same
company which makes the Tallow product
maraki medicinal and this is what I
suggest I actually reached out to them
looked at their COA and I I trust in
them because obviously I use their
product so I reached out to them got a
discount code for 15% off if you want to
use it you could do that and there we
have it that's your entire rundown on
Metaline blue I know I covered quite a
lot of information in this video if you
want a official summary of everything
we've discussed so far there is an email
intake form in the description I will
send you my personal show notes every
single time there's a lecture you'll get
the show notes so if you want that and
all the links everything will be
included right so put your email in
there other than that tomorrow's lecture
is going to be on the red white and blue
protocol what's that so right now it's
winter I mean you may not guess that
it's winter
because I'm in Hawaii and the place is
gorgeous it's always kind of summer or
spring here but if you are in the the
United States or in the UK and the in
European countries it's winter right now
so you don't have a lot of sunlight it's
likely that you're not having a lot of
movement you're not getting a lot of
exercise you might have seasonal
depression which is nothing it's not
actually a depression it's more like a
metabolic health issue and it's a
vitamin D deficiency so I'm going to
create well I'm not going to create I'm
going to give a lecture on the red white
and blue protocol which eliminates that
completely from your life I used to live
in Indiana so I know how it feels like
to have gray skies day after day for 6
months so this is going to be really
helpful for those who are living in cold
climates and finally if you like me I'm
not talking about my content if you like
me personally then follow me on
Instagram you get to know like what I do
on a daily basis and other random
information as I'm living my life I
share it on Instagram all right boys
that's the lecture I appreciate your
time I'll see you in the next one and
I'll flip this camera around and see if
there's any questions