I can't believe Hamza has 400 000 guys
bopping their dicks that was the
fundamentals course this is the advanced
lesson not only that I'm going to show
you how to make the best omelet you've
ever made in your life just to outdo it
out compete what harms I did in his
video you see Hamza forgot to mention
hydration hydration gets your muscles
looking thick and juicy and same is true
also for your shaft grab a big glass of
water add some table salt to it and chug
it that's going to give you the
vascularity and I assure you that adds
greatly to her pleasure another huge
fundamental is getting sunlight early in
the morning when that early morning
sunlight hits your eyes it's going to
recharge your dopamine circuits and
that's going to make you much more
receptive to the kind of pleasure a
woman can bring you and of course that's
going to make you perform far better but
not only that not only that so when you
have sunlight exposure in the morning it
also activates your pineal gland which
is essentially your center of Sexual
Energy so sunlight in the morning is an
absolute non-negotiable said something
about eggs and absolutely he's correct
eggs are a fundamental to high
testosterone and high testosterone is a
huge factor of course in sexual
performance so here I'm going to show
you how to make the perfect egg omelette
which you're actually going to enjoy
eating and actually enjoy making because
if you don't enjoy yourself while you're
cooking and eating you're not really
going to do it it's not going to be a
consistent habit for you in the long run
so first you need high quality eggs
what's a high quality egg it has to be
either free range or pasture raised why
is that it's because when you have hens
laying these eggs inside a coop instead
of building inside a closed environment
the hens don't have vitamin D so there's
no vitamin D in the eggs naturally right
you need the hens to be outdoors eating
insects and worms and whatever it is
that hens eat being exposed to sunlight
so that they can actually store that
vitamin D in their eggs which then you
can consume to obtain that vitamin D in
a bioavailable form so I got some
beautiful blue eggs right here with me
I'm going to break them and just look at
the color of that yolk that yolk is so
beautiful
nice orange deep color that shows you
that it's good quality eggs it doesn't
have to be that way there's eggs which
are yellow and they're still good
quality but this is what but this just
looks nice to me
then you go ahead and you beat them
and the more time you spend beating the
better and more smooth and consistent
your omelette is going to be I have to
tell you this which is very important
regarding your sexual performance
essentially is that you can have the
perfect diet you can have the perfect
sleep perfect everything and you might
still mess up because I haven't
discussed and even Hamza didn't really
discuss the biggest problem that you're
going to have especially if it's your
first time especially if you're not
experienced so you have to be very
Vigilant about your performance anxiety
and this is the make or break Factory
even more important than getting
sunlight in the morning which I consider
to be highly highly important so I'm
going to help you overcome performance
anxiety for the rest of your life
including your very first time but first
let me get this omelette started I'm
going to let my cast iron heat up a
little bit when I add some ghee onto it
ghee is a saturated fat highly stable
highly nutritious strongly recommend
ghee for cooking it's just as good as
butter if not even better than butter so
hamsa mentioned the importance of butter
why because butter is a saturated fat
just like ghee and the mainstream wisdom
is that saturated fats are bad for you
and polysaturated fats are good for you
this I believe to be wrong I believe
that saturated fats are actually the way
to go this is what our ancestor ate for
millions of years and had zero problems
with it until the modern day when
cardiac arrest and other diseases have
began to proliferate I find it hard to
believe that that which was working for
millions of years suddenly stopped
working so we have our ghee melting nice
and good I'm going to spread the ghee
out a little bit
so when you're in the bedroom or the
kitchen or the garage wherever you all
want to do it the thing which is going
to get you is the performance anxiety
I'm telling you right now that it's okay
not to perform during your first time or
even second or third time
is because you will have many many
opportunities my friend you'll have a
thousand hundred opportunities later in
your life to bang her brains out her or
some other girls brains out right so
don't stress it on your first time
you're literally inexperienced think
about it if you were told to make a
painting you think your first painting
would be your best painting or would it
even be a good painting obviously not in
no skill are we expected high
performance in the very first attempt
why is it that we have this extreme
pressure on ourselves when it comes to
sexual performance that we need to
perform from day one the first attempt
ever don't have this crazy performance
anxiety don't have this crazy pressure
on your head to perform that you have to
impress this girl and you have to do
perfectly the very first time you're not
going to succeed in that you're not you
don't have any experience you're not
going to be good at the first time
and you know what a lot of guys don't
understand
it's quite often that the girl is
actually more nervous than we are she's
even more afraid of her performance than
we ever are but the difference is you
know girls can kind of hide their
performance they can hide or you know
fake their orgasm we have to display
everything right our organism our
performance is very much visible so
perhaps there's a little bit more
performance anxiety because of that but
I assure you in her mind she's also
going crazy she's like you know can I
deliver pressure pleasure to this guy
can I
can I do my part can I make him happy
all these thoughts are going on in her
head far worse than it is going on with
your head so have some compassion for
her you know it's not a competition it's
not a fight it's literally sex
it's supposed to be one of the most
beautiful experiences a human being has
and if you don't perform you know what
the sun is still gonna rise you're still
gonna be okay the world is going to
continue it's not the end of your life
trust me I know the feeling I was a
young idiot once too right I was going
out with a beautiful Brazilian
volleyball player at the time and I got
this terrible terrible advice from
literally The Men's Health Magazine it
said something along the lines of you
need to bust a nut essentially you need
to masturbate before you have sex so
that you last longer this is utter
garbage watching porn or masturbation
destroys your sexual energy and you
won't be able to actually get hard and
perform with an actual female real human
being woman if you engage in those kind
of activities so literally my very first
time with this beautiful Brazilian chick
who is actually a nuclear physicist
right now it's kind of crazy so I had
taken this bad advice and not only that
this girl was making a Brazilian drink
called a caipirinya or something like I
know how to pronounce it right but like
this Brazilian drink and you know I
wasn't anxious I was nervous so I had
one too many drinks and alcohol is
terrible for boners I assure you like if
you have alcohol the chance of you
getting a proper boner diminishes
rapidly so I had taken that bad Men's
Health advice I was already anxious and
nervous plus I was having alcohol so you
know it was already game over for me I
mean I know that in retrospect there's
already a game over for me but I didn't
know it at the time so I couldn't
perform I'm not going to go into the
Gory details because I don't even want
to go back there in my even in my
memories right and
you know it was a disappointing and
painful night however
are still in the game the next morning
you see the sun is your ally the next
morning well it wasn't just the sun
which was Rising let's just say she
definitely got it she was yelling in
Portuguese and everything so I succeeded
in the end but trust me when I tell you
I know the pain of bad performance I
hope it doesn't happen to you but if it
does it's fine you can joke about it
later hell me and that girl actually
joked about it later like a couple weeks
later well she joked about it to be
honest me in my head like I was laughing
but in my head I was like you know sharp
bit and you know it was a fun time but I
just want to alleviate your performance
anxiety it's not that serious but on a
more serious note here's the omelet
almost coming up
um it's got a little bit stuck to the
pan this happens if your pan isn't hot
enough to begin with like I said this
stove is kind of [ __ ] so my omelette is
not perfect it is what it is I have to
tell you something more serious though
so porn addiction this is gonna mess you
up in a big way because
porn affects your dopamine system it
affects your prefrontal cortex which is
the center of stoicism in your body and
your brain it's not the perfect omelette
but man is better than what hamzo is
having so I'll call it a win and so you
have your omelette it's all really nice
and made it has the ghee texture it has
a ghee flavor what I'm gonna do is put
this aside and cut my piece of bread
regarding porn addiction right you
obviously want to break free from that
and I'm going to be making a video about
this very topic I already made it
actually it just needs to be edited and
this video is so good that I will
actually make you a personal promise
that video is coming out in a couple of
weeks if you watch that video you will
break free from your porn addiction for
the rest of your life I literally
explained step by step exactly what you
need to do to break the addiction so
watch out for that video
meanwhile we have our breakfast almost
ready I have my Italian bread I have my
omelette cooked in ghee and of course I
have a piece of nice dark chocolate this
is 85 cocoa
dark chocolate and I will pour myself a
little bit of olive oil a little bit on
the Omelette itself and a little bit on
the side olive oil is a mono unsaturated
fatty acid so it's not as stable as your
ghee it's not as stable as butter but
still plenty Stables it's very healthy
olive oil is been used for thousands of
years right so nothing surprising there
far more healthy than your seed oils
and here we have it perfect breakfast
you don't have to have breakfast I like
breakfast so I have it it's pretty light
breakfast so it works for me find out
what works for you and have a nice day