hey guys so I just watched uh hamza's
video on astrogenics it's a pretty good
introduction to the field of estrogenics
but some things he missed out or
something that I think could be
explained better
one thing he speaks about the sauna and
how the sauna has a great place to detox
that's true but it's not it's not
complete so when you're in the sauna
you're going to sweat out a lot of your
estrogenic mode from your fat cells but
you need to use a towel and wipe
yourself off constantly while you're in
the sauna and you need to wipe yourself
off completely before you leave the
sauna because those estrogenics are
still going to be in your sweat so if
you leave the sauna and your sweat dries
on you those estrogenics will just seep
back into your skin you don't get the
full benefit so you need to have a towel
when you create a sauna second thing
water
you need to have a metal water bottle
with you
in the sauna and drink water constantly
because your estrogenics will leave your
body not only from the sweat but also
through the urine so drink a lot of
water because your cells are going to be
agitated by the Heat and that's going to
release the estrogens into your well
into your blood and you know whatever
fluids in your body but you can only get
them out of your body when you urinate
or sweat so make sure you're drinking a
lot of water third thing and actually a
caution or dishonor the heat in the
sauna will actually kind of fry your
balls like you your sperm
will sometimes get damaged if you spend
too long in the sauna which is fine for
most people but if you're trying to have
a kid in the next 90 days you shouldn't
be using the sauna or if you are then
you always have a bottle of the cold
water and you just pour cold water on
your balls and keep them cold because
heat does destroy spermine that's one
thing
another thing he mentioned was uh
Omega-3s so oftentimes we'll get our
Omega-3s through cod liver oil or fish
oil which is fine but
the oceans and rivers of the Earth are
polluted with estrogens and other things
like which are not even estrogenated
which are like heavy metals and Arsenic
and whatnot so when you're consuming cod
liver oil or any other fish oil or any
fish products that matter you need to
make sure it's from a clean source that
means you cannot buy the standard
omega-3 you know fish oil supplements
off the counter in your CVS those
probably will do more harm than good
because even though they contain the
Omega-3s they also contain estrogenics
so you need to do your research again
man it's all a matter of awareness and
understanding where your food supply is
coming from it's not simple that's why
this channel exists