ever brainwashed myself was to get girls
and I use the first two techniques here
logos and mental rehearsals so this was
no ordinary girl man she was special I
was walking down the central atrium of
my big Library building in my University
and I see this girl in the corner of my
eye she had red hair which caught my
attention she was wearing green moss
green which was my favorite color so
immediately I was interested I I saw her
she was wearing gold rim glasses which I
think the glint of that is what caught
my eye in the first place she had like a
gold uh not gold gold and Jade locket on
and she was Dro dead gorgeous she kind
of looked Irish she had the perfect
physique it was kind of um fall season
so she was wearing the fall you know the
kind of things which girls wear during
the fall she looked like a work of art
all right and I was very desirous you
know ravenous I was desirous of going
and talking to her well I was desirous
of a little bit more than that but let's
keep it familyfriendly all right so I
take take a step I'm going towards her
and immediately there's an objection in
my mind she's busy like she's plugged in
like she has her airpods on she has her
laptop in front of her she's clearly
intent on whatever she's doing like I
couldn't go and you know interrupt her
she's maybe she's taking the quiz right
maybe she's listening to a lecture from
her professor right I shouldn't go and
talk to her right now she's not
receptive I also see this people Milling
around so it's objection number two this
people these like nerds who are going to
listen to my conversation if I try to
pull moves like everybody's going to
know everybody's going to hear it it's
going to be kind of cringe so I don't
really want that and I take another step
even despite the objection and a third
objection appears in my mind she
probably has a boyfriend a girl like
that is not going to be single for very
long she probably is taken and I could
put in all this risk and effort and
everything and there would be no point
because she's obviously going to be
taken put another step forward still
walking towards her she's this close she
her table and like she's working on on
her laptop and I just walk past her I
just walk past
her I want you to remember this phrase
rejection is always better than
regret I walk past her and I keep
walking along I go to my classes I'm
still thinking about this chick and I do
my classes I'm walking the opposite
direction but when I'm walking the
opposite direction I see her computer
screen she's not busy she's not doing a
quiz she's on Netflix she just
distracted like everybody else so
immediately my first objection is proven
to be false by direct
observation and I realized maybe the
second and third objections are also
incorrect so I I analyze this I'm
looking at it
logically like there's people around and
they are going to hear but if the price
to pay is a bunch of dbes listening in
that's a price that I'm willing to pay
if all that's standing behind me and
banging this girl's brains out it's a
bunch of onlookers who probably not even
going to remember me the next day then
I'm willing to pay that price any day
right I'm willing to pay that price so
second objection is immediately
destroyed third objection is she has a
boyfriend but I don't know that I don't
know if she has a boyfriend why am I
placing an objection in front of myself
which I don't even know to be true for
all I know she could be receptive maybe
she's single I don't know and I
shouldn't be putting a defeat in in
front of myself before I even make an
attempt
so I was like okay I don't even have any
objections anymore I have to talk to her
but even so my body doesn't cooperate I
am not able to go and speak to this
chick and I sit down I sit down and I'm
like okay I'm going to practice this
before I go so in my mind I'm
visualizing how this is going to play
out like the entire scenario I walk up
to her pull the chair and I'm like hey
is this seat taken she's probably going
to say no it's not taken go ahead and so
I'll sit down I'll pull out my laptop
act like I'm doing something thank you
what's your name and she would say her
name and she can do one of two things
she
could she could just continue her work
in which case she's either not
interested at all or she's actually busy
and I should leave her alone fine or she
could say and what's
yours that means she is in that means
one she's willing to be distracted and
two she's either attracted or at least
curious and I'll take that right I'll
take that any day so that was my
objective that was my mission parameters
so I do exactly as I rehearsed I walk up
pull the chair ask if I can sit down she
says yes I ask her what's her name Avery
she says and what's yours she says it in
a kind of cheerful and girly kind of way
I'm in it's already a success I'm
already meeting 100% of mission
parameters I've already won I don't care
at that point I genuinely didn't care
what happen in a conversation whether I
get her number or not it doesn't matter
I've already done what I said I would do
using the power of mental rehearsal and
logos so I'm going to explain these in
autistic level details so that you can
actually use them in real life but
perhaps you want me to finish the story
so I talked to this chick and this girl
has girl game so just as we as men have
a certain level of Charisma and game
when when we talk to girls right she had
the girls equivalent of this she didn't
need it she was Dro dead gorgeous and
she didn't need any kind of social
skills to be more attractive I don't
even know if she could be more
attractive she was kind of pale skinned
but her lips were still you know bright
and attractive she had green eyes moss
green eyes which is my favorite color
like I said she was playing with her
locket she was playing with her hair her
voice was a little bit high pitched she
was doing that thing which girls do when
they're kind of interested they'll kind
of bunch their shoulders and kind of
move side to side she was doing that she
was telling her telling me about
herself our conversation was objectively
not flotation if you just look at the
words we're just speaking about you know
future goals and like all kind of benal
lame
stuff but it was in the eye contact
flirtation the only difference between
flirtation and a conversation is the eye
contact and Body Language I of course
that might be a topic for a different
video like how do you actually talk to
girls and everything but
fine let's let's leave that for a
different video right so I talk to this
girl get her number uh if I did that
today like with what I know now I would
go for the same day date 100% of the
time
easy but I went for the number which was
fine got her number and I should say
this don't go for the insta go for the
number rather than insta unless you have
more than 5,000 followers on Insta if
you have more than 5,000 it means that
you have some clout and it actually
might help build up her attraction but
if not go for the number it's more
direct it's just more sexual Instagram
is kind of um androgynous you know guys
ask guys for their insta girls ask girls
for their insta it's just it's not
necessarily intimate the phone number is
necessarily intimate so go for the phone
number 100% of the time unless you're
actually famous on
Insta starting to rain here which is
fine I've done stuff in rain before
that's for sure so that's mental
rehearsal and logos let's run through
the autistic level steps and and
speaking of which after the date I will
just say
that she's a very loving girl let's
let's leave it at that she's a very
loving individual it didn't work out
long term because like this girl like
she was she had a notch count on her and
she was one of those girls who had the
popular on Tinder badge so like she
wasn't the right girl for a long-term
relationship but you know I have no
regrets whatsoever all right so let's
just leave it at that and go into the
actual actionable steps so the first
technique Tech I told you was logos
logos is a technique to use against
limiting beliefs so first you need to
isolate and detect limiting beliefs what
you do is whenever you have something
that you want to pursue but you don't
pursue it because of some reason analyze
what that reason is that reason is a
limiting belief you use logic to analyze
the belief is this actually objectively
true or is it something which I'm making
up or something which I've picked up
along the course of my life most of the
time it's going to be the latter and
anybody can fall into this trap is
somebody which you and I both respect he
had a limiting belief about money he
thought that if he sold something he
would lose his audience not the case
he's still growing people love him and
he's making hell lot of
money I had a limiting belief about
sleep I thought that I was an insomniac
turns out that I could not fall asleep
if I had an unproductive day and because
I was at that phase of my life I was
unproductive basically every day I
didn't get
sleep and so analyze your beliefs
destroy them see if they're actually
true I was abusing melatonin for years
up to that point I realized that
melatonin is not actually good for you
and I should stop I like am I actually
an insomniac or is it something which
I've made up in my mind and because I
realized it was something I made up in
my mind I was able to destroy it that's
logos the second technique is mental
rehearsals mental rehearsals are kind of
what I described in that story acting
out the thing that you're going to do in
the mind before you actually do it and
to do this you're using your eye the eye
of your mind basically the Mind's Eye
and I'll prove to you that you have a
Mind's Eye all right I want you to
visualize this imagine this it's raining
right now I kind of like it I like the
rain imagine it's raining all right it's
a dark and stormy night and there's an
old man he's he's bundled up in his
robes he's feeling cold his bones are
achy he's walking and he has this
crooked cane that he carries around with
him and in a in a puddle to the left of
him he hears a sound and it's a little
baby bird he picks it up and it's
showering it's pouring and this little
bird he cows it in his cloak and says
hey little one you're safe now you could
imagine that couldn't you you could
visualize this entire scene couldn't you
that's your mind's eye now you don't
have to visualize others people's
stories you can make that story and
visualize it yourself in your own mind
when you do that you're actually putting
in the Reps when you do that you're
putting in the Reps and this is a
technique which is used in sports all
the time Elite level coaches mediocre
coaches don't do this but Elite level
coaches do this all the time especially
in tennis and golf they will teach the
correct form to their athletes and ask
the athlete to visualize the form not
even actually physically do it just
imagine what muscles are Contracting and
how the wind blows across your forearm
as you strike the ball visualize it
right and you can this is very common in
tennis you can actually visualize the
ball coming in across the net taking a
bounce Twang and you see the balls going
in the exact trajectory that you had
charted out for it you can use this for
music you can use this for public
speaking so I actually do mental
rehearsals for these videos and these
lectures I do three mental rehearsals
one immediately after I conceptualize
and kind of script out my lecture second
at any random point in the day and the
third right before I sleep why do this
it because it's because it tells your
REM sleep mind what to dream about and
in your dreams you run through the
scenario like 500,000 times so basically
I have like a 500,000 or 5,000 reps
before I even give this lecture which is
why I'm able to do it with relative ease
and fluidity I don't have to be sad
there or I don't have to consult notes I
have no notes around me right
now so that's mental rehearsals you can
use it for practically anything
life-changing technique highly recommend
you use it now the question is like why
should you be brainwashing yourself
anyway well I'll tell you this that
everybody's Brainwashed the only
question is who's brainwashing you and
what they're brainwashing you with even
the great men of history have been
brainwashed Alexander was brainwashed by
his mother into believing that he was
semi-immortal
divine you know General and he
manifested that in real life didn't he
he truly believed himself to be great
and Immortal he Le the charge from the
front he was the first man to charge
into Enemy Lines every time his his
companions he had this Elite Cavalry
called the companion Cavalry they would
try to race him and get there first but
they couldn't Alexander was always
number one guy on the battlefield
Napoleon brainwashed himself Napoleon
brainwashed himself and he did so he was
living in the island of Corsica which is
like a poor little island off the coast
of France and Frenchmen actually they
despise or you know they see corsicans
as beneath them when Napoleon was in
Corsica he would used to imagine war
games and strategies if Corsica was
invaded by a foreign Force what would he
do where would he place the Cannons what
would be the Arc of Fire where would he
place his battalions where would he
place his ships and everything of course
when he became a general he had already
put in a, 5,000 10,000 reps before
commanding his first battle
so if the great men of history
brainwashed themsel I can do that you
can do that everybody should be doing
that and that brings us to the next um
technique which I'm going to sh share
with you which is the art of future
sight so future site is an advanced
version of the mental
rehearsal future sight you're not
practicing a given skill you are instead
practicing the version of yourself that
you're going to become in a year or
two's time for me me personally I
manifest or I wouldn't say manifest I
imagine I imagine the 30-year-old
version of myself every morning after I
do the three s's so my morning routine
is ultra simple Sunshine salt which is
electrolytes and uh shower shower salt
and sunshine after I get these three my
morning routine is basically done I'll
sit down outside on a porch chair and I
visualize the version of myself when I'm
30 years of age I see my Palms are
callous due to the weightlifting I can
see my forearms are big I can feel that
my neck is thicker I can feel that my
voice is more deep I can feel I've have
grown out my hair I can feel that I have
a beard because at this point my
military contract would be done and
actually have a beard I can imagine this
version of myself his ability to speak
is you know unparalleled he he has
perfect enunciation he can command the
room he can tell these stories which are
gripping and emotionally resonant he has
this voice that commands the room people
actually listen they want to listen to
him starting to pour out here
boys that's the version of myself that I
need to be right now essentially what
I'm doing is I'm bringing the version
which I will be to the
present so how does one do
this one does this by focusing on the
details what does your hands look like
what does your mind feel like most most
importantly so I visualized the
30-year-old version of's mind being like
a Lake
Placid glacial calm but when there's
something to do a task to be achieved
100% Focus like a laser cutting through
steel that's the mind which I want to
have just as you put in the Reps in the
gym to improve your muscles you put in
reps in your mind to improve your
mind and finally we have the final
technique which is
lucid dreaming is a weird technique and
I'm not going to go into it too deeply
in this video tomorrow's lecture is
going to be lucid dreaming because lucid
dreaming has risks it has risks involved
the other three techniques which I
showed you anybody can do it you can do
it how many other times you want there's
no risks it's all benefit but lucid
dreaming is something which I used to do
I stopped doing for a long time I'm
starting again right now so I'll explain
why and the risks and the rewards so
lucid dreaming for those who don't know
is the art and skill of able to control
your dreams you can
actually dream about the thing which you
want to get good at and do the Reps in
your dreams so Tim Ferris actually is
was the one who introduced me to this
Tim Ferris actually says that he got
good at wrestling because he used to
practice wrestling in his
dreams and it's true man you practice
the thing in your dreams and it carries
over to real life they did experiments
about this too so it's not like just me
making some stuff up the actual
scientific literature does exist now
I'll go into the exact techniques in the
lecture tomorrow so if you want to visit
that then you absolutely should it's a
powerful technique it has some risks but
if you're mature enough to use it
correctly it can be extremely powerful
I'm using lucid dreaming right now to
get good at speaking without edits like
speaking without relying on cuts and you
know AI generated Graphics to get a good
video so that's lucid dreaming I'm going
to talk about it in detail tomorrow and
I have a challenge for you all these
lectures they are not free there is a
fee to be paid in the in the effort that
you put in the challenge for today is
choose one of the first three techniques
either you're choosing logos mental
rehearsal or the future site and what
you're going to do is you're going to en
enact that technique and you are going
to give us a report of your experience
with that so if you're on YouTube you
can leave a comment saying this is a
technique I used and this is what I
learned if you're on Call's Country Club
do it inside the community instead
finally the yesterday's lesson was one
on purpose if you want to watch that
I'll have the tile pop up if you are
struggling to find your duty and your
destiny that is the lecture you want to
watch all right boys I'll see you next
one