some of my Fondest Memories were
actually playing Assassin's Creed 2 back
in the day when it came out I remember
playing the game doing the missions and
going to school discussing them with my
friends me and my closest friend at the
time we would discuss the weapon sets
the armors all these Secret locations in
the game we discussed the music the art
the culture the characters the story our
language our way of speaking even
evolved we learned new words from that
game and even to this day so a couple
months ago I was in the City of Florence
and I remember just looking at all the
real architecture there and remembering
looking at the same exact structures in
the game years and years ago as a child
and now I had the means to just go to
the City of Florence and enjoy it in
real life a real highlight for me this
year was to go to the top of the Duomo
in Florence and get that exact same view
that edzio gets when he reaches the top
of that building a lot of us have
forgotten what video games can be video
games are a beautiful medium they can be
just as valuable as a great piece P of
fiction a good story and for the same
reasons a piece of classical literature
or a beautifully written story a work of
fiction can be immensely valuable it
teaches you storytelling skills it
teaches you an appreciation for
Aesthetics it teaches you ethics and
morality and indeed some of the deepest
truths of human nature are discovered in
fiction in stories and not in self-help
books and business books as much as we
who like to improve oursel are obsessed
with improving productivity and learning
new business skills and improving our
lead generation and all this all these
are valuable definitely but we should
not pursue these at the cost of our
moral ethical and aesthetic development
and some video games not all of them can
play a role in this when I was in
Tuscany this summer I remember looking
at the Orchards and Vineyards and
remembering it looks exactly like what
was in Witcher 3 when Gerald runs his
horse across these Meadows and those who
watch my videos on the Roman Empire and
its demise and what we can learn from
that in the modern society you will know
that I'm big into history and one of the
reasons for this is because back in the
day I used to play a lot of Age of
Empires and playing age of the empires
gave me the Curiosity to learn more I
used to browse on the internet I had
even this encyclopedia which I used to
go to history books and I learned about
various cultures I learned about the
Greeks the Romans the ruts the Samurai
and the Mongols I learned about all
these cultures as a result of that game
so you could say that Age of Empires did
actually shape my intellectual growth
but it's not always Sunshine trust me
later I picked up a very specific game
called Rome to Total War and this is
where the trouble starts all the games
that I mentioned so far except age of
the empires are pretty non replayable
you can just play them once you get
through the story and that's your
entertainment from that game but Total
War Rome 2 was very replayable and
here's the problem this game was
perfectly designed to to addict my
psyche specifically when I talk of games
like Assassin's Creed The Witcher and
even AJ vampires I kind of talk about it
with fondness I remember those memories
those are great times playing those
games discussing it with friends
obsessing over strategy getting to know
these unit types and unlocking cool
weapons earning new armors and learning
and developing strategies from other
people who are playing the game and
having it even influence our fashion
sense and all these like little little
things details which really made the
game come to life for us as a child I
don't talk about any of that fondness
when it comes to Rome 2 this game was
like crack to me I was genuinely
addicted to this and it all comes down
to the context the greater context of my
life so had just got into college and
this was a huge change which I wasn't
prepared for high school and middle
school for me were not a challenge I
enjoyed it I had a great time in high
school and middle school I was not the
victim of bullying I was smart enough to
get decent grades I was Notorious in
school for having discipline issues and
answering back to teachers and things
like this but this only kind of brose my
popularity so to speak and I had
acceptable levels of of interest from
girls and everything so high school and
middle school were fine for me I enjoyed
it but as as soon as I came to college
it was a the complete reset I had status
and it was all gone in a matter of a day
I started from scratch no status
whatsoever and looking back at it now
it's I suppose it's kind of childish but
at the time it mattered a lot I was
alone I had no friends I was confused
and to be honest the reason I was
choosing to do engineering was to some
extent because I felt like I had no
other option I didn't even know other
options existed I hadn't put in enough
intention I hadn't explored enough and I
was just following the track which I
felt I had really no other paths to
follow this lack of Direction the
loneliness and the feeling that I didn't
have control over my destiny all
combined to make it ripe for me to fall
into an addiction and Rome 2 was that
addiction for me you see Rome 2 is an
interesting game it's it's a strategy
game it's a very complex game with
thousands of moving Parts it's an empire
building game where you have control
over various settlements each settlement
has their own buildings there's a whole
economy to manage and on top of that
there's these realtime battles where
where you are kind of the general you're
looking at the battlefield from above
and you can move your unit around create
the perfect formation the perfect Shield
wall you can use hammer and annal
tactics you can choose heavy shock
Cavalry or you can choose melee Cavalry
you can choose horse archers you can
choose foot archers there was hundreds
of units to choose from there was
Byzantine catari there was Roman
priorians there was Spartan hopl lights
there was rodian Slingers there was
baleric Slingers there was different
Technologies to research There Was You
Know Siege engines there was this there
was that it was rich it was so rich and
and here's the thing in real life I had
no status but in that game I had massive
status in that game I was a general I
was a commander of men I had armies to
my name I had Legions I had settlements
that would answer to my command and the
problem solving aspect what do you do
when an invasion occurs from a border
which you didn't really guard what do
you do when your econom is collapsing
but barbarians are at the gates this
game was designed is a massive puzzle a
problem solving exercise with multiple
moving pieces all of them which interact
with each other and you have to have a
lot of knowledge and a lot of
understanding to play your pieces right
and that aspect and being rewarded for
knowledge and hard work was very much
addictive to me it was crack to me man I
just dove into it and my entire freshman
year of college I became an expert in
that one game putting hundreds of hours
into it and you know there was no real
benefit in the end of the day had I
played that game for just a couple hours
here and there that would be fun I would
have learned some history I would have
learned cool unit types which existed in
real life I would have gained a new
aesthetic understanding and I would have
of course had some Leisure and some
downtime but that's not how I treated
the game I treated the game as my career
and so no I do not remember this
particular game and this period of my
life at any fondness and to this day I
avoid playing any Total War games
because I know that my psyche is kind of
vulnerable to that kind of game so how
do you actually overcome this addiction
I didn't overcome the addiction what
happened was my computer died and I
couldn't afford a better computer Compu
and so I was forced to stop playing and
this at the time yeah of course it
caused pain but by God that was a
pivotal movement for me losing my laptop
my gaming laptop so if you're addicted
to video games trust me just toss out
your computer get yourself a Mac which
doesn't even have games and your
productivity will just Skyrocket and so
my second year of college I didn't have
that same addiction to Rome 2 I had
moved on I joined a fraternity which
that's a separate story for a different
time I had a different kind of social
life alog together and then I detached
from that I separated from that and I
created a more wholesome friend Circle I
picked up a whole bunch of different new
hobbies I learned how to do ballroom
dance for example and things started to
become better because I was more mature
I knew myself better I knew what not to
do I knew what to do I had developed my
social skills I developed my presence
and overall I was just a more mature
individual so if you feel right now that
you're young and dumb and you're getting
addicted to all kinds of pointless
things you have no Direction well that's
everybody's story man you you will
figure it out you have time the worst
thing you can do for yourself right now
is live in anxiety and hopelessness have
faith in yourself first and foremost and
then you can begin to direct your life
towards a higher purpose just have blind
faith faith in oneself which is
completely irrational completely blind
is the biggest asset that you can
cultivate so last year of college I had
a genuinely wonderful friend Circle I
was practicing martial arts I was
practicing ballroom dance I had
something going for me and of course
then
I graduated and everybody I knew was
scattered and they went their own ways
for their own jobs across the country
and that was another reset back to zero
you know no status no nothing no friends
again this time I was also kind of burnt
out from college and finishing my degree
and everything and I had downtime I
wasn't ready to go get a job I wanted
some time to just relax and wind down I
picked up a game I picked up a video
game called BioShock Infinite and this
game was awesome man if you haven't
played BioShock Infinite you got to get
into it I know a fan of firstperson
Shooters myself but the storyline and
the visuals and the Aesthetics of
BioShock Infinite make it completely
worth it BioShock Infinite is a master
class in storytelling and building up
suspense and having foreshadowing for an
eventual massive plot TST and the story
line is as good as any work of fiction
or any kind of movie youve ever watched
and it's a video game which is my point
my point is a video game is nothing but
a medium it can genuinely be a work of
art make sure that you're choosing games
which are not replayable like BioShock
Infinite once you go through the story
learn the game play and finish out your
missions like you don't feel like going
back and playing it again and if you do
it's probably going to be in a year or
two because of nostalgia and that's fine
games like League or fortnite or
something like this which is extremely
replayable or Call of Duty these are the
ones which have serious addiction risk
or of course like RuneScape and stuff if
you were back in the day and once I
played BioShock Infinite I was not
addicted able to go and try different
things I was able to even create an
e-commerce business so after I got done
with all that I actually invented this
so it doesn't seem like much does it but
get this all right so this is a robe and
the interesting thing about this is it
has a loop and button system so when you
have your robe on you can actually pull
the sleeve back and draw out this loop
system which has a button which it goes
into so you can actually roll up the
sleeve and cinch it in place which is
not any great Innovation admittedly but
this was something I'm proud of to be
honest it was a kind of a simp first
product which I tried I got into markets
I ordered product off China brought it
all the way here had inventory sold a
couple on Shopify through Instagram ads
then of course Co happened and there was
a huge iOS update those who are in
e-commerce know what I'm talking about
and yeah my company died like overnight
and that was fine cuz the amount I
learned from that company my first ever
business venture makes life so much
easier today so will I ever play video
games in the future do I actually
recommend playing games well here's the
thing I'm waiting for one specific game
and that is Space Marine 2 when Space
Marine 2 comes out you bet I'm going to
play the [ __ ] out of it hell I might
even stream it on YouTube I am really
excited for that one game and see here's
the thing I am mature enough to be able
to balance my business manage my
personal life and a Leisure and hobby
activity that's fine it's all a matter
of one understanding yourself your
strengths and weaknesses and two
assessing your lifestyle and your goals
to understand how much leisure time you
actually have and three having the
discipline to actually control yourself
and four actually choosing the right
games choose games that are genuinely
going to be enjoyable to you and are not
replayable so what games were important
to you when you were younger were there
any standout games which kind of defined
you as a person if so leave a comment I
do read these comments and of course are
any of the games which were in my list
in yours just like video games and
indeed works of fiction which means
story books some movies can also be
really good I'll have two TI pop up one
is going to be a video on why reading
fiction is good and going to give you
recommendations on what fiction to read
and the second is going to be my review
of the movie Napoleon and why it fails
to be what it could have been and in
that video I speak of the truth of
Napoleon's story and what you can learn
from that to improve your mindset right
now