you took me from 25 Subs to 800 Subs in
one day and then to 1300 Subs overnight
and you'd think I was extremely happy
about this which I am however there was
this undercurrent of nervousness which
is bothering me I read every single
comment that was left all hundreds of
them and every comment I was always
thinking the next comment is going to be
the racist one it's going to be the one
which kind of ruins my day and affects
my mood but that never happened so you
have to understand I'm not one of these
like liberal types I'm not looking for
racism I'm not a feminist none of that
in fact I'd probably consider myself
more of a conservative than anything
else I don't even mean that in a
political sense because both parties in
the US kind of suck I just mean that I
always assumed I was the thick-skinned
kind of guy and I wouldn't care about
things like this so I was on the lookout
for comments you know calling out my
accent or my appearance or something
like this and that just never happened
and by the way guys this is how you tell
if your bread is good or not all it
should have is enriched flour water
olive oil sea salt and herbs if that's
all the ingredients you have you have a
good piece of bread that's when I
realized it wasn't a fear of racism for
me it was internal self-limiting beliefs
that manifested themselves as this
irrational fear every comment I read has
been overwhelmingly positive my boys
were in India were just so thrilled that
I was using ghee instead of oil to make
my omelette this just goes to show you
that perhaps the demons are not always
out there but sometimes the demons are
in here they were for me for the longest
time I put off YouTube I put off you
know making videos and all this because
I always assumed that people would be
terrible to me online and this is such a
weird topic for me to discuss because I
don't have a victim mindset or anything
like this I go about my life in real
life full of confidence I don't
necessarily fear exposure so where is
this coming from so there's this book
called The War of art written by Stephen
pressfield and Stephen pressfield is an
author of Epic War literature and he
writes this book which is very popular
among creative types and business types
and by the way guys you should always
purchase extra virgin olive oil and
ideally not Blended this is the stuff
which has a lot of antioxidants and it's
really good for healthy fats that it
contains and in this book The War of art
Stephen pressfield talks about
resistance resistance not just
resistance doing something but
resistance with the capital r like a
proper noun resistance and he talks
about how for every single person who
ever tries to create something whether
it be content or whether it be a
business every single person has a
resistance within them which takes the
shape of their worst insecurity but the
fact is this video is not even actually
about racism this video is about one
man's journey through his insecurities
and emerging on the other side A Little
Bit Stronger thanks to you everybody who
left comments encouraging me to create
more content I think I might now coming
back to the more important thing this
amazing breakfast that I'm preparing I
have high quality bread high quality
olive oil and all my middle eastern boys
out there you know how nutritious dates
are also everybody has this thing
against chocolate but if you have even
70 above dark chocolate it's actually
really good for you in fact I prefer
dark chocolate over coffee both of them
contain caffeine but this is combined
with healthy fats and so it kind of
modifies the effect of caffeine and
doesn't make you jittery or doesn't have
the caffeine crash effect this is the
good stuff a block of chocolate and then
this right here is a egg milkshake crazy
right you never think you would make an
egg milkshake it's amazing it has two
eggs a whole bunch of milk extremely
good extremely good nutritious breakfast
so here's your homework think about the
thing that you have been wanting to do
or wanting to try but you haven't been
able to because you've had this internal
resistance within you write down what
shape that resistance is taking and then
test the assumptions I assume that the
internet was a bad place full of bad
people who would seek to insult and
bring me down this assumption was born
to be false each of you left a comment
had nothing but praise and encouragement
for me you have helped me realize that
the pursuit of one's purpose is as much
an internal Journey as an external one
and for that I thank you and of course
thank you to my editor Jan for editing
this video
[Music]
thank you