jump into the real story of Napoleon and
see what we can learn from him first I
want to make it clear that yes I am
absolutely idolizing him and yes I am
sweeping under the rug the hundreds of
thousands of deaths that he caused
that's because I'm using Napoleon as a
dactic instrument just as plutar did and
yes this would be considered hero
worship what of it you want to fill your
mind with Spirits greater than yourself
with thoughts of men who are greater
than you you do not want to fill your
head with thoughts of nobody's in our
time and indeed even these men of
history chose their own role models from
history Caesar looked up to Alexander
and Napoleon looked up to Caesar these
are men that Define their entire Epoch
and I use the acts and mindset of these
men as my shining star when Caesar was
outnumbered in Gaul when he was
surrounded on all sides did he give up
or did he rise to the occasion creating
new Battlefield tactics in order to make
the best of the situation Caesar used
his mind his tactical Brilliance and of
course the blessings of the Goddess
Fortuna to bring Victory to his people
when Napoleon was facing two entire
armies at the same time in aitz instead
of seeing this as a potential disaster
he saw it as an opportunity he used his
understanding of the environment and the
terrain to bring death to his foes it's
not the big flashy victories either
before the Battle of I think fredland
Napoleon was known to be in his tent
planning education reforms on the eve of
battle imagine how crazy this is the man
had a real ability to detach we in our
modern times we freak out if there's an
exam the next day an exam which is
completely forgotten about a year from
now something as Petty as an exam has
the power to stress us and this man he
had a whole battle to fight the next day
and he still had the mental bandwidth to
focus on a different task this is what
is meant by Detachment the ability to
look upon the battlefield from above and
make the tactically just Choice based on
logic and reason alone these are some of
the lessons that we can learn from
Napoleon not just focus on his sexual
deviances In Our Lifetime a suspect that
that an American Napoleon an American
Caesar will be born and I'm not even
saying that's a good thing indeed he
would be a nemesis of the status quo he
might already be born he might be
watching this video right now I believe
this because the conditions are ripe for
a Napoleon or a Caesar to arise the land
is fertile for such a man to arise on
American soil it might be you if you are
up to it and I'll leave you with some
further reading if you're so inclined if
you enjoyed the Aesthetics and the
Romance of the French Revolution period
I strongly suggest Alexander Dumas The
Count of Monte Christo this is a
brilliant book and the complexity of the
plot is insane this is the story of a
young lad named Edmund Dantes and he's a
just a young wholesome young man who
wants to live his life create his
business have a wife and go about his
day but he is betrayed by his closest
friends and allies and he's thrown into
prison for trumped up charges for 20
years but when he returns he's a changed
man so he has a mentor in prison who
teaches science intuition observation
and philosophy and when he comes out
he's able to use that to build an Empire
and fight a multigenerational war
against his betrayers really cool and
dark story strongly recommend if you're
interested in the tactics of Napoleon
check out the series about Napoleonic
Wars by epic history TV really cool
History Channel on YouTube if you're
interested in watching a movie that
actually does Justice to Napoleon's
Battle Tactics then watch the movie
waterl This of course is just a bonus
clip from the actual full review of this
movie if you are so inclined go ahead
and give that a watch