is it even possible in the age of
denialism decadence and nihilism to see
a religious Awakening I'm going to walk
you through the history of religion in
the age of the internet to understand
the current Vibe shift and then we'll be
in a better position to predict exactly
what shape if any this new religious
Awakening will have here I'm speaking
only of the West and I'm taking the
position of an objective Outsider as I
was not born in the
west if you feel that Society feels
weird and wrong nowadays you are not
alone we live in the age of nihilism and
neoism you see it wasn't always like
this it accelerated with 911 911 was the
true vibe shift 911 was as important an
event to the destiny of mankind as was
the sack of Rome 911 was the key event
of the century and so much of the
current [ __ ] can be traced back to
that one afternoon 911 2001 marks the
end of the past Century and the
beginning of the neoo era 911 was
fundamental in shaping religion in the
millennial generation and of course it
was them who shaped the current ERA I
remember those events clear as day I
remember it because I was young right I
walked into my home after spending the
day Outdoors climbing trees and eating
berries my mother was crying looking at
the TV screen and I was confused I was
confused because bombings and Terror
attacks this kind of stuff happens in
the news and my mother had watched them
before without crying about it this time
it was different turns out my mother was
crying because she knew her brother my
uncle worked at the World Trade Center
even though I was very young I
understood that everything had changed
9/11 was a victory for the enemies of
the United States there's no question
about this if the goal was to destroy
the United States then they succeeded
the United States we live in now is not
the real United States I remember a time
where airports had no TSA security we
just grabbed boarding passes and just
walked to the gate and you'll see this
in movies like home alone you know old
movies which were shot before 2001 if
you read Edward snowden's account of 911
which every freedom loving man and women
should read you would see how the CIA
NSA and other governmental bodies
basically got unlimited power and zero
accountability after 911 the vile
abortion of the Patriot Act was born in
the fires of that Unholy day immediately
after 9111 there was a surge in
patriotism and Christianity and all of
America was United for one brief moment
in time 911 could have been the Catalyst
for a new golden age for America where
the ciens of the land were United in
purpose and Mission but this was not to
be the wars and the lies that came after
911 killed any trust in the United
States the United States that stood for
freedom and liberty was exchanged for a
surveillant state of disunity and
distrust this brings us few years later
to 2005 9/11 happened in 2001 2005 the
war was still raging in Afghanistan and
Iraq but people had kind of moved on
with their lives and the internet became
a cultural Force for the first time
today it's easy to imagine that the
culture is shaped by the internet but at
the time it was actually unheard of the
internet had existed since the '90s but
it was a place for business activity
emails and porn but by 2005 there's
actually stuff to do for just normal
people online Internet speeds had gotten
to a point where video in at Mass scale
was finally possible and this was the
Golden Era of YouTube mid 2000s YouTube
was just a different kind of energy I
actually kind of feel bad for the young
guys who never got to see the true
potential of YouTube everybody right now
on YouTube is here to make videos to
make money about anything else video
sharing on YouTube is seen as lead
generation for businesses but during
2005 nobody expected to make a single
dollar so all the biggest names at the
time were people who started uploading
for no reason other than than wanted to
make some videos I seek to emulate the
energy of this era I want to make videos
for a purpose greater than just making
money I want making money to be a side
effect of making videos this was the
first time when legit celebrities could
be created on YouTube this was the era
of PewDiePie and [ __ ] Higa there was
Jenna Marbles and Philip def Franco
Hamza was like 10 years old at the time
and Tate himself was 25 something like
that at the time there was two important
cultural movements that shaped early
YouTube the first was the pickup artist
movement which I spoke about in my
previous vide I'll be very brief about
it here but it's basically a bunch of
young guys realizing that everything
they thought they knew about girls was
just naive [ __ ] they used scientific
level analysis to get laid there was
Neil Strauss there was mystery there was
Tyler Duran that came into play that the
Genesis of the red pill comes from this
era Our dating vocabulary in comes from
this era we speak about things like lay
Count Day game look maxing approach
anxiety cold approach all this
terminology comes from that era and I
described this in the previous videos
I'm not going to go into it too much
here I will instead speak of the second
movement that shaped YouTube and this
was the more important cultural movement
it was called the new atheist movement
most people don't know this but there
was a concerted and vigorous attempt to
remove religion from internet culture
and indeed all of society this was the
new atheist movement of the mid 2000s
and to my eternal cringe I was a part of
this movement just as I was a part of
the Pua movement there was actually a
lot of crossover between these movements
the big difference was that this
movement was pioneered not by a bunch of
horny nerds but by actual scientists and
intellectuals we had Christopher
Hitchens a remarkable and Prussian
journalist who literally predicted the
deranged LGBT fueled feminism and the
transgender propaganda a decade before
it happened we had Sam Harris a super
sharp neurobiologist who tried to study
God and religion from a neurological
perspective we had Dan dennet a legit
philosopher and we had Richard Dawkins a
wonderful writer and an expert biologist
who literally coined the term Meme and
redefined the way genetics was
understood to this day these four were
called The Four Horsemen of the
Apocalypse or of atheism and they set
out with the express goal of demolishing
The Logical and moral underpinnings of
religion mostly Christianity why cuz 911
had stirred up religious fervor in the
US especially in the Bible Belt you know
Texas Georgia the Carolinas the big
churches in this region were pushing for
change in public education they wanted
to teach intelligent design in public
schools instead of evolution through
natural selection this of course created
conflict so what happened here was
Christopher Hitchens got into the fry
because he wanted to have separation of
church and state Dawkins got into it
because he was already a renowned
biologist and he saw intelligent design
as a bunch of nonsense the main points
of the new atheists were basically this
first religion is immoral because it
makes people do acts of great harm they
used 911 as the main example for this
they argued that without religion the
world would be a more peaceful place
second they said that religion did not
have sufficient scientific backing they
believed that anything that didn't have
sufficient science behind it should be
treated as unknown and Blind Faith had
no place in a thinking man's mind
and whatever your beliefs might be about
this The Four Horsemen of the new
atheist movement were excellent at
debate they were clear with their
beliefs they spoke with intelligence and
precision I'd go so far as to say that
they won every single debate they went
to they debated Catholics they debated
creationist Islamic thinkers they even
debated the new age spiritualist types
and they came out on top every single
time despite their unbroken string of
Victories though you probably don't even
recognize these names at the tail end of
the movement around 2010 the new
atheists stood Victorious over their
enemies only to see that the arena was
empty by 2010 everything that was to be
said about the pros and cons about
religion had been said and people heard
every basic argument and had already
made up their minds as to which side
they belong to thousands of people had
moved away from religion under the
absolute Firepower of the new atheist
arguments and nobody could really debate
science and religion Again on YouTube
because everybody kind of knew where
that debate would eventually end up it
looked as though religion had finally
been logically defeated but something
new and funny happened so a new religion
emerged and hijacked the new atheist
movement it was the funniest cultural
shift i' had ever seen and to this day
the godforsaken social justice Warriors
took over new atheism you probably don't
even recognize that term because it's
fallen out of fashion but sjw social
justice Warrior was at at that time the
new Big Bad enemy suddenly the new
atheists and the religious folk found
themselves on the same side trying to
defeat this new monster that this
atheist had created now I am no atheist
now but I'm immensely grateful for the
cultural achievements of the new atheist
movement new atheists like Hitchens and
Dawkins combined the power of Greek
philosophy with the knowledge of modern
science the new atheist weren't bad
people they just chose The Wrong Enemy
they thought that the creationists and
the Christians were the enemy while
actually they were allies against the
NEOS socialists the new atheist stuff
kind of died down as gamergate took over
YouTube I briefly described gamergate in
my previous video but I will give you a
whole new angle into this gamergate was
the Scandal that rocked the gaming
industry the feminist sjws had slowly
crept up and infected the gaming media
outlets and they used their power to
attack men specifically straight white
men as being a bunch of rapists creeps
and misogynists so all nonsense of
course and it came to light later that
all these sexual harassment allegations
were just baseless lies for political
gain the meoo movement that came later
was actually a child of gamergate
naturally there was a reaction to the
sjws the supporters of the new atheist
movement became the first anti-feminists
of the gamergate era the perfect example
of this was Saron of fad and thunderfoot
they went from making anti-creationist
videos to making anti-feminist videos
they're already good they're already
practiced in logical thinking and debate
so they were able to crush the feminist
arguments it was like looking at a bunch
of toddlers breaking toys in fact the
debates of what it meant to be a man or
woman in this era laid the intellectual
foundations of the Hamza and Tate era
but the first objective was just to win
the culture war against the leftists the
science versus religion war was over and
The Gamers versus feminists War had
started but even this wouldn't last very
long gamergate happened in 2015 but
another cultural event a massively
important cultural event happened in
2016 so about a year later the brexit
referendum the brexit referendum was
basically the British people given a big
[ __ ] you to the European Union because
the EU was placing a lot of restrictions
on the British economy and was flooding
the British Isles with immigrants so
there was another cultural issue right a
bunch of Elites basically had decided
that Europe didn't belong to the
Europeans now that's a topic for a
different discussion but this changed
the face of YouTube yet again this was a
new war of globalists were populist this
was the same movement that pitted Trump
against Hillary in that same year the
great meme war of 2016 had begun Trump
was the populist and Hillary was the
globalist shill to be mocked funnily
enough brexit also marked the true and
Final End of the new atheist movement
Dawkins basically humiliated himself by
entering the cultural Arena on the
globalist side Dawkins was a biologist
so he didn't really understand why it
was that the Britains wanted to leave
the European Union so what happened was
brexit happened because the British
people were sick and tired of the dumb
EU regulations and mass enforced
immigration systemic destruction of the
British culture the British people voted
for independence from EU tyranny the
British people hoped for a resurgent and
vitalized Nation but of course looking
back from 2024 that clearly has not
happened Dawkins argued that the brexit
was a mistake and the referendum should
be ignored essentially the people's will
should be ignored Sargon of aad when and
Dawkins were at odds for the first time
and Sargon crushed Dawkins in his videos
because Sargon understood politics
Dawkins understood biology the other
three Horsemen also retreated from the
field Sam Harris got tired of
controversy and he left Christopher
Hitchens got cancer and trien died Dan
dennet just faded away into Academia
where he always belonged across the
Atlantic in the US the meme factories
were open for business and the great
meme war of 2016 was fully underway in
the winter of 2016 Trump took the throne
but it wasn't the end of the culture War
the entire four years of the Trump
presidency was a period of great
cultural conflict the conflict was about
what it meant to be an American but is
also so much more the leftist try to
make Trump seem like this monster which
he clearly wasn't but it's actually
clearer now than ever that the Trump
years of presidency were actually some
years of peace and quiet compared to the
absolute [ __ ] show that is the Biden
presidency two groups had basically
formed in the years of conflict the pro
free speech pro- freedom broadly
right-wing Coalition and the opposite
was the pro- censorship Pro LGBT Pro
feminist leftwing Coalition so where did
religion come into all this I'll tell
you a new era of conflict started with
the introduction of Bill c16 in mid 2017
so not too long after the Trump
presidency had begun one unknown
Canadian Professor takes up a position
against the transgender agenda he's
smart articulate and very very well read
he looks at the government mandate to
use these transgender pronouns and says
I'm not doing it Jordan Peterson has
entered the scene and immediately causes
a huge Vibe shift the new atheists well
it's in the name they were obviously
atheists even the anti-feminists like
Sargon were at the time atheists but
Jordan Peterson he was the first
internet icon who is unquestionably
knowledgeable about science but was
sympathetic to religion he didn't think
Christianity was this darkid ideology
that should be buried at the end of the
century JP revitalized religion by
explaining the Bible in a new way he
used evolutionary biology and psychology
to explain ancient truths this was the
opposite of the new atheists the new
atheist had created a huge cultural Rift
between science and religion but Jordan
Peterson was kind of mending that Rift
he explained that the Bible was not a
book to be discarded but actually was a
part of the solution to the problems of
the Modern Age age on one side he fought
a brutal campaign against the leids for
free speech and individualism on the
other he provided a new Christian
framework for those looking for a
meaning in life recently huberman talks
about how he believes in God he was
asked about and he quotes the great
Heisenberg of the uncertainty principle
Fame he says the first gulp from the
glass of the Natural Sciences will turn
you into an atheist but at the bottom of
the glass God is waiting for you the
quote is basically is saying that if you
start learning science it seems
irrational to believe in a higher power
but as you learn more and more it just
doesn't feel that irrational anymore and
this has been my journey as well I was
an atheist in my first year of undergrad
as a bioengineer but by the end of
undergrad I was an agnostic a few years
into the PHD program and things changed
even more even the new atheists have
recently changed their minds recently
Dawkins talks about how he's a cultural
Christian he talks about how he loves
the cultural aspects of Christianity
loves Christmas carols and hymns and
Cathedrals and churches but here's the
thing you don't get Christmas without
Christ you cannot have your beautiful
architecture music poetry and art
without divine inspiration look at the
art and architecture made in the Godless
atheistic and modern world these are
artless and soulless Creations compared
to the works of men who are divinely
inspired I think the best argument
against the postmodern atheistic and
nihilistic worldview is not an argument
that put into words but rather can be
just seen and felt just look at the
differences in the artistic expressions
of these eras the fact that Dawkins now
supports Christianity which is hilarious
is a huge indicator of the current Vibe
shift I'll give you another example
which you'll actually recognize Jimmy
Jiang this guy is a great YouTuber he is
the king of Asian Riz he's made videos
about dating girls from practically
every country and even many porn stores
he was in the streets he was on the
streets and he was off the streets but
he recently quit and he tells in his
video why it's very good video and it's
very authentic he says simply he doesn't
want to be a [ __ ] everybody is
realizing that the headism of the past
years especially postco has not led to
any kind of lasting happiness in some
sense the Hedonism and materialism of
the Tate and Hamza era are a result of
our Collective loneliness and depression
during the
lockdowns now that that honic treadmill
has run its of course people are
realizing that the currency of Hedonism
is just plain old
nihilism to look ahead we must look back
the Renaissance was a blossoming of
culture like the world hadn't seen in
Generations the Renaissance was a fusion
of the Christian and the classical the
greatest minds of the generation saw
that they could harness classical
vitality and heroic energy and channel
it through Christianity I think this is
what is coming to the West I think the
normes will continue on the trajectory
of decline but a new and revitalized
spirit is coming to the intelligencia of
the West and you are in the absolute
Forefront of this shift in this video
I'm not going to try to change your
views on anything I have nothing to say
to those who are not already like me and
less do I care about convincing when I
mentioned gamergate and the war of the
feminists versus The Gamers I didn't
tell you who won the goddamn feminists
won look at all the gaming media outlets
right now nothing's really changed the
feminists not only kept their ground but
actually solidified their position I
look at the new atheist movement what
happened here The Atheist objectively
won every debate but there was no surge
in atheism just a surge in nihilism and
those with religious beliefs just kept
doing their own thing anyway and who won
brexit the populists might have won the
referendum and Trump might have won the
election but the main thing they wanted
to stop was mass immigration and the
collapse of their cultures but they
ultimately they fail to do so the great
immigration and cultural crises of the
West are now worse than they have ever
been right now I have friends in my unit
helping the Texas National Guard to
protect the Border they put up fences
but the feds just come and remove them
the next day the point is merely this
the side that has True Believers always
wins True Believers play the long game
True Believers will do whatever it takes
to ensure that they get what they want
debate and logic is useful but faith is
ultimately the more powerful force so
social justice warriors were True
Believers creationists were True
Believers the neoo are True Believers if
we stay on the current path the neoo
will Grind All virtue into dust they've
already destroyed the universities which
used to be a true beacon in the dark
they've destroyed the Public School
Systems which to be fair there's already
a s off they've destroyed the childhood
of so many young and Confused kids with
their poisons both mental and chemical
they are the enemies of Freedom Beauty
and achievement but they are not stupid
they're not lazy and they are at the
edge of victory for a good reason they
are more powerful than you think it is
not just a bunch of dumb kids in college
with blue hair speaking of which these
dumb kids do eventually enter the
workforce and saturate the HR
departments and HR is in charge of
hiring and firing decisions regardless
of the employees performance metrics it
is not just the media and Hollywood who
are guilty for the most egregious crimes
against women who will Point their dirty
fingers at the common man it is not just
the [ __ ] politicians who sell out to
the highest is bitter it is also the
bankers and the financiers who pull the
strings that truly matter so what will
happen now that is the question is it
not so let me lay it out to you my
argument piece by piece just like the
new atheists would first the West is
under existential threat from economic
collapse cultural dilution and unchecked
immigration second every time the West
has come close to collapse this has been
some kind of a defense mechanism that
kicks in to save the day if one and two
are true then we can expect that defense
mechanism to start forming very soon
question is what form will this take
will there be a return to Christianity
no not exactly because the kind of
Christianity that's taught in the
churches is the lamest most boring low
testosterone version of Christianity in
fact I consider this kind of
Christianity would be a extension of
leftism think about it how many churches
have you seen with the rainbow flag
flying the Pope the head of Catholicism
washs the feet of Muslim immigrants the
type of Christianity that is all about
turning the cheek and to love their
neighbor is not what we need right now
the modern church has perverted these
teachings to mean that Christians should
just tolerate any humiliation and should
welcome unlimited immigration this is
the regime approved Christianity this is
the Christianity of the fat little
Pastor or the nerd Theologian who rather
sit inside and read books rather than go
outside and experience the beauty of
creation this is the religious arm of
the
neoo this is not the only Christianity
there is however again we look to
history yes it is true that Christ said
turn the other cheek but how many cheeks
do you have you have two so basically a
two strikes and you're out policy the
first time you tolerate it the second
time you endure it but the third time it
is game over this is the form of
Christianity that will come to
Resurgence it will not appeal to the
masses but that's okay this is the type
of Christianity that will appeal only to
the intelligencia the intelligencia are
the young ambitious and intelligent
group of people both men and women who
will shape culture in the next next
decades in other words it is you this
vital Christianity is the most powerful
ideology that's ever been seen on the
face of this Earth this is the ideology
that that fueled the art and sculpture
of the Renaissance let me explain this
more clearly during the Renaissance the
greatest Minds did not just look towards
Christianity they looked to the
classical Pagan era for inspiration this
proved that it was possible to take the
heroic ideal and love for beauty that
the pagans had and combine it with the
structure of the church I should explain
what the word Pagan means it simply
refers to the pantheons of the Gods the
people believed in before Christianity
there are many flavors of this there was
the Roman Pantheon there was the Greek
pantheon there was the Norse pantheon
and of course there was the
Indo-European Pantheon Jupiter Zeus Odin
and Indra was the same deity nobody is
expecting anybody to start believing in
these old gods right but rather take the
love for adventure Beauty and expansion
from these culture
and nourished them within the Christian
framework the Renaissance was a
synthesis of classical thinking
Christian Frameworks and scientific
inquiry by combining the three you had
something that was more powerful than
any one of them would have been
independently Renaissance Men read
classical Works they read Virgil Plato
chis and Aristotle some of them were
intensely religious like B Chelly who
painted The Birth of Venus a pagan deity
Michelangelo painted or sculpted
classical figures that was commissioned
by the church itself and one must
remember that the Renaissance was not a
time of Peace it is not the case that a
bunch of painters and Poets could just
work on their art Carefree actually it
was a period of great technological
advancement especially in Warfare did
not DaVinci draw sketches for tanks and
helicopters Firearms became more than
just a niche armor-piercing weapon
culverin were invented a special kind of
long Cannon basically it would shatter
old fortifications so new kind of
castles had to be built and these were
called star Forts and they were designed
to specifically combat the new weapons
technology and I'll give even more
examples of this warlike and vital
Christianity think of the great
explorers of the age of sale I was in
Portugal last summer and I saw the
fruits of vital Christianity right in
front of me and even before that think
of the Reon Kista think of all of Spain
was taken over by invading forces and
Christendom looked lost but then a man
of great Vitality arose by the name of
elid and he pushed the foreign influence
out and ushered in a golden age for his
people some of the greatest warriors of
History were Christians the Templar
hosts the Portuguese teros tonic Knights
and the winged husars of Poland and even
before them the Legos of Byzantium did
not Justinian a Christian Emperor
command belisarius to take the catari
and bring Rome back into Christendom the
Christianity of the fat little Pastor in
your local church is not the only option
that you have think of Charles Martell
the hammer of France did he not crush
the invading Muslim forces despite being
outnumbered did he not do this deed in
the Name of Christ and Crown and in more
recent times the founding fathers of the
United States were literally the perfect
examples of whal Christianity they were
not fans of the old claustrophobic and
decaying churches of Europe and they
were certainly not enemies of
Christianity they embraced the spirit of
expansion of the classical Greeks and
the Romans and they built great
architecture in the GRE style in fact
the founding fathers would perfect
examples of the Renaissance men they
were writers politicians leaders
scientists and warriors this is the
spirit that I want to see reawakened now
listening to this you might think well
I'm not a Christian so what do I do well
firstly I'm not asking you to do
anything I'm making a prediction of
what's coming rather than a prescription
Christianity is the Bedrock of the West
not Islam not Hinduism not bahai not
Shinto the thing is you don't need to be
a hardcore Christian to be a part of
this anybody who wants to stand for a
greater future can stand for all this do
you believe in a higher power do you
stand against neoism well that's all you
really need the real enemy is atheistic
nihilism and the cultural and
demographic shift that is being forced
upon the West like I mentioned Richard
Dawkins the most insistent enemy of
Christianity has turned around and said
that Christianity is actually worth
defending in fact if you ask Jordan
Peterson if he believes in God he
actually never says yes or no he always
says I act as though God exists I always
thought this was hogwash I always
thought he was trying to avoid the
question by using fancy words and
philosophy I don't think so anymore
there's some truth in what he says
nobody can just decide to have faith
faith is not a switch that you can
simply turn on and off if I tell you
I'll give you a million dollars if you
believe for one day that the sky is
purple you still couldn't really do it
there's no way to choose consciously to
have faith or believe anything but by
acting as though you do have faith in a
higher power is a potential First Step
you instantly get a power boost if you
do this prayer absolutely gives you a
power boost now I had to find my own way
to that point and learn how to harness
this power because nobody really teaches
this in any really understandable way
anymore but there is a way think about
this the greatest weaknesses of
self-improvement is that it is so
self-centered self-improvement begins
and ends with you it all hinges on how
to improve yourself for your own
gratification and really nothing more it
could be girls it could be cars or the
most boring of all it could be just a
bank balance peasant mentality instead
of going to the gym for female attention
what if you went to the gym to honor the
temple that is your body what if you
dedicated the last and most difficult
set to something greater this is a
practical change that you can make right
now start dedicating things to something
bigger than yourself this extends to
other things and of course if you don't
want to do spiritual stuff that's fine
if you're at work cool dedicate the work
not just to your your advancement but
perhaps the family you plan to have the
kids who are yet to be born the
ancestors who allowed you to exist this
gives you a frame that absolutely
swallows nihilism you cannot be
nihilistic if you go about your daily
task with a degree of Excellence because
you aren't doing everything for yourself
but always for something greater this
Frame will naturally lead to doing
higher quality work because you cannot
possibly do lower quality work and
dedicated to any higher power do it for
God your family your parents your future
Legacy you can see the truth of this in
the gym dedicate your last set to the
heavens and you will notice the weights
feel lighter try this today and tell me
if it doesn't work it's not just the gym
of course where this applies you're
struggling with noof fap or any kind of
addiction squeak out a tiny prayer
before typing the letter P on the
keyboard I guarantee you won't be able
to finish typing it out you basically
take your small amount of willpower and
multiply it times infinity if you're
struggling with diet it's very hard to
stuff your mouth with Cheetos knowing
that your body is the Temple of your
spirit this even extends to social
skills and Charisma when you move
through the world with the feeling that
the forces of Heaven have got your back
you just give off a different kind of
energy people notice it and they take
you seriously I know this sounds crazy I
know this sounds made up I can easily
make some kind of pseudo scientific
rationale saying well people are just
responding to your new found confidence
right but who cares I don't care about
the explanation of why it works just
that it does if you want a full more
like actionable guide let me know in the
comments this video is mostly the
knowledge the second part of this is how
do you tap into that vital energy that I
spoke of there are two answers the first
answer is in esoteric Health I've made
many videos about this topic and I would
like you to put them into action the
second answer is to absorb energy from
past Heroes every culture of this Earth
has a version of this there are energies
that can be absorbed by reading about
the Deeds of Achilles Caesar and
Alexander if e vitalism is more to your
taste then read the ramayan and the
Mahabharat the heroism and the Grand
Adventure of the East is no less in the
west if you know what to look for
specifically here's what I recommend all
men and women of the new intelligencia
must read The Iliad this is
non-negotiable however the ilad is a
difficult book to get into because it
gives zero context for the Trojan War it
jumps right into the middle of the story
and gives zero character introductions
it assumes that the reader is already
familiar with the setting so I don't
recommend The Iliad for a beginner or a
novice instead you should read Troy by
Steven fry this is an amazing book that
does Justice to The Iliad while actually
improving upon it by providing context
historical analysis mythological
analysis and additional stories from the
same time period to give you a rounded
experience of the Trojan War one of the
best books I've ever read strongly
recommend so is this surge of vital
Christianity going to sweep across the
West no it is not the normies will never
never understand this think about how a
Normy will will react to this video they
won't get it right the average person is
not courageous enough to be a Christian
nor do they have the raw vital energy of
the classical man they cannot be a part
of this mov and that's fine cultural
change does not come from convincing
everybody of your views cultural change
comes from the the conversion of the
intelligencia the current intelligencia
are informed by their college education
and it's not serving them the leftist
thought leads only in One Direction
downwards it leads to socialism atheism
and eventually Hedonism nihilism and
even physical ugliness leftists pursue
pleasure above all because why not the
leftist thought believes that nothing
really matters because at the end of the
day everything ends in the heat dep of
the universe so there's no logical point
in denying pleasure firstly we do not
know if the universe will end in a heat
death and secondly there is an antidote
to nihilism in fact there's more than
one antidote to nihilism one of the
antidotes is Faith but there are answers
as well the pursuit of beauty Legacy
Family and art nobody even talks about
these even the self-improvement guys
will basically cap out at build body get
girls buy cars this is why I believe we
will see a revitalization of this
ancient Spirit the new intelligencia
will be informed not by the top- down
structures of the University Systems nor
the big and famous celebrities but by
doing their own research and reading
they will be informed by reading history
and philosophy but by also watching
YouTube videos and why not YouTube is
the new Public Square this is the
battlefield of ideas and this is where
the ideas of the new intelligencia will
be shaped and you will be the one to
shape it now if you decide to go the
Christian route I have one more tool of
power for you I'm not telling you to be
a Christian I have zero authority to
tell anybody what to believe but if you
did desde to go that route then I will
ask you this if Christ is King then
surely he needs his Knights are you
worthy of that title exactly 5 years a
the notredame cathedral was burned and
the authorities said that it was an
accident but there are many questions
and observations that indicate otherwise
Christians did nothing about the
desecration of one of the most important
and greatest monuments to Beauty
architecture mathematics and
Christianity I believe that if the same
thing happened 10 years from now there
would be a very different
reaction a good question to ask is
what's my St in all this do I have a dog
in this fight obviously I am not off the
West so why should I really care well
from a personal standpoint I have one
foot in the west and one foot in the
East I was born in the East but some of
my most important memories are in the
West My First Crush was in the west but
my first kiss was in the East but the
first time I got laid was in the west
three different girls mind you the first
money I made was in the west all my
degrees are in the West in some sense my
home is in the west so this gives me a
wide perspective of the playing field I
respect and understand both cultures and
I can say with confidence that the West
deserves to survive and thrive perhaps I
am just a messenger of sorts and
secondly my parents sacrificed much to
get me and my sister here and I'll be
damned if I can't do my part to secure
the price of their sacrifice this
another question you should be asking me
is why did I stop being an atheist I
told you the story of me walking into my
childhood home and watching my mom cry
because she thought her brother was dead
I didn't tell you the full story a few
days before 9/11 my grandmother called
and spoke to my mom and I overheard the
whole
conversation my grandmother was telling
my mom of a dream that she had she
described a dark and scary tunnel with a
train track inside which is very
confusing to her in this Vision she she
saw a wondrous being of light running
full speed at this train fearlessly
trying to stop it she didn't know what
to make of the dream of course but she
knew that it was a sign of great danger
to her son my mother's brother my uncle
who worked at the World Trade Center she
knew that she would pray for her son but
that's all she could really do on 9/11
which is a few days after this dream we
genuinely thought he was dead all
Communications went down after the
attack and it was impossible to make a
phone call to that area but then he
called he was not dead he was alive and
he told us the story there was a subway
station under the World Trade Center and
he was going to get on the rail to go to
that subway station because it's his
office he was late to work that day
because something had come up but he
missed his regular time he waited and
got into the one right after but some
alarms went off and they had to evacuate
the one that he was supposed to be on
was under the building at the time and
was crushed by the collapse how do you
explain this kind of thing I had kind of
put this memory out of my mind for
decades but in recent years I've been
observing more phenomena that challenge
the purely materialistic worldview that
I deeply held before I close out I want
to share one of these phenomena with you
I'm actually really struggling because I
don't know if I should share this
because I don't think anybody's going to
believe me but it's fine I think I'm
driven to share this so I I'll do
it I want to show you something really
cool I want to show you the back of this
jacket the back of this jacket has this
beautiful patch and this is the painting
of the Archangel triumphant Archangel
Michael Triumph
and it's important to me
because I had a vision or dream of this
painting years ago and it struck with me
and it was in my memory and I didn't
know it was a real painting and then
eventually I came to learn that it was a
real painting and I was just struck with
awe because i' had seen this painting in
detail before knowing it was even a real
thing a real physical painting and I was
in Europe last summer I I had a
beautiful Europe tour I I traed the path
of Hannibal Barka as he goes through
Spain and France through Italy through
the Alps and into actual Italy proper
and in that journey in Florence I had
this jacket made I didn't think of it
too much I went to Rome and I had this
thought why don't I just Google where
this painting is actually located and it
turns out this painting is in a small
little unknown church that was within
walking distance of where I lived in
Rome pure coincidence and every every
day for 7even days that I was in Rome I
went and spent time in this church my
first time ever spending any time in any
church and I suppose to some extent that
the video that you are watching right
now is a product of my experience in
Rome