Most people don't know this, but the
esoteric health movement was born out of
the pandemic. We all know that Fizer,
the vaccine companies, walked away with
billions of dollars. They acted above
the law. You couldn't sue them for
vaccine injury. I'm going to share with
you a story that I saw in real life.
When I was getting my surgery done for
fixing the structures of my nose, I was
seated beside another patient who was
talking to the doctor and there was only
a curtain separating us so I could hear
the conversation. The doctor asked her
about her frozen shoulder. Now, at the
time, I didn't know what frozen shoulder
was. It's essentially a muscularkeeletal
injury that prevents free movement of
the shoulder joint. The doctor asked her
an interesting question. He asked her
which side did she get her COVID shot
on? And she said it was the side where
she has the frozen shoulder. What he
remarked was first that he has he's been
seeing more frozen shoulder injuries
than ever before which that that in
itself is suspicious but he also said
that the shoulder injury this the frozen
shoulder always happens on the side in
which the patient got the COVID 19 shot.
Here's another place where I lost trust
in the health institutions. Back when
the pandemic was still raging, there was
this observation made that the black
community had higher rates of
complication from this disease. Further
investigation led to the finding that it
was because the black community had
higher rates of obesity and that obesity
was driving complications with COVID 19.
But that's not what was pushed out. What
they pushed out was it's because of
systemic racism. They could have used
the opportunity to chart a path towards
a healthier society. They did not do
this. Instead, they drove us apart and
made it about race rather than actually
helping people. All they had to do to
reduce the complication rates and even
the mortality rates of COVID 19 was to
attack obesity. If Americans could just
become less obese, many more people
would have survived the pandemic. But
that's not what they focused on.
Instead, they focused on pharmaceutical
intervention. They focused on a vaccine
that enriched them and made the pharma
companies billions. And so the people
felt betrayed. We looked up to the
government for guidance, but instead
received nothing. And so we looked to
each other and a grassroots movement was
born which was the esoteric health
movement. As a recent graduate of one of
the best biosciences program in the US
and possibly the world. I was torn
between trusting the scientific
institutions and the scientific method.
For me science was always about asking
questions and not about blind faith in
authority. So I try to find answers for
myself about my health because in the
end of the day the only person
responsible for my health is myself. not
the government, not doctors, not the
CDC's, and certainly not health
insurance or the pharma companies. Soon
I found others like myself who had
turned away from the consensus and
instead to each other. It was around
this time that I started making my first
YouTube videos to spread the message of
esoteric health and to reveal some of
the lies that we have been fed. I was
one of the first to talk about estrogens
in the water supply and that you should
be using a shower filter. I was one of
the first to talk about tallow to be
used as a skinincare product. I was one
of the first to start talking about
fluoride in the water and why you should
use a reverse osmosis filter or a carbon
filter to protect yourself. I was also
speaking of using saturated fats in your
diet like butter and eggs despite what
the doctors might say. What are the core
tenants of the esoteric health movement?
The first is that don't trust
authorities blindly. The second is
embrace traditions and time-tested
methods towards help. And the third is
to embrace self-experimentation and
trying to figure things out for
yourself. And this brings us to the
current timeline, the decade of
divergence. My objective with this
channel was always to make the esoteric
more accessible. And I want to announce
to you quite happily that we have won.
On the political front, it looks like
Red 40 might be on track to getting
banned. Very cool. Second, if you didn't
know this, baby formula is actually
required by law to have seed oils in
them and that's under investigation and
might also get banned. And thirdly,
there's an investigation going into
fluoride in the water and that too might
be removed. Now, here's an important
point I'd like to make. If you're
worried that health is becoming
political, guess what? Health was always
political. It's not a bad thing. This is
the way change happens from a cultural
standpoint. What are we seeing? I
actually saw this in real life when I
was in the locker room in my university
gym a couple months ago. I overheard a
conversation between a couple young guys
and they were talking about where to get
food. It was late in the day. They said
that they were going to go to B-Dubz
Buffalo Wild Wings for those who don't
know. They said that they would go there
because they didn't use seed oils. Now,
I don't know if this is true, but the
fact that they are even speaking of seed
oils is a conversation that would not
happen could not happen 2 years ago. And
we see that some companies, some fast
food companies like Steak and Shake are
moving from using seed oils to tallow.
Now, what does this mean? It's possible
that other chains will start to follow.
McDonald's used to use tallow for their
fries. They stopped because of a scop.
They stopped because Proctor and Gamble
funded the AHA, the American Heart
Association, to convince the boomers
that seed oil was healthy and the tallow
was not. And this caused a change in
public perception, which is why
McDonald's decided to switch from tallow
to seed oils. So if the public
perception shifts again, there's no
reason why McDonald's wouldn't shift
from seed oils back to Tallow. So in the
end of the day, these companies, they
will just follow the trend. So it is up
to us to make sure that the culture is
correct. Other crazy observations in
Walmart, you can find fluoride free
toothpaste back in the day. Like back
when I say back in the day, I mean like
two years ago. Two years ago, you could
only find fluoride free toothpaste in
Whole Foods or like high-end chains or
you'd have to search for it online. But
nowadays, Walmart carries it. And not
just that, you can find reliably, you
can reliably find products, skincare
products which are not toxic like Dr.
Squatch. You can find Dr. Squatch at
Walmart. Again, pretty good product. No
toxins. How long before Walmart start
carrying tallow bomb? How long before
Walmart carries methylene blue? End of
the day, this is a huge victory for us
and we should be proud of how far our
movement has come. But here's the thing.
Whenever a movement starts to gain
traction, there are always bad actors
who will try to use this for their own
selfish ends. Let's look at an easy
example. Liver King back in the day, he
was one of the first to talk about raw
meat, talking about raw eggs, raw milk.
He was speaking of spending time in the
sun. He was speaking about an ancestral
diet. All very good things, all messages
which I can get behind. However, this
was essentially a marketing stunt. He
didn't really believe in any of these
things because at the end of the day, he
was promoting this message and using his
physique as proof, but he was using
steroids to get his physique and he was
lying about it. And once he was exposed,
what did he do? He didn't have any
shame. He just kept on doing the same
thing, promoting the same message. Well,
obviously his results did not come from
those methods. It came from the
anabolics. So, to be clear, I'm not
against using anabolics. You do whatever
you want. I'm against lying. I'm against
lying about the source of your results.
Now, here's the thing. I focus on Liver
King because it's such a stark example
of doing wrong. But here's the truth,
right? Many many influencers, many who
you probably follow and trust are also
using steroids, also doing it covertly,
and you just don't know. You just buy
their supplements because you think that
you'll get the results which they have,
but actually their results come from the
anabolics. Let's talk about supplements
in general. 90% of supplements are
garbage. They are a waste of your money.
Just save your money. is focus on the
basics. There is an esoteric arms race
going on. Every influencer wants to be
the first to talk about the next
supplement. We have influencers who are
talking about using deer antler velvet
to boost their testosterone. They're
talking about colostrum to increase
their IGF-1 to hopefully get taller.
They're speaking of using pine pollen in
order to again increase their
testosterone. All this stuff is
[ __ ] Highly expensive supplements
for almost negligible gains and possibly
side effects which are not well studied.
The reason people buy supplements is
nothing to do with the science behind
them. The science behind them is usually
very shoddy. It's all to do with the
copyrightiting. Each supplement company
has dedicated copywriters whose entire
job is to write these words, these
scripts which convince you that this is
the next thing that you need. And if you
just had the supplement, you would have
the dream outcome. And even with
messaging, different creators within the
health space are on the quest to find
the next controversial take, the next
hot take about health in order to
convince you that by following them, you
are at the cutting edge of health. And
by following them, you are given this
advantage over others. The truth is, if
you focus on the fundamentals, you're
probably going to be ahead of everybody
anyway. The fundamentals haven't
changed. The human being as a biological
entity hasn't changed in the past 5,000
years, probably much more than that. And
the fundamentals again are sleep,
exercise, and diet. If you are not
optimized in these three, then what's
the point of supplements? And the second
phenomenon coming out of health is the
cultlike personalities. Things like
Brian Johnson trying to start an actual
cult. So don't die is a religion. Don't
die is an economic system. Don't die is
is a political system. Don't die as an
ethical, moral, and social system that
we have. Let's say we have something
like a trillion dollars under management
where people take their savings and they
put it into a don't die managed fund
where we can move money in markets to
actually move towards things that uh
push towards don't die. But basically
trying to build a nation state and a
religion and a social uh movement in
like a two-year time period. I get why
people have said um you're obsessed with
Joseph Smith and and you want to be your
own Joseph Smith. So that I didn't
understand before and I I actually it's
not Joseph Smith. My competitor is
Jesus. The first tenant of the esoteric
health movement is don't blindly trust
authorities. It means don't trust the
CDC. Don't trust the pharma companies.
Don't trust the government. But it also
means don't trust influencers. Includes
individuals among us. People in among
us. The [ __ ] Got distracted. And this
includes myself. Everything I say you
should verify and can test on your own.
So here's the big question. Who do you
trust? Who's left that you can actually
trust? The answer is you need to
actually have a filter. You need to
learn philosophy. This is why philosophy
is important. You need to be able to
detect double speak. Double speak is a
term invented by George Orwell. And what
it means is you're using language not to
communicate but rather to obfiscate. The
topic of double speak is something which
I want to explore in depth. This is not
the time or place. But there's one point
which I want you to carry with you. You
are not dumb. You are not stupid. If
somebody who's in a position of
authority is saying things in such a way
that you're thinking, I don't fully
understand it, but I trust it. It means
they're using double speak. You should
be able to understand the arguments
being made. You should be able to
understand the words and ideas being
presented clearly. If somebody is not
taking the effort to make their ideas
succinct, understandable, and
digestible, either they're being lazy
and you should not respect them, or they
are actively trying to deceive you, in
which case you should not trust them.
And just as a side note, if somebody
says that they're competing with Jesus,
I'm not inclined to trust