so five years you're gonna spend five
years with Rags instead of good clothes
not meeting any women because quite
honestly if you're doing this then women
don't want to talk to you anyway and
cutting your own hair to save money yo
that's dumb
the only guy who'll sell his supplements
in his ebook before the video even
starts the perfect male timeline exact
systems
step by step doing the right things at
the right time to have the perfect male
life
yo living your life as a step-by-step
process from going A to Z is not a way
to live a good life I truly believe that
male life is all about timing and that's
exactly your life is not all about
timing life is about what you do with
the time that you're given from 25 to 35
you need to pretty much give up women
the majority of your social life you
need to have an exact routine and stick
to it for 10 years be dedicated to one
idea
give up your social life give up women
give up everything for 10 years of your
life in order to do what you know you
might want to rise up to a top level
management job with a six figure salary
and you think once I get there I'm mate
okay so that might so from ages 25 to 30
you dedicate everything that you have
you sacrifice your friend's Circle you
sacrifice your social life you sacrifice
meeting women and then you become the MD
of a company when you're 35 and you have
a six figure salary that sounds awful if
you get there if you have a nice bank
account you have six figure salary and
you're 35 and you missed out a Whole
Decade of the best years of your life
you're going to look back and you would
swap in a heartbeat all that money to go
back to 25 and relive that life the
actual way you know actually have fun
and do something you know memorable with
the best years of your life you could
you could just be a big stock you got
all the way up to 35 and then cut some
of the body fat
what he's suggesting is from the ages 25
to 35 you just bulk bulk bulk and you
become this huge stocky guy and then
when you reach 35 then you start cutting
I think that's ridiculous that's a
horrible way to live why would you first
off why do you want to look stocky who
wants to look stocky anyway you want to
live a healthy Fit Life throughout your
life it's not like when you become 35
suddenly Fitness becomes important I'm
not against bulking but you shouldn't be
bulking for 10 years you're gonna have
to give up night time you're gonna have
to give thanks
majority of the time if it lands on your
lap if there's like a straight eight out
of ten and she's like
you're gonna waste like two hours of
your life don't do it because that
opportunity might not pop up yeah so for
10 years of your life 24 ages 25 to 35
you're just going to not interact with
women at all unless they interact with
you first that's a terrible idea like by
the end of it when you're 35 and you're
you know the MD of a company and you're
rich you are gonna not have the skills
anymore you know this old 35 year old
guy who completely lost touch with
everything doesn't have social skills no
no like you have a bank account what are
you gonna do with the bank account you
can't get the affection of women with
just a bank account the most interesting
people in history they experiment they
aren't you know risking and feeling this
fear of you got to do this this and this
from ages 25 to 35 and then you can set
yourself up for Success from 35 to 45.
the interesting people in history don't
do this they live storied life they go
and do things which may or may not
succeed what Chris is describing is
actually a cowardly and weak kind of way
of living when you plan everything out
and you think it's going to go perfect
but it never actually will like think
about Winston Churchill think about the
Lawrence of Arabia these men went out
there and even risked their lives to do
these crazy things because they wanted
to and because it would be an adventure
to do so they didn't sit there planning
their life and you know Investment
Portfolio 25 years to 35 years I got a
bulk from 25 to 35 and then I'll cut and
then I'll look good you have the control
over your life you don't have to time
everything perfectly and if you do try
to time everything perfectly you will
guaranteed fail
the overlap so on the next one number
three this is from 30 to 35 five years
of Jesus loans it's five years and not
dating any women not seeing any women
basically necessarily seeing them but
you're not seeing them in that capacity
so five years you're gonna spend five
years with Rags instead of good clothes
not meeting any women because quite
honestly if you're doing this then women
don't want to talk to you anyway and
cutting your own hair to save money man
imagine once you get out of that five
years right when you're ready to start
living your life so to speak your
confidence is going to be trash like you
haven't spoken to girls in five years
you haven't had friends you're wearing
Rags you're cutting your own hair it's
not possible for a human being to just
live a certain way for five years and
then suddenly become the social
butterfly and you're good with women you
have friends and you have good fashion
that's not how life works you cannot
just segment parts of your life and say
you'll just work for five years and then
you play for five years that's not how
it is you have to find a blend of what
you love and what you can do what you're
passionate about and also gives you a
financial reward while you're still
maintaining a social life and then
that's how you live a blended happy life
and when you look back when you're 50
you actually did something fun you did
eventful things you have stories to tell
to your grandchildren the way he's
living or this way He suggests that you
live that's not how you make stories and
life is about making stories not about
perfect timing but that first five years
is military right you're doing five
hours of sleep but dedicate your
business and nothing but Fitness you
just that's a terrible idea so he's
literally suggesting I'm not making this
up he literally just said you should be
sleeping for about five hours per night
for those five years you know what's
that gonna do to your health if you
sleep for only five hours per night
that's not gonna be good for your
business and success your creativity is
going to come down your actual work
being done per day will come down the
way you interact with your team is not
going to be good and you know business
is not just about how much work and how
many hours you put in business is about
how much passion you have for the
product what the product brings to other
people's lives what meaning it creates
for them and you know you need your
sleep for first a healthy body and
healthy mind but also for the actual
monetary and financial rewards which
come with business you need your sleep
depending on these two things you might
sleep a little bit more for Fitness
purposes but you are dedicating every
minute hour second but then in the
second half of those five we introduce
stuff like better skin okay start taking
care of your skin your hair if you've
got it your beard hair Etc no you won't
you won't have your hair look at your
you look at you look at your head that's
what he has done to himself he did his
dedication for five years straight
sleeping for five hours and that's why
he probably lost his hair you know the
amount of stress that your body goes
through when it doesn't get enough sleep
that's probably what did it to you man
military lifestyle like I'm in the
military we don't sleep for just five
hours that happens if you're in the
field yes but usually you'll try to get
as much sleep as possible so that you're
having the performance level you need
for the next day the health is so
important once you get past 30 and
that's why I think because in your 20s
you can get away with me health is
important throughout your life not just
after you turn 35 just wanted to put it
out there maybe I wouldn't recommend
this but worst case scenario you could
have a [ __ ] diet get to 30 and you know
your box you'll just you've been hitting
the gym but you've had a [ __ ] diet [ __ ]
lifestyle you're not sleeping well at 30
you've got change Jack I know you said
you don't recommend this but you kind of
did recommend this you're basically
saying you sacrifice everything you're a
bulk person with bad diet bad Health bad
sleep and then you turn 35 and then
you're trying to turn all this around
that's terrible advice because you are
the habits that you build and you can
just suddenly change all your habits
when you turn 35 like if you have a lot
of healthy habits bad sleep and bad diet
that's going to continue it's going to
have its own momentum and you can just
turn it around when you're 35. now the
next one is to become more well-rounded
once you get to 30 I think it's
important to start learning languages
start working on yourself to start
incorporating fashion let's say into
your okay so you want to become a
well-rounded person after you turn 35
and then you start learning languages
and traveling you don't just get to
become a well-rounded person a
well-rounded person is not somebody who
has a lot of skills and experiences a
well-rounded person has a character of
his own he is organically just gone and
had a lot of experiences and learned a
lot of skills throughout his life it's
not something you can just log in when
you're 35 that's not how it works it can
be like you can start dressing better
I'm going to start like I said skin and
stuff like that you just become a better
individual you go and learn different
things outside of just successfulness
whatever you become a better person okay
yeah yeah you wait till you're 35 to
become a better person great idea Chris
guys adrenal fatigue chronic fatigue
whatever you want to call it
hypothyroidism I've suffered from all of
them and it came I'm not surprised I'm
not surprised I'm from just working too
hard I've done it guys I've done it I've
done is I did it from like probably 21
to like 25 I burnt out two three times I
don't have any energy I got depressed to
the point I stood on the top of five
buildings like so so why haven't you
learned anything from this Chris you're
talking about chronic fatigue and how
you've been through this grind and you
were stood at the top of buildings he
was literally considering ending it all
because of the workload that he put on
himself this is not a sustainable way to
live and he should know this because
he's been through this and he saw the
results of this he's been suffering
so when is it right to invest your money
in crypto rather than your own health
crypto may or may not give you a return
I don't know but you should always be
okay with investing in your health you
know your health is always going to pay
dividends your health is always going to
pay you a reward there's no reason to
sacrifice your health for the pursuit of
money because then you have to spend
your money to get your health back it's
stupid you have to find a balance that
works for you because those days when a
man's life starts and it begins so I
think the idea that a man's life starts
when he's 30 is simply wrong man's life
starts when he's born he tries to make
the distinction between a woman's life
and a man's life and how a man gets its
Advantage when he's 30. there might be
truth to the idea that man gets an
advantage when he's 30. however his life
starts long before this the stories the
experiences the people who he meets the
skills that he learns the stories that
he reads places that he's been the foods
that he's eaten these are the things
which make him who he is when he turns
30 he's already a man he's already
accrued all these experiences and by
sacrificing these experiences you're
still a boy you're still not grown you
know you're still a teenager because you
fail to have the experiences now you're
just a kid with money
decisions let your employees work for
you let your money work for you and just
cement that well so Chris's ideology in
a nutshell is to sacrifice everything
you sacrifice sleep your diet your
health social life women everything for
five years so that you can make money
and then you use the money to get back
the things that you sacrificed this is
ass backwards thinking I think the
better idea is to incorporate pieces of
all these things in your life as you're
making money and the reason is simple I
don't think what Chris is saying
actually works like if you try to
sacrifice everything to make money I
think you'll be less successful at
making money than the guy who's found a
way to synergize all these activities
that he genuinely enjoys with his
business life I just think it's
important to get to the end of your life
look back and be like I did everything
with perfect timing who wants to get on
their deathbed and then look back and
see that he has done everything in the
perfect timing rather you want to look
back and say I did this this and this
this was amazing you know I helped so
many people with their lives I had this
adventure I met this woman I've tried
this this and this I've been to 20
countries and and of course family you
want to spend time with your family I'm
sad here editing my video and I realized
how negative it sounds it sounds as
though I'm doing a 10 minute character
assassination of Chris that's not my
intention I disagree with Chris on all
these points but I still respect the guy
[Music]