have you ever gotten caught cheating I
was sat there at the back of the lecture
hall we were having an exam we're having
an exam and the professor let's call her
professor s she was all the way on the
front left side she was quite far from
me so I didn't expect her to be able to
see me at all and this was a
thermodynamics exam if you know anything
about thermodynamics like it's a hard
subject so I had my answers um answer
sheets where I would write on I had my
question sheet and under the answer
sheet I had a little bit of extra notes
which I wasn't supposed to have just
against the rules and I knew it it was
dishonest but I had these notes under
there and every now and then when I was
struggling with a question I would
consult these equations and I would
proceed I would try to answer the
questions based on my my hidden
notes and I was doing that and out the
corner of my left eye I see footsteps I
I hear a little bit of footsteps and I
see
like her shoes I see her shoes and I
freeze I try to play it cool it's like
you know I'm not I'm not going to expose
myself I'm going to try to play it cool
maybe she didn't see me I shouldn't
overreact and I slide the hidden notes
under my sheets and act as though
nothing happened she gets closer I still
try to play cool but at this point my
heart's freaking beating right I'm my
heart's beating so at that point I know
the game's up but I still try to play
cool and but she's like right right to
my left she's right here she's looking
at me and I act as though you know
nothing nothing's going on I'm just an
honest student doing my my work why is
she disturbing me she says would you
please lift up your answer sheets and I
do and my notes are right there I got
caught
red-handed she takes the notes says
continue on your exam and walks away and
the next 1 hour were a blur you know my
heart was pounding I was completely
reflexive I wasn't a very bad mental
state because I believed that I would
get expelled because I did get caught
red-handed and the policy for dishonesty
in examinations is ex uh expulsion from
the
University but it didn't quite hit me
then you know I I did my best I
completed the exam I submitted the paper
I left and then it hit me I was like
my parents spent almost $90,000 over the
period of two years almost 100K of their
life savings basically so my parents of
course they are from India they sold
their property let me close
this they sold their property to be able
to fund my
college experience and I had blown it
right I not only I didn't fail out I
literally got kicked out for dishonesty
which is the worst so I didn't get
kicked out at this point I I thought I
would so I thought I was going to get
kicked out and you know that was the
probably the most depressed I've ever
been in my life cuz I had essentially
betrayed my parents' trust in me I could
visualize my
mother's sadness and disappointment my
father's anger and resentment and that's
not something I could face up to and to
this day like when I think about that
it's like godamn I was in a bad place
right but yeah man
so I mean at this point might seem like
a simple thing but actually that's not
even true even now that pain is still
there I thought I had wasted
$100,000 of my parents hard-earned
income which they literally sold a
property for to be able to finance my
college so it wasn't about the cheating
it's about betrayal of the
parents
but you know I was in a bad place I
never got close cl to you know you know
that but if I ever got close to it it
was on that day but I received an email
from that Professor saying you know
visit me in my office at so and so time
the next day it's like okay fine let me
do this let me see what happens and I
can proceed based on what happens so I
go to her office let's call her Dr
s she's talking to a different student
and that student walks out I knock at
the door she sees who it is gets me in
and on her desk was the notes that I use
like the the evidence basically that I
cheated was right there you know there's
no denying it there's nothing I could do
she had the proof it was in my
handwriting so there was no backing out
there was no it was straight up like hey
yeah I I cheated you know I I broke the
rules and the consequence for that was
exposion I knew that I knew the
consequence it's like okay you know I'm
going to face this like a man
let's go and talk this with the
professor let's see what happens
and it was bad for her too because she
was a new professor she was new to the
job she didn't know what she was doing
and she didn't want to have this extra
burden of a disciplinary action against
a student she didn't want it I didn't
want it we were both in this terrible
situation which I had put us into and
she looks at me and she says why you
know why do this you could have asked me
for help before the exam I would have
gladly given it like yeah she probably
would
have and she asked me did I cheat on the
midterms like yeah I cheated on the
midterms as well and I was I was honest
I didn't lie I cheated both on both
exams I cheated on the homework too but
she didn't ask that question so I let it
pass then she's like yeah I'm going to
have to I'm going to have to show this
to the disciplinary committee or the
Ethics Committee whatever it's called
it's like yeah I'm aware of this and
there's nothing to be said she has to do
what she has to do according to the
protocol she has to show it to the
Ethics Committee and the ethics
committee decides what disciplinary
reaction to take it's like okay fine
it's in their it's in their hands I was
like okay I get up to leave I'm leaving
out the door just about to leave I
almost closed the door she said she says
wait calls me by name calls me back in
and she says the words which I will
remember forever she
says you know I've decided to handle
this
internally and I just felt the weight
get off my shoulders man because that's
basically the code word for saying I'm
going to throw these notes in the trash
I'm going to forget this ever happened
go about your day it's like holy
this is the best possible outcome this
is the best possible outcome she said I
that she would give me a D she' give me
a zero on the exam I was like okay no
problem give me a zero that's
fine just let me out of here don't tell
the disciplinary Committee just I'm done
you know so I passed that course a d is
not a fail an F is a fail a d is a is a
pass so I got a D in thermodynamics 1
and I passed I was done thermodynamics 1
was done I didn't need to do it
again but next semester was
thermodynamics 2 and I was not going to
put myself in the same position as I did
in thermodynamics 1 hell no Thermo one I
was sucking man I was I hated it I was
not good at it I didn't know how to
learn and that was the thing I realized
that I didn't know how to learn until
that point I could just use you know my
brain power I guess to just grind it out
do the repetitions and get good at
whatever subject I was trying to handle
calc 1 calc 2 whatever it was it was
only when I hit theramic one as at the
limit of my brain's power so that's why
I ended up cheating that's why this
entire episode happened so
thermodynamics 2 is a more difficult
course than thermodynamics 1 so I was
like yeah I I'm going to end up in the
same exact exact position if I don't
learn how to learn so between the two
semesters there's a few weeks of no
classes I'm going to use that time to
understand how to optimize the
performance of my brain and how to
really have a system for mastering
anything no matter how difficult
including thermodynamics 2 and that's
the system which I'm going to impart to
you today it's the magic hourglass
method and this is a actual lecture so
I'm going to use an actual whiteboard I
have my markers and everything and I'm
going to teach you the method which made
me immensely
successful in a even more difficult
topic than Thermo one so what's the
what's a magic hourglass good question
let me draw one out so let's
see
that's what an hourglass looks like
hopefully the wind isn't making my voice
too hard to comprehend that's an
hourglass yeah an hourglass has
sand and that sand is going to trickle
down and you have more
sand a magic hourglass is when you put
sand on the top glass of The Hourglass
and when it trickles down something
happens at this point to turn this into
gold so you have g o l d gold dust the
magic hourglass is an ancient technology
of esoteric or Origins and Arcane
transmutative power this device is now
in the lost city of Atlantis and I'm
going to bring this technology to you
today so what's going on in the magic
hourglass and what does it have to do
with learning all right I will explain
the theory behind this at this time so
first you have the input that's the sand
you're inputting information into your
brain which you're trying to master and
here the first point under
input
is take breaks so let me explain more I
realized that my biggest downfall when
it came to learning any subject was I
would try to cram because cramming is
the technique all right it's the
technique which they teach in schools in
India and that's where I did middle
school high school so cramming is the
only technique I knew so the idea of
studying was basically if you haven't
examine let's say thermodynamics grab
the textbook start doing problem after
problem again and again and again and
again just cram cram cram for like week
straight and then you hit the exam
doesn't work doesn't work it's not ideal
because studying or learning something
is not like going to the gym when you go
to the gym you want to push through the
last few reps with all your willpower
because that's where the gains are when
it comes to learning it's not like that
learning is not forced learning is
receptive so when you are trying to
learn something you're going to force it
into your brain man what you got to do
is it's like filling a glass with
Coca-Cola if you try to just glug the
entire Bottle Into Your Glass what's
going to happen is the Fizz is going to
rise it's going to overflow and when the
Fizz dies down you're not even going to
be left with that much liquid that not
much Coca-Cola
so what do you actually do what you need
to do is pour a bit by bit you're going
to pour a little bit allow the fist to
rise let the fist settle down pour a
little bit more allow the fist to rise
let it settle down and then pour some
more you do it piece by piece cuz you
need the liquid to settle that's how
Learning Happens so when you're studying
or learning something take breaks as
often as your brain tells you to with
time you'll get better and you'll need
fewer braks but when you're starting out
your brain is going to get tired it's
going to get Bor is going to get anxious
and it's going to tell you to stop take
that queue stop learning step away from
your desk and here's the trick you do
not consume any other input nor do you
distract yourself with any kind of
stimulation all right so you're studying
let's say you're studying calculus
you're studying mathematics whatever it
is you get bored you hit a problem that
you can't solve you'll leave the desk
and you do nothing you do not get on
your phone you do not get on YouTube you
do not watch Netflix you do not play
video games you don't even check
Instagram you don't even check your text
messages you do not distruct yourself by
doing so-called productive activities
such as cleaning your room cooking food
nothing your only allowed activity is
walking you can walk outside you can
walk inside your house I don't care you
are not stimulating yourself and you're
not giving further input because that's
what allows the brain that time to
settle that information and actually
absorb absorb and distill and you know
synthesize it into its brain so that's
how you do good
input now here this magic magic location
in the magic hourglass is called
transmutation
trans
mutation transmutation is the magic of
taking sand into gold and in
transmutation have a couple pointers for
you the first one is passive and it's
sleep so they did an experiment with
mice they took a bunch of mice and put
them through a maze which they like to
do the scientists and they put probes in
its brain to measure its electrical
signals and they measured it while it
was solving the maze they made it Mouse
solve the maze like 10 times in a day
and they got the data and they let the
mouse sleep and they looking at the data
when it slept they're looking at its
Dreams they're looking at what happened
happens when it has REM sleep so what
they found was when the mouse was
sleeping it was solving the maze so the
same exact electrical signals while it
was solving the maze were recurring when
the mouse was dreaming so the mouse was
actually replaying that maze in its head
but here's the thing it's doing it 100x
faster if it takes the mouse a minute to
solve the maze in its mind while
dreaming it solving it in 10 seconds 5
Seconds 1 second like really rapidly and
here's the key part it is solving the
maze from you know point A to point B it
is also solving the maze point B to
point a it is also solving the maze in
segments and at random order so the mice
the mouse was solving a a
computationally powerful difficult
problem multiple times in its sleep so
if a mouse can do that imagine what the
human mind can do so you need to
optimize your sleep to get good at
problem solving memory literally
anything cognition based so how do you
optimize sleep I have a whole video on
sleep optimization I'll link that in the
description or I'll have the end tile
pop up that's the video you need to
master sleep so that's the passive
technique of transmutation there are two
active techniques which I'm going to
teach you the first the the well second
technique for the first active technique
it is called mental rehearsal so mental
rehearsal mental rehearsal is literally
what I did to do this lecture think
about this I'm giving a full lecture I'm
barely Consulting my notes how is that
possible it's because I've done it two
times already in my mind so they had an
experiment they did an experiment with
dart players you know what's darts right
they have a it's like a game you play in
I imagine it as being played in like old
timey British bars like you have this
circle that's the goal you have darts
you got to throw it and the closer you
get to the the center of it that's the
higher points you get I've never played
darts but I know what it looks like
so they had three groups let's call them
group a b and c group a was not given
any chance to practice all right and
they took the score like they took the
score of what groups A's performance was
at this game of darts Group B got the
chance to practice they practiced and
then they took the score
Group C was told hey you can't actually
practice what you can do is Imagine This
is a dart imagine a dart and imagine the
muscular sequence it takes to launch a
dart now like I don't know how to play
darts but I imagine if I was in that
group if I was in group C I'd imagine
holding a dart visualizing the center of
the target you know holding my dart back
kind of making an eye connection and
then launching it that's how I would
imagine it and these guys did something
similar they tried mental repetitions
now who do you think they did the best
if hopefully okay so this live stream
was I didn't know how to start
the live stream so hopefully it's going
on right now if you think group a one
type A if you think it's B type B if
it's C type
c so to nobody's surprise Group B did
the best because Group B got to practice
no no surprise there and of course group
a did the worst cuz they got zero
practice whatsoever the surprising
finding was Group C which didn't
actually practice all they did was
mentally visualize the practice they
came pretty damn close like they were
didn't beat the group which practiced
but they got close like how how all they
did was practice in the mind but this is
actually a Time tested technique in many
sports especially tennis and golf what
the coaches found was a combination of
actual physical practice plus mental
rehearsals equals greater than just
mental practice or just physical
practice that's mental rehearsals so you
might think well I'm not playing golf
I'm not playing tennis I'm not playing
darts how is it relevant to me you can
do mental rehearsals for anything you
just have to be a bit creative I did
mental rehearsals for this lecture I
want to have you know a a Charisma I
want to have a good storytelling ability
I want to have confidence I want to
speak
eloquently I have to practice to do that
but I can't I didn't the best way to
practice that without actually doing it
is in the mind I practiced this before I
came here in the mind before I slept it
was encoded I dreamt about it I had done
this 100 times before I'm doing it
because I did it in my R sleep right so
at this point I have I have the best
amount of camera presence I can muster
at this time because I've done the
repetitions while I was
sleeping that is the power of mental
rehearsal I'll tell you something funny
so I had all the notes for this lecture
prepared and printed out and I left it
in my desk at home I forgot to bring it
so I set up my setup and everything I
have my camera like my phone I have my
whiteboard all that I didn't have my
notes so 10 minutes before this lecture
I recreated 100% of my notes word for
word in this gym notebook which I have I
will actually show it to you I created
two pages words of notes from my memory
alone that's the power of mental
rehearsal you can do this for any
subject if you're trying to get good at
mathematics here's what you do you
imagine the the version of yourself
which is good at mathematics all
right you imagine the version which has
already succeeded at learning calculus
so you're not necessarily trying to
solve the problem in your mind though
you can do that what you're doing is
you're visualizing the that version
which has succeeded and when he sees a
mathematical problem he's like ah okay
so that's how you do this starts writing
the answer you know you can hear the
scratching of his pencil on the on the
surface you can feel him arriving at the
conclusions faster than he's able to
write it down that's the visualization
you're going for and this is true for
mathematics maybe you're trying to learn
biology maybe you're trying to learn
mitosis and meosis cool you're imagining
a version of yourself who already knows
it he knows the steps of meosis and
mitosis he knows it without any
confusion you're
visualizing that person why I was
reading this book psycho cybernetics and
it makes this point very forcefully that
is your success always lags behind your
mental image of yourself if you believe
that you're too dumb to solve a
mathematical problem you are not going
to succeed at cracking it if you feel
that you are your memory is not good
enough to memorize all these anatomical
names names of all the bones in the
human body you're trying to be a doctor
you'll never succeed if on the other
hand you have the image you believe that
you are the kind of person who is
already good at memorization already
good at solving mathematics already good
at engineering then when you start
solving the problem your brain is in a
relaxed state so this is not this is not
manifestation it's not some
girly thing that you think of something
is going to happen no it's very
straightforward a recept cve mind gets
better ideas can process thoughts more
fluidly a receptive mind is open to put
it metaphysically is open to the word of
God and there is no we don't get good
ideas good ideas come to you you cannot
force good ideas and I think it was n
who said you only should trust the
thoughts and ideas that come to you
outdoors in the open and you know that's
why I'm
here that is the power of mental
rehearsal but there was another Dart
study another study of throwing darts
and what these guys did they did the
experiment a little bit differently they
had two groups let's call them group a
and Group B group a had a external locus
of control and Group B had an internal
locus of control so I'll explain what
locus of control is shortly what they
found was the guys with the external
locus of
control for them mental rehearsal didn't
work at all they did all the mental
rehearsal but they didn't see any
Improvement Group B who had an internal
locus of control they got good through
mental rehearsal alone so what's locus
of control we talked about mental
rehearsal locus of control is the idea
of your mind that you have the ability
to control your destiny basically you
have control over where your life is
going your surroundings this is the
masculine way to live you have an
internal locus of control so locus of
control is basically who do you think
controls your destiny if it's an
internal locus of control it means you
control your destiny people with an
external locus of control basically
believe you know the government is going
to control their Destiny or their
genetics is going to control their
Destiny their parenting their education
their their looks is going to control
their Destiny internal locus of control
which is what I have I believe I am in
charge I am in charge of the course of
my life whether it goes to or I
become something great it's on me I have
internal locus of control it's me I
believe that duty is Destiny this is the
lesson of the bhagwad Gita which is an
ancient religious text duty is Destiny
you perform the duty that is given to
you again and again with the highest
caliber of performance and Destiny takes
care of itself in other words I want you
to listen to this and then repeat it in
your mind as a form of mental
rehearsal your thoughts and actions
shape your character character is who
you are and the character shapes your
destiny so say it with me in your mind
thoughts and actions shape
character character shapes Destiny
that's going to give you an internal
locus of control which is point number
three I'm just going to say I internal
locus of control ilc if you have these
three you are trans mutating you're
transforming what you learn into
something greater into
output so you might have heard of
definement technique all these you know
Ali abdal types they always talk about
finement technique you know finement
technique is nothing it's just if you
teach something you're going to get
better at it so if you're trying to
master calculus you grab a friend teach
him the problem that you learn learned
and as he asks questions and you
interact you get damn good at that
subject cool the thing is most of us
don't have very good friend circles or
we don't even have friends or
your friends are not interested in the
same things that you're interested in or
are in different subjects than you so
may not be possible and also maybe you
don't really want to talk about like
academics with your friends it's fine
what you do instead is you make a
YouTube
series what you do is say you're trying
to learn calculus become a con Academy
onto yourself start posting on YouTube
get a whiteboard like this one be like
hey you know calculus first concept of
calculus differentiation this is what
differentiation is or integrals this is
what integrals is make video after video
explaining the stuff as you learn cuz
when you're making a video about
something you have to transmute it you
have to synthesize it you have to
simplify it so your audience understands
you have to make it come to life so your
audience understands you don't need an
audience on YouTube you can post stuff
for free maybe nobody watches them but
who cares you've improved your public
speaking you've improved your presence
you've actually Gotten Good at that
subject and I know this to be true so
nutrition I'm very passionate about
nutrition I have a lot of knowledge
about nutrition I learned a lot of
nutrition to make these videos but it is
only when I made my nutrition course
that I reach a new level of confidence
and competent
at this
topic when I made the course I made like
40 modules of nutrition topics I had to
figure out you know how does this module
fit in the section how do the sections
fit into this course Etc in doing that
not only did I learn more also the
thoughts which I already had in my head
were arranged it was it's like taking a
Rubik's Cube and solving it I had this
unsolved Rubik's cube of nutrition facts
and as I created the course I was
solving it and at the end I kind of
understood nutrition I was like you know
if somebody ask me to give a lecture on
nutrition like that I could probably do
it I could probably do a damn good job
of it and I was confident and competent
at that topic of nutrition because I had
made a course on it now you don't have
to make a whole ass course but if you do
you will master that topic guaranteed
that is output make a YouTube
series so you're harnessing the power of
YouTube for learning not by watching
videos but by making them by being in
the Creator's seat and that's how the
magic hourglass method works and I use
this man I use this very method to
master to get really good as at
thermodynamics 2 so Thermo 2 is a more
difficult topic and was by a different
Professor you know Dr s who I shall not
mention her name she's out of the
picture she's done that Thermo one
Thermo 2 was another professor his name
was
Campanella and he was a master of
thermodynamics he was a seven or eight
figure entrepreneur in Agri business and
he loved thermodynamics so much that
when he retired he's like can I teach at
University and he was teaching this high
level thermodynamics class and of course
he was a master in his field right of
course he was he was a professor in one
of the best engineering
colleges probably on the
planet and there was one problem he was
solving and the problem was about pipes
and how heat escapes from pipes which is
a common thermodynamics
problem and it was a difficult problem
and it's actually a very interesting
thing so as you increase the insulation
on a pipe when you go from zero to a
little bit of insulation actually the
heat which escapes increases and then it
starts to decrease again as you increase
the insulation so I don't need to
explain thermodynamics on this lecture
right but basically it was a complicated
simulation and complicated mathematical
equations which which go with it and he
was solving it on the board and at this
time I was I was pretty good like that's
pretty good at thermodynamics I was like
you know this doesn't make intuitive
sense to me and my mathematics is
looking a little bit different from what
was on the board so after the class I
was like hey professor you know I don't
think this is like I my intuition is
telling me that my solution is correct
and he looks over my solution it says
you got to come to my office at 6:00
p.m. later today it's like okay you know
I I knew I didn't do anything wrong so I
was like I'll go to his office I went to
his office and this was a parallel to my
office visit to Dr s in thermal
one so same building right same floor
even but this time I had solved
something I went in and by the time it
was 6:00 I had run some more simulations
I was getting even more confident of my
solution to the problem like hey
professor like I know I'm right I ran
the solution through Wolfram Alpha which
is like um computational software it's
like this is the graphs which came out
and everything all right so Professor
sees it he's like yeah I know cuz I did
the same thing and he's like I've been
teaching this problem wrong for 5 years
and nobody's corrected
me you are really good at your
intuition and you know I was feeling
really proud of myself and he says he
says when you're looking for a letter of
recommendation you come to
me you have to understand professors
don't hand out letters of recommendation
students have to kind of like beg for
them have just scrun around for
professors who are willing to write you
a letter of recommendation and this
professor one of the best in his field
offered it to me it was a a true honor a
true highlight of my academic career as
it
was and of course I took him up on the
offer I got into grad school because of
this
experience and that was through the
power of this very technique which I've
given you
and you know I wish I could just end off
at a high note I had done the technique
and I had succeeded guys you know listen
to my technique cuz I succeeded it
wasn't like that man so I got good at
thermodynamics I used the same method on
other topics I got good like I got good
grades for the first time in engineering
I succeeded I graduated with pretty
decent grade I was
okay and graduation was the worst day of
my life even thinking back about it now
it's like God damn that was a bad day I
made my mother cry during the day of
graduation so the reason why I was so
upset and depressed when I got caught
cheating was because I thought I
betrayed my parents and I wasted their
money their hard earned income because I
was no good at engineering so I
believed after I actually completed my
engineering degree it dawned on me that
I'd have to get an engineering job at
this point and I didn't actually enjoy
mathematics and
Engineering now I had spent almost $200
,000 of my parents money instead of the
100,000 in thermo one I finished my
degree right I spent $200,000 of my
parents money probably even more because
I didn't even factor in like you know
room and board right so I was like God I
spent so much of your money but I don't
actually want to get the engineering job
that this degree allows me to get what
do I do I wanted to study biology I want
to study science and that's not exactly
high
paying engineering is super high paying
but science really isn't so I was like
hell I got this degree I did so
much hard work and I still ended up
betraying my parents because my parents
vision for me was not going to get
filled and I was very rude I was very
upset I was very angry at myself and I
let that affect my parents I was very
rude I was brusk I didn't thank them for
their support over the past four years
and I literally made my mother cry
because I couldn't control my own
emotions I wasn't in I I wasn't taking
charge of my own actions and my own
destiny so I've completed my engineering
degree and the Learning lesson here is
that you can use this technique to get
good at anything but you shouldn't get
good at anything you should get good at
the thing which matters to you don't use
this technique to get good at
thermodynamics if you don't enjoy
thermodynamics don't get good
at soccer if you don't even enjoy soccer
don't get
good at copyrighting if you don't even
enjoy writing don't get good at the
guitar if you don't enjoy music you have
a finite amount of time in life if all
you're doing
is learning and educating and studying
to impress your parents then you are a
dork I was a dork so not anymore
that now I do things for myself if
you're doing things just to impress your
parents you you are a dork if you're
doing things just for money you are a
nerd if all you're doing is you're
learning coding and computational skills
because you want to work for Microsoft
you don't actually care about coding all
you want to do is get the highp Ping job
you are a nerd do not study to
impress your parents do not study to get
money study learn and educate yourself
because it is a Divine Duty learning you
have to understand that tightens off our
civilization our kedes our Aristotle
tmy Socrates arabat all these Newton
galwa gaus all these guys they learned
educated themselves and practiced in
order to expand their minds the same as
going to the gym it's same as practicing
combat Arts they were practicing the
talents of their
mind gaus I think it was who said I get
it now have to really get it what he was
talking about
was the power of intuition and divine
reception so once you make up your mind
you have a why on why you want to learn
something you want to master
thermodynamics because you want to
create food preservation systems which
will save people's lives all right
that's a good why learning learning
thermodynamics to impress your parents
that's not a good why so let's say you
have the why that point learning is not
a matter of any of these things it's
divine the heavens will give you divine
inspiration on how to get good at stuff
ideas will come to you so going back to
gaus and his quote gaus was a
mathematician par Excellence right he
was a master
mathematician he saw a mathematical
problem and his intuition gave him the
solution he knew the solution to his
mathematical problem but he didn't know
the steps to get there so he said I get
it I see the solution but now I have to
get it cuz he has to prove his solutions
to his mathematical buddies right that
is the metaphysical and a Divine aspect
of learning and of course the opposite
to that is the Divine aspect of teaching
I do not consider these lectures to be a
way to get money I mean of course I will
but there's something else going on
right it goes deeper the act of learning
creating transmutation and teaching
which is output has a metaphysical and
divine how would you say
it purpose the purpose is a weak word
let's go for a stronger word Duty it has
Duty and of course I said duty is
Destiny so that's why I'm here that's
why I'm doing this lecture I have a
Divine duty to teach you the things that
I know I have a Divine duty to teach you
everything that I
know a lot of people think that my
channel is a health education
self-improvement Channel which I guess
it some sometimes is it's not the end
goal never
was I was working for Hamza as you know
this was this was years ago Hamza is a
world-class Storyteller and expert
YouTuber
and when I was working with him I
realized that I was older than him I had
an engineering job at the time so this
was after my undergrad I had an
engineering job which is making Fair bit
of money I realized Hamza is not
necessarily more talented or more
educated or smarter than me yet he was
making 10x the money I was making and
this because he was living to his
purpose he was living according to his
mission and I had a mission too and
because I wasn't living to that mission
I wasn't making half the money he was
making so so that's why I started the
YouTube channel is the mission I had was
more important than hamza's what's the
mission it's not heal the mission has to
do with two axioms the first axom is
that all governments tend to tyranny
there's been zero exceptions to this
rule throughout history you will see
that every single government always
tends to become tyrannical with time
this is an ironclad rule of History the
second axom is that for the next 10
years next 20 years technology is going
to improve so how do these two combine
it's because in the past when you had
Stalin and Hitler these tyrants these
tyrants wanted total to sorry
totalitarian control over you they want
to control every aspect of your life but
they couldn't do it they couldn't do it
because they didn't have the technology
to do it they didn't have the
technology so even though they wanted to
know your thoughts they wanted to know
your actions they wanted to know your
worldview they wanted to know what you
read what you ate everything they
couldn't do it if you're in you know
nowhere Russia Stalin is not
going to be able to enforce his will on
you he couldn't do it even if he wanted
to but if you look at the social credit
system in
China at this point in history because
of the technology that we have including
artificial intelligence governments can
actually monitor you in real time every
day till the day you die from the from
the time you born it's going to
happen I Rebel at this the thought of it
makes my skin crawl I have to do
something against it when there's still
time what I'm going to do is create a
parallel Society a society a group of
indiv a group of men and women who think
of Health Care and education differently
that is what I want to establish I want
to
create that is why I do what I do that's
the purpose that's what makes this all
worth
it
so I I started doing this in my private
Community K's Country Club speaking of
which I have homework for you so you
attended my lecture cool I have homework
for you who are listening right now I
want you to write down one thing that
you want to master in the year of 2024
could be anything playing the guitar are
talking to women could be social skills
public speaking making YouTube videos it
could be calculus it could be
trigonometry it could be any kind of you
know English writing copywriting sales I
don't care one thing that you're going
to become a master of you're going to
reach the 1% of performance at that one
thing I want you to write a detailed
action plan as how you are going to
achieve that thing I will tell you mine
my the skill I want to master is the
skill of camera presence and story
telling and the detailed plan on how to
achieve that is by doing these live
lectures when you have live lectures
there's no editing there's no fancy
Graphics background music nothing if you
are engaged by this it is because of my
storytelling my pacing the enunciation
of my words all that that's what I want
to get good at I want to reach the top
1% of the 1% of top performance at
storytelling and education content to do
that I need repetition I need to do all
the steps which are here that's my
detailed plan I want you to write this
down if you're in KCC right now if
you're a member you you already paid
you're a member I want you to go into
KCC and write a post in the newly
created challenges section describing
this I will come in there give you
feedback if you are not in KCC it's fine
do it in the comment section if you're
watching this live you can't do it right
now but I'm going to upload this as a
regular video and in that case you can
actually write it in the comment section
your detailed plan that's your homework
you must do it in order to succeed at
this all right you're going to do the
homework few other things I'm going to
have two tiles pop up at the end of this
video one is going to lead to the Sleep
video which you're going to learn how to
master sleep the other is going to be to
the next video tomorrow's lecture is
going to be
entitled how to make the greatest
comeback of your life so same time as
today attend the lecture tomorrow how to
make the greatest comeback of your
life so I want you to enable
notification for that so that's your
homework write down your goals goal like
single goal a single skill that you want
to master write down the detail steps on
how you're going to get there then
you're going to either watch the Sleep
video or make yourself a notification
for tomorrow's
lecture and with that I conclude this
lesson about the magic hourglass method
on how to master anything I appreciate
your time I I believe it well spent and
all right have a nice day I'm enjoying
the beautiful here at in Hawaii cheers