have you ever heard of parallel
societies and parallel institutions well
of course that's the question jelly
mobile asks me so do you know what
parallel lines are parallel lines are
lines which never intersect they never
conflict they never cut each other
that's exactly what it is with parallel
societies but a group of people in a
society lose trust in the mainstream
narrative they form their own systems
their own beliefs and their own
practices and thereby form a parallel
Society they don't seek to conflict with
the mainstream they just want to do
their own thing sounds familiar doesn't
it so if you want a full video on that
let me know who TFS Daniel asks about
pesticides and Foods well the first
thing you gotta know is blueberries so
blueberries are highly nutritious for
you but they're coated in pesticides and
fungicides and that's true for all
berries and all fruits you definitely
need to wash your fruits and vegetables
before you consume them how do you wash
them vinegar plus baking soda seems to
do the trick soak for a couple minutes
and then you're just scrub them with
your own hands and then you're ready to
go Gokul Vijay asks are there any
alternatives to telephone well certainly
there are so Taliban is the best thing
for your skin 100 and the brand that I
trust and use is vintage tradition
because I literally know the guy who
produces this stuff I'll put a discount
code in the description if you want to
use it but as for Alternatives what
you're looking for is a
non-petroleum-based product and the good
thing is more and more such products are
coming out onto the market every single
day mark my words so this movement of
esoteric health is far broader than this
channel it's happening at a societal
level many businesses are propping up
non-toxic alternatives to traditional
products if you're an entrepreneur or a
businessman or if you want to get into
that I I'm telling you non-toxic items I
would strongly recommend creating a
product in that area and then promoting
it that's the field which is going to
grow in the next 10 to 15 years lack
places us are we supposed to be hanging
on Vines and branches because we evolve
to do so we're not exactly we evolve
from great apes and those also walked on
two legs so you don't need to hang from
branches because that's what we want to
do but you should hang on your pull-up
bar or a branch or whatever it is a few
times or at least one time per day
because of the spinal decompression
benefits best time to do it before you
sleep the brain detoxes itself only at
night and it can only do so when it
purchases toxins into the spinal fluid
so it's very important to decompress
your spine or at least alleviate
pressure on the spine so that your brain
can actually detox Sam gaming asks I
have yellow teeth how do I make them
white well you need to use a tooth
powder the one I've been using is one by
a company called van man and they've
come up with this hydroxyapatite tooth
powder which is really quite good and
they also have deodorant so a lot of
people ask me what kind of deodorant
should you use most deodorants are toxic
but a van man has come up with this
deodorant I believe it's a
magnesium-based product it's pretty good
actually I've used it myself and I can
watch for it username bot asks
recommended books well interestingly
enough fiction is actually really quite
useful so a lot of people in the
self-improvement type Community we just
talk about self-improvement books that's
a mistake there's spectacular learnings
to be learned from fiction for example
how do you learn to get good at making
friends and influencing people most
people would say read that book by the
same exact name right and other people
would say read 48 Laws of Power that
gives you the real depth into human
nature I think both of those are wrong
better to read actually the Game of
Thrones series Game of Thrones shows you
the Dark Side of human nature and
manipulation but also shows you that
true friendship and kindness do actually
pay if you're smart enough to use those
properly it's gonna be a dumbass like
Ned stork then you're gonna get what's
coming to you I'm gonna have a
full-fledged book club in my country
club so if you're interested in that EJ
Kraft kid asks are there any
alternatives to Cologne well cologne is
highly highly estrogenic so there's a
whole bunch of aromatic molecules in all
colognes which mess you up for example
Dior Savage which is a very common very
popular cologne it's most pretty good to
be honest but it contains literally
contains red forts listed in the
ingredients it contains Redford so
mainstream designer fragrances are a
complete no-go however there are natural
fragrances coming out so I saw this one
on my Instagram recently called Soul
scent it's actually pretty good I bought
it it was reasonably priced and it
smells pretty good no natural fragrance
is going to last as long as your
designer fragrances that's completely to
be expected so know that going in not
exactly a question but I want to shout
out no Goods no glory because he wrote a
whole ass essay on the Roman education
system and how it prepped young Roman
young Noble Romans to be psyop free
actually anti-scion they were genuinely
taught how to think and not what to
think like how we are in our school
systems and even college to be honest
you know that young Roman Nobles they
would their fathers would send them
abroad on actual missions even as young
as like 14 15 16 17. they might have a
bodyguard and everything with them but
the fact is they would entrust genuine
valuable missions to Young Romans so
that even at a young age they had a
sense of responsibility a sense of Duty
and a sense that they genuinely matter
can you imagine how valuable that is for
a young man when your father literally
entrusts you with a mission off state to
go and perform we have no equivalent of
that in the modern world guys are like
21 22-23 and they're still basically
children but coming back to no goats no
glory so the fact is I've never seen
other channels commenters running a
whole essay and he's not the only one
many places I've seen people writing
whole essays and dissertations on my
videos and posts huge respect to those
guys another example Cornell gave me a
whole research essay on the education
system in the comments so I made a
community post talking about well you
know the education board was sponsored
by The Rockefellers and they designed it
in such a way that it mimics the
Prussian school system which is
literally designed to dump people down
and make them workers not thinkers and
Cornell went and fact checked me found
the relevant facts cited them and
actually wrote a whole essay in my post
my respect and gratitude I think the
viewer base watching this is genuinely
different from other places on YouTube
and I'll do my best to return that trust
Domino kiris asks what jobs have I
worked and what's a good nine to five
for a young man the best job I ever
worked was actually as a cashier in my
university school cafeteria the reason
is they were very chill I don't have to
like wear a uniform or anything so I
would wear literally a polo like this
one and I would be the door Checker so
I'll be the cashier in the front of the
cafeteria and what I do is I used to
have this speaker built into my collar
like under my collar and I'll have a
picture pop up and I used to listen to
audio books Incognito so the speaker
would be kind of invisible because it'd
be under my collar and I'd listen to
audiobooks as I do my shift and earn
money so I remember a summer was was two
months I finished something like 50
books in two months now be careful like
I'm not saying you should read 50 books
because what happens often is people
read books and don't take any action but
that was not the kind of books I was
reading anyway I was reading history and
philosophy so it wasn't exactly
actionable books so it just gave me a
lot of wisdom and knowledge which I
could use at a later date mythbot asked
can semen retention boost testosterone
well not directly so the direct effect
is actually on the dopamine circuitry
and I have a full guide coming out on
addiction so any kind of addiction you
can delete when you watch that video
samsara Indo asks about hair how do you
have good hair and why do homeless
people have such good hair I don't know
if homeless people actually have such
good hair and talks about how shampoo is
bad well shampoo is certainly bad most
shampoo is trash I've actually
experimented with using Tallow soap as a
shampoo so Tallow soap is what it sounds
like right it's soap with the main
ingredient is Tallow and I get it from
vintage tradition like all my towel
products I have this one Tello soap
which is mostly olive oil based and that
happens to be very good for hair so I
just use that for hair if you want to
know Atomic door asks me to make an
esoteric clothing guide well it's pretty
simple don't use synthetics use natural
fabrics and if you can help it don't
wear underwear done video is done I will
eat 100 apples ask what are your
thoughts on vaccines
Frank Vienna says how can I find a
community of like-minded individuals
like an esoteric Network well funny you
should say that he actually says it's a
business idea well it is certainly a
business idea the country club will
hopefully be available in the next two
weeks maybe at the time of watching you
only have Country Club available in
which case that's your esoteric
Community right there well I will
literally teach you everything I know
and this is a question I get all the
time in my DMs is supplements what kind
of supplements are good well I'll tell
you right now most supplements are kind
of trash most of the drugstore
supplements are trash especially even
even fish oil a lot of fish oil is kind
of trash and the reason for this is fish
oils are Omega-3s right that's what
you're looking for in fish oils mostly
those are highly unstable so if you heat
them too much in day nature so companies
which don't know how to store them
properly are giving you denatured oils
so are there some good Alternatives
certainly there are the most expensive
alternative is a company called Rosita
they make good stuff but it is expensive
another company is Nordic Naturals they
make fish oil I don't think they make
Cod liver oil which I prefer cod liver
oil because it has more vitamin D so
what do I use personally I use a product
by Green Pastures so Green Pastures
makes this very interesting product they
have a blend of butter oil and cod liver
oil they blend the two very unique
product definitely esoteric approved and
actually reach out to them and got a
discount code so if you want to use that
you could and last question by RC Slim
so I was just at the dentist and for the
first time in my life they did the teeth
cleaning and it didn't hurt like a
the hydroxy appetite actually works but
more importantly I'm going on a void to
the Old World on the 12th of this month
so I'm going to go to Venice Florence
and all the Italian states I'm going to
Portugal Spain France Italy and then
going to the south of Italy so I'm
following the path of Hannibal Barker
one of the famous generals of history
and every step of the way I'm going to
be sharing forbidden wisdom and showing
you these amazing cities on my Instagram
links in description