some of the best sleep I ever had was
curled up in a trash bag in the nasty
swampy Woods of Fort Benning Georgia
using the top secret U.S military
discovered and perfected sleep
techniques which I'm going to share with
you today but before that the first
thing is your bed is both estrogenic and
carcinogenic why do they think they have
a label on them which says air out for
24 hours before you use that's right
your mattress is literally off-gassing
toxins that you are breathing in every
single night so you might think to
yourself well why is this it's because
50 years ago the mainstream wisdom was
that smoking was good for you so the
media propagated smoking the science
said smoking was good so of course
people were smoking preferably after sex
on their bed and when you have smoking
in bed very naturally you have a flame
Hazard like a fire hazard and of course
the mattress company started putting
flame retardants into them beds so that
they don't catch fire which makes sense
Until you realize that the flame
retardants they used were highly toxic
you were probably exposed to these
estrogenic and toxic substances as a
baby when your mother laid you down to
bed on a toxic mattress of course she
didn't know any better and then your
father probably purchased for you
teething toys you know the toys which
babies chew on they often contain high
levels of BPA and when the companies
realize that there was bad press are on
BPA what do they do they switched out
the BPA for BPS and BPF which are
actually even more toxic than BPA ever
was so you were poisoned not just today
but as an infant hell even before you
were born in the womb you were poisoned
and then the scientists are trying to
figure out you know why are the sperm
counts going low why why is testosterone
falling and why so many kids are being
diagnosed with mental illnesses well
that's not the question the real
question is how we as a species are even
functional after we've been exposed to
so many toxins is basically chemical
warfare well the answer is humans and if
course nature in general is very
anti-fragile once you give nature or
humans a chance to recover we can
recover we can fix ourselves just
naturally and sleep is a key part of
this process sleep is when your body
detoxes and releases a lot of toxins
which builds up both from the brain and
the body I'm going to teach you the
exact way you optimize sleep including a
lot of tips which you've never heard of
because sleep is going to give you the
ultimate asymmetric Advantage because
sleep if you're young it's only actually
increase your height because you have
more human growth hormone if you're a
man it's going to increase your
testosterone make you more competitive
in the gym with women making money
everything if you're a woman it's even
more important for you because it helps
you regulate your cycle literally sleep
recharges your dopamine that's right
dopamine is not a toxin you should not
be doing a dopamine detox rather you
should be recharging dopamine and sleep
recharges dopamine the more dopamine you
have the more motivated you are and more
productivity you have per day it gives
you the ultimate unfair advantage in
life literally sleep affects the size of
your balls and the size of your dick if
that doesn't make you want to optimize
your sleep I don't know what's going to
do it for you book one the Sleep
environment the first thing is of course
your bed you need to have a non-toxic
bed I'm talking about a bed which is
completely made of organic substances
latex cotton wool your entire bed is
made of these and the funny thing is
when you make a bed out of these organic
substances it's almost naturally flame
retardant so you don't have to add
toxins in order to make a flame
retardant and the good thing is more and
more companies are coming out which are
making non-toxic products nowadays
you're able to find companies which
don't put toxins into their mattresses
now completely organic mattresses may be
outside your price range maybe you can
afford it in which case I had three
budget options first is the military
option a military cot it's a folding cut
which falls out doesn't have any toxins
in it and you can put a cotton liner on
top and then lay on top of the cotton
liner so your body is some completely
safe from any kind of toxin and the
second option is the samurai option it's
called a a tummy mat you can find these
things on Amazon you can find them in
many different sites it's basically a
Japanese strong mat and this is
literally what the samurai used
completely non-toxic safe to sleep on
highly recommend then we have the tribo
option this is just a simple straw mat
you just roll it out put a cotton liner
on top of it and there you go sleep on
the floor on that mat that's better for
you than these toxic mattresses are your
question now might be well these are too
uncomfortable to sleep on how do you
sleep on these things well I'll address
all those questions in the sleep posture
part of this guide but before we get
there what should you wear when you're
sleeping ideally nothing sleep naked
because your body is thermoregulations
which is a temperature regulation of
your body is very very important when
you sleep it's a huge role in whether
you get good quality sleep or not if you
sleep naked you're essentially ensuring
that your body has the ability to rid
itself with extra heat and get a better
quality sleep of course if you're not
able to sleep naked for some reason just
wear a cotton boxers cotton undershirt
something really light so it doesn't
impede your body's ability ability to
eject extra heat book two sleep posture
so what's the best way to sleep should
you sleep in your back your side your
belly don't sleep on your belly that's
the worst possible position you have two
options back or your side I prefer side
and here's the reason why all Apes sleep
on their side which shows that nature
has a preference for sleeping on its
side and also all pre-modern people so
literally like tribal people who have
not been influenced by modernity these
individuals sleep on their side why is
this the reason is the scientists have
found out that when you sleep in your
side the brain can actually detox itself
much better so the brain like the rest
of your body builds up toxins as you go
about the day but the difference is your
body can actually detox some of these
toxins into the bloodstream during the
day but the brain cannot do that the
brain can only detox during the night it
literally flushes the toxins into your
spinal fluid and the spinal fluid
carries these toxins to your body where
it gets purged it turns out that if
you're lying on your side it's actually
easier for the toxins to enter your
spinal fluid and get removed so humans
seem to have evolved to sleep on their
side so that this brain toxins are
removed more easily if you're going to
sleep on your side make sure you have a
pillow between your knees as you're
lying on your side the reason is it
opens up your hip angle a little bit
which is very important for better blood
flow and circulation also puts less
stress on your joints you're going to
figure it out by now that the spine
Integrity the Integrity of your spinal
column is very important for ensuring
that the brain becomes detoxified at the
end of this video I'll show you some
stretching practices to ensure that your
spine is ready to detox the brain I'm
literally a certified yoga instructor so
I know what I'm talking about another
thing when you're sleeping on your side
is your pillow probably never seen a
pillow like this why because its pillow
is height adjustable it's important
because when you're sleeping on your
side you don't want your neck to be kind
of like crane because it's going to hurt
your neck and also not going to allow
the blood flow required for the brain
detoxification so you need a pillow
which is about the same size of your
shoulder so that your neck remains
intact and is in line with your spine so
this pillow is called a buckwheat pillow
so it's another Japanese product it's
filled with something called buckwheat
so there's a zip on here which you can
actually open and you can take out some
of the buckwheat and put it in a
separate bag to reduce or increase the
height like if you had this bag it'll
obviously increase the height so why did
I choose this it's because I could have
chosen a foam pillow which I'm not going
to do because it's toxic I could have
chosen a cotton or down or wool kind of
pillow which is fine but it tends to
irritate my nose for some reason so
buckwheat is completely non-allergenic
so this is a good choice for those
people who have some kind of allergy to
Cotton wool down but regardless if
breathing at night is a problem for you
you need to watch my esoteric breathing
guide in which I break down different
ways to improve your breathing does this
mean you should never sleep on your back
actually no back is not bad so long as
you don't have any breathing issues if
you're sleeping in your back there's a
higher chance that you might be snoring
because of the throat being constricted
but if you don't have that issue then
back sleeping is not bad but make sure
that you have a pillow placed below your
knees again when you're sleeping on your
back so if this is you and you're
sleeping in your back you want a pillow
under your knees because it's going to
elevate your legs slightly and that also
helps you you purge your toxins better
so you have something called a lymphatic
system which is the toxin removal system
is going to work better if your feet are
slightly elevated and before I forget a
sleep mask or a sleep like iPad whatever
you want to call these things buy a silk
iPad which goes over your eyes and shuts
out the light very important for your
Sleep Quality make sure it's silk if you
can because two reasons one silk is very
good for your skin in the sense that
cotton might have some abrasive effect
but silk is actually pretty smooth so it
doesn't do anything to your skin and the
second reason is silk doesn't warm you
up so you are covering half your face
with the iPad obviously so you don't
want something which retains heat a lot
so cotton or wool iPads are not the best
option silk is the better option you
also should be using a silk pillowcase
or pillow cover why because again same
reasons you're going to be sleeping on
your side your face is in contact with
the silk for nine hours and you
certainly don't want an allergenic or
synthetic substance touching your face
for so long book three breathing sadly
the air we breed as humans to day is not
the air our ancestors used to breathe
you wouldn't need a HEPA filter if
you're in Ancient Rome or mohenjo daro
you only need a HEPA filter nowadays
because our air is hyper concentrated
with all kinds of pollutants pollen and
toxins so you need a HEPA filter in your
home to filter those out and mold mold
spores are pretty common in most
people's houses so that's another reason
people's nose get congested because it's
little mold going growing in your home
is a HEPA filter as you can see it has a
filter it has a fan so it's basically
sucking air through the sides purifying
it and then releasing it into my room
then you might want to consider having a
humidifier the air in your room is dry
this is going to help you moisturize
your nose and make sure that it's not
inflamed then this is a tip which my dad
gave me you can apply a single drop of
coconut oil in the inside of your nose
and this is going to prevent it from
drying out and prevent some inflammation
you're able to breathed better and get
better sleep and lastly tape over your
mouth right this is a common one just
apply a piece of medical tape over your
mouth so you're not mouth breathing this
is important not only for your sleep
quality but also for your facial
attractiveness like how symmetrical your
face is is dependent on how you breathe
so if you care about how you look which
everybody cares about how they look
consider having a piece of medical tape
over your mouth as you sleep book four
supplements first off melatonin is a
no-go melatonin is a psyop so first
thing all drugstore bought melatonin has
very poor quality control you have no
idea how much Melatonin is actually in
there second thing artificial melatonin
it's a melatonin you get in a bottle
that's going to interfere with your
actual natural melatonin production in
your pineal gland your pineal gland is
one of the most important parts of your
brain very delicate and important
structure in your brain produces
melatonin so I don't trust anything
which interferes with the function of
the pineal gland including fluoride in
our water if you want to know more about
that topic you should go to my fluoride
video one question you might have is
caffeine should you have caffeine does
it interfere with sleep well of course
it interferes with sleep so you should
only have caffeine in the morning one
hour after you wake up not immediately
immediately after you wake up that's
important because it prevents a caffeine
crash later on in the day but make sure
you aren't using one of those nasty ass
coffee machines the reason is it sends
the hot water through plastic tubes into
your coffee and even if the water is
pure because the hot water is running
through plastic tubes it's going to pick
up the talates from the plastic tube and
make your coffee estrogenic so be
careful there so what supplement can you
take to actually improve your sleep well
I got the solution for you the esoteric
sleep elixir
book five blue light you already know
this one I'm not gonna waste your time
blue light glasses do work to some
extent but you shouldn't be using your
screens and phone two hours before
sleeping I'll give you some information
which you didn't know watching the
sunset is actually an important part of
your sleep routine if you watch the
sunlight go down the way the wavelengths
interact with your eye informs your
brain at its sleep time and that
actually protects you from the blue
light radiation from your phones but
even more important than that is waking
up in the morning and actually stepping
outside your home and getting some
direct sunlight into your eyes no
sunglasses nothing guess you're outside
of the home and you're looking in the
direction of the sun you don't have to
literally look at the sun just look in
the direction of the sun this is very
very important because of three reasons
one it's going to recharge your dopamine
which is going to affect literally every
single component of your life and I'm
going to go into this in detail in the
next video I make which is going to be
the most important video I make called
your brain on porn I'm going to teach
you literally how to break your porn
addiction for the rest of your life and
a big component of that is a dopamine
recharge so getting sunlight early in
the morning is actually an important
part of that but not just for the
dopamine though getting sunlight in the
morning is going to purge your brain of
melatonin and adenosine which are not
bad compounds or anything but they're
sleep compounds so you don't really want
them in the morning sunlight will
literally reject all those from your
brain making you ready for the rest of
your day what about artificial light so
just like your lights would light up
your room during the night is that okay
actually no I have a programmable light
which I'll show you on screen it turns
red literally automatically turns red at
10 pm and it turns off automatically at
midnight for me I prefer midnight but
the ideal like the scientifically proven
best time to sleep is 10 pm find out
what works for you for me midnight seems
to work well so my light literally turns
red automatically at 10 pm it turns off
literally at midnight and in the morning
automatically turns on at 7 00 am which
signals my brain and my body and it's
time to wake up so that's right I don't
use an alarm I use this automatic light
as an alarm when the lights go on it
gives my body the cue to wake up and I
just gradually wake up naturally instead
of being Jarred awake by an alarm
because you don't sleep in a linear
fashion you sleep in a cycle and when
you have an alarm it might jar you out
of deep sleep and you'll just feel
groggy and tired for the rest of the day
so much better to use a light alarm
rather than an actual like sound alarm
in addition to the red light in my room
I'll also use candles or an oil lamp
instead of like actual lights but if
you're going to use a candle be sure
that it's a beeswax candle not one of
these artificial candles which have
scent in them because when you have a
scented candle these release toxins into
the air if you have a bird like if you
own Birds you'll know for a fact that
you should never have a scented candle
why because a birds literally die
because of the toxins present in your
scent of candles so it's literally a
canary in the coal mine type situation
book six mental game sometimes you can
have the perfect night routine and
everything but when you lay down to
sleep your thoughts just start racing
you know your mind is racing you're
thinking of past the present the future
you're making plans you're strategizing
and you simply aren't able to fall
asleep this is a common problem for me
and the way I got around this is by
using the techniques which I'm going to
show you right now but before we go into
the techniques the best way to actually
fall asleep is by closing all the loops
let me explain if you're an overthinker
if you're having racing thoughts at
night the reason why this is happening
is because you didn't have a productive
day there was a lot of things you wanted
to do during the day but you didn't get
them done for one reason or another your
brain leaves those Loops running so what
happens is your brain is constantly
thinking of ways to correct that you
know Finding ways to complete those
tasks but if you have an actually
productive day and you knock out all the
tasks that you intended to do your brain
closes all those loops and says to your
body it's time to sleep your brain
finally goes into wholesome beautiful
detoxifying sleep so I'll give you two
techniques both of them adapted from the
kind of the army technique which I was
taught in basic training which basically
allows you to communicate with your body
and tell it to not be in the fight or
flight mode and rather be in the rest
and relax mode it's not very surprising
that a soldier's life on the battlefield
can be extremely stressful and that's an
understatement so the Army actually came
up with sleep techniques to make sure
that soldiers and Pilots get good
quality sleep even if they are
chronically stressed I've modified these
a little bit and I'm going to give you
like a simplified and easy version which
is just as effective so this is a body
scan what you're doing is when you're
laying on your bed you're laying flat on
your bed so on your back and you have
the pillow under your knees like I
mentioned before you place one hand on
your chest and one hand on your belly as
you're lying flat on your back so you
can literally feel your breathing enter
your nose to your chest to your belly
and then out the same way and as you're
feeling your breathing what you're going
to do is a body scan so you're going to
start by thinking and focusing on the
top of your head and work your way down
to the base of your feet other people
say that you should start at the feet
and go to your head they're wrong this
is a better way to do it I promise so
you literally go body part by body part
so you start with your scalp your
forehead eyebrows eyes nose mouth
whatever it is your neck shoulders arms
body torso glutes ties calves feet you
think of each of these parts and you
essentially wish them well you wish them
relaxation and peace and you in fact
give these parts of your body gratitude
for doing such a great job during the
day this tells your body it's in rest
and relaxed mode it's essentially a way
you communicate between the mind and the
body and you do this through your
breathing so every time you're focusing
on a body part you're taking in a deep
breath and then visualizing the stress
leaving you as you breathe out like I
said the hands are placed on your chest
and belly so you can literally feel the
air going in and out and that is going
to relieve the stress from your body and
help you go to sleep in about 10 minutes
if you want me to cover more esoteric
topics like lucid dreaming let me know
in the comments another esoteric concept
is nsdr non-sleep deep rest which was
traditionally known for thousands and
tens of thousands of years as Yoga Nidra
which means yogic sleep essentially and
this is a science approved and tradition
approved rest practice which I'll have
to make a separate video because it's
essentially like a guided meditation you
aren't sleeping but you're deriving most
of the benefits of sleep you can do this
anytime including at night or the day
and it restores your dopamine and you
can increase your productivity like
crazy so make that separate video and
you can use that as a special resource
now going on to the topic of Dreams
should you pay any heed to dreams you
know I have personal opinion absolutely
yes in the modern world we've kind of
discarded the idea of Dreams nobody even
talks about dreams even in other sleep
related videos no one talks about dreams
it's almost like a non-scientific thing
but that's not true some of the greatest
inventions the greatest pieces of music
the greatest pieces of art have come
from the dreams of these artists hell
you know the movie Terminator apparently
came from James Cameron's dreams
literally the structure of DNA the
structure of benzene a million other
inventions have come from our dreams and
most probably you don't even dream do
you they did a very interesting
experiment on mice so they took a bunch
of mice put them through a maze and then
they had these like probes in their
brain recording every single like neural
impulse as they're going through the
Maze and then when they were sleeping
they put the probes back in to see what
they were dreaming about and sure enough
the mice were actually dreaming of their
Journey Through The Maze and here's
what's interesting they dreamed of going
through the maze linearly they dreamed
going backwards and they dreamed even
skipping portions off the maze
essentially they were doing a complex
problem-solving thing in their brain
during their dreams and finding out
alternate creative ways to navigate that
maze so a mouse can do that kind of
creative thinking then imagine what
power we have as human beings now
afternoon naps should you sleep during
the afternoon answer is actually yes
sleeping during the afternoon is known
to boost brain function mental health
mental Clarity everything however it may
not be practical for a lot of us in
which case it should resort to nsdr
which I mentioned before book Seven
waking up if you want an esoteric
morning routine guide let me know I'll
make video but for here I'll just say
the one thing which I already said
before you need to get out of your house
house and get some direct sunlight in
the morning that should be the most
important part of your morning routine
literally fixes other problems in your
life and also say something about diet
eat eggs eat mushrooms these ones have
vitamin D which your body synthesizes
and helps you regulate your circadian
rhythm by the way if you literally want
a biologist and somebody who's well
versed in history and philosophy to work
for you full time consider joining my
community the country club I will
literally give you the ultimate
asymmetric Advantage by giving you the
top tier science and tradition tools to
improve your health and not only that
I'll give you knowledge about history
and philosophy so that you not only
become healthier and stronger but also
become wiser and smarter links in the
description book 8 esoteric nighttime
routine a key component of your
nighttime routine needs to be regulating
your body temperature so here's what you
do you get yourself a little spray
bottle of water or of course you can
splash water from your sink you spray
your forearms with water and you spray
your face with water you spray your ears
and your neck with water this allows
your body to eject extra heat cools your
body down and it's very very important
for high quality sleep next thing you
should take your phone turn it
completely off and put it aside why
because your phone is always radiating
something called RF emws radio frequency
electromagnetic waves and these are
shown to be bad for living tissue it's
bad for your testosterone production
it's bad for your sperm production it's
bad for your heart it's bad for your
brain spending nine hours with a phone
next to you terrible idea put it aside
my guys and you know how I have the
psyak method using science intuition
observation and philosophy this is not
my observation or intuition this is
literally science showing you that your
phone is bad for you I literally linked
the studies in the description below if
you want to check them out book nine
visualization imagine it's 10 pm you've
already completed the day's tasks you've
had an immensely productive day
literally you're weeks ahead of your
12-week plan even though others haven't
seen the change you know that things are
getting serious momentum the automatic
red lights have come on you've completed
your sleep routine you've already had
your chamomile tea and you're feeling
slightly tired there's a slight bit of
soreness from the powerful workout you
completed earlier in the day you sit
down on your slightly cold bed you take
a deep breath and do a full body scan
every part of your body checks out as
fully operational and before you know it
you're asleep when you awake the next
day you feel massive energy surging
through your body you have a massive
erection you barely can piss because
your dick is so hard and when you manage
that you get a big drink of the
electrolyte Elixir and you step out into
the Sun the sunlight is a little bit
strong at first but your eyes adjust
then you feel an additional surge of
energy as you realize not a single task
today will be too difficult for you to
conquer everything will fall into place
as though by divine intervention for the
forces of chaos have no chance when the
forces of Heaven have got your back as I
told you the spine Integrity is the most
important part of your brain
detoxification as you sleep so I'm going
to show you the stretches which is going
to help with this first we're going to
start off in shivasana which is just
laying down so just laying down flat on
the mat
and you're going to do
exactly as I say so I am literally a
certified yoga instructor so I know what
I'm talking about so you lie down flat
on your back
and first thing
let out a nice deep breath so that
you're nice and controlled you're in the
present
it's actually important to get your mind
right when you're doing this that does
genuinely help with muscle relaxation
so once you're here
you're going to take your left leg
Point left toes upwards arms at a 45
degree angle to your torso
and you're going to drop the left leg
across your body
and your gaze is going to shift to the
opposite direction
you can use this offhand to secure your
knee it's up to you
and you'll spend some time here
and I'm trying to not let my shoulders
raise off the ground so I'm not letting
myself do something like this the
shoulders remain flat
and this is going to give you a nice
stretch on your glutes and of course
you're going to get a nice spinal twist
which is the objective then we use our
hand
to move the knee back to neutral
drop it down of course I'm going a
little bit fast because of the nature of
YouTube but you would take as much time
as you need you'll take your right leg
drop it across the body and move your
gaze to the opposite side
and spend some time here as long as it
feels comfortable to you
take your left hand
move the knee back
to neutral
drop it down
then you do a figure four stretch so
you'll get your left leg bent at the
knee take your right leg and actually
bend it across your left leg bringing
the right ankle to left knee and from
here we'll take our right hand and push
away
on the right knee so you get a nice
stretch on the hip flexor muscles
and of course you can actually take your
right hand pass it through the Gap clasp
left knee bring your left hand around
clasp left knee and bring the entire hip
girdle off the ground that's a nice big
glute stretch very very useful if you
spend a lot of time sitting and working
100 useful if you want a full video on
all the most effective stretches let me
know and I will make that it'll be
probably one of the most important
reasons I make because if you have a
good stretching routine
and you actually implement it day after
day it's genuinely a life-changing
addition to your life huge return on
investment so once you're done with your
figure four stretch
you can actually sit up
and get into a nice deep squat so deep
squat literally what it sounds like
you're going to sit down nice and deep
now if you are more experienced and you
can do crazy stuff like you know balance
on one leg and everything but you don't
need to do that a nice deep squat is
going to give you a lot of spine Bend
I'm allowing my lower back to bend it's
not like a weighted squat you're not
trying to maintain a squat position
you're actually trying to get as Loose
as possible
and then from here
we are going to go into a cobra sequence
so we'll start off
kind of in a push-up position arms are
by your chest level
your feet are pointed to the ground so
you're flat
you'll press up
and allow your hips to Sag so you're not
doing a push-up you're just doing a
cobra pose it's called and you're
letting your shoulders ride forward
and this is your Cobra post so it's kind
of the opposite of the deep squat right
it's stretching the spine in the
opposite direction so hold this for a
little bit as long as it's comfortable
for you
and drop it down
and then you'll go into a quad stretch
so just sit back
on your ankles so I'm not able to do
this properly because I took a Savage
kick to my left knee while kickboxing
then you're gonna take your hands place
them slightly behind you and then
lean backwards and open up your chest
very good for your spinal Integrity it's
also good for your shoulders and traps
and everything and then we go into a
child's pose which is the opposite
you'll start by putting your elbows in
the ground your forearms your palms your
forehead and this is a child's pose
you can increase the distance between
your knees and really sink into it it's
up to you spend as much time in this
position as you want it's a nice rest
position
then you'll walk it back come back to
where you were
and then I like to finish it off with a
massage gun so I got this Bob and Brad
massage guns literally you press this
button
and
I place it on my traps because trap is
where I tend to get tense
I'll put a link to it in the description
so I know I went a little bit fast and
that's because of the nature of this
particular video but if you want an
actual guide like an in-depth guide on
how to actually do the stuff properly
along with a morning stretch routine let
me know and I'll make it after my trip
to Europe that's right I'm actually
going to Portugal Spain France and Italy
and I'm going to be sharing my entire
Journey along with other forbidden
wisdom on my Instagram so you should
follow me there