one two please
when the media came for Hillary
you're under arrest it hurt her her
credibility with her base was destroyed
or at least weakened however when it
came to Donald Trump China China
the media could say whatever they wanted
but he would actually gain from it Trump
would actually get stronger when the
media attacked him Trump was
anti-fragile and Hillary was fragile
let's look at Damocles you see Damocles
was a hero or at least a character in
Greek mythology and he accepted
the Throne of his kingdom under the
condition
that a sword be suspended
over his head
and the sword was suspended by a single
length of horse hair
you see the slightest shock
and that sword will come crashing down
on his head and democles was
democles was fragile
and next we have the Phoenix you see
Phoenix is a mythical bird
what's so special about it is you can't
kill it
you can put the Phoenix through a wood
chipper and next dates back at work
you can put you can shoot the Phoenix in
the head in a couple hours you'll just
regenerate
but the Phoenix
never
gets any stronger so it's Phoenix it's a
robust system this is kind of fun
actually
shooting Outdoors instead inside yeah
I'm not going down this way I'll fall
guaranteed on a fragile system
all right down we go
next we're going to talk about
the learning Hydra the Hydra
the multi-headed beast from ancient
Greek mythology was what Hercules fought
so Hercules one of his tasks was to kill
the Hydra and when he was fighting it he
chopped off his head
but even shoved off that hydra's head
another grew into place
so the hydro is twice as strong
they cut off both heads another Hydra is
four times as strong cut off four heads
they have 16 heads 36 heads and every
time the Hydra was attacked it would go
stronger and stronger to the point even
the great Hercules could not fight the
Hydra so Hercules could no longer fight
with his strength he had to fight by
being strategic
which is something I highly Advocate on
this channel
Hercules decided to take
a burning hot sword a red hot sword
and then he would cauterize
this the next stumps of the Hydra so you
would cut off a hydra's head and then he
would burn it with that burning sword
and that would prevent it from growing a
new head
you see
Hercules to defeat the Hydra had to take
away the hydra's ability
to be anti-fragile he had to take away
the anti-fragile power of the Hydra in
order to win so at this point you might
be asking well why is this relevant to
you you're not Hercules you're not a
phoenix you're not Damocles how do you
become
anti-fragile well you already kind of
are
a healthy human being when he gets you
know the flu some other disease and
recovers from it would actually be
anti-fragile against it he'll be
stronger against that virus once he's
done recovering your immune system is an
example of an anti-fragile system the
next question is are your systems
fragile I've told you in a different
video that discipline is one part of
success but it's more important or at
least equally important to have success
systems in your life and these systems
need to be robust or even anti-fragile
so a common system which everybody on
YouTube always love to talk about is
monk mode you know the idea that you
give up a lot of things and you have to
make the sacrifices and be completely
disciplined for a couple months and
you'll find amazing success I have
nothing against monk mode but you have
to know that monk mode is a fragile
system when you break your discipline
you break your streak of Monk mode
immediately over your brain thinks you
know if you've already broken the streak
you've already messed up so you might as
well mess up more so what I find in monk
mode and also for my coaching clients is
they get on monk mode and then they mess
up you know they don't take their cold
shower one day or they go back to bad
habits like like porn or something I
mean once they've breached their
discipline
it becomes a Snowball Effect and they
just keep breaching their discipline and
that way monkey will never actually
works for them
or and it didn't even work for me
because it relied on perfect discipline
which is fragile the slightest break in
your discipline is gone and then the
rest of the system doesn't work so I'm
not a huge fan of monkboard anymore I
think the better option is to have
habits and systems which understand that
you do make mistakes do have breaches
and discipline and still Propel you
towards future success do you hear
the tree creaking
I feel like that branch is going to fall
off anytime
and then we have people who can be
anti-fragile a great example is Jordan
Peterson you know the entire media
establishment the whole university
system came after him called him you
know racist and bigoted and homophobic
and this and that but in the end you
know he actually Rose from that and now
he's more popular than ever and more
credible than ever because he was able
to stand up to his opposition
so he I believe is an anti-fragile
person
and of course entire nations can be
anti-fragile
best example I can think of is the Roman
Republic after the Second Punic War so
Hannibal Barca the finest military
general of History
carthaginian General he took his army
with elephants and marched them from the
north of Italy through the Alps
in winter
and came into the Roman Republic
completely by surprise with this whole
Army and and he was such a good General
he would just destroy Roman armies left
right and center with an army half their
size and the Romans the Romans would you
know they won't give up Romans in that
time period they don't know how to give
up they would send Army after Army
against Hannibal parka and they would
lose they would lose 60 000 men 80 000
men they would lose a whole part of
their population just in a day
but you see
the Roman Republic not the Roman Empire
at least in his later stages was
anti-fragile the Roman Republic
eventually defeated the genius General
Hannibal
and came out stronger on the other side
destroyed the carthaginian empire
insulted their fields raised their lands
erased Carthage from the records and
then they created an Empire
twice as strong that's an example of an
anti-fragile Nation
we especially in the West
are not by any means anti-fragile
we are extremely fragile yes the West is
strong yes the United States is strong
however deep mistakes made at higher
levels
have cost the country to be fragile I
don't believe despite its strength the
U.S is as robust as it once was
that's a different topic for a different
day
and now let's talk about the most
anti-frasal one of them all your
favorite top G Andrew freaking
Tate the man has
sexual assault charges on him and even
then and very well it's not a support or
dismissal of him even then his
popularity
doesn't shrink it just keeps growing
Andrew Tate has created himself to be
anti-fragile to the media in another
video I describe my hypothesis that I
under Trade probably jailed himself
using the Romanian Authority's
corruption in order to get massive
popularity by being the highest profile
case of a man being wrongfully
imprisoned and now I see that there's a
rumor of him getting cancer and then he
puts on his Twitter that he doesn't have
cancer but think about that who does
that rumor actually benefit it benefits
State doesn't it the sympathy wave
created by Him whether he actually has
cancer or not I don't know you know the
sympathy wave created by this is to his
benefit
that's high level strategy if my
hypothesis is true
you see good strategy is the ultimate
superpower
it was true back in Roman times and it's
true today he'll always be true
if you want help with your YouTube
strategy or your life strategy then you
should check out the link in the
description below if you think I can
help you oh and by the way I'm not
trying to take credit for coming up with
the concept of anti-fragility it was
actually by a mathematician Economist
very interesting person by the name of
Naseem Nicholas taleb and Talib he made
massive wealth in creating I believe it
is Forex Trading and then he decides to
be a mathematician and Economist and
comes up with this idea of
anti-fragility and among other
interesting ideas like ergodicity and
you can read more about it in his book
anti-fragility very interesting guy and
I think he is the one who came up with
the term [ __ ] you money so if these are
topics that you would like me to talk
about please let me know
[Music]
thank you