years after its first gay pride Edition
the mainstream narrative is that the
rise of the presence of LGBT individuals
is because of the heroic efforts of the
activists this is not true this is not
true because this phenomenon is just as
true for humans as it is in the animal
kingdom across the planets all animals
especially the marine animals who are
most exposed to endocrine disrupting
chemicals or exhibiting anomalies
anomalies in both their physiology so
their body their reproductive parts but
also their behaviors this is very much
in line with the most recent science to
do with endocrine disrupting chemicals
for many species this is an existential
threat and so it is with humans sperm
quality and quantity have dropped by 50
in just 50 years in another 50 years
it's going to drop by another 50 percent
most men will not get to be fathers only
a selective group of men who have the
resources and the knowledge will have
the ability to Father kids and it's even
worse it's even worse for women the rate
of miscarriage that is the child dying
in the womb has almost doubled in that
same time frame imagine how terrible a
miscarriage truly is the room and the
mother who literally has to carry the
dead corpse of her unborn child
to birth imagine the level of trauma
that inflicts on a woman and this is
only getting worse year by year as we're
exposed to more and more toxins in our
environment we are all suffering men are
being faced with depression at an
unprecedented rate they are engaging in
self-harm and even self-delution at a
rate never before seen on the face of
the Earth in the history of mankind and
all we do is we harp about mental health
awareness week without connecting this
issue back to testosterone the science
on this is very clear and has been for
decades and here we are walking around
with the green ribbon because we're
aware of mental health this is not the
way we're in this together men women
liberals and conservatives straight and
even the LGBT community because they are
not to blame for any of this they were
as infants as infants in the womb they
were exposed to these endocrine
disrupting chemicals how can we possibly
have any hate or any animosity towards
these individuals it doesn't make sense
they are not the enemy they never were
the enemy and they don't deserve any
blame for this the Liberals and the
conservatives are tearing the nation
apart while the real villains laugh in
the distance everybody is struggling men
with depression women with anxiety the
LGBT individuals with their own identity
issues we were poisoned at Birth and
after birth why are young boys
prescribed with mind-numbing drugs just
because they act in the exact way that
nature prescribed them to act in why are
young girls being prescribed with birth
control drugs just to cure their acne do
you know what is meant by bread and
circuses the Roman emperors would spend
their entire treasury on free handouts
they would spend it on meaningless
entertainment because if the populace if
the citizenry knew of the crimes they
had committed it would be their head on
a spike the multinational companies and
the government are not here for us and
the scientists will not be able to solve
the problem because it'll be too late by
the time they devise some magical
solution it's up to us to take things
into our own hands we must learn to make
better buying decisions we must
understand what is toxic and what is not
we must spur the growth of a whole new
economy we must start with ourself our
friends and our families fixing
ourselves mentally physically and
spiritually and hormonally this is not
some concealed attack on the lgbtq I'm
somewhat of a Libertarian in the sense
that if you leave me alone I'll leave
you alone but I understand that some
people genuinely dislike or even hate
the LGBT but what happens if you are one
of those individuals and your child is
born intersex what are you gonna do hate
him hate her
good luck with that and what if you're a
hardcore feminist woman and you have a
miscarriage because of exposure to the
edcs what are you gonna do blame the
patriarchy I'd like to see you try you
see we are truly in this together
whether we like it or not we are on the
same ship and it is sinking fast they
don't care if you're black or white
Latino Or Hispanic or gay or straight
nothing matters so long as you're a good
Cog in the machine but imagine this
imagine a society where we are all
immune to psychological operations we're
all maxed out on our health both mental
physical and spiritual and hormonal
imagine we're raising kids to be even
more strong and resilient than we ever
were imagine we could put down our
differences just for a moment and gaze
upon the powers that be they will
tremble in fear for we are their worst
nightmare
[Music]
[Applause]
all right
foreign
[Applause]