300 is the movie the Greeks themselves
would have made it perfectly encapsulate
the Greek mindset and indeed this is why
the dark film critics still fro at the
mouth when they hear the name of
Leonidas and his 300 Spartans even the
history nerds will often spaz out when
they hear about the movie 300 cuz
they'll say things like oh but the
Spartans wore heavy bronze armor they
weren't half naked while they fought at
thermopolymerization
they try to fight as much as possible in
a shield wall formation but all this
misses the point because if you look at
the actual artwork created by the Greeks
on Wes you'll find that they portray the
Spartans fighting exactly like how they
do in the movie they show Spartans and
other Greeks fighting one-on-one they
showed them fighting half naked if not
fully naked in this video you're going
to see a completely contrarian take on
the movie 300 not only that but you'll
also receive answers to such questions
as why modern historians push the agenda
that the Greeks were gay so hard and
does it have any basis in reality you
also gain new insights about how
democracy in the Greek World actually
works and you'll even get a brief
introduction to the art of understanding
history and Civics but trust me this is
no history lesson this is about the
Spartan mindset and what we can learn
from them not only about Society at
large but how we can improve ourselves
you see most people don't know this but
the movie 300 is 100% accurate to the
mindset that the Greeks had and no movie
like 300 will ever be made again think
about this the modern Hollywood society
would never make a movie glorifies honor
Duty courage and individual action they
would never make a movie which shows
that it is okay to fight for one's own
people and even when 300 was released
most critics did not support that movie
when they aired that movie in the Berlin
Film Festival a lot of these neroid
critics actually got up and left cuz
they couldn't tolerate what they were
watching on screen the only inaccurate
thing about the movie 300 is that
Leonidas was actually 60 years old at
the time of the battle of theropo you
see at the time of this battle old man
Leonidas was old as your grandfather and
yet he could absolutely outrun you he
could outfight you he could outlift you
and here's the thing he could probably
outthink you these men were better than
us almost every single metric in this
video I seek to answer the question why
is it that the Spartans captur the male
psyche so well at the sight of the
battle of theropo there's an Epitaph and
what it says is tell the Spartans passer
by that here by Spartan law they lie but
the story of the 300 Spartans doesn't
start there the story of the Greco
Persian War starts decades earlier at
the Battle of Marathon and some of you
might have heard the story of the
marathon Race how it started that the
Greek Runner runs for what is it 26
miles and then he collapses dead but
this is not the full story of the
marathon Race you see the battle was
fought at this beach called Marathon
Persians made their landing at this
beach and the Athenians were waiting for
them you see the Athenians not the
Spartans were completely outnumbered by
the Persian Force what the Persians
expected them to do was to hold up in
the city of Athens which had walls at
the time and just you know Siege it out
but the Athenians had another plan they
would wait in Ambush they would would
wait for the Persian forces to land at
the beach and before the Persians had
the chance to get out of their boats and
really set themselves up they would
attack immediately pushing them back
into the ocean and this day did imagine
if you're a Persian Soldier you get out
of your boat you know your ship with
your horses and whatnot after months of
travel your seasick you haven't walked
or exercised properly in months and now
you suddenly see on the horizon a tide
of bronze Shields coming at you with
everything they've got it must have been
a terrifying sight and absolutely the
Athenians slaughtered them and
immediately after this pitched back ATT
they marched 26 miles back to the city
of Athens to prevent another attack on
their city and you have to understand
these weren't the special forces of
Athens these were just the citizen
soldiers of Athens this was her everyday
citizen of Athens performing a feat a
military feat and a physical feat as
great as anything which our best special
operators would struggle to do that's
right the average Athenian citizen was
as good as our special forces and Navy
Seals and speaking of the Athenians as
the Spartans were demolishing the
Persian Army at the mopi the Athenians
were sending the Persian Fleet to the
bottom of the ocean at salamis decades
later when the Persians decided to
resume their attack and this time go
through the mountain passes they had the
terrible misfortune of meeting Leonidas
and his 300 each of the 300 was an apex
predator each and every Warrior of them
could absolutely lead troops in battle
they could conduct CT operations they
could fight hand to hand or they can
fight in formation they could conduct
night raids or they could form Shield
wall but here's the thing each of them
was trained also in ret public speaking
writing reading Civics history culture
religion debate and logic these weren't
just soldiers these were the citizen
Elite of Sparta and each of them was
considered a warrior monk a sword Saint
they not only honed their skill at War
and physical Prest they also hone their
mind to Perfection you see this is what
I consider to be the classical man the
Spartans were famed across the
mediterian for being quick witted and
well spoken not in the sense that they
could debate for long hours or give huge
speeches no they were Fame for being tur
your Fame for saying the minimum amount
of words to make the Maximum Impact this
requires a mind as Keen as their swords
you couldn't bribe them you couldn't
bargain with them you couldn't scop them
and you couldn't manipulate them and
certainly you couldn't threaten them
when Philip II the father of Alexander
came to conquer Sparta what he says is
if I conquer you I will destroy your
city I will enslave your women I will
kill your children and the Spartans
reply with just one word if and even in
the movie they do a good job of showing
this when the Persian messenger comes
and says says you know our arrows will
blot out the Sun the Spartans simply say
okay cool we'll fight in the shade but
now you think these Spartans were always
you know Dow and tur always talking
about discipline and warfare but I don't
think this is true I think if you look
at the elite soldiers of today if you
look at the way Navy Seals Army SF
Rangers conduct themselves they aren't a
bunch of strict disciplinarians who only
focus on discipline discipline
discipline they're actually really funny
they're actually really good socially
they can absolutely hang out they can
drink they can party they enjoy life and
indeed the more Elite the soldiers the
better Bond and Brotherhood they have
with each other they have their own
internal language their own internal
Words which only they understand they
have these unique experiences which no
Outsider can really respect and only by
really joining a part of these SF teams
or Navy SEAL Teams whatever it is can
you truly be a part of them the spec op
guys are some of the least neurotic
people on the entire planet they've
mastered so many skills that they've
gotten to a point of immense perfect
confidence in themselves this means they
practically have zero anxiety not only
do they know that they can fight it out
in the field they also know they can
survive indefinitely out there they know
that if somebody gets shot they can
patch them up often times these guys are
competent in multiple languages I
suspect that after a Spartan goes
through the initial training phase after
that it's not a bad life probably after
that the adult Spartan who are already
initiated into the order they would just
work out train on weapons play sports
get massages Under the Sun and then go
back to their wives even in the movie
they show this when the Persian arrows
come flying down the Spartans get under
their shield and they're just laughing
this is exactly how modern SF would have
reacted to the same situation now moving
to a different topic within this a lot
of film critics and articles have come
out criticizing the Spartans in fact
criticizing the idea that the Spartans
should be respected and should occupy
such a big space in the cultural
Zeitgeist they said that Spartans can
only do what they could do you know be
full-time soldiers because they had
slaves and slavery is bad therefore
Spartan society should not be remembered
tons of movie reviews and historical
fact Checkers and article writers always
criticize the Spartans because they had
slav they say the Spartans are
hypocritical when the movie shows them
to be fighting for Freedom when the
Spartans themselves had a whole bunch of
slaves yes the Spartans had slaves but
they were not hypocritical you see the
Spartans didn't believe in Freedom as an
abstraction they didn't care about
Freedom as some Universal concept or a
human right they only cared about their
own freedom and went through atrocious
lengths to preserve that they knew that
freedom isn't free and it's only paid by
Blood now the lesson from this is not
that slavery is good The Lesson from
this is very specific and this is the
lesson of history at large you see
history has one iron rule the strong
take what they will and the weak must
suffer what they must this is the
Ironclad rule of history there are no
exceptions to this rule our modern
ethics saying yes slavery is bad is
completely inconsequential the only
thing of consequence is can we enforce
that or not it doesn't matter if you
condemn the Spartans for having slaves
or not I want you to understand that
Concepts like freedom and human rights
only have any meaning so long as the
power of violence is used to enforce
their presence and indeed in a society
where most men are scoped into
degeneracy and imbecility the powers
that be can use these Concepts like
civil liberties and freedom and human
rights to perpetuate the exact opposite
of what these Concepts truly mean the
same us which supposedly goes to war for
human rights abuses commits those exact
same abuses and any dork film critic who
wants to criticize as Spartans for
holding slaves where there is slavery
today there is slavery in many parts of
the globe who do you think built the
skyscrapers of Dubai who do you think
makes up the workforce of countries like
Oman there's slavery out there today if
you care about the topic so much then
why don't you go and fight them that's
right these film critics and all these
leftists who rage against slavery they
don't actually do anything about it do
they because again the iron law of
History states that the strong take what
they will and the weak must suffer what
they must all this means is you and I
must be at the level of capability to
protect our own freedoms that's the true
lesson which is taught by Spartans
holding slaves if you don't want to be a
slave then you have to be able to rise
up against your Masters while yes the
Ultimate Force is always physical
violence that is always to be treated as
the last possible Resort if you feel
like your country is being led astray
and if you remain silent then you are a
part of the problem coming back to the
question of why it is that the Spartans
captured the psyche so well it's because
people that have pride in themselves and
indeed prioritize their own Freedom not
as an abstraction but rather as a true
need in the blood these people are not
to be subjugated they will pay any cost
cost in blood for their freedom
Extinction is preferable to subjugation
for such peoples and of course the
Greeks and the SPs were not the only
people like this the Germanic tribes
across the danu would rather die to a
man rather than being subjugated by the
Romans many Native American tribes would
rather perish than be yolked by the
white man did not porus the Elephant
King of India rather fight than
subjugate himself to Alexander who
literally conquered the rest of the
Known World this is the kind of attitude
that I want to instill upon the individ
idual and therefore have an effect on
Society at large the core of all this is
simply to say that rights and freedoms
only have any meaning if you're willing
to use them and indeed bleed for them if
need be and I want you to be completely
Incorruptible as the Spartans were when
the Persians offered to the Spartans
endless gold all the land of Greece and
to make the Spartan King the warlord of
all Greece the Spartans refuse when the
Persians asked them to lay down their
arms the Spartan simply hold on to their
weapons and say come and take them and
indeed for example even in modern times
the the US didn't gain its independence
through peaceful protest now did it I'd
argue that the fundamental freedoms of
the United States citizen rests not upon
the First Amendment but the second if
you're interested in Greek and Roman
history you'll often come across this
line of argument that homosexuality was
very much common in Greece this is an
utter sop completely false completely BS
this line of argument was completely
fabricated by modern historians the
evidence for this is so sparse okay you
don't understand so the big evidence
which these kind of historians Point
towards is a few artworks which may
portray homosexuality but it's utter
nonsense among a huge volume of art
maybe one or two a very tiny fraction
show anything that could be considered
homosexuality and what's the thing is
this isn't between two men usually it's
between mythological creatures like
saturs it's very bizarre that they could
take one or two random artworks and
claimed that yes Greek was this LGBT
Paradise if you want to know more about
this specific topic a link to a video
down below modern writers even push this
idea that Achilles was gay absolutely
pathetic this is this is why this
happens all right the legendary
friendship between Achilles and patrus
is made to seem as a gay relationship
because the writers the modern nerd
historian cannot even conceive that such
a friendship could be truly a friendship
because such friendships don't even
exist today such a deep bond between two
men is immediately made suspicious it's
immediately made trans transactional and
immediately made carnal but this
reflects not the Greeks but rather the
poverty of our current historical
community and indeed the poverty of our
society which doesn't have that kind of
friendship anymore and indeed strong
bonds between young men is the most
powerful and indeed most destabilizing
factor in a stagnant Society this is one
of the reasons why the modern film
critic hates this movie so much and this
is the reason why you and I enjoy this
movie so much cuz we feel it in our
blood we know in our bones that this is
how it was meant to be and for this
reason I give the movie 300 a 4.5
Corinthian Helms out of five why only
4.5 why not just a total score of five
out of five because there's this stupid
plotline in this movie of the Spartan
Queen you see like I said before I have
a lot of respect for Spartan women they
were very very capable but in this movie
all the queen really does is sleeps with
another man while her husband is out
fighting for her freedom and the idea is
she did this in order to help him
because to send a Greek army to support
him but even this doesn't really work it
completely backfires and she ends up
having to steal a sword from the
traitorous Senator and going to stab him
and it only works because that
traitorous Senator had Persian coins in
his wallet so everybody knew that he was
a traitor instantly this is a stupid
plotline and it does a lot of Injustice
to the True Glory of the Spartan wom it
almost shows it as though Spartan
woman's only weapon was to use sex but
that's not true Spartan women were as
smart and cunning as Spartan men so they
could have had a better flot line for
that which is why I give it a 4.5 out of
five but now the final question is
Spartan society to be emulated was it
perfect hardly I can prove it to you in
the historical context bartan Society
was so traditional and so aifi that they
were becoming militarily inefficient
after the Greco Persian War when the
Persians had been beaten and sent away a
new war started a war between Athens and
Sparta and Sparta was on the losing side
Athens was almost going to win the
Athenians had a better economy they were
modernizing faster they had better
technology they had more scholarship
they had everything going for them and
because the Spartans stuck to their
tradition so much they weren't able to
make progress and in the end the
Spartans only won against the Athenians
because they literally took money from
the Persians to do it so no absolutely
Sparta is not perfect as a society
because Sparta would have literally lost
against Athens if it wasn't for the
bribes that they took from the Persians
and also a devastating plague which hit
the Athenian so wise man looks at
history understands what's going on
takes the parts which he should copy and
rejects the parts that he should not and
you know I'll tell you something funny
about this video like very meta right so
when I was writing the script for this
video which was a couple months ago I
happened to look up the date of the
battle of theropo as part of the
research and it happened just by pure
coincidence happened to be the same date
as when I was writing the script which
you know how what a coincidence right I
see that as a good omen